<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>v</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>v</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>V
     
        Upper case V, {ASCII} character 86, known in {INTERCAL} as
        book.
     
        1. A testbed for distributed system research.
     
        2. Wide-spectrum language used in the knowledge-based
        environment {CHI}.  "Research on Knowledge-Based Software
        Environments at Kestrel Inst", D.R.  Smith et al, IEEE Trans
        Soft Eng SE-11(11):1278-1295 (1985).
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>v</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>V \V\ (v[=e]).
   1. V, the twenty-second letter of the English alphabet, is a
      vocal consonant. V and U are only varieties of the same
      character, U being the cursive form, while V is better
      adapted for engraving, as in stone. The two letters were
      formerly used indiscriminately, and till a comparatively
      recent date words containing them were often classed
      together in dictionaries and other books of reference (see
      {U}). The letter V is from the Latin alphabet, where it
      was used both as a consonant (about like English w) and as
      a vowel. The Latin derives it from it from a form (V) of
      the Greek vowel [Upsilon] (see {Y}), this Greek letter
      being either from the same Semitic letter as the digamma F
      (see {F}), or else added by the Greeks to the alphabet
      which they took from the Semitic. Etymologically v is most
      nearly related to u, w, f, b, p; as in vine, wine;
      avoirdupois, habit, have; safe, save; trover, troubadour,
      trope. See U, F, etc.
      [1913 Webster] See Guide to Pronunciation, [sect] 265;
      also [sect][sect] 155, 169, 178-179, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. As a numeral, V stands for five, in English and Latin.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>v</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>v
     adj : being one more than four [syn: {five}, {5}]
     n 1: a unit of potential equal to the potential difference
          between two points on a conductor carrying a current of
          1 ampere when the power dissipated between the two
          points is 1 watt; equivalent to the potential difference
          across a resistance of 1 ohm when 1 ampere of current
          flows through it [syn: {volt}]
     2: a soft silvery white toxic metallic element used in steel
        alloys; it occurs in several complex minerals including
        carnotite and vanadinite [syn: {vanadium}, {atomic number
        23}]
     3: the cardinal number that is the sum of four and one [syn: {five},
         {5}, {cinque}, {quint}, {quintet}, {fivesome}, {quintuplet},
         {pentad}, {fin}, {Phoebe}, {Little Phoebe}]
     4: the 22nd letter of the Roman alphabet
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
