<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>value</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>value</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>value
     
        {brightness}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>value</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Value \Val"ue\, n. [OF. value, fr. valoir, p. p. valu, to be
   worth, fr. L. valere to be strong, to be worth. See
   {Valiant}.]
   1. The property or aggregate properties of a thing by which
      it is rendered useful or desirable, or the degree of such
      property or sum of properties; worth; excellence; utility;
      importance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye are all physicians of no value.    --Job xiii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye are of more value than many sparrows. --Matt. x.
                                                  31.
      [1913 Webster]

            C[ae]sar is well acquainted with your virtue,
            And therefore sets this value on your life.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Before events shall have decided on the value of the
            measures.                             --Marshall.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Trade &amp; Polit. Econ.) Worth estimated by any standard of
      purchasing power, especially by the market price, or the
      amount of money agreed upon as an equivalent to the
      utility and cost of anything.
      [1913 Webster]

            An article may be possessed of the highest degree of
            utility, or power to minister to our wants and
            enjoyments, and may be universally made use of,
            without possessing exchangeable value. --M'Culloch.
      [1913 Webster]

            Value is the power to command commodities generally.
                                                  --A. L. Chapin
                                                  (Johnson's
                                                  Cys.).
      [1913 Webster]

            Value is the generic term which expresses power in
            exchange.                             --F. A.
                                                  Walker.
      [1913 Webster]

            His design was not to pay him the value of his
            pictures, because they were above any price.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In political economy, value is often distinguished as
         intrinsic and exchangeable. Intrinsic value is the same
         as utility or adaptation to satisfy the desires or
         wants of men. Exchangeable value is that in an article
         or product which disposes individuals to give for it
         some quantity of labor, or some other article or
         product obtainable by labor; as, pure air has an
         intrinsic value, but generally not an exchangeable
         value.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. Precise signification; import; as, the value of a word;
      the value of a legal instrument --Mitford.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Esteem; regard. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            My relation to the person was so near, and my value
            for him so great                      --Bp. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.) The relative length or duration of a tone or note,
      answering to quantity in prosody; thus, a quarter note [?]
      has the value of two eighth notes [?].
      [1913 Webster]

   6. In an artistical composition, the character of any one
      part in its relation to other parts and to the whole; --
      often used in the plural; as, the values are well given,
      or well maintained.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Valor. [Written also {valew}.] [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   8.
      (a) That property of a color by which it is distinguished
          as bright or dark; luminosity.
      (b) Degree of lightness as conditioned by the presence of
          white or pale color, or their opposites.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Math.) Any particular quantitative determination; as, a
      function's value for some special value of its argument.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. [pl.] The valuable ingredients to be obtained by
       treatment from any mass or compound; specif., the
       precious metals contained in rock, gravel, or the like;
       as, the vein carries good values; the values on the
       hanging walls.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Value received}, a phrase usually employed in a bill of
      exchange or a promissory note, to denote that a
      consideration has been given for it. --Bouvier.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>value</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Value \Val"ue\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Valued}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Valuing}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To estimate the value, or worth, of; to rate at a certain
      price; to appraise; to reckon with respect to number,
      power, importance, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mind doth value every moment.     --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The queen is valued thirty thousand strong. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king must take it ill,
            That he's so slightly valued in his messenger.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Neither of them valued their promises according to
            rules of honor or integrity.          --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To rate highly; to have in high esteem; to hold in respect
      and estimation; to appreciate; to prize; as, to value one
      for his works or his virtues.
      [1913 Webster]

            Which of the dukes he values most.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To raise to estimation; to cause to have value, either
      real or apparent; to enhance in value. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Some value themselves to their country by jealousies
            of the crown.                         --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be worth; to be equal to in value. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The peace between the French and us not values
            The cost that did conclude it.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To compute; rate; appraise; esteem; respect; regard;
        estimate; prize; appreciate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>value</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>value
     n 1: a numerical quantity measured or assigned or computed; "the
          value assigned was 16 milliseconds"
     2: the quality (positive or negative) that renders something
        desirable or valuable; "the Shakespearean Shylock is of
        dubious value in the modern world"
     3: the amount (of money or goods or services) that is
        considered to be a fair equivalent for something else; "he
        tried to estimate the value of the produce at normal
        prices" [syn: {economic value}]
     4: relative darkness or lightness of a color; "I establish the
        colors and principal values by organizing the painting
        into three values--dark, medium...and light"-Joe Hing Lowe
     5: (music) the relative duration of a musical note [syn: {time
        value}, {note value}]
     6: an ideal accepted by some individual or group; "he has
        old-fashioned values"
     v 1: fix or determine the value of; assign a value to; "value the
          jewelry and art work in the estate"
     2: hold dear; "I prize these old photographs" [syn: {prize}, {treasure},
         {appreciate}]
     3: regard highly; think much of; "I respect his judgement"; "We
        prize his creativity" [syn: {respect}, {esteem}, {prize},
        {prise}] [ant: {disrespect}, {disrespect}]
     4: place a value on; judge the worth of something; "I will have
        the family jewels appraised by a professional" [syn: {measure},
         {evaluate}, {valuate}, {assess}, {appraise}]
     5: estimate the value of; "How would you rate his chances to
        become President?"; "Gold was rated highly among the
        Romans" [syn: {rate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
