<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>valve</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>valve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>valve
     
        &lt;electronics&gt; UK term for a {vacuum tube}.
     
        (1996-01-10)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>valve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Valve \Valve\, n. [L. valva the leaf, fold, or valve of a door:
   cf. F. valve.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A door; especially, one of a pair of folding doors, or one
      of the leaves of such a door.
      [1913 Webster]

            Swift through the valves the visionary fair
            Repassed.                             --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Heavily closed, . . . the valves of the barn doors.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lid, plug, or cover, applied to an aperture so that by
      its movement, as by swinging, lifting and falling,
      sliding, turning, or the like, it will open or close the
      aperture to permit or prevent passage, as of a fluid.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A valve may act automatically so as to be opened by the
         effort of a fluid to pass in one direction, and closed
         by the effort to pass in the other direction, as a
         clack valve; or it may be opened or closed by hand or
         by mechanism, as a screw valve, or a slide valve.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Anat.) One or more membranous partitions, flaps, or
      folds, which permit the passage of the contents of a
      vessel or cavity in one direction, but stop or retard the
      flow in the opposite direction; as, the ileocolic, mitral,
      and semilunar valves.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bot.)
      (a) One of the pieces into which a capsule naturally
          separates when it bursts.
      (b) One of the two similar portions of the shell of a
          diatom.
      (c) A small portion of certain anthers, which opens like a
          trapdoor to allow the pollen to escape, as in the
          barberry.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.) One of the pieces or divisions of bivalve or
      multivalve shells.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Air valve}, {Ball valve}, {Check valve}, etc. See under
      {Air}. {Ball}, {Check}, etc.

   {Double-beat valve}, a kind of balance valve usually
      consisting of a movable, open-ended, turban-shaped shell
      provided with two faces of nearly equal diameters, one
      above another, which rest upon two corresponding seats
      when the valve is closed.

   {Equilibrium valve}.
      (a) A balance valve. See under {Balance}.
      (b) A valve for permitting air, steam, water, etc., to
          pass into or out of a chamber so as to establish or
          maintain equal pressure within and without.

   {Valve chest} (Mach.), a chamber in which a valve works;
      especially (Steam Engine), the steam chest; -- called in
      England {valve box}, and {valve casing}. See {Steam
      chest}, under {Steam}.

   {Valve face} (Mach.), that part of the surface of a valve
      which comes in contact with the {valve seat}.

   {Valve gear}, or {Valve motion} (Steam Engine), the system of
      parts by which motion is given to the valve or valves for
      the distribution of steam in the cylinder. For an
      illustration of one form of valve gear, see {Link motion}.
      

   {Valve seat}. (Mach.)
      (a) The fixed surface on which a valve rests or against
          which it presses.
      (b) A part or piece on which such a surface is formed.

   {Valve stem} (Mach.), a rod attached to a valve, for moving
      it.

   {Valve yoke} (Mach.), a strap embracing a slide valve and
      connecting it to the valve stem.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>valve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>valve
     n 1: a structure in a hollow organ (like the heart) with a flap
          to insure one-way flow of fluid through it
     2: device in a brass wind instrument for varying the length of
        the air column to alter the pitch of a tone
     3: control consisting of a mechanical device for controlling
        the flow of a fluid
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
