<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>veil</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vail \Vail\, v. t. [Aphetic form of avale. See {Avale}, {Vale}.]
   [Written also {vale}, and {veil}.]
   1. To let fail; to allow or cause to sink. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Vail your regard
            Upon a wronged, I would fain have said, a maid!
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lower, or take off, in token of inferiority, reverence,
      submission, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            France must vail her lofty-plumed crest! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Without vailing his bonnet or testifying any
            reverence for the alleged sanctity of the relic.
                                                  --Sir. W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vail \Vail\, v. i.
   To yield or recede; to give place; to show respect by
   yielding, uncovering, or the like. [Written also {vale}, and
   {veil}.] [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Thy convenience must vail to thy neighbor's necessity.
                                                  --South.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Veil \Veil\ (v[=a]l), n. [OE. veile, OF. veile, F. voile, L.
   velum a sail, covering, curtain, veil, probably fr. vehere to
   bear, carry, and thus originally, that which bears the ship
   on. See {Vehicle}, and cf. {Reveal}.] [Written also {vail}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Something hung up, or spread out, to intercept the view,
      and hide an object; a cover; a curtain; esp., a screen,
      usually of gauze, crape, or similar diaphnous material, to
      hide or protect the face.
      [1913 Webster]

            The veil of the temple was rent in twain. --Matt.
                                                  xxvii. 51.
      [1913 Webster]

            She, as a veil down to the slender waist,
            Her unadorn['e]d golden tresses wore. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A cover; disguise; a mask; a pretense.
      [1913 Webster]

            [I will] pluck the borrowed veil of modesty from the
            so seeming Mistress Page.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.)
      (a) The calyptra of mosses.
      (b) A membrane connecting the margin of the pileus of a
          mushroom with the stalk; -- called also {velum}.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Eccl.) A covering for a person or thing; as, a nun's
      veil; a paten veil; an altar veil.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.) Same as {Velum}, 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To take the veil} (Eccl.), to receive or be covered with, a
      veil, as a nun, in token of retirement from the world; to
      become a nun.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Veil \Veil\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Veiled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Veiling}.] [Cf. OF. veler, F. voiler, L. velarc. See {Veil},
   n.] [Written also {vail}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To throw a veil over; to cover with a veil.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her face was veiled; yet to my fancied sight,
            Love, sweetness, goodness, in her person shined.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: To invest; to cover; to hide; to conceal.
      [1913 Webster]

            To keep your great pretenses veiled.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Caul \Caul\ (k[add]l), n. [OE. calle, kelle, prob. fr. F. cale;
   cf. Ir. calla a veil.]
   1. A covering of network for the head, worn by women; also, a
      net. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Anat.) The fold of membrane loaded with fat, which covers
      more or less of the intestines in mammals; the great
      omentum. See {Omentum}.
      [1913 Webster]

            The caul serves for the warming of the lower belly.
                                                  --Ray.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A part of the amnion, one of the membranes enveloping the
      fetus, which sometimes is round the head of a child at its
      birth; -- called also a {veil}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            It is deemed lucky to be with a caul or membrane
            over the face. This caul is esteemed an infallible
            preservative against drowning . . . According to
            Chrysostom, the midwives frequently sold it for
            magic uses.                           --Grose.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was born with a caul, which was advertised for
            sale, in the newspapers, at the low price of fifteen
            guineas.                              --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>veil
     n 1: a garment that covers the head and face [syn: {head covering}]
     2: the inner embryonic membrane of higher vertebrates
        (especially when covering the head at birth) [syn: {caul},
         {embryonic membrane}]
     3: a vestment worn by a priest at High Mass in the Roman
        Catholic Church; a silk shawl [syn: {humeral veil}]
     v 1: to obscure, or conceal with or as if with a veil; "women in
          Afghanistan veil their faces" [ant: {unveil}]
     2: make undecipherable or imperceptible by obscuring or
        concealing; "a hidden message"; "a veiled threat" [syn: {obscure},
         {blot out}, {obliterate}, {hide}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
