<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>vein</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vein</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vein \Vein\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Veined}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Veining}.]
   To form or mark with veins; to fill or cover with veins.
   --Tennyson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vein</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vein \Vein\, n. [OE. veine, F. veine, L. vena.]
   1. (Anat.) One of the vessels which carry blood, either
      venous or arterial, to the heart. See {Artery}, 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) One of the similar branches of the framework of a
      leaf.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) One of the ribs or nervures of the wings of
      insects. See {Venation}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Geol. or Mining) A narrow mass of rock intersecting other
      rocks, and filling inclined or vertical fissures not
      corresponding with the stratification; a lode; a dike; --
      often limited, in the language of miners, to a mineral
      vein or lode, that is, to a vein which contains useful
      minerals or ores.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A fissure, cleft, or cavity, as in the earth or other
      substance. ``Down to the veins of earth.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let the glass of the prisms be free from veins.
                                                  --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A streak or wave of different color, appearing in wood,
      and in marble and other stones; variegation.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A train of association, thoughts, emotions, or the like; a
      current; a course.
      [1913 Webster]

            He can open a vein of true and noble thinking.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Peculiar temper or temperament; tendency or turn of mind;
      a particular disposition or cast of genius; humor; strain;
      quality; also, manner of speech or action; as, a rich vein
      of humor; a satirical vein. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Certain discoursing wits which are of the same
            veins.                                --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Invoke the Muses, and improve my vein. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vein</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>vein
     n 1: a blood vessel that carries blood from the capillaries
          toward the heart; all veins except the pulmonary carry
          unaerated blood [syn: {vena}, {venous blood vessel}]
     2: a distinctive style or manner; "he continued in this vein
        for several minutes"
     3: any of the vascular bundles or ribs that form the branching
        framework of conducting and supporting tissues in a leaf
        or other plant organ [syn: {nervure}]
     4: a layer of ore between layers of rock [syn: {mineral vein}]
     5: one of the horny ribs that stiffen and support the wing of
        an insect [syn: {nervure}]
     v : make a veinlike pattern
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
