<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>verge</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>verge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Verge \Verge\, n. [F. verge, L. virga; perhaps akin to E. wisp.]
   1. A rod or staff, carried as an emblem of authority; as, the
      verge, carried before a dean.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The stick or wand with which persons were formerly
      admitted tenants, they holding it in the hand, and
      swearing fealty to the lord. Such tenants were called
      tenants by the verge. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Eng. Law) The compass of the court of Marshalsea and the
      Palace court, within which the lord steward and the
      marshal of the king's household had special jurisdiction;
      -- so called from the verge, or staff, which the marshal
      bore.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A virgate; a yardland. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A border, limit, or boundary of a space; an edge, margin,
      or brink of something definite in extent.
      [1913 Webster]

            Even though we go to the extreme verge of
            possibility to invent a supposition favorable to it,
            the theory . . . implies an absurdity. --J. S. Mill.
      [1913 Webster]

            But on the horizon's verge descried,
            Hangs, touched with light, one snowy sail. --M.
                                                  Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A circumference; a circle; a ring.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inclusive verge
            Of golden metal that must round my brow. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Arch.)
      (a) The shaft of a column, or a small ornamental shaft.
          --Oxf. Gloss.
      (b) The edge of the tiling projecting over the gable of a
          roof. --Encyc. Brit.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Horol.) The spindle of a watch balance, especially one
      with pallets, as in the old vertical escapement. See under
      {Escapement}.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Hort.)
      (a) The edge or outside of a bed or border.
      (b) A slip of grass adjoining gravel walks, and dividing
          them from the borders in a parterre.
          [1913 Webster]

   10. The penis.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Zo["o]l.) The external male organ of certain mollusks,
       worms, etc. See Illustration in Appendix.
       [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Border; edge; rim; brim; margin; brink.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>verge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Verge \Verge\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Verged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Verging}.] [L. vergere to bend, turn, incline; cf. Skr. v?j
   to turn.]
   1. To border upon; to tend; to incline; to come near; to
      approach.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To tend downward; to bend; to slope; as, a hill verges to
      the north.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our soul, from original instinct, vergeth towards
            him as its center.                    --Barrow.
      [1913 Webster]

            I find myself verging to that period of life which
            is to be labor and sorrow.            --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>verge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>verge
     n 1: a region marking a boundary [syn: {brink}, {threshold}]
     2: the limit beyond which something happens or changes; "on the
        verge of tears"; "on the brink of bankruptcy" [syn: {brink}]
     3: a ceremonial or emblematic staff [syn: {scepter}, {sceptre},
         {wand}]
     4: a grass border along a road
     v : border on; come close to; "His behavior verges on the
         criminal"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
