<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>veronica</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veronica</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Veronica
     
        &lt;information science&gt; Very Easy Rodent-Oriented Net-wide Index
        to Computerized Archives.  Veronica offers a keyword search of
        most {gopher} menu titles in the entire gopher web.  As
        {archie} is to {FTP} archives, Veronica is to {Gopherspace}.
        A Veronica search produces a menu of Gopher items, each of
        which is a direct pointer to a Gopher data source.  Because
        Veronica is accessed through a Gopher Client, it is easy to
        use, and gives access to all types of data supported by the
        Gopher {protocol}.
     
        To try Veronica, select it from the "Other Gophers" menu on
        Minnesota's gopher server, or point your gopher at:
     
         Name=veronica (search menu items in most of GopherSpace)
         Type=1
         Port=70
         Path=1/veronica
         Host=gopher.scs.unr.edu
     
        {(gopher://gopher.scs.unr.edu/1/veronica)}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veronica</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Veronica \Ve*ron"i*ca\, n. [LL.; -- so called from Veronica, a
   woman who, according to an old legend, as Christ was carrying
   the cross, wiped his face with a cloth, which received an
   impression of his countenance; Veronica is fr. MGr. ?, fr.
   Macedonian ?, for Gr. ?, literally, carrying off victory,
   victorious.]
   1. A portrait or representation of the face of our Savior on
      the alleged handkerchief of Saint Veronica, preserved at
      Rome; hence, a representation of this portrait, or any
      similar representation of the face of the Savior. Formerly
      called also {Vernacle}, and {Vernicle}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) A genus scrophulariaceous plants; the speedwell.
      See {Speedwell}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Several herbaceous species are common in both Europe
         and America, most of which have small blue flowers. A
         few shrubby species from New Zealand are sometimes
         found in cultivation.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veronica</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>VERONICA
     Very Easy Rodent-Orientated Netwide Index of Computerized Archives
     (Internet)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>veronica</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>veronica
     n : any plant of the genus Veronica [syn: {speedwell}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
