<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>vessel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vessel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vessel \Ves"sel\, n. [OF. vessel, veissel, vaissel, vaissiel, F.
   vascellum, dim. of vasculum, dim. of vas a vessel. Cf.
   {Vascular}, {Vase}.]
   1. A hollow or concave utensil for holding anything; a hollow
      receptacle of any kind, as a hogshead, a barrel, a firkin,
      a bottle, a kettle, a cup, a bowl, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            [They drank] out of these noble vessels. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A general name for any hollow structure made to float upon
      the water for purposes of navigation; especially, one that
      is larger than a common rowboat; as, a war vessel; a
      passenger vessel.
      [1913 Webster]

            [He] began to build a vessel of huge bulk. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fig.: A person regarded as receiving or containing
      something; esp. (Script.), one into whom something is
      conceived as poured, or in whom something is stored for
      use; as, vessels of wrath or mercy.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is a chosen vessel unto me.        --Acts ix. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The serpent] fit vessel, fittest imp of fraud, in
            whom
            To enter.                             --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Anat.) Any tube or canal in which the blood or other
      fluids are contained, secreted, or circulated, as the
      arteries, veins, lymphatics, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Bot.) A continuous tube formed from superposed large
      cylindrical or prismatic cells (trache[ae]), which have
      lost their intervening partitions, and are usually marked
      with dots, pits, rings, or spirals by internal deposition
      of secondary membranes; a duct.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Acoustic vessels}. See under {Acoustic}.

   {Weaker vessel}, a woman; -- now applied humorously. ``Giving
      honor unto the wife, as unto the weaker vessel.'' --1
      Peter iii. 7. ``You are the weaker vessel.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vessel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vessel \Ves"sel\, v. t.
   To put into a vessel. [Obs.] --Bacon.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vessel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>vessel
     n 1: a tube in which a body fluid circulates [syn: {vas}]
     2: a craft designed for water transportation [syn: {watercraft}]
     3: an object used as a container (especially for liquids)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
