<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>vest</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vest, KY
  Zip code(s): 41772
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vest \Vest\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Vested}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Vesting}.] [Cf. L. vestire, vestitum, OF. vestir, F.
   v[^e]tir. See {Vest}, n.]
   1. To clothe with, or as with, a vestment, or garment; to
      dress; to robe; to cover, surround, or encompass closely.
      [1913 Webster]

            Came vested all in white, pure as her mind.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            With ether vested, and a purple sky.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To clothe with authority, power, or the like; to put in
      possession; to invest; to furnish; to endow; -- followed
      by with before the thing conferred; as, to vest a court
      with power to try cases of life and death.
      [1913 Webster]

            Had I been vested with the monarch's power. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To place or give into the possession or discretion of some
      person or authority; to commit to another; -- with in
      before the possessor; as, the power of life and death is
      vested in the king, or in the courts.
      [1913 Webster]

            Empire and dominion was [were] vested in him.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To invest; to put; as, to vest money in goods, land, or
      houses. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) To clothe with possession; as, to vest a person with
      an estate; also, to give a person an immediate fixed right
      of present or future enjoyment of; as, an estate is vested
      in possession. --Bouvier.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vest \Vest\, n. [L. vestis a garment, vesture; akin to Goth.
   wasti, and E. wear: cf. F. veste. See {Wear} to carry on the
   person, and cf. {Divest}, {Invest}, {Travesty}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. An article of clothing covering the person; an outer
      garment; a vestment; a dress; a vesture; a robe.
      [1913 Webster]

            In state attended by her maiden train,
            Who bore the vests that holy rites require.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any outer covering; array; garb.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not seldom clothed in radiant vest
            Deceitfully goes forth the morn.      --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically, a waistcoat, or sleeveless body garment, for
      men, worn under the coat.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Garment; vesture; dress; robe; vestment; waistcoat.

   Usage: {Vest}, {Waistcoat}. In England, the original word
          waistcoat is generally used for the body garment worn
          over the shirt and immediately under the coat. In the
          United States this garment is commonly called a vest,
          and the waistcoat is often improperly given to an
          under-garment.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vest \Vest\, v. i.
   To come or descend; to be fixed; to take effect, as a title
   or right; -- followed by in; as, upon the death of the
   ancestor, the estate, or the right to the estate, vests in
   the heir at law.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>VEST
     VAX Environment Software Translator (VAX, DEC)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>vest
     n 1: a man's sleeveless garment worn underneath a coat [syn: {waistcoat}]
     2: a collarless men's undergarment for the upper part of the
        body [syn: {singlet}, {undershirt}]
     v 1: provide with power and authority; "They vested the council
          with special rights" [syn: {invest}, {enthrone}] [ant: {divest}]
     2: place (authority, property, or rights) in the control of a
        person or group of persons; "She vested her vast fortune
        in her two sons"
     3: become legally vested; "The property vests in the trustees"
     4: clothe oneself in ecclesiastical garments
     5: clothe formally; especially in ecclesiastical robes [syn: {robe}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
