<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>vested</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vested</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vest \Vest\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Vested}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Vesting}.] [Cf. L. vestire, vestitum, OF. vestir, F.
   v[^e]tir. See {Vest}, n.]
   1. To clothe with, or as with, a vestment, or garment; to
      dress; to robe; to cover, surround, or encompass closely.
      [1913 Webster]

            Came vested all in white, pure as her mind.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            With ether vested, and a purple sky.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To clothe with authority, power, or the like; to put in
      possession; to invest; to furnish; to endow; -- followed
      by with before the thing conferred; as, to vest a court
      with power to try cases of life and death.
      [1913 Webster]

            Had I been vested with the monarch's power. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To place or give into the possession or discretion of some
      person or authority; to commit to another; -- with in
      before the possessor; as, the power of life and death is
      vested in the king, or in the courts.
      [1913 Webster]

            Empire and dominion was [were] vested in him.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To invest; to put; as, to vest money in goods, land, or
      houses. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) To clothe with possession; as, to vest a person with
      an estate; also, to give a person an immediate fixed right
      of present or future enjoyment of; as, an estate is vested
      in possession. --Bouvier.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vested</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vested \Vest"ed\, a.
   1. Clothed; robed; wearing vestments. ``The vested priest.''
      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) Not in a state of contingency or suspension; fixed;
      as, vested rights; vested interests.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Vested legacy} (Law), a legacy the right to which commences
      in pr[ae]senti, and does not depend on a contingency; as,
      a legacy to one to be paid when he attains to twenty-one
      years of age is a vested legacy, and if the legatee dies
      before the testator, his representative shall receive it.
      --Blackstone.

   {Vested remainder} (Law), an estate settled, to remain to a
      determined person, after the particular estate is spent.
      --Blackstone. --Kent.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vested</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>vested
     adj : fixed and absolute and without contingency; "a vested right"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
