<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>vine</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vine
   one of the most important products of Palestine. The first
   mention of it is in the history of Noah (Gen. 9:20). It is
   afterwards frequently noticed both in the Old and New
   Testaments, and in the ruins of terraced vineyards there are
   evidences that it was extensively cultivated by the Jews. It was
   cultivated in Palestine before the Israelites took possession of
   it. The men sent out by Moses brought with them from the Valley
   of Eshcol a cluster of grapes so large that "they bare it
   between two upon a staff" (Num. 13: 23). The vineyards of
   En-gedi (Cant. 1:14), Heshbon, Sibmah, Jazer, Elealeh (Isa.
   16:8-10; Jer. 48:32, 34), and Helbon (Ezek. 27:18), as well as
   of Eshcol, were celebrated.
   
     The Church is compared to a vine (Ps. 80:8), and Christ says
   of himself, "I am the vine" (John 15:1). In one of his parables
   also (Matt. 21:33) our Lord compares his Church to a vineyard
   which "a certain householder planted, and hedged round about,"
   etc.
   
     Hos. 10:1 is rendered in the Revised Version, "Israel is a
   luxuriant vine, which putteth forth his fruit," instead of
   "Israel is an empty vine, he bringeth forth fruit unto himself,"
   of the Authorized Version.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vine \Vine\, n. [F. vigne, L. vinea a vineyard, vine from vineus
   of or belonging to wine, vinum wine, grapes. See {Wine}, and
   cf. {Vignette}.] (Bot.)
      (a) Any woody climbing plant which bears grapes.
      (b) Hence, a climbing or trailing plant; the long, slender
          stem of any plant that trails on the ground, or climbs
          by winding round a fixed object, or by seizing
          anything with its tendrils, or claspers; a creeper;
          as, the hop vine; the bean vine; the vines of melons,
          squashes, pumpkins, and other cucurbitaceous plants.
          [1913 Webster]

                There shall be no grapes on the vine. --Jer.
                                                  viii. 13.
          [1913 Webster]

                And one went out into the field to gather herbs,
                and found a wild vine, and gathered thereof wild
                gourds.                           --2 Kings iv.
                                                  89.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Vine apple} (Bot.), a small kind of squash. --Roger
      Williams.

   {Vine beetle} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      beetles which are injurious to the leaves or branches of
      the grapevine. Among the more important species are the
      grapevine fidia (see {Fidia}), the spotted {Pelidnota}
      (see {Rutilian}), the vine fleabeetle ({Graptodera
      chalybea}), the rose beetle (see under {Rose}), the vine
      weevil, and several species of {Colaspis} and {Anomala}.
      

   {Vine borer}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any one of several species of beetles whose larv[ae]
          bore in the wood or pith of the grapevine, especially
          {Sinoxylon basilare}, a small species the larva of
          which bores in the stems, and {Ampeloglypter
          sesostris}, a small reddish brown weevil (called also
          {vine weevil}), which produces knotlike galls on the
          branches.
      (b) A clearwing moth ({[AE]geria polistiformis}), whose
          larva bores in the roots of the grapevine and is often
          destructive.

   {Vine dragon}, an old and fruitless branch of a vine. [Obs.]
      --Holland.

   {Vine forester} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      moths belonging to {Alypia} and allied genera, whose
      larv[ae] feed on the leaves of the grapevine.

   {Vine fretter} (Zo["o]l.), a plant louse, esp. the phylloxera
      that injuries the grapevine.

   {Vine grub} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of insect
      larv[ae] that are injurious to the grapevine.

   {Vine hopper} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of leaf
      hoppers which suck the sap of the grapevine, especially
      {Erythroneura vitis}. See Illust. of {Grape hopper}, under
      {Grape}.

   {Vine inchworm} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of any species of
      geometrid moths which feed on the leaves of the grapevine,
      especially {Cidaria diversilineata}.

   {Vine-leaf rooer} (Zo["o]l.), a small moth ({Desmia
      maculalis}) whose larva makes a nest by rolling up the
      leaves of the grapevine. The moth is brownish black,
      spotted with white.

   {Vine louse} (Zo["o]l.), the phylloxera.

   {Vine mildew} (Bot.), a fungous growth which forms a white,
      delicate, cottony layer upon the leaves, young shoots, and
      fruit of the vine, causing brown spots upon the green
      parts, and finally a hardening and destruction of the
      vitality of the surface. The plant has been called {Oidium
      Tuckeri}, but is now thought to be the conidia-producing
      stage of an {Erysiphe}.

   {Vine of Sodom} (Bot.), a plant named in the Bible (--Deut.
      xxxii. 32), now thought to be identical with the apple of
      Sodom. See {Apple of Sodom}, under {Apple}.

   {Vine sawfly} (Zo["o]l.), a small black sawfiy ({Selandria
      vitis}) whose larva feeds upon the leaves of the
      grapevine. The larv[ae] stand side by side in clusters
      while feeding.

   {Vine slug} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of the vine sawfly.

   {Vine sorrel} (Bot.), a climbing plant ({Cissus acida})
      related to the grapevine, and having acid leaves. It is
      found in Florida and the West Indies.

   {Vine sphinx} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of hawk
      moths. The larv[ae] feed on grapevine leaves.

   {Vine weevil}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Vine borer}
      (a) above, and {Wound gall}, under {Wound}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>vine
     n : weak-stemmed plant that derives support from climbing,
         twining, or creeping along a surface
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
