<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>vision</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vision</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vision
   (Luke 1:22), a vivid apparition, not a dream (comp. Luke 24:23;
   Acts 26:19; 2 Cor. 12:1).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vision</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vision \Vi"sion\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Visioned}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Visioning}.]
   To see in a vision; to dream.
   [1913 Webster]

         For them no visioned terrors daunt,
         Their nights no fancied specters haunt.  --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vision</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vision \Vi"sion\, n. [OE. visioun, F. vision, fr. L. visio, from
   videre, visum, to see: akin to Gr. ? to see, ? I know, and E.
   wit. See {Wit}, v., and cf. {Advice}, {Clairvoyant}, {Envy},
   {Evident}, {Provide}, {Revise}, {Survey}, {View}, {Visage},
   {Visit}.]
   1. The act of seeing external objects; actual sight.
      [1913 Webster]

            Faith here is turned into vision there. --Hammond.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Physiol.) The faculty of seeing; sight; one of the five
      senses, by which colors and the physical qualities of
      external objects are appreciated as a result of the
      stimulating action of light on the sensitive retina, an
      expansion of the optic nerve.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is seen; an object of sight. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Especially, that which is seen otherwise than by the
      ordinary sight, or the rational eye; a supernatural,
      prophetic, or imaginary sight; an apparition; a phantom; a
      specter; as, the visions of Isaiah.
      [1913 Webster]

            The baseless fabric of this vision.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            No dreams, but visions strange.       --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, something unreal or imaginary; a creation of fancy.
      --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Arc of vision} (Astron.), the arc which measures the least
      distance from the sun at which, when the sun is below the
      horizon, a star or planet emerging from his rays becomes
      visible.

   {Beatific vision} (Theol.), the immediate sight of God in
      heaven.

   {Direct vision} (Opt.), vision when the image of the object
      falls directly on the yellow spot (see under {Yellow});
      also, vision by means of rays which are not deviated from
      their original direction.

   {Field of vision}, field of view. See under {Field}.

   {Indirect vision} (Opt.), vision when the rays of light from
      an object fall upon the peripheral parts of the retina.

   {Reflected vision}, or {Refracted vision}, vision by rays
      reflected from mirrors, or refracted by lenses or prisms,
      respectively.

   {Vision purple}. (Physiol.) See {Visual purple}, under
      {Visual}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vision</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>vision
     n 1: a vivid mental image; "he had a vision of his own death"
     2: the ability to see; the faculty of vision [syn: {sight}, {visual
        sense}, {visual modality}]
     3: the perceptual experience of seeing; "the runners emerged
        from the trees into his clear vision"; "he had a visual
        sensation of intense light" [syn: {visual sensation}]
     4: the formation of a mental image of something that is not
        perceived as real and is not present to the senses;
        "popular imagination created a world of demons";
        "imagination reveals what the world could be" [syn: {imagination},
         {imaginativeness}]
     5: a religious or mystical experience of a supernatural
        appearance; "he had a vision of the Virgin Mary"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
