<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>visionary</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>visionary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>visionary
     
        1. One who hacks vision, in the sense of an Artificial
        Intelligence researcher working on the problem of getting
        computers to "see" things using TV cameras.  (There isn't any
        problem in sending information from a TV camera to a computer.
        The problem is, how can the computer be programmed to make use
        of the camera information?  See {SMOP}, {AI-complete}.)
     
        2. [IBM] One who reads the outside literature.  At IBM,
        apparently, such a penchant is viewed with awe and wonder.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>visionary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Visionary \Vi"sion*a*ry\, a. [Cf. F. visionnaire.]
   1. Of or pertaining to a visions or visions; characterized
      by, appropriate to, or favorable for, visions.
      [1913 Webster]

            The visionary hour
            When musing midnight reigns.          --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Affected by phantoms; disposed to receive impressions on
      the imagination; given to reverie; apt to receive, and act
      upon, fancies as if they were realities.
      [1913 Webster]

            Or lull to rest the visionary maid.   --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Existing in imagination only; not real; fanciful;
      imaginary; having no solid foundation; as, visionary
      prospect; a visionary scheme or project. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Fanciful; fantastic; unreal. See {Fanciful}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>visionary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Visionary \Vi"sion*a*ry\, n.; pl. {Visionaries}.
   1. One whose imagination is disturbed; one who sees visions
      or phantoms.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One whose imagination overpowers his reason and controls
      his judgment; an unpractical schemer; one who builds
      castles in the air; a daydreamer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>visionary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>visionary n. 1. One who hacks vision, in the sense of an Artificial
   Intelligence researcher working on the problem of getting computers to
   `see' things using TV cameras. (There isn't any problem in sending
   information from a TV camera to a computer. The problem is, how can the
   computer be programmed to make use of the camera information? See
   {SMOP}, {AI-complete}.) 2. [IBM] One who reads the outside literature.
   At IBM, apparently, such a penchant is viewed with awe and wonder.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>visionary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>visionary
     adj : not practical or realizable; speculative; "airy theories
           about socioeconomic improvement"; "visionary schemes
           for getting rich" [syn: {airy}, {impractical}, {Laputan}]
     n 1: a person given to fanciful speculations and enthusiasms with
          little regard for what is actually possible
     2: a person with unusual powers of foresight [syn: {illusionist},
         {seer}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
