<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>voice</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>voice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Voice \Voice\, n. [OE. vois, voys, OF. vois, voiz, F. voix, L.
   vox, vocis, akin to Gr. ? a word, ? a voice, Skr. vac to say,
   to speak, G. erw["a]hnen to mention. Cf. {Advocate},
   {Advowson}, {Avouch}, {Convoke}, {Epic}, {Vocal}, {Vouch},
   {Vowel}.]
   1. Sound uttered by the mouth, especially that uttered by
      human beings in speech or song; sound thus uttered
      considered as possessing some special quality or
      character; as, the human voice; a pleasant voice; a low
      voice.
      [1913 Webster]

            He with a manly voice saith his message. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her voice was ever soft,
            Gentle, and low; an excellent thing in woman.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy voice is music.                   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Join thy voice unto the angel choir.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Phon.) Sound of the kind or quality heard in speech or
      song in the consonants b, v, d, etc., and in the vowels;
      sonant, or intonated, utterance; tone; -- distinguished
      from mere breath sound as heard in f, s, sh, etc., and
      also whisper.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Voice, in this sense, is produced by vibration of the
         so-called vocal cords in the larynx (see Illust. of
         {Larynx}) which act upon the air, not in the manner of
         the strings of a stringed instrument, but as a pair of
         membranous tongues, or reeds, which, being continually
         forced apart by the outgoing current of breath, and
         continually brought together again by their own
         elasticity and muscular tension, break the breath
         current into a series of puffs, or pulses, sufficiently
         rapid to cause the sensation of tone. The power, or
         loudness, of such a tone depends on the force of the
         separate pulses, and this is determined by the pressure
         of the expired air, together with the resistance on the
         part of the vocal cords which is continually overcome.
         Its pitch depends on the number of a["e]rial pulses
         within a given time, that is, on the rapidity of their
         succession. See Guide to Pronunciation, [sect][sect] 5,
         146, 155.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The tone or sound emitted by anything.
      [1913 Webster]

            After the fire a still small voice.   --1 Kings xix.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Canst thou thunder with a voice like him? --Job xl.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

            The floods have lifted up their voice. --Ps. xciii.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

            O Marcus, I am warm'd; my heart
            Leaps at the trumpet's voice.         --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The faculty or power of utterance; as, to cultivate the
      voice.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Language; words; speech; expression; signification of
      feeling or opinion.
      [1913 Webster]

            I desire to be present with you now, and to change
            my voice; for I stand in doubt of you. --Gal. iv.
                                                  20.
      [1913 Webster]

            My voice is in my sword.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let us call on God in the voice of his church. --Bp.
                                                  Fell.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Opinion or choice expressed; judgment; a vote.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sic. How now, my masters! have you chose this man?
            1 Cit. He has our voices, sir.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some laws ordain, and some attend the choice
            Of holy senates, and elect by voice.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Command; precept; -- now chiefly used in scriptural
      language.
      [1913 Webster]

            So shall ye perish; because ye would not be obedient
            unto the voice of the Lord your God.  --Deut. viii.
                                                  20.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. One who speaks; a speaker. ``A potent voice of
      Parliament.'' --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Gram.) A particular mode of inflecting or conjugating
      verbs, or a particular form of a verb, by means of which
      is indicated the relation of the subject of the verb to
      the action which the verb expresses.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Active voice} (Gram.), that form of the verb by which its
      subject is represented as the agent or doer of the action
      expressed by it.

   {Chest voice} (Phon.), a kind of voice of a medium or low
      pitch and of a sonorous quality ascribed to resonance in
      the chest, or thorax; voice of the thick register. It is
      produced by vibration of the vocal cords through their
      entire width and thickness, and with convex surfaces
      presented to each other.

   {Head voice} (Phon.), a kind of voice of high pitch and of a
      thin quality ascribed to resonance in the head; voice of
      the thin register; falsetto. In producing it, the
      vibration of the cords is limited to their thin edges in
      the upper part, which are then presented to each other.

   {Middle voice} (Gram.), that form of the verb by which its
      subject is represented as both the agent, or doer, and the
      object of the action, that is, as performing some act to
      or upon himself, or for his own advantage.

   {Passive voice}. (Gram.) See under {Passive}, a.

   {Voice glide} (Pron.), the brief and obscure neutral vowel
      sound that sometimes occurs between two consonants in an
      unaccented syllable (represented by the apostrophe), as in
      able (a"b'l). See {Glide}, n., 2.

   {Voice stop}. See {Voiced stop}, under {Voiced}, a.

   {With one voice}, unanimously. ``All with one voice . . .
      cried out, Great is Diana of the Ephesians.'' --Acts xix.
      34.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>voice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Voice \Voice\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Voiced}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Voicing}.]
   1. To give utterance or expression to; to utter; to publish;
      to announce; to divulge; as, to voice the sentiments of
      the nation. ``Rather assume thy right in silence and . . .
      then voice it with claims and challenges.'' --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was voiced that the king purposed to put to death
            Edward Plantagenet.                   --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Phon.) To utter with sonant or vocal tone; to pronounce
      with a narrowed glottis and rapid vibrations of the vocal
      cords; to speak above a whisper.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fit for producing the proper sounds; to regulate the
      tone of; as, to voice the pipes of an organ.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To vote; to elect; to appoint. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>voice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Voice \Voice\, v. i.
   To clamor; to cry out. [Obs.] --South.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>voice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>voice vt. To phone someone, as opposed to emailing them or connecting
   in {talk mode}. "I'm busy now; I'll voice you later."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>voice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>VOICE
     Virtual OS/2 International Consumer Education (OS/2, user group)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>voice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>voice
     n 1: the distinctive quality or pitch or condition of a person's
          speech; "A shrill voice sounded behind us"
     2: the sound made by the vibration of vocal folds modified by
        the resonance of the vocal tract; "a singer takes good
        care of his voice"; "the giraffe cannot make any
        vocalizations" [syn: {vocalization}, {vocalisation}, {phonation},
         {vox}]
     3: a sound suggestive of a vocal utterance; "the noisy voice of
        the waterfall"; "the incessant voices of the artillery"
     4: expressing in coherent verbal form; "the articulation of my
        feelings"; "I gave voice to my feelings" [syn: {articulation}]
     5: a means or agency by which something is expressed or
        communicated; "the voice of the law"; "the Times is not
        the voice of New York"; "conservatism has many voices"
     6: something suggestive of speech in being a medium of
        expression; "the wee small voice of conscience"; "the
        voice of experience"; "he said his voices told him to do
        it"
     7: (metonymy) a singer; "he wanted to hear trained voices sing
        it"
     8: an advocate who represents someone else's policy or purpose;
        "the meeting was attended by spokespersons for all the
        major organs of government" [syn: {spokesperson}, {interpreter},
         {representative}]
     9: the ability to speak; "he lost his voice"
     10: (linguistics) the grammatical relation (active or passive)
         of the grammatical subject of a verb to the action that
         the verb denotes
     11: the melody carried by a particular voice or instrument in
         polyphonic music; "he tried to sing the tenor part" [syn:
          {part}]
     v 1: give voice to; "He voiced his concern"
     2: utter with vibrating vocal chords [syn: {sound}, {vocalize},
         {vocalise}] [ant: {devoice}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
