<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>vote</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vote</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>VOTE, n.  The instrument and symbol of a freeman's power to make a
fool of himself and a wreck of his country.


                                  W


W (double U) has, of all the letters in our alphabet, the only
cumbrous name, the names of the others being monosyllabic.  This
advantage of the Roman alphabet over the Grecian is the more valued
after audibly spelling out some simple Greek word, like
_epixoriambikos_.  Still, it is now thought by the learned that other
agencies than the difference of the two alphabets may have been
concerned in the decline of "the glory that was Greece" and the rise
of "the grandeur that was Rome."  There can be no doubt, however, that
by simplifying the name of W (calling it "wow," for example) our
civilization could be, if not promoted, at least better endured.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vote</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vote \Vote\, n. [L. votum a vow, wish, will, fr. vovere, votum,
   to vow: cf. F. vote. See {Vow}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. An ardent wish or desire; a vow; a prayer. [Obs.]
      --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A wish, choice, or opinion, of a person or a body of
      persons, expressed in some received and authorized way;
      the expression of a wish, desire, will, preference, or
      choice, in regard to any measure proposed, in which the
      person voting has an interest in common with others,
      either in electing a person to office, or in passing laws,
      rules, regulations, etc.; suffrage.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That by means of which will or preference is expressed in
      elections, or in deciding propositions; voice; a ballot; a
      ticket; as, a written vote.
      [1913 Webster]

            The freeman casting with unpurchased hand
            The vote that shakes the turrets of the land.
                                                  --Holmes.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Expression of judgment or will by a majority; legal
      decision by some expression of the minds of a number; as,
      the vote was unanimous; a vote of confidence.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Votes, collectively; as, the Tory vote; the labor vote.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Casting vote}, {Cumulative vote}, etc. See under {Casting},
      {Cumulative}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vote</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vote \Vote\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Voted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Voting}.] [Cf. F. voter.]
   To express or signify the mind, will, or preference, either
   viva voce, or by ballot, or by other authorized means, as in
   electing persons to office, in passing laws, regulations,
   etc., or in deciding on any proposition in which one has an
   interest with others.
   [1913 Webster]

         The vote for a duelist is to assist in the prostration
         of justice, and, indirectly, to encourage the crime.
                                                  --L. Beecher.
   [1913 Webster]

         To vote on large principles, to vote honestly, requires
         a great amount of information.           --F. W.
                                                  Robertson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vote</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Vote \Vote\, v. t.
   1. To choose by suffrage; to elec?; as, to vote a candidate
      into office.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To enact, establish, grant, determine, etc., by a formal
      vote; as, the legislature voted the resolution.
      [1913 Webster]

            Parliament voted them one hundred thousand pounds.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To declare by general opinion or common consent, as if by
      a vote; as, he was voted a bore. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To condemn; to devote; to doom. [Obs.] --Glanvill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>vote</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>vote
     n 1: a choice that is made by voting; "there were only 17 votes
          in favor of the motion" [syn: {ballot}, {voting}, {balloting}]
     2: the opinion of a group as determined by voting; "they put
        the question to a vote"
     3: a legal right guaranteed by the 15th amendment to the US
        constitution; guaranteed to women by the 19th amendment;
        "American women got the vote in 1920" [syn: {right to vote},
         {suffrage}]
     4: a body of voters who have the same interests; "he failed to
        get the Black vote"
     5: the total number of votes cast; "they are hoping for a large
        vote" [syn: {voter turnout}]
     v 1: express one's preference for a candidate or for a measure or
          resolution; cast a vote; "He voted for the motion";
          "None of the Democrats voted last night"
     2: express one's choice or preference by vote; "vote the
        Democratic ticket"
     3: express a choice or opinion; "I vote that we all go home";
        "She voted for going to the Chinese restaurant"
     4: be guided by in voting; "vote one's conscience"
     5: bring into existence or make available by vote; "They voted
        aid for the underdeveloped countries in Asia"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
