<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>calendar</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>calendar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Calendar \Cal"en*dar\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Calendared}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Calendaring}.]
   To enter or write in a calendar; to register. --Waterhouse.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>calendar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Calendar \Cal"en*dar\, n. [OE. kalender, calender, fr. L.
   kalendarium an interest or account book (cf. F. calendrier,
   OF. calendier) fr. L. calendue, kalendae, calends. See
   {Calends}.]
   1. An orderly arrangement of the division of time, adapted to
      the purposes of civil life, as years, months, weeks, and
      days; also, a register of the year with its divisions; an
      almanac.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Eccl.) A tabular statement of the dates of feasts,
      offices, saints' days, etc., esp. of those which are
      liable to change yearly according to the varying date of
      Easter.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An orderly list or enumeration of persons, things, or
      events; a schedule; as, a calendar of state papers; a
      calendar of bills presented in a legislative assembly; a
      calendar of causes arranged for trial in court; a calendar
      of a college or an academy.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Shepherds of people had need know the calendars of
         tempests of state. --Bacon.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Calendar clock}, one that shows the days of the week and
      month.

   {Calendar month}. See under {Month}.

   {French Republican calendar}. See under {Vend['e]miaire}.

   {Gregorian calendar}, {Julian calendar}, {Perpetual
   calendar}. See under {Gregorian}, {Julian}, and {Perpetual}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>calendar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>calendar
     n 1: a system of timekeeping that defines the beginning and
          length and divisions of the year
     2: a list or register of events (appointments or social events
        or court cases etc); "I have you on my calendar for next
        Monday"
     3: a tabular array of the days (usually for one year)
     v : enter into a calendar
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
