<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>camel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CAMEL, n.  A quadruped (the _Splaypes humpidorsus_) of great value to
the show business.  There are two kinds of camels -- the camel proper
and the camel improper.  It is the latter that is always exhibited.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Camel
   from the Hebrew _gamal_, "to repay" or "requite," as the camel
   does the care of its master. There are two distinct species of
   camels, having, however, the common characteristics of being
   "ruminants without horns, without muzzle, with nostrils forming
   oblique slits, the upper lip divided and separately movable and
   extensile, the soles of the feet horny, with two toes covered by
   claws, the limbs long, the abdomen drawn up, while the neck,
   long and slender, is bent up and down, the reverse of that of a
   horse, which is arched."
   
     (1.) The Bactrian camel is distinguished by two humps. It is a
   native of the high table-lands of Central Asia.
   
     (2.) The Arabian camel or dromedary, from the Greek _dromos_,
   "a runner" (Isa. 60:6; Jer. 2:23), has but one hump, and is a
   native of Western Asia or Africa.
   
     The camel was early used both for riding and as a beast of
   burden (Gen. 24:64; 37:25), and in war (1 Sam. 30:17; Isa.
   21:7). Mention is made of the camel among the cattle given by
   Pharaoh to Abraham (Gen. 12:16). Its flesh was not to be eaten,
   as it was ranked among unclean animals (Lev. 11:4; Deut. 14:7).
   Abraham's servant rode on a camel when he went to fetch a wife
   for Isaac (Gen. 24:10, 11). Jacob had camels as a portion of his
   wealth (30:43), as Abraham also had (24:35). He sent a present
   of thirty milch camels to his brother Esau (32:15). It appears
   to have been little in use among the Jews after the conquest. It
   is, however, mentioned in the history of David (1 Chr. 27:30),
   and after the Exile (Ezra 2:67; Neh. 7:69). Camels were much in
   use among other nations in the East. The queen of Sheba came
   with a caravan of camels when she came to see the wisdom of
   Solomon (1 Kings 10:2; 2 Chr. 9:1). Benhadad of Damascus also
   sent a present to Elisha, "forty camels' burden" (2 Kings 8:9).
   
     To show the difficulty in the way of a rich man's entering
   into the kingdom, our Lord uses the proverbial expression that
   it was easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle
   (Matt. 19:24).
   
     To strain at (rather, out) a gnat and swallow a camel was also
   a proverbial expression (Matt. 23:24), used with reference to
   those who were careful to avoid small faults, and yet did not
   hesitate to commit the greatest sins. The Jews carefully
   filtered their wine before drinking it, for fear of swallowing
   along with it some insect forbidden in the law as unclean, and
   yet they omitted openly the "weightier matters" of the law.
   
     The raiment worn by John the Baptist was made of camel's hair
   (Matt. 3:4; Mark 1:6), by which he was distinguished from those
   who resided in royal palaces and wore soft raiment. This was
   also the case with Elijah (2 Kings 1:8), who is called "a hairy
   man," from his wearing such raiment. "This is one of the most
   admirable materials for clothing; it keeps out the heat, cold,
   and rain." The "sackcloth" so often alluded to (2 Kings 1:8;
   Isa. 15:3; Zech. 13:4, etc.) was probably made of camel's hair.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>camel \cam"el\ (k[acrf]m"[e^]l), n. [Oe. camel, chamel, OF.
   camel, chamel, F. chameau L. camelus, fr. Gr. ka`mhlos; of
   Semitic origin; cf. Heb. g[=a]m[=a]l, Ar. jamal. Cf. As.
   camel, fr. L. camelus.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) A large ruminant used in Asia and Africa for
      carrying burdens and for riding. The camel is remarkable
      for its ability to go a long time without drinking. Its
      hoofs are small, and situated at the extremities of the
      toes, and the weight of the animal rests on the callous.
      The dromedary ({Camelus dromedarius}) has one bunch on the
      back, while the Bactrian camel ({Camelus Bactrianus}) has
      two. The llama, alpaca, and vicu[~n]a, of South America,
      belong to a related genus ({Auchenia}).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) A water-tight structure (as a large box or boxes)
      used to assist a vessel in passing over a shoal or bar or
      in navigating shallow water. By admitting water, the camel
      or camels may be sunk and attached beneath or at the sides
      of a vessel, and when the water is pumped out the vessel
      is lifted.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Camel bird} (Zo["o]l.), the ostrich.

   {Camel locust} (Zo["o]l.), the mantis.

   {Camel's thorn} (Bot.), a low, leguminous shrub ({Alhagi
      maurorum}) of the Arabian desert, from which exudes a
      sweetish gum, which is one of the substances called manna.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>camel
     n : cud-chewing mammal used as a draft or saddle animal in
         desert regions
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
