<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>camp</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Camp
   During their journeys across the wilderness, the twelve tribes
   formed encampments at the different places where they halted
   (Ex. 16:13; Num. 2:3). The diagram here given shows the position
   of the different tribes and the form of the encampment during
   the wanderings, according to Num. 1:53; 2:2-31; 3:29, 35, 38;
   10:13-28.
   
     The area of the camp would be in all about 3 square miles.
   After the Hebrews entered Palestine, the camps then spoken of
   were exclusively warlike (Josh. 11:5, 7; Judg. 5:19, 21; 7:1; 1
   Sam. 29:1; 30:9, etc.).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Camp, AR
  Zip code(s): 72520
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Camp \Camp\ (k[a^]mp), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Camped} (k[a^]mt;
   215); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Camping}.]
   To afford rest or lodging for, as an army or travelers.
   [1913 Webster]

         Had our great palace the capacity
         To camp this host, we all would sup together. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Camp \Camp\, v. i.
   1. To pitch or prepare a camp; to encamp; to lodge in a camp;
      -- often with out.
      [1913 Webster]

            They camped out at night, under the stars. --W.
                                                  Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [See {Camp}, n., 6] To play the game called camp. [Prov.
      Eng.] --Tusser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Camp \Camp\ (k[a^]mp), n. [F. camp, It. campo, fr. L. campus
   plant, field; akin to Gr. kh^pos garden. Cf. {Campaign},
   {Champ}, n.]
   1. The ground or spot on which tents, huts, etc., are erected
      for shelter, as for an army or for lumbermen, etc. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A collection of tents, huts, etc., for shelter, commonly
      arranged in an orderly manner.
      [1913 Webster]

            Forming a camp in the neighborhood of Boston. --W.
                                                  Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A single hut or shelter; as, a hunter's camp.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The company or body of persons encamped, as of soldiers,
      of surveyors, of lumbermen, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            The camp broke up with the confusion of a flight.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Agric.) A mound of earth in which potatoes and other
      vegetables are stored for protection against frost; --
      called also {burrow} and {pie}. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. [Cf. OE. &amp; AS. camp contest, battle. See {champion}.] An
      ancient game of football, played in some parts of England.
      --Halliwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Camp bedstead}, a light bedstead that can be folded up onto
      a small space for easy transportation.

   {camp ceiling} (Arch.), a kind ceiling often used in attics
      or garrets, in which the side walls are inclined inward at
      the top, following the slope of the rafters, to meet the
      plane surface of the upper ceiling.

   {Camp chair}, a light chair that can be folded up compactly
      for easy transportation; the seat and back are often made
      of strips or pieces of carpet.

   {Camp fever}, typhus fever.

   {Camp follower}, a civilian accompanying an army, as a
      sutler, servant, etc.

   {Camp meeting}, a religious gathering for open-air preaching,
      held in some retired spot, chiefly by Methodists. It
      usually last for several days, during which those present
      lodge in tents, temporary houses, or cottages.

   {Camp stool}, the same as {camp chair}, except that the stool
      has no back.

   {Flying camp} (Mil.), a camp or body of troops formed for
      rapid motion from one place to another. --Farrow.

   {To pitch (a) camp}, to set up the tents or huts of a camp.
      

   {To strike camp}, to take down the tents or huts of a camp.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>camp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>camp
     adj : providing sophisticated amusement by virtue of having
           artificially (and vulgarly) mannered or banal or
           sentimental qualities; "they played up the silliness of
           their roles for camp effect"; "campy Hollywood musicals
           of the 1940's" [syn: {campy}]
     n 1: temporary living quarters specially built by the army for
          soldiers; "wherever he went in the camp the men were
          grumbling" [syn: {encampment}, {cantonment}, {bivouac}]
     2: a group of people living together in a camp; "the whole camp
        laughed at his mistake"
     3: temporary lodgings in the country for travelers or
        vacationers; "level ground is best for parking and camp
        areas"
     4: an exclusive circle of people with a common purpose [syn: {clique},
         {coterie}, {ingroup}, {inner circle}, {pack}]
     5: a prison for forced laborers; "China has many work camps for
        political prisoners"
     6: something that is considered amusing not because of its
        originality but because of its unoriginality; "the
        livingroom was pure camp"
     7: shelter for persons displaced by war or political oppression
        or for religious beliefs [syn: {refugee camp}]
     8: a site where care and activities are provided for children
        during the summer months; "city kids get to see the
        country at a summer camp" [syn: {summer camp}]
     v 1: live in or as if in a tent; "Can we go camping again this
          summer?"; "The circus tented near the town"; "The
          houseguests had to camp in the living room" [syn: {encamp},
           {camp out}, {bivouac}, {tent}]
     2: establish or set up a camp [syn: {camp down}]
     3: give an artificially banal or sexual quality to
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
