<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>capital</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capital</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CAPITAL, n.  The seat of misgovernment.  That which provides the fire,
the pot, the dinner, the table and the knife and fork for the
anarchist; the part of the repast that himself supplies is the
disgrace before meat.  _Capital Punishment_, a penalty regarding the
justice and expediency of which many worthy persons -- including all
the assassins -- entertain grave misgivings.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capital</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Capital \Cap"i*tal\, a. [F. capital, L. capitalis capital (in
   senses 1 &amp; 2), fr. caput head. See {Chief}, and cf.
   {Capital}, n.]
   1. Of or pertaining to the head. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Needs must the Serpent now his capital bruise
            Expect with mortal pain.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Having reference to, or involving, the forfeiture of the
      head or life; affecting life; punishable with death; as,
      capital trials; capital punishment.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many crimes that are capital among us. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            To put to death a capital offender.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. First in importance; chief; principal.
      [1913 Webster]

            A capital article in religion         --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whatever is capital and essential in Christianity.
                                                  --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Chief, in a political sense, as being the seat of the
      general government of a state or nation; as, Washington
      and Paris are capital cities.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Of first rate quality; excellent; as, a capital speech or
      song. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Capital letter} [F, lettre capitale] (Print.), a leading or
      heading letter, used at the beginning of a sentence and as
      the first letter of certain words, distinguished, for the
      most part, both by different form and larger size, from
      the small (lower-case) letters, which form the greater
      part of common print or writing.

   {Small capital letters} have the form of capital letters and
      height of the body of the lower-case letters.

   {Capital stock}, money, property, or stock invested in any
      business, or the enterprise of any corporation or
      institution. --Abbott.

   Syn: Chief; leading; controlling; prominent.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capital</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>capital \cap"i*tal\ (k[a^]p"[i^]*tal), n. [Cf. L. capitellum and
   capitulum, a small head, the head, top, or capital of a
   column, dim. of caput head; F. chapiteau, OF. capitel. See
   {chief}, and cf. {cattle}, {chattel}, {chapiter}, {chapter}.]
   1. (Arch.) The head or uppermost member of a column,
      pilaster, etc. It consists generally of three parts,
      abacus, bell (or vase), and necking. See these terms, and
      {Column}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [Cf. F. capilate, fem., sc. ville.] (Geog.) The seat of
      government; the chief city or town in a country; a
      metropolis. ``A busy and splendid capital'' --Macauly.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. [Cf. F. capital.] Money, property, or stock employed in
      trade, manufactures, etc.; the sum invested or lent, as
      distinguished from the income or interest. See {Capital
      stock}, under {Capital}, a.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Polit. Econ.) That portion of the produce of industry,
      which may be directly employed either to support human
      beings or to assist in production. --M'Culloch.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When wealth is used to assist production it is called
         capital. The capital of a civilized community includes
         {fixed capital} (i.e. buildings, machines, and roads
         used in the course of production and exchange) and
         {circulating capital} (i.e., food, fuel, money, etc.,
         spent in the course of production and exchange). --T.
         Raleigh.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. Anything which can be used to increase one's power or
      influence.
      [1913 Webster]

            He tried to make capital out of his rival's
            discomfiture.                         --London
                                                  Times.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Fort.) An imaginary line dividing a bastion, ravelin, or
      other work, into two equal parts.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A chapter, or section, of a book. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Holy St. Bernard hath said in the 59th capital.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Print.) See {Capital letter}, under {Capital}, a.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Active capital}. See under {Active},

   {Small capital} (Print.), a small capital letter; informally
      referred to (in the plural) as {small caps}; as, the
      technical terms are listed in {small caps}. See under
      {Capital}, a.

   {To live on one's capital}, to consume one's capital without
      producing or accumulating anything to replace it.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capital</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>capital
     adj 1: first-rate; "a capital fellow"; "a capital idea"
     2: punishable by death; "a capital offense"
     3: of primary important; "our capital concern was to avoid
        defeat"
     4: uppercase; "capital A"; "great A"; "many medieval
        manuscripts are in majuscule script" [syn: {great}, {majuscule}]
     n 1: assets available for use in the production of further assets
          [syn: {working capital}]
     2: wealth in the form of money or property owned by a person or
        business and human resources of economic value
     3: a seat of government
     4: one of the large alphabetic characters used as the first
        letter in writing or printing proper names and sometimes
        for emphasis; "printers once kept the type for capitals
        and for small letters in separate cases; capitals were
        kept in the upper half of the type case and so became
        known as upper-case letters" [syn: {capital letter}, {upper
        case}, {upper-case letter}, {majuscule}] [ant: {small
        letter}]
     5: a book written by Karl Marx (1867) describing his economic
        theories [syn: {Das Kapital}]
     6: the upper part of a column that supports the entablature
        [syn: {chapiter}, {cap}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
