<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>capsule</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capsule</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Capsule \Cap"sule\ (k[a^]p"s[=u]l), n. [L. capsula a little box
   or chest, fr. capsa chest, case, fr. capere to take, contain:
   cf. F. capsule.]
   1. (Bot.) a dry fruit or pod which is made up of several
      parts or carpels, and opens to discharge the seeds, as,
      the capsule of the poppy, the flax, the lily, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Chem.)
      (a) A small saucer of clay for roasting or melting samples
          of ores, etc.; a scorifier.
      (b) a small, shallow, evaporating dish, usually of
          porcelain.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Med.) A small cylindrical or spherical gelatinous
      envelope in which nauseous or acrid doses are inclosed to
      be swallowed.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Anat.) A membranous sac containing fluid, or investing an
      organ or joint; as, the capsule of the lens of the eye.
      Also, a capsulelike organ.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A metallic seal or cover for closing a bottle.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A small cup or shell, as of metal, for a percussion cap,
      cartridge, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Atrabiliary capsule}. See under {Atrabiliary}.

   {Glisson's capsule}, a membranous envelope, entering the
      liver along with the portal vessels and insheathing the
      latter in their course through the organ.

   {Suprarenal capsule}, a ductless gland secreting epinephrine,
      norepinephrine, and steroid hormones, on the upper end of
      each kidney. It is also called the {adrenal gland},
      {glandula suprarenalis}, {suprarenal gland}, {epinephros},
      {atrabiliary capsule}, and {adrenal capsule}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capsule</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>capsule
     n 1: a small container
     2: a pill in the form of a small rounded gelatinous container
        with medicine inside
     3: a dry dehiscent seed vessel or the spore-containing
        structure of e.g. mosses
     4: a shortened version of a written work [syn: {condensation},
        {abridgement}, {abridgment}]
     5: a structure that encloses a body part
     6: a spacecraft designed to transport people and support human
        life in outer space [syn: {space capsule}]
     7: a pilot's seat in an airplane that can be forcibly ejected
        in the case of an emergency; then the pilot descends by
        parachute [syn: {ejection seat}, {ejector seat}]
     v 1: enclose in a capsule [syn: {capsulate}, {capsulize}, {capsulise}]
     2: put in a short or concise form; reduce in volume; "capsulize
        the news" [syn: {encapsulate}, {capsulize}, {capsulise}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
