<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>capture</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capture</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Capture \Cap"ture\, n. [L. capture, fr. caper to take: cf. F.
   capture. See {Caitiff}, and cf. {aptive}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of seizing by force, or getting possession of by
      superior power or by stratagem; as, the capture of an
      enemy, a vessel, or a criminal.
      [1913 Webster]

            Even with regard to captures made at sea.
                                                  --Bluckstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The securing of an object of strife or desire, as by the
      power of some attraction.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The thing taken by force, surprise, or stratagem; a prize;
      prey.

   Syn: Seizure; apprehension; arrest; detention.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capture</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Capture \Cap"ture\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Captured}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Capturing}.]
   1. To seize or take possession of by force, surprise, or
      stratagem; to overcome and hold; to secure by effort.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. to record or make a lasting representation of (sound or
      images); as, to capture an event on videotape; the artist
      captured the expression of grief on his face.
      [PJC]

   3. (Games) to take control of, or remove from play; as, to
      capture a piece in chess.
      [PJC]

   4. to exert a strong psychological influence on; as, to
      capture the heart of a maiden; to capture the attention of
      the nation.
      [PJC]

   5. (Computers) to record (data) in a computer-readable form;
      as, to capture a transaction in a database.
      [PJC]

            Her heart is like some fortress that has been
            captured.                             --W. Ivring.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>capture</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>capture
     n 1: the act of forcibly dispossessing an owner of property [syn:
           {gaining control}, {seizure}]
     2: a process whereby a star or planet holds an object in its
        gravitational field
     3: any process in which an atomic or nuclear system acquires an
        additional particle
     4: the act of taking of a person by force [syn: {seizure}]
     5: the removal of an opponent's piece from the chess board
     v 1: succeed in representing or expressing something intangible;
          "capture the essence of Spring"; "capture an idea"
     2: attract; cause to be enamored; "She captured all the men's
        hearts" [syn: {enamour}, {trance}, {catch}, {becharm}, {enamor},
         {captivate}, {beguile}, {charm}, {fascinate}, {bewitch},
        {entrance}, {enchant}]
     3: succeed in catching or seizing, especially after a chase;
        "We finally got the suspect"; "Did you catch the thief?"
        [syn: {get}, {catch}]
     4: bring about the capture of an elementary particle or
        celestial body and causing it enter a new orbit; "This
        nucleus has captured the slow-moving neutrons"; "The star
        captured a comet"
     5: take possession of by force, as after an invasion; "the
        invaders seized the land and property of the inhabitants";
        "The army seized the town"; "The militia captured the
        castle" [syn: {appropriate}, {seize}, {conquer}]
     6: capture as if by hunting, snaring, or trapping; "I caught a
        rabbit in the trap toady" [syn: {catch}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
