<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>captain</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>captain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Captain
   (1.) Heb. sar (1 Sam. 22:2; 2 Sam. 23:19). Rendered "chief,"
   Gen. 40:2; 41:9; rendered also "prince," Dan. 1:7; "ruler,"
   Judg. 9:30; "governor,' 1 Kings 22:26. This same Hebrew word
   denotes a military captain (Ex. 18:21; 2 Kings 1:9; Deut. 1:15;
   1 Sam. 18:13, etc.), the "captain of the body-guard" (Gen.
   37:36; 39:1; 41:10; Jer. 40:1), or, as the word may be rendered,
   "chief of the executioners" (marg.). The officers of the king's
   body-guard frequently acted as executioners. Nebuzar-adan (Jer.
   39:13) and Arioch (Dan. 2:14) held this office in Babylon.
   
     The "captain of the guard" mentioned in Acts 28:16 was the
   Praetorian prefect, the commander of the Praetorian troops.
   
     (2.) Another word (Heb. katsin) so translated denotes
   sometimes a military (Josh. 10:24; Judg. 11:6, 11; Isa. 22:3
   "rulers;" Dan. 11:18) and sometimes a civil command, a judge,
   magistrate, Arab. _kady_, (Isa. 1:10; 3:6; Micah 3:1, 9).
   
     (3.) It is also the rendering of a Hebrew word (shalish)
   meaning "a third man," or "one of three." The LXX. render in
   plural by _tristatai_; i.e., "soldiers fighting from chariots,"
   so called because each war-chariot contained three men, one of
   whom acted as charioteer while the other two fought (Ex. 14:7;
   15:4; 1 Kings 9:22; comp. 2 Kings 9:25). This word is used also
   to denote the king's body-guard (2 Kings 10:25; 1 Chr. 12:18; 2
   Chr. 11:11) or aides-de-camp.
   
     (4.) The "captain of the temple" mentioned in Acts 4:1 and
   5:24 was not a military officer, but superintendent of the guard
   of priests and Levites who kept watch in the temple by night.
   (Comp. "the ruler of the house of God," 1 Chr. 9:11; 2 Chr.
   31:13; Neh. 11:11.)
   
     (5.) The Captain of our salvation is a name given to our Lord
   (Heb. 2:10), because he is the author and source of our
   salvation, the head of his people, whom he is conducting to
   glory. The "captain of the Lord's host" (Josh. 5:14, 15) is the
   name given to that mysterious person who manifested himself to
   Abraham (Gen. 12:7), and to Moses in the bush (Ex. 3:2, 6, etc.)
   the Angel of the covenant. (See {ANGEL}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>captain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Master \Mas"ter\ (m[.a]s"t[~e]r), n. [OE. maistre, maister, OF.
   maistre, mestre, F. ma[^i]tre, fr. L. magister, orig. a
   double comparative from the root of magnus great, akin to Gr.
   me`gas. Cf. {Maestro}, {Magister}, {Magistrate}, {Magnitude},
   {Major}, {Mister}, {Mistress}, {Mickle}.]
   1. A male person having another living being so far subject
      to his will, that he can, in the main, control his or its
      actions; -- formerly used with much more extensive
      application than now.
      (a) The employer of a servant.
      (b) The owner of a slave.
      (c) The person to whom an apprentice is articled.
      (d) A sovereign, prince, or feudal noble; a chief, or one
          exercising similar authority.
      (e) The head of a household.
      (f) The male head of a school or college.
      (g) A male teacher.
      (h) The director of a number of persons performing a
          ceremony or sharing a feast.
      (i) The owner of a docile brute, -- especially a dog or
          horse.
      (j) The controller of a familiar spirit or other
          supernatural being.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. One who uses, or controls at will, anything inanimate; as,
      to be master of one's time. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Master of a hundred thousand drachms. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are masters of the sea.            --Jowett
                                                  (Thucyd.).
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who has attained great skill in the use or application
      of anything; as, a master of oratorical art.
      [1913 Webster]

            Great masters of ridicule.            --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            No care is taken to improve young men in their own
            language, that they may thoroughly understand and be
            masters of it.                        --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A title given by courtesy, now commonly pronounced
      m[i^]ster, except when given to boys; -- sometimes written
      {Mister}, but usually abbreviated to Mr.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A young gentleman; a lad, or small boy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where there are little masters and misses in a
            house, they are impediments to the diversions of the
            servants.                             --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) The commander of a merchant vessel; -- usually
      called {captain}. Also, a commissioned officer in the navy
      ranking next above ensign and below lieutenant; formerly,
      an officer on a man-of-war who had immediate charge, under
      the commander, of sailing the vessel.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A person holding an office of authority among the
      Freemasons, esp. the presiding officer; also, a person
      holding a similar office in other civic societies.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Little masters}, certain German engravers of the 16th
      century, so called from the extreme smallness of their
      prints.

   {Master in chancery}, an officer of courts of equity, who
      acts as an assistant to the chancellor or judge, by
      inquiring into various matters referred to him, and
      reporting thereon to the court.

   {Master of arts}, one who takes the second degree at a
      university; also, the degree or title itself, indicated by
      the abbreviation M. A., or A. M.

   {Master of the horse}, the third great officer in the British
      court, having the management of the royal stables, etc. In
      ceremonial cavalcades he rides next to the sovereign.

   {Master of the rolls}, in England, an officer who has charge
      of the rolls and patents that pass the great seal, and of
      the records of the chancery, and acts as assistant judge
      of the court. --Bouvier. --Wharton.

   {Past master},
      (a) one who has held the office of master in a lodge of
          Freemasons or in a society similarly organized.
      (b) a person who is unusually expert, skilled, or
          experienced in some art, technique, or profession; --
          usually used with at or of.

   {The old masters}, distinguished painters who preceded modern
      painters; especially, the celebrated painters of the 16th
      and 17th centuries.

   {To be master of one's self}, to have entire self-control;
      not to be governed by passion.

   {To be one's own master}, to be at liberty to act as one
      chooses without dictation from anybody.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Master, signifying chief, principal, masterly,
         superior, thoroughly skilled, etc., is often used
         adjectively or in compounds; as, master builder or
         master-builder, master chord or master-chord, master
         mason or master-mason, master workman or
         master-workman, master mechanic, master mind, master
         spirit, master passion, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

               Throughout the city by the master gate.
                                                  --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Master joint} (Geol.), a quarryman's term for the more
      prominent and extended joints traversing a rock mass.

   {Master key}, a key adapted to open several locks differing
      somewhat from each other; figuratively, a rule or
      principle of general application in solving difficulties.
      

   {Master lode} (Mining), the principal vein of ore.

   {Master mariner}, an experienced and skilled seaman who is
      certified to be competent to command a merchant vessel.

   {Master sinew} (Far.), a large sinew that surrounds the hough
      of a horse, and divides it from the bone by a hollow
      place, where the windgalls are usually seated.

   {Master singer}. See {Mastersinger}.

   {Master stroke}, a capital performance; a masterly
      achievement; a consummate action; as, a master stroke of
      policy.

   {Master tap} (Mech.), a tap for forming the thread in a screw
      cutting die.

   {Master touch}.
      (a) The touch or skill of a master. --Pope.
      (b) Some part of a performance which exhibits very
          skillful work or treatment. ``Some master touches of
          this admirable piece.'' --Tatler.

   {Master work}, the most important work accomplished by a
      skilled person, as in architecture, literature, etc.;
      also, a work which shows the skill of a master; a
      masterpiece.

   {Master workman}, a man specially skilled in any art,
      handicraft, or trade, or who is an overseer, foreman, or
      employer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>captain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Captain \Cap"tain\ (k[a^]p"t[i^]n), n. [OE. capitain, captain,
   OF. capitain, F. capitaine (cf. Sp. capitan, It. capitano),
   LL. capitaneus, capitanus, fr. L. caput the head. See under
   {Chief}, and cf. {Chieftain}.]
   1. A head, or chief officer; as:
      (a) The military officer who commands a company, troop, or
          battery, or who has the rank entitling him to do so
          though he may be employed on other service.
      (b) An officer in the United States navy, next above a
          commander and below a commodore, and ranking with a
          colonel in the army.
      (c) By courtesy, an officer actually commanding a vessel,
          although not having the rank of captain.
      (d) The master or commanding officer of a merchant vessel.
      (e) One in charge of a portion of a ship's company; as, a
          captain of a top, captain of a gun, etc.
      (f) The foreman of a body of workmen.
      (g) A person having authority over others acting in
          concert; as, the captain of a boat's crew; the captain
          of a football team.
          [1913 Webster]

                A trainband captain eke was he.   --Cowper.
          [1913 Webster]

                The Rhodian captain, relying on . . . the
                lightness of his vessel, passed, in open day,
                through all the guards.           --Arbuthnot.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A military leader; a warrior.
      [1913 Webster]

            Foremost captain of his time.         --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Captain general}.
      (a) The commander in chief of an army or armies, or of the
          militia.
      (b) The Spanish governor of Cuba and its dependent
          islands.

   {Captain lieutenant}, a lieutenant with the rank and duties
      of captain but with a lieutenant's pay, -- as in the first
      company of an English regiment.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>captain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Captain \Cap"tain\, v. t.
   To act as captain of; to lead. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Men who captained or accompanied the exodus from
         existing forms. --Lowell.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>captain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Captain \Cap"tain\, a.
   Chief; superior. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         captain jewes in the carcanet.           --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>captain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>captain
     n 1: an officer holding a rank below a major but above a
          lieutenant
     2: the naval officer in command of a military ship [syn: {skipper}]
     3: a policeman in charge of a precinct [syn: {police captain},
        {police chief}]
     4: an officer who is licensed to command a merchant ship [syn:
        {master}, {sea captain}, {skipper}]
     5: the leader of a group of people; "a captain of industry"
        [syn: {chieftain}]
     6: the pilot ins charge of an airship [syn: {senior pilot}]
     7: a diningroom attendant who is in charge of the waiters and
        the seating of customers [syn: {headwaiter}, {maitre
        d'hotel}, {maitre d'}]
     v : be the captain of a sports team
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
