<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>car</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>car</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gauge \Gauge\, n. [Written also gage.]
   1. A measure; a standard of measure; an instrument to
      determine dimensions, distance, or capacity; a standard.
      [1913 Webster]

            This plate must be a gauge to file your worm and
            groove to equal breadth by.           --Moxon.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is not in our hands any fixed gauge of minds.
                                                  --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Measure; dimensions; estimate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gauge and dimensions of misery, depression, and
            contempt.                             --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach. &amp; Manuf.) Any instrument for ascertaining or
      regulating the dimensions or forms of things; a templet or
      template; as, a button maker's gauge.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Physics) Any instrument or apparatus for measuring the
      state of a phenomenon, or for ascertaining its numerical
      elements at any moment; -- usually applied to some
      particular instrument; as, a rain gauge; a steam gauge.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.)
      (a) Relative positions of two or more vessels with
          reference to the wind; as, a vessel has the weather
          gauge of another when on the windward side of it, and
          the lee gauge when on the lee side of it.
      (b) The depth to which a vessel sinks in the water.
          --Totten.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. The distance between the rails of a railway.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The standard gauge of railroads in most countries is
         four feet, eight and one half inches. Wide, or broad,
         gauge, in the United States, is six feet; in England,
         seven feet, and generally any gauge exceeding standard
         gauge. Any gauge less than standard gauge is now called
         narrow gauge. It varies from two feet to three feet six
         inches.
         [1913 Webster]

   7. (Plastering) The quantity of plaster of Paris used with
      common plaster to accelerate its setting.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Building) That part of a shingle, slate, or tile, which
      is exposed to the weather, when laid; also, one course of
      such shingles, slates, or tiles.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Gauge of a carriage}, {car}, etc., the distance between the
      wheels; -- ordinarily called the {track}.

   {Gauge cock}, a stop cock used as a try cock for ascertaining
      the height of the water level in a steam boiler.

   {Gauge concussion} (Railroads), the jar caused by a car-wheel
      flange striking the edge of the rail.

   {Gauge glass}, a glass tube for a water gauge.

   {Gauge lathe}, an automatic lathe for turning a round object
      having an irregular profile, as a baluster or chair round,
      to a templet or gauge.

   {Gauge point}, the diameter of a cylinder whose altitude is
      one inch, and contents equal to that of a unit of a given
      measure; -- a term used in gauging casks, etc.

   {Gauge rod}, a graduated rod, for measuring the capacity of
      barrels, casks, etc.

   {Gauge saw}, a handsaw, with a gauge to regulate the depth of
      cut. --Knight.

   {Gauge stuff}, a stiff and compact plaster, used in making
      cornices, moldings, etc., by means of a templet.

   {Gauge wheel}, a wheel at the forward end of a plow beam, to
      determine the depth of the furrow.

   {Joiner's gauge}, an instrument used to strike a line
      parallel to the straight side of a board, etc.

   {Printer's gauge}, an instrument to regulate the length of
      the page.

   {Rain gauge}, an instrument for measuring the quantity of
      rain at any given place.

   {Salt gauge}, or {Brine gauge}, an instrument or contrivance
      for indicating the degree of saltness of water from its
      specific gravity, as in the boilers of ocean steamers.

   {Sea gauge}, an instrument for finding the depth of the sea.
      

   {Siphon gauge}, a glass siphon tube, partly filled with
      mercury, -- used to indicate pressure, as of steam, or the
      degree of rarefaction produced in the receiver of an air
      pump or other vacuum; a manometer.

   {Sliding gauge}. (Mach.)
      (a) A templet or pattern for gauging the commonly accepted
          dimensions or shape of certain parts in general use,
          as screws, railway-car axles, etc.
      (b) A gauge used only for testing other similar gauges,
          and preserved as a reference, to detect wear of the
          working gauges.
      (c) (Railroads) See Note under {Gauge}, n., 5.

   {Star gauge} (Ordnance), an instrument for measuring the
      diameter of the bore of a cannon at any point of its
      length.

   {Steam gauge}, an instrument for measuring the pressure of
      steam, as in a boiler.

   {Tide gauge}, an instrument for determining the height of the
      tides.

   {Vacuum gauge}, a species of barometer for determining the
      relative elasticities of the vapor in the condenser of a
      steam engine and the air.

   {Water gauge}.
      (a) A contrivance for indicating the height of a water
          surface, as in a steam boiler; as by a gauge cock or
          glass.
      (b) The height of the water in the boiler.

   {Wind gauge}, an instrument for measuring the force of the
      wind on any given surface; an anemometer.

   {Wire gauge}, a gauge for determining the diameter of wire or
      the thickness of sheet metal; also, a standard of size.
      See under {Wire}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>car</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Automobile \Au"to*mo*bile`\, n. [F.]
   a self-propelled vehicle used for transporting passengers,
   suitable for use on a street or roadway. Many diferent models
   of automobiles have beenbuilt and sold commercially,
   possessing varied features such as a retractable roof (in a
   {convertible}), different braking systems, different
   propulsion systems, and varied styling. Most models have four
   wheels but some have been built with three wheels.
   Automobiles are usually propelled by internal combustion
   engines (using volatile inflammable liquids, as gasoline or
   petrol, alcohol, naphtha, etc.), and sometimes by steam
   engines, or electric motors. The power of the driving motor
   varies from under 50 H. P. for earlier models to over 200 H.
   P. larger models or high-performance sports or racing cars.
   An automobile is commonly called a {car} or an {auto}, and
   generally in British usage, {motor cars}.

   Syn: car, auto, machine, motorcar.
        [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>car</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Car \Car\, n. [OF. car, char, F. cahr, fr. L. carrus, Wagon: a
   Celtic word; cf. W. car, Armor. karr, Ir. &amp; Gael. carr. cf.
   {Chariot}.]
   1. A small vehicle moved on wheels; usually, one having but
      two wheels and drawn by one horse; a cart.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A vehicle adapted to the rails of a railroad. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In England a railroad passenger car is called a railway
         carriage; a freight car a goods wagon; a platform car a
         goods truck; a baggage car a van. But styles of car
         introduced into England from America are called cars;
         as, tram car. Pullman car. See {Train}.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. A chariot of war or of triumph; a vehicle of splendor,
      dignity, or solemnity. [Poetic].
      [1913 Webster]

            The gilded car of day.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The towering car, the sable steeds.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Astron.) The stars also called Charles's Wain, the Great
      Bear, or the Dipper.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Pleiads, Hyads, and the Northern Car. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The cage of a lift or elevator.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The basket, box, or cage suspended from a balloon to
      contain passengers, ballast, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A floating perforated box for living fish. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Car coupling}, or {Car coupler}, a shackle or other device
      for connecting the cars in a railway train. [U. S.]

   {Dummy car} (Railroad), a car containing its own steam power
      or locomotive.

   {Freight car} (Railrood), a car for the transportation of
      merchandise or other goods. [U. S.]

   {Hand car} (Railroad), a small car propelled by hand, used by
      railroad laborers, etc. [U. S.]

   {Horse car}, or {Street car}, an omnibus car, draw by horses
      or other power upon rails laid in the streets. [U. S.]

   {Palace car}, {Drawing-room car}, {Sleeping car}, {Parlor
   car}, etc. (Railroad), cars especially designed and furnished
      for the comfort of travelers.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>car</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CAR
     Central Access Routing (RND)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>car</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CAR
     Computer Assisted Radiology
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>car</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CAR
     Computer Aided Retrieval
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>car</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>car
     n 1: 4-wheeled motor vehicle; usually propelled by an internal
          combustion engine; "he needs a car to get to work" [syn:
           {auto}, {automobile}, {machine}, {motorcar}]
     2: a wheeled vehicle adapted to the rails of railroad; "three
        cars had jumped the rails" [syn: {railcar}, {railway car},
         {railroad car}]
     3: a conveyance for passengers or freight on a cable railway;
        "they took a cable car to the top of the mountain" [syn: {cable
        car}]
     4: car suspended from an airship and carrying personnel and
        cargo and power plant [syn: {gondola}]
     5: where passengers ride up and down; "the car was on the top
        floor" [syn: {elevator car}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
