<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>card</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>card</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>card
     
        1. A circuit board.
     
        2. A {punched card}.
     
        3. &lt;hypertext&gt; An alternative term for a {node} in a system
        (e.g. {HyperCard}, {Notecards}) in which the node size is
        limited.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>card</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Card \Card\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Carded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Carding}.]
   To play at cards; to game. --Johnson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>card</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Card \Card\, n. [F. carde teasel, the head of a thistle, card,
   from L. carduus, cardus, thistle, fr. carere to card.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. An instrument for disentangling and arranging the fibers
      of cotton, wool, flax, etc.; or for cleaning and smoothing
      the hair of animals; -- usually consisting of bent wire
      teeth set closely in rows in a thick piece of leather
      fastened to a back.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A roll or sliver of fiber (as of wool) delivered from a
      carding machine.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Card clothing}, strips of wire-toothed card used for
      covering the cylinders of carding machines.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>card</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Card \Card\ (k[aum]rd), n. [F. carte, fr. L. charta paper, Gr. ?
   a leaf of paper. Cf. {Chart}.]
   1. A piece of pasteboard, or thick paper, blank or prepared
      for various uses; as, a playing card; a visiting card; a
      card of invitation; pl. a game played with cards.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our first cards were to Carabas House. --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A published note, containing a brief statement,
      explanation, request, expression of thanks, or the like;
      as, to put a card in the newspapers. Also, a printed
      programme, and (fig.), an attraction or inducement; as,
      this will be a good card for the last day of the fair.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A paper on which the points of the compass are marked; the
      dial or face of the mariner's compass.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the quartere that they know
            I' the shipman's card.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Weaving) A perforated pasteboard or sheet-metal plate for
      warp threads, making part of the Jacquard apparatus of a
      loom. See {Jacquard}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An indicator card. See under {Indicator}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Business card}, a card on which is printed an advertisement
      or business address.

   {Card basket}
      (a) A basket to hold visiting cards left by callers.
      (b) A basket made of cardboard.

   {Card catalogue}. See {Catalogue}.

   {Card rack}, a rack or frame for holding and displaying
      business or visiting card.

   {Card table}, a table for use inplaying cards, esp. one
      having a leaf which folds over.

   {On the cards}, likely to happen; foretold and expected but
      not yet brought to pass; -- a phrase of fortune tellers
      that has come into common use; also, according to the
      programme.

   {Playing card}, cards used in playing games; specifically,
      the cards cards used playing which and other games of
      chance, and having each pack divided onto four kinds or
      suits called hearts, diamonds, clubs, and spades. The full
      or whist pack contains fifty-two cards.

   {To have the cards in one's own hands}, to have the winning
      cards; to have the means of success in an undertaking.

   {To play one's cards well}, to make no errors; to act
      shrewdly.

   {To play snow one's cards}, to expose one's plants to rivals
      or foes.

   {To speak by the card}, to speak from information and
      definitely, not by guess as in telling a ship's bearing by
      the compass card.

   {Visiting card}, a small card bearing the name, and sometimes
      the address, of the person presenting it.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>card</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Card \Card\, v. t.
   1. To comb with a card; to cleanse or disentangle by carding;
      as, to card wool; to card a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            These card the short comb the longer flakes. --Dyer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To clean or clear, as if by using a card. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This book [must] be carded and purged. --T. Shelton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To mix or mingle, as with an inferior or weaker article.
      [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            You card your beer, if you guests being to be drunk.
            -- half small, half strong.           --Greene.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the manufacture of wool, cotton, etc., the process
         of carding disentangles and collects together all the
         fibers, of whatever length, and thus differs from
         combing, in which the longer fibers only are collected,
         while the short straple is combed away. See {Combing}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>card</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>card
     n 1: one of a set of small pieces of stiff paper marked in
          various ways and used for playing games or for telling
          fortunes; "he collected cards and traded them with the
          other boys"
     2: a card certifying the identity of the bearer; "he had to
        show his card to get in" [syn: {identity card}]
     3: a rectangular piece of stiff paper used to send messages
        (may have printed greetings or pictures); "they sent us a
        card from Miami"
     4: thin cardboard, usually rectangular
     5: a witty amusing person who makes jokes [syn: {wag}, {wit}]
     6: a sign posted in a public place as an advertisement; "a
        poster advertised the coming attractions" [syn: {poster},
        {posting}, {placard}, {notice}, {bill}]
     7: a printed or written greeting that is left to indicate that
        you have visited [syn: {calling card}, {visiting card}]
     8: (golf) a record of scores (as in golf); "you have to turn in
        your card to get a handicap" [syn: {scorecard}]
     9: a list of dishes available at a restaurant; "the menu was in
        French" [syn: {menu}, {bill of fare}, {carte du jour}, {carte}]
     10: (baseball) a list of batters in the order in which they will
         bat; "the managers presented their cards to the umpire at
         home plate" [syn: {batting order}, {lineup}]
     11: a printed circuit that can be inserted into expansion slots
         in a computer to increase the computer's capabilities
         [syn: {circuit board}, {circuit card}, {board}]
     v 1: separate the fibers of; "tease wool" [syn: {tease}]
     2: ask someone for identification to determine whether he or
        she is old enough to consume liquor; "I was carded when I
        tried to buy a beer!"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
