<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>carpet</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carpet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Carpet \Car"pet\ (k[aum]r"p[e^]t), n. [OF. carpite rug, soft of
   cloth, F. carpette coarse packing cloth, rug (cf. It. carpita
   rug, blanket), LL. carpeta, carpita, woolly cloths, fr. L.
   carpere to pluck, to card (wool); cf. Gr. karpo`s fruit, E.
   {Harvest}.]
   1. A heavy woven or felted fabric, usually of wool, but also
      of cotton, hemp, straw, etc.; esp. a floor covering made
      in breadths to be sewed together and nailed to the floor,
      as distinguished from a rug or mat; originally, also, a
      wrought cover for tables.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tables and beds covered with copes instead of
            carpets and coverlets.                --T. Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A smooth soft covering resembling or suggesting a carpet.
      ``The grassy carpet of this plain.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Carpet beetle} or {Carpet bug} (Zo["o]l.), a small beetle
      ({Anthrenus scrophulari[ae]}), which, in the larval state,
      does great damage to carpets and other woolen goods; --
      also called {buffalo bug}.

   {Carpet knight}.
      (a) A knight who enjoys ease and security, or luxury, and
          has not known the hardships of the field; a hero of
          the drawing room; an effeminate person. --Shak.
      (b) One made a knight, for some other than military
          distinction or service.

   {Carpet moth} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of an insect which feeds
      on carpets and other woolen goods. There are several
      kinds. Some are the larv[ae] of species of {Tinea} (as
      {Tinea tapetzella}); others of beetles, esp. {Anthrenus}.
      

   {Carpet snake} (Zo["o]l.), an Australian snake. See {Diamond
      snake}, under {Diamond}.

   {Carpet sweeper}, an apparatus or device for sweeping
      carpets.

   {To be on the carpet}, to be under consideration; to be the
      subject of deliberation; to be in sight; -- an expression
      derived from the use of carpets as table cover.

   {Brussels carpet}. See under {Brussels}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carpet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Carpet \Car"pet\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Carpeted}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Carpeting}.]
   To cover with, or as with, a carpet; to spread with carpets;
   to furnish with a carpet or carpets.
   [1913 Webster]

         Carpeted temples in fashionable squares. --E. Everett.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carpet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>carpet
     n : floor covering consisting of a piece of thick heavy fabric
         (usually with nap or pile) [syn: {rug}, {carpeting}]
     v 1: form a carpet-like cover (over)
     2: cover completely, as if with a carpet; "flowers carpeted the
        meadows"
     3: cover with a carpet; "carpet the floors of the house"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
