<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>carrier</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carrier</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Carrier, OK (town, FIPS 12200)
  Location: 36.47675 N, 98.01438 W
  Population (1990): 171 (74 housing units)
  Area: 41.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 73727
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carrier</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Carrier \Car"ri*er\, n. [From {Carry}.]
   1. One who, or that which, carries or conveys; a messenger.
      [1913 Webster]

            The air which is but . . . a carrier of the sounds.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who is employed, or makes it his business, to carry
      goods for others for hire; a porter; a teamster.
      [1913 Webster]

            The roads are crowded with carriers, laden with rich
            manufactures.                         --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.) That which drives or carries; as:
      (a) A piece which communicates to an object in a lathe the
          motion of the face plate; a lathe dog.
      (b) A spool holder or bobbin holder in a braiding machine.
          (c) A movable piece in magazine guns which transfers
          the cartridge to a position from which it can be
          thrust into the barrel.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Carrier pigeon} (Zo["o]l.), a variety of the domestic pigeon
      used to convey letters from a distant point to to its
      home.

   {Carrier shell} (Zo["o]l.), a univalve shell of the genus
      {Phorus}; -- so called because it fastens bits of stones
      and broken shells to its own shell, to such an extent as
      almost to conceal it.

   {Common carrier} (Law.) See under {Common}, a.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carrier</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>carrier
     n 1: someone whose employment involves carrying something; "the
          bonds were transmitted by carrier" [syn: {bearer}, {toter}]
     2: a self-propelled wheeled vehicle designed specifically to
        carry something; "refrigerated carriers have
        revolutionized the grocery business"
     3: a large warship that carries planes and has a long flat deck
        for take-offs and landings [syn: {aircraft carrier}, {flattop},
         {attack aircraft carrier}]
     4: an inactive substance that is a vehicle for a radioactive
        tracer of the same substance and that assists in its
        recovery after some chemical reaction
     5: a person or firm in the business of transporting people or
        goods or messages [syn: {common carrier}]
     6: a radio wave that can be modulated in order to transmit a
        signal [syn: {carrier wave}]
     7: a man who delivers the mail [syn: {mailman}, {postman}, {mail
        carrier}, {letter carrier}]
     8: a boy who delivers newspapers [syn: {newsboy}]
     9: a person who has some pathogen to which he is immune but who
        can pass it on to others [syn: {immune carrier}]
     10: a rack attached to a vehicle; for carrying luggage or skis
         or the like
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
