<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>carry</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Carry \Car"ry\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Carried}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Carrying}.] [OF. carier, charier, F. carrier, to cart, from
   OF. car, char, F. car, car. See {Car}.]
   1. To convey or transport in any manner from one place to
      another; to bear; -- often with away or off.
      [1913 Webster]

            When he dieth he shall carry nothing away. --Ps.
                                                  xiix. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

            Devout men carried Stephen to his burial. --Acts
                                                  viii, 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Another carried the intelligence to Russell.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sound will be carried, at the least, twenty
            miles.                                --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To have or hold as a burden, while moving from place to
      place; to have upon or about one's person; to bear; as, to
      carry a wound; to carry an unborn child.
      [1913 Webster]

            If the ideas . . . were carried along with us in our
            minds.                                --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To move; to convey by force; to impel; to conduct; to lead
      or guide.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go, carry Sir John Falstaff to the Fleet. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He carried away all his cattle.       --Gen. xxxi.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

            Passion and revenge will carry them too far.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To transfer from one place (as a country, book, or column)
      to another; as, to carry the war from Greece into Asia; to
      carry an account to the ledger; to carry a number in
      adding figures.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To convey by extension or continuance; to extend; as, to
      carry the chimney through the roof; to carry a road ten
      miles farther.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To bear or uphold successfully through conflict, as a
      leader or principle; hence, to succeed in, as in a
      contest; to bring to a successful issue; to win; as, to
      carry an election. ``The greater part carries it.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The carrying of our main point.       --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To get possession of by force; to capture.
      [1913 Webster]

            The town would have been carried in the end.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To contain; to comprise; to bear the aspect of; to show or
      exhibit; to imply.
      [1913 Webster]

            He thought it carried something of argument in it.
                                                  --Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

            It carries too great an imputation of ignorance.
                                                  --Lacke.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To bear (one's self); to behave, to conduct or demean; --
      with the reflexive pronouns.
      [1913 Webster]

            He carried himself so insolently in the house, and
            out of the house, to all persons, that he became
            odious.                               --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To bear the charges or burden of holding or having, as
       stocks, merchandise, etc., from one time to another; as,
       a merchant is carrying a large stock; a farm carries a
       mortgage; a broker carries stock for a customer; to carry
       a life insurance.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Carry arms} (Mil. Drill), a command of the Manual of Arms
      directing the soldier to hold his piece in the right hand,
      the barrel resting against the hollow of the shoulder in a
      nearly perpendicular position. In this position the
      soldier is said to stand, and the musket to be held, at
      carry.

   {To carry all before one}, to overcome all obstacles; to have
      uninterrupted success.

   {To carry arms}
       (a) To bear weapons.
       (b) To serve as a soldier.

   {To carry away}.
       (a) (Naut.) to break off; to lose; as, to carry away a
           fore-topmast.
       (b) To take possession of the mind; to charm; to delude;
           as, to be carried by music, or by temptation.

   {To carry coals}, to bear indignities tamely, a phrase used
      by early dramatists, perhaps from the mean nature of the
      occupation. --Halliwell.

   {To carry coals to Newcastle}, to take things to a place
      where they already abound; to lose one's labor.

   {To carry off}
       (a) To remove to a distance.
       (b) To bear away as from the power or grasp of others.
       (c) To remove from life; as, the plague carried off
           thousands.

   {To carry on}
       (a) To carry farther; to advance, or help forward; to
           continue; as, to carry on a design.
       (b) To manage, conduct, or prosecute; as, to carry on
           husbandry or trade.

   {To carry out}.
       (a) To bear from within.
       (b) To put into execution; to bring to a successful
           issue.
       (c) To sustain to the end; to continue to the end.

   {To carry through}.
       (a) To convey through the midst of.
       (b) To support to the end; to sustain, or keep from
           falling, or being subdued. ``Grace will carry us . .
           . through all difficulties.'' --Hammond.
       (c) To complete; to bring to a successful issue; to
           succeed.

   {To carry up}, to convey or extend in an upward course or
      direction; to build.

   {To carry weight}.
       (a) To be handicapped; to have an extra burden, as when
           one rides or runs. ``He carries weight, he rides a
           race'' --Cowper.
       (b) To have influence.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Carry \Car"ry\, v. i.
   1. To act as a bearer; to convey anything; as, to fetch and
      carry.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To have propulsive power; to propel; as, a gun or mortar
      carries well.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To hold the head; -- said of a horse; as, to carry well i.
      e., to hold the head high, with arching neck.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Hunting) To have earth or frost stick to the feet when
      running, as a hare. --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To carry on}, to behave in a wild, rude, or romping manner.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Carry \Car"ry\, n.; pl. {Carries}.
   A tract of land, over which boats or goods are carried
   between two bodies of navigable water; a carrying place; a
   portage. [U.S.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>carry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>carry
     n : the act of carrying something
     v 1: move while supporting, either in a vehicle or in one's hands
          or on one's body; "You must carry your camping gear";
          "carry the suitcases to the car"; "This train is
          carrying nuclear waste"; "These pipes carry waste water
          into the river" [syn: {transport}]
     2: have with oneself; have on one's person; "She always takes
        an umbrella"; "I always carry money"; "She packs a gun
        when she goes into the mountains" [syn: {pack}, {take}]
     3: transmit or serve as the medium for transmission; "Sound
        carries well over water"; "The airwaves carry the sound";
        "Many metals conduct heat" [syn: {conduct}, {transmit}, {convey},
         {channel}]
     4: serve as a means for expressing something; "The painting of
        Mary carries motherly love"; "His voice carried a lot af
        anger" [syn: {convey}, {express}]
     5: bear or be able to bear the weight, pressure,or
        responsibility of; "His efforts carried the entire
        project"; "How many credits is this student carrying?";
        "We carry a very large mortgage"
     6: support or hold in a certain manner; "She holds her head
        high"; "He carried himself upright" [syn: {hold}, {bear}]
     7: contain or hold; have within; "The jar carries wine"; "The
        canteen holds fresh water"; "This can contains water"
        [syn: {hold}, {bear}, {contain}]
     8: extend to a certain degree; "carry too far"; "She carries
        her ideas to the extreme"
     9: continue or extend; "The civil war carried into the
        neighboring province"; "The disease extended into the
        remote mountain provinces" [syn: {extend}]
     10: be necessarily associated with or result in or involve;
         "This crime carries a penalty of five years in prison"
     11: win in an election; "The senator carried his home state"
     12: include, as on a list; "How many people are carried on the
         payroll?"
     13: behave in a certain manner; "She carried herself well"; "he
         bore himself with dignity"; "They conducted themselves
         well during these difficult times" [syn: {behave}, {acquit},
          {bear}, {deport}, {conduct}, {comport}]
     14: have on hand; "Do you carry kerosene heaters?" [syn: {stock},
          {stockpile}]
     15: include as the content; broadcast or publicize; "We ran the
         ad three times"; "This paper carries a restaurant
         review"; "All major networks carried the press
         conference" [syn: {run}]
     16: propel, "Carry the ball"; "dribble the ball" [syn: {dribble}]
     17: pass on a communication; "The news was carried to every
         village in the province"
     18: have as an inherent or characteristic feature or have as a
         consequence; "This new washer carries a two year
         guarantee"; "The loan carries a high interest rate";
         "this undertaking carries many dangers"; "She carries her
         mother's genes"; "These bonds carry warrants"; "The
         restaurant carries an unusual name"
     19: be conveyed over a certain distance; "Her voice carries very
         well in this big opera house"
     20: keep up with financial support; "The Federal Government
         carried the province for many years"
     21: have or possess something abstract; "I carry her image in my
         mind's eye"; "I will carry the secret to my grave"; "I
         carry these thoughts in the back of my head"; "I carry a
         lot of life insurance"
     22: win approval or support for; "Carry all before one"; "His
         speech did not sway the voters" [syn: {persuade}, {sway}]
     23: compensate for a weaker partner or member by one's own
         performance; "I resent having to carry her all the time"
     24: take further or advance; "carry a cause"
     25: have on the surface or on the skin; "carry scars"
     26: capture after a fight; "The troops carried the town after a
         brief fight"
     27: transfer (entries) from one account book to another [syn: {post}]
     28: transfer (a number, cipher, or remainder) to the next column
         or unit's place before or after, in addition or
         multiplication; "put down 5 and carry 2"
     29: pursue a line of scent or be a bearer; "the dog was taught
         to fetch and carry"
     30: bear (a crop); "this land does not carry olives"
     31: propel or give impetus to; "The sudden gust of air propelled
         the ball to the other side of the fence"
     32: drink alcohol without showing ill effects; "He can hold his
         liquor"; "he had drunk more than he could carry" [syn: {hold}]
     33: be able to feed; "This land will carry ten cows to the acre"
     34: have a certain range; "This rifle carries for 3,000 feet"
     35: cover a certain distance or advance beyond; "The drive
         carried to the green"
     36: secure the passage or adoption (of bills and motions); "The
         motion carried easily"
     37: be successful in; "She lost the game but carried the match"
     38: sing or play against other voices or parts; "He cannot carry
         a tune"
     39: be pregnant with; "She is bearing his child"; "The are
         expecting another child in January"; "I am carrying his
         child" [syn: {have a bun in the oven}, {bear}, {gestate},
          {expect}]
     [also: {carried}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
