<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cartoon</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cartoon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>comic strip \com"ic strip`\ (k[o^]m"[i^]k str[i^]p), n.
   a brief sequence of drawings, usually with characters drawn
   only sketchily, as in a cartoon, with dialog written in
   ``balloons'' over a character's head, and depicting a
   fictional and usually comical incident; -- also called a
   {cartoon}. Each comic strip contains typically from four to
   six panels arranged horizontally, but widely varying
   arrangements are published. In modern newspapers, weekly
   comic strips are in color, and daily strips are usually in
   black and white. In some, the story depicted may be
   serialized and continuous, carried over from day to day or
   week to week. Stories of adventure, drama, mystery or an
   otherwise non-comical nature depicted in the same style are
   also called comic strips.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cartoon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cartoon \Car*toon"\, n. [F. carton (cf. It. cartone pasteboard,
   cartoon); fr. L. charta. See 1st {card}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A design or study drawn of the full size, to serve as a
      model for transferring or copying; -- used in the making
      of mosaics, tapestries, fresco pantings and the like; as,
      the cartoons of Raphael.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A large pictorial sketch, as in a journal or magazine;
      esp. a pictorial caricature; as, the cartoons of ``Puck.''
      [1913 Webster]

   3. same as {comic strip}.
      [PJC]

   4. a motion picture consisting of a series of frames, each
      being a photograph of a drawing rather than a frame
      produced by filming a scene of true action, and in which
      the objects are displaced slightly in succeeding frames so
      as to give the appearance of motion when projected as a
      motion picture on the screen. The types of characters
      portrayed in such films are often similar or identical to
      those in a {comic strip}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cartoon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cartoon
     n 1: a humorous or satirical drawing published in a newspaper or
          magazine [syn: {sketch}]
     2: a film made by photographing a series of cartoon drawings to
        give the illusion of movement when projected in rapid
        sequence [syn: {animated cartoon}]
     v : draw cartoons of
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
