<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>casting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>casting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cast \Cast\ (k[.a]st), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cast}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Casting}.] [Cf. Dan. kaste, Icel. &amp; Sw. kasta; perh. akin
   to L. {gerere} to bear, carry. E. jest.]
   1. To send or drive by force; to throw; to fling; to hurl; to
      impel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Uzziah prepared . . . slings to cast stones. --2
                                                  Chron. xxvi.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cast thy garment about thee, and follow me. --Acts.
                                                  xii. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

            We must be cast upon a certain island. --Acts.
                                                  xxvii. 26.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To direct or turn, as the eyes.
      [1913 Webster]

            How earnestly he cast his eyes upon me! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To drop; to deposit; as, to cast a ballot.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To throw down, as in wrestling. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To throw up, as a mound, or rampart.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thine enemies shall cast a trench [bank] about thee.
                                                  --Luke xix.
                                                  48.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To throw off; to eject; to shed; to lose.
      [1913 Webster]

            His filth within being cast.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Neither shall your vine cast her fruit. --Mal. iii.
                                                  11
      [1913 Webster]

            The creatures that cast the skin are the snake, the
            viper, etc.                           --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To bring forth prematurely; to slink.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy she-goats have not cast their young. --Gen. xxi.
                                                  38.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To throw out or emit; to exhale. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This . . . casts a sulphureous smell. --Woodward.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To cause to fall; to shed; to reflect; to throw; as, to
      cast a ray upon a screen; to cast light upon a subject.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To impose; to bestow; to rest.
       [1913 Webster]

             The government I cast upon my brother. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             Cast thy burden upon the Lord.       --Ps. iv. 22.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To dismiss; to discard; to cashier. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

             The state can not with safety cast him.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To compute; to reckon; to calculate; as, to cast a
       horoscope. ``Let it be cast and paid.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             You cast the event of war, my noble lord. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To contrive; to plan. [Archaic]
       [1913 Webster]

             The cloister . . . had, I doubt not, been cast for
             [an orange-house].                   --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. To defeat in a lawsuit; to decide against; to convict;
       as, to be cast in damages.
       [1913 Webster]

             She was cast to be hanged.           --Jeffrey.
       [1913 Webster]

             Were the case referred to any competent judge, they
             would inevitably be cast.            --Dr. H. More.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. To turn (the balance or scale); to overbalance; hence, to
       make preponderate; to decide; as, a casting voice.
       [1913 Webster]

             How much interest casts the balance in cases
             dubious!                             --South.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. To form into a particular shape, by pouring liquid metal
       or other material into a mold; to fashion; to found; as,
       to cast bells, stoves, bullets.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Print.) To stereotype or electrotype.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. To fix, distribute, or allot, as the parts of a play
       among actors; also to assign (an actor) for a part.
       [1913 Webster]

             Our parts in the other world will be new cast.
                                                  --Addison.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To cast anchor} (Naut.) See under {Anchor}.

   {To cast a horoscope}, to calculate it.

   {To cast a} {horse, sheep}, or other animal, to throw with
      the feet upwards, in such a manner as to prevent its
      rising again.

   {To cast a shoe}, to throw off or lose a shoe, said of a
      horse or ox.

   {To cast aside}, to throw or push aside; to neglect; to
      reject as useless or inconvenient.

   {To cast away}.
       (a) To throw away; to lavish; to waste. ``Cast away a
           life'' --Addison.
       (b) To reject; to let perish. ``Cast away his people.''
           --Rom. xi. 1. ``Cast one away.'' --Shak.
       (c) To wreck. ``Cast away and sunk.'' --Shak.

   {To cast by}, to reject; to dismiss or discard; to throw
      away.

   {To cast down}, to throw down; to destroy; to deject or
      depress, as the mind. ``Why art thou cast down. O my
      soul?'' --Ps. xiii. 5.

   {To cast forth}, to throw out, or eject, as from an inclosed
      place; to emit; to send out.

   {To cast in one's lot with}, to share the fortunes of.

   {To cast in one's teeth}, to upbraid or abuse one for; to
      twin.

   {To cast lots}. See under {Lot}.

   {To cast off}.
       (a) To discard or reject; to drive away; to put off; to
           free one's self from.
       (b) (Hunting) To leave behind, as dogs; also, to set
           loose, or free, as dogs. --Crabb.
       (c) (Naut.) To untie, throw off, or let go, as a rope.

   {To cast off copy}, (Print.), to estimate how much printed
      matter a given amount of copy will make, or how large the
      page must be in order that the copy may make a given
      number of pages.

   {To cast one's self on} or {To cast one's self upon} to yield
      or submit one's self unreservedly to, as to the mercy of
      another.

   {To cast out}, to throw out; to eject, as from a house; to
      cast forth; to expel; to utter.

   {To cast the lead} (Naut.), to sound by dropping the lead to
      the bottom.

   {To cast the water} (Med.), to examine the urine for signs of
      disease. [Obs.].

   {To cast up}.
       (a) To throw up; to raise.
       (b) To compute; to reckon, as the cost.
       (c) To vomit.
       (d) To twit with; to throw in one's teeth.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>casting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Casting \Cast"ing\, n.
   1. The act of one who casts or throws, as in fishing.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act or process of making casts or impressions, or of
      shaping metal or plaster in a mold; the act or the process
      of pouring molten metal into a mold.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is cast in a mold; esp. the mass of metal so
      cast; as, a casting in iron; bronze casting.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The warping of a board. --Brande &amp; C.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The act of casting off, or that which is cast off, as
      skin, feathers, excrement, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Casting of draperies}, the proper distribution of the folds
      of garments, in painting and sculpture.

   {Casting line} (Fishing), the leader; also, sometimes applied
      to the long reel line.

   {Casting net}, a net which is cast and drawn, in distinction
      from a net that is set and left.

   {Casting voice}, {Casting vote}, the decisive vote of a
      presiding officer, when the votes of the assembly or house
      are equally divided. ``When there was an equal vote, the
      governor had the casting voice.'' --B. Trumbull.

   {Casting weight}, a weight that turns a balance when exactly
      poised.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>casting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>casting
     n 1: object formed by a mold [syn: {cast}]
     2: the act of creating something by casting it in a mold [syn:
        {molding}]
     3: the act of throwing a fishing line out over the water by
        means of a rod and reel [syn: {cast}]
     4: the choice of actors to play particular roles in a play or
        movie
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
