<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cattle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cattle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cattle
   abounded in the Holy Land. To the rearing and management of them
   the inhabitants chiefly devoted themselves (Deut. 8:13; 12:21; 1
   Sam. 11:5; 12:3; Ps. 144:14; Jer. 3:24). They may be classified
   as,
   
     (1.) Neat cattle. Many hundreds of these were yearly consumed
   in sacrifices or used for food. The finest herds were found in
   Bashan, beyond Jordan (Num. 32:4). Large herds also pastured on
   the wide fertile plains of Sharon. They were yoked to the plough
   (1 Kings 19:19), and were employed for carrying burdens (1 Chr.
   12:40). They were driven with a pointed rod (Judg. 3:31) or goad
   (q.v.).
   
     According to the Mosaic law, the mouths of cattle employed for
   the threshing-floor were not to be muzzled, so as to prevent
   them from eating of the provender over which they trampled
   (Deut. 25:4). Whosoever stole and sold or slaughtered an ox must
   give five in satisfaction (Ex. 22:1); but if it was found alive
   in the possession of him who stole it, he was required to make
   double restitution only (22:4). If an ox went astray, whoever
   found it was required to bring it back to its owner (23:4; Deut.
   22:1, 4). An ox and an ass could not be yoked together in the
   plough (Deut. 22:10).
   
     (2.) Small cattle. Next to herds of neat cattle, sheep formed
   the most important of the possessions of the inhabitants of
   Palestine (Gen. 12:16; 13:5; 26:14; 21:27; 29:2, 3). They are
   frequently mentioned among the booty taken in war (Num. 31:32;
   Josh. 6:21; 1 Sam. 14:32; 15:3). There were many who were owners
   of large flocks (1 Sam. 25:2; 2 Sam. 12:2, comp. Job 1:3). Kings
   also had shepherds "over their flocks" (1 Chr. 27:31), from
   which they derived a large portion of their revenue (2 Sam.
   17:29; 1 Chr. 12:40). The districts most famous for their flocks
   of sheep were the plain of Sharon (Isa. 65: 10), Mount Carmel
   (Micah 7:14), Bashan and Gilead (Micah 7:14). In patriarchal
   times the flocks of sheep were sometimes tended by the daughters
   of the owners. Thus Rachel, the daughter of Laban, kept her
   father's sheep (Gen. 29:9); as also Zipporah and her six sisters
   had charge of their father Jethro's flocks (Ex. 2:16). Sometimes
   they were kept by hired shepherds (John 10:12), and sometimes by
   the sons of the family (1 Sam. 16:11; 17:15). The keepers so
   familiarized their sheep with their voices that they knew them,
   and followed them at their call. Sheep, but more especially rams
   and lambs, were frequently offered in sacrifice. The shearing of
   sheep was a great festive occasion (1 Sam. 25:4; 2 Sam. 13:23).
   They were folded at night, and guarded by their keepers against
   the attacks of the lion (Micah 5:8), the bear (1 Sam. 17:34),
   and the wolf (Matt. 10:16; John 10:12). They were liable to
   wander over the wide pastures and go astray (Ps. 119:176; Isa.
   53:6; Hos. 4:16; Matt. 18:12).
   
     Goats also formed a part of the pastoral wealth of Palestine
   (Gen. 15:9; 32:14; 37:31). They were used both for sacrifice and
   for food (Deut. 14:4), especially the young males (Gen. 27:9,
   14, 17; Judg. 6:19; 13:15; 1 Sam. 16:20). Goat's hair was used
   for making tent cloth (Ex. 26:7; 36:14), and for mattresses and
   bedding (1 Sam. 19:13, 16). (See {GOAT}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cattle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cattle \Cat"tle\ (k[a^]t"t'l), n. pl. [OE. calet, chatel, goods,
   property, OF. catel, chatel, LL. captale, capitale, goods,
   property, esp. cattle, fr. L. capitals relating to the head,
   chief; because in early ages beasts constituted the chief
   part of a man's property. See {Capital}, and cf. {Chattel}.]
   Quadrupeds of the Bovine family; sometimes, also, including
   all domestic quadrupeds, as sheep, goats, horses, mules,
   asses, and swine.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Belted cattle}, {Black cattle}. See under {Belted}, {Black}.
      

   {Cattle guard}, a trench under a railroad track and alongside
      a crossing (as of a public highway). It is intended to
      prevent cattle from getting upon the track.

   {cattle louse} (Zo["o]l.), any species of louse infecting
      cattle. There are several species. The {H[ae]matatopinus
      eurysternus} and {H[ae]matatopinus vituli} are common
      species which suck blood; {Trichodectes scalaris} eats the
      hair.

   {Cattle plague}, the rinderpest; called also {Russian cattle
      plague}.

   {Cattle range}, or {Cattle run}, an open space through which
      cattle may run or range. [U. S.] --Bartlett.

   {Cattle show}, an exhibition of domestic animals with prizes
      for the encouragement of stock breeding; -- usually
      accompanied with the exhibition of other agricultural and
      domestic products and of implements.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cattle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cattle
     n : domesticated bovine animals as a group regardless of sex or
         age; "so many head of cattle"; "wait till the cows come
         home"; "seven thin and ill-favored kine"- Bible; "a team
         of oxen" [syn: {cows}, {kine}, {oxen}, {Bos taurus}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
