<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cellular</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cellular</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cellular
     
        &lt;language, cellular automaton&gt; A system for {cellular
        automaton} programming by J Dana Eckart
        &lt;dana@faculty.cs.runet.edu&gt;.  Cellular includes a {byte-code
        compiler}, {run-time system}, and a viewer.
     
        Latest version: 2.0, as of 1993-04-03.
     
        Posted to comp.sources.unix, volume 26.
     
        See also {Cellang}.
     
        (2000-10-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cellular</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cellular \Cel"lu*lar\ (s[e^]l"[u^]*l[~e]r; 135), a. [L. cellula
   a little cell: cf. F. cellulaire. See {Cellule}.]
   1. Consisting of, or containing, cells; of or pertaining to a
      cell or cells.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. porous; containing cavities.
      [PJC]

   3. pertaining to or using a system of transmission of
      telephone signals by radio, in which areas are divided
      into geographical parts (cells), each of which is served
      by a transmitter whose range is limited to that region,
      thus permitting a single transmission frequency to be used
      simulataneously in different parts of the same area.
      Cellular telephones are typically small and battery
      powered, allowing a subscriber with such a telephone to
      carry the telephone in a pocket or purse, over the entire
      area served, and to be contacted by a single telephone
      number. The system became widespread and popular in the
      1980's and 1990's; as, cellular telephones sometimes lose
      their link unpredictably.
      [PJC]

   {Cellular plants}, {Cellular cryptogams} (Bot.), those
      flowerless plants which have no ducts or fiber in their
      tissue, as mosses, fungi, lichens, and alg[ae].

   {Cellular theory}, or {Cell theory} (Biol.), a theory,
      according to which the essential element of every tissue,
      either vegetable or animal, is a cell; the whole series of
      cells having been formed from the development of the germ
      cell and by differentiation converted into tissues and
      organs which, both in plants and animals, are to be
      considered as a mass of minute cells communicating with
      each other.

   {Cellular tissue}.
      (a) (Anat.) See {conjunctive tissue} under {Conjunctive}.
      (b) (Bot.) Tissue composed entirely of parenchyma, and
          having no woody fiber or ducts.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cellular</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cellular
     adj 1: relating to cells; "cellular walls"; "cellular physiology"
     2: characterized by or divided into or containing cells or
        compartments (the smallest organizational or structural
        unit of an organism or organization); "the cellular
        construction of a beehive"; "any effective opposition to a
        totalitarian regime must be secretive and cellular"; "a
        cellular phone uses a network of shortrange transmitters
        located in overlapping cells" [ant: {noncellular}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
