<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>center</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>center</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Center, CO (town, FIPS 12855)
  Location: 37.75183 N, 106.10990 W
  Population (1990): 1963 (770 housing units)
  Area: 2.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 81125
Center, KY
  Zip code(s): 42214
Center, MO (city, FIPS 12592)
  Location: 39.50985 N, 91.52851 W
  Population (1990): 552 (272 housing units)
  Area: 1.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 63436
Center, ND (city, FIPS 13180)
  Location: 47.11495 N, 101.29692 W
  Population (1990): 826 (351 housing units)
  Area: 0.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Center, NE (village, FIPS 8360)
  Location: 42.60891 N, 97.87588 W
  Population (1990): 112 (55 housing units)
  Area: 0.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 68724
Center, TX (city, FIPS 13732)
  Location: 31.79353 N, 94.17827 W
  Population (1990): 4950 (2161 housing units)
  Area: 16.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 75935
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>center</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Center \Cen"ter\, n. [F. centre, fr. L. centrum, fr. round which
   a circle is described, fr. ? to prick, goad.]
   1. A point equally distant from the extremities of a line,
      figure, or body, or from all parts of the circumference of
      a circle; the middle point or place.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The middle or central portion of anything.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A principal or important point of concentration; the
      nucleus around which things are gathered or to which they
      tend; an object of attention, action, or force; as, a
      center of attaction.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The earth. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Those members of a legislative assembly (as in France) who
      support the existing government. They sit in the middle of
      the legislative chamber, opposite the presiding officer,
      between the conservatives or monarchists, who sit on the
      right of the speaker, and the radicals or advanced
      republicans who occupy the seats on his left, See {Right},
      and {Left}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Arch.) A temporary structure upon which the materials of
      a vault or arch are supported in position until the work
      becomes self-supporting.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mech.)
      (a) One of the two conical steel pins, in a lathe, etc.,
          upon which the work is held, and about which it
          revolves.
      (b) A conical recess, or indentation, in the end of a
          shaft or other work, to receive the point of a center,
          on which the work can turn, as in a lathe.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: In a lathe the

   {live center} is in the spindle of the head stock; the

   {dead center} is on the tail stock.

   {Planer centers} are stocks carrying centers, when the object
      to be planed must be turned on its axis.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Center of an army}, the body or troops occupying the place
      in the line between the wings.

   {Center of a curve} or {Center of a surface} (Geom.)
      (a) A point such that every line drawn through the point
          and terminated by the curve or surface is bisected at
          the point.
      (b) The fixed point of reference in polar co["o]rdinates.
          See {Co["o]rdinates}.

   {Center of curvature of a curve} (Geom.), the center of that
      circle which has at any given point of the curve closer
      contact with the curve than has any other circle whatever.
      See {Circle}.

   {Center of a fleet}, the division or column between the van
      and rear, or between the weather division and the lee.

   {Center of gravity} (Mech.), that point of a body about which
      all its parts can be balanced, or which being supported,
      the whole body will remain at rest, though acted upon by
      gravity.

   {Center of gyration} (Mech.), that point in a rotating body
      at which the whole mass might be concentrated
      (theoretically) without altering the resistance of the
      intertia of the body to angular acceleration or
      retardation.

   {Center of inertia} (Mech.), the center of gravity of a body
      or system of bodies.

   {Center of motion}, the point which remains at rest, while
      all the other parts of a body move round it.

   {Center of oscillation}, the point at which, if the whole
      matter of a suspended body were collected, the time of
      oscillation would be the same as it is in the actual form
      and state of the body.

   {Center of percussion}, that point in a body moving about a
      fixed axis at which it may strike an obstacle without
      communicating a shock to the axis.

   {Center of pressure} (Hydros.), that point in a surface
      pressed by a fluid, at which, if a force equal to the
      whole pressure and in the same line be applied in a
      contrary direction, it will balance or counteract the
      whole pressure of the fluid.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>center</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Center \Cen"ter\, Centre \Cen"tre\, v. t.
   1. To place or fix in the center or on a central point.
      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To collect to a point; to concentrate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy joys are centered all in me alone. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mech.) To form a recess or indentation for the reception
      of a center.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>center</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Center \Cen"ter\, Centre \Cen"tre\ v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Centered} or {Centred}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Centering} or
   {Centring}.]
   1. To be placed in a center; to be central.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be collected to a point; to be concentrated; to rest
      on, or gather about, as a center.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where there is no visible truth wherein to center,
            error is as wide as men's fancies.    --Dr. H. More.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our hopes must center in ourselves alone. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>center</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>center
     adj 1: equally distant from the extremes [syn: {center(a)}, {halfway},
             {middle(a)}, {midway}]
     2: of or belonging to neither the right nor the left
        politically or intellectually [ant: {right}, {left}]
     n 1: an area that is approximately central within some larger
          region; "it is in the center of town"; "they ran forward
          into the heart of the struggle"; "they were in the eye
          of the storm" [syn: {centre}, {middle}, {heart}, {eye}]
     2: the piece of ground in the outfield directly ahead of the
        catcher; "he hit the ball to deep center" [syn: {center
        field}]
     3: a building dedicated to a particular activity; "they were
        raising money to build a new center for research" [syn: {centre}]
     4: a point equidistant from the ends of a line or the
        extremities of a figure [syn: {centre}, {midpoint}]
     5: the choicest or most essential or most vital part of some
        idea or experience; "the gist of the prosecutor's
        argument"; "the heart and soul of the Republican Party";
        "the nub of the story" [syn: {kernel}, {substance}, {core},
         {essence}, {gist}, {heart}, {heart and soul}, {inwardness},
         {marrow}, {meat}, {nub}, {pith}, {sum}, {nitty-gritty}]
     6: the object upon which interest and attention focuses; "his
        stories made him the center of the party" [syn: {center of
        attention}]
     7: a cluster of nerve cells governing a specific bodily
        process; "in most people the speech center is in the left
        hemisphere" [syn: {centre}, {nerve center}, {nerve centre}]
     8: the middle of a military or naval formation; "they had to
        reinforce the center"
     9: (basketball) the person who plays center on a basketball
        team
     10: (football) the person who plays center on the line of
         scrimmage and snaps the ball to the quarterback; "the
         center fumbled the handoff" [syn: {snapper}]
     11: a place where some particular activity is concentrated;
         "they received messages from several centers" [syn: {centre}]
     12: politically moderate persons; centrists
     13: (ice hockey) the person who plays center on a hockey team
     14: the sweet central portion of a piece of candy that is
         enclosed in chocolate or some other covering [syn: {centre}]
     15: mercantile establishment consisting of a carefully
         landscaped complex of shops representing leading
         merchandisers; usually includes restaurants and a
         convenient parking area; a modern version of the
         traditional marketplace; "a good plaza should have a
         movie house"; "they spent their weekends at the local
         malls" [syn: {plaza}, {mall}, {shopping mall}, {shopping
         center}, {shopping centre}]
     16: the position on a hockey team of the player who participates
         in the face off at the beginning of the game
     17: the position of the player on the line of scrimmage who puts
         the ball in play; "it is a center's responsibility to get
         the football to the quarterback"
     18: a position on a basketball team of the player who
         participates in the center jump to start the game
     v 1: center upon; "Her entire attention centered on her
          children"; "Our day revolved around our work" [syn: {focus
          on}, {center on}, {revolve around}, {revolve about}, {concentrate
          on}]
     2: direct one's attention on something; "Please focus on your
        studies and not on your hobbies" [syn: {concentrate}, {focus},
         {centre}, {pore}, {rivet}]
     3: move into the center; "That vase in the picture is not
        centered" [syn: {centre}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
