<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ceremony</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ceremony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ceremony \Cer"e*mo*ny\, n.; pl. {Ceremonies}. [F.
   c['e]r['e]monie, L. caerimonia; perh. akin to E. create and
   from a root signifying to do or make.]
   1. Ar act or series of acts, often of a symbolical character,
      prescribed by law, custom, or authority, in the conduct of
      important matters, as in the performance of religious
      duties, the transaction of affairs of state, and the
      celebration of notable events; as, the ceremony of
      crowning a sovereign; the ceremonies observed in
      consecrating a church; marriage and baptismal ceremonies.
      [1913 Webster]

            According to all the rites of it, and according to
            all the ceremonies thereof shall ye keep it [the
            Passover].                            --Numb. ix. 3
      [1913 Webster]

            Bring her up the high altar, that she may
            The sacred ceremonies there partake.  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The heralds] with awful ceremony
            And trumpet's sound, throughout the host proclaim
            A solemn council.                     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Behavior regulated by strict etiquette; a formal method of
      performing acts of civility; forms of civility prescribed
      by custom or authority.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ceremony was but devised at first
            To set a gloss on . . . hollow welcomes . . .
            But where there is true friendship there needs none.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Al ceremonies are in themselves very silly things;
            but yet a man of the world should know them.
                                                  --Chesterfield.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A ceremonial symbols; an emblem, as a crown, scepter,
      garland, etc. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Disrobe the images,
            If you find them decked with ceremonies.
            . . . Let no images
            Be hung with C[ae]sar's trophies.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A sign or prodigy; a portent. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            C[ae]sar, I never stood on ceremonies,
            Yet, now they fright me.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Master of ceremonies}, an officer who determines the forms
      to be observed, or superintends their observance, on a
      public occasion.

   {Not to stand on ceremony}, not to be ceremonious; to be
      familiar, outspoken, or bold.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ceremony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ceremony
     n 1: a formal event performed on a special occasion; "a ceremony
          commemorating Pearl Harbor" [syn: {ceremonial}, {ceremonial
          occasion}, {observance}]
     2: any activity that is performed in an especially solemn
        elaborate or formal way; "the ceremony of smelling the
        cork and tasting the wine"; "he makes a ceremony of
        addressing his golf ball"; "he disposed of it without
        ceremony"
     3: the proper or conventional behavior on some solemn occasion;
        "an inaugural ceremony"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
