<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>chamber</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chamber</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chamber
   "on the wall," which the Shunammite prepared for the prophet
   Elisha (2 Kings 4:10), was an upper chamber over the porch
   through the hall toward the street. This was the "guest chamber"
   where entertainments were prepared (Mark 14:14). There were also
   "chambers within chambers" (1 Kings 22:25; 2 Kings 9:2). To
   enter into a chamber is used metaphorically of prayer and
   communion with God (Isa. 26:20). The "chambers of the south"
   (Job 9:9) are probably the constelations of the southern
   hemisphere. The "chambers of imagery", i.e., chambers painted
   with images, as used by Ezekiel (8:12), is an expression
   denoting the vision the prophet had of the abominations
   practised by the Jews in Jerusalem.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chamber</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chamber \Cham"ber\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Chambered}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Chambering}.]
   1. To reside in or occupy a chamber or chambers.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be lascivious. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chamber</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chamber \Cham"ber\, v. t.
   1. To shut up, as in a chamber. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To furnish with a chamber; as, to chamber a gun.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chamber</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chamber \Cham"ber\, n. [F. chambre, fr. L. camera vault, arched
   roof, in LL. chamber, fr. Gr. ? anything with a vaulted roof
   or arched covering; cf. Skr. kmar to be crooked. Cf.
   {Camber}, {Camera}, {Comrade}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A retired room, esp. an upper room used for sleeping; a
      bedroom; as, the house had four chambers.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. Apartments in a lodging house. ``A bachelor's life in
      chambers.'' --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A hall, as where a king gives audience, or a deliberative
      body or assembly meets; as, presence chamber; senate
      chamber.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A legislative or judicial body; an assembly; a society or
      association; as, the Chamber of Deputies; the Chamber of
      Commerce.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A compartment or cell; an inclosed space or cavity; as,
      the chamber of a canal lock; the chamber of a furnace; the
      chamber of the eye.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. pl. (Law.) A room or rooms where a lawyer transacts
      business; a room or rooms where a judge transacts such
      official business as may be done out of court.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A chamber pot. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mil.)
      (a) That part of the bore of a piece of ordnance which
          holds the charge, esp. when of different diameter from
          the rest of the bore; -- formerly, in guns, made
          smaller than the bore, but now larger, esp. in
          breech-loading guns.
      (b) A cavity in a mine, usually of a cubical form, to
          contain the powder.
      (c) A short piece of ordnance or cannon, which stood on
          its breech, without any carriage, formerly used
          chiefly for rejoicings and theatrical cannonades.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Air chamber}. See {Air chamber}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Chamber of commerce}, a board or association to protect the
      interests of commerce, chosen from among the merchants and
      traders of a city.

   {Chamber council}, a secret council. --Shak.

   {Chamber counsel} or {Chamber counselor}, a counselor who
      gives his opinion in private, or at his chambers, but does
      not advocate causes in court.

   {Chamber fellow}, a chamber companion; a roommate; a chum.

   {Chamber hangings}, tapestry or hangings for a chamber.

   {Chamber lye}, urine. --Shak.

   {Chamber music}, vocal or instrumental music adapted to
      performance in a chamber or small apartment or audience
      room, instead of a theater, concert hall, or church.

   {Chamber practice} (Law.), the practice of counselors at law,
      who give their opinions in private, but do not appear in
      court.

   {To sit at chambers}, to do business in chambers, as a judge.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chamber</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>chamber
     n 1: a natural or artificial enclosed space
     2: an enclosed volume (as the aqueous chamber of the eyeball or
        the chambers of the heart)
     3: a room where a judge transacts business
     4: a deliberative or legislative or administrative or judicial
        assembly; "the upper chamber is the senate"
     5: a room used primarily for sleeping [syn: {bedroom}, {sleeping
        room}, {bedchamber}]
     v : place in a chamber
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
