<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>change</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>change</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exchange \ex*change"\ ([e^]ks*ch[=a]nj"), n. [OE. eschange,
   eschaunge, OF. eschange, fr. eschangier, F. ['e]changer, to
   exchange; pref. ex- out + F. changer. See {Change}, and cf.
   {Excamb}.]
   1. The act of giving or taking one thing in return for
      another which is regarded as an equivalent; as, an
      exchange of cattle for grain.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of substituting one thing in the place of another;
      as, an exchange of grief for joy, or of a scepter for a
      sword, and the like; also, the act of giving and receiving
      reciprocally; as, an exchange of civilities or views.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The thing given or received in return; esp., a publication
      exchanged for another. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Com.) The process of setting accounts or debts between
      parties residing at a distance from each other, without
      the intervention of money, by exchanging orders or drafts,
      called bills of exchange. These may be drawn in one
      country and payable in another, in which case they are
      called foreign bills; or they may be drawn and made
      payable in the same country, in which case they are called
      inland bills. The term bill of exchange is often
      abbreviated into exchange; as, to buy or sell exchange.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A in London is creditor to B in New York, and C in
         London owes D in New York a like sum. A in London draws
         a bill of exchange on B in New York; C in London
         purchases the bill, by which A receives his debt due
         from B in New York. C transmits the bill to D in New
         York, who receives the amount from B.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) A mutual grant of equal interests, the one in
      consideration of the other. Estates exchanged must be
      equal in quantity, as fee simple for fee simple.
      --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The place where the merchants, brokers, and bankers of a
      city meet at certain hours, to transact business; also,
      the institution which sets regulations and maintains the
      physical facilities of such a place; as, the New York
      Stock Exchange; a commodity exchange. In this sense the
      word was at one time often contracted to {'change}
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   {Arbitration of exchange}. See under {Arbitration}.

   {Bill of exchange}. See under {Bill}.

   {Exchange broker}. See under {Broker}.

   {Par of exchange}, the established value of the coin or
      standard of value of one country when expressed in the
      coin or standard of another, as the value of the pound
      sterling in the currency of France or the United States.
      The par of exchange rarely varies, and serves as a measure
      for the rise and fall of exchange that is affected by the
      demand and supply. Exchange is at par when, for example, a
      bill in New York, for the payment of one hundred pounds
      sterling in London, can be purchased for the sum. Exchange
      is in favor of a place when it can be purchased there at
      or above par.

   {Telephone exchange}, a central office in which the wires of
      any two telephones or telephone stations may be connected
      to permit conversation.

   Syn: Barter; dealing; trade; traffic; interchange.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>change</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Change \Change\ (ch[=a]nj), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Changed}
   (ch[=a]njd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Changing}.] [F. changer, fr.
   LL. cambiare, to exchange, barter, L. cambire. Cf.
   {Cambial}.]
   1. To alter; to make different; to cause to pass from one
      state to another; as, to change the position, character,
      or appearance of a thing; to change the countenance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore will I change their glory into shame.
                                                  --Hosea. iv.
                                                  7.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To alter by substituting something else for, or by giving
      up for something else; as, to change the clothes; to
      change one's occupation; to change one's intention.
      [1913 Webster]

            They that do change old love for new,
            Pray gods, they change for worse!     --Peele.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give and take reciprocally; to exchange; -- followed by
      with; as, to change place, or hats, or money, with
      another.
      [1913 Webster]

            Look upon those thousands with whom thou wouldst
            not, for any interest, change thy fortune and
            condition.                            --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically: To give, or receive, smaller denominations
      of money (technically called change) for; as, to change a
      gold coin or a bank bill.
      [1913 Webster]

            He pulled out a thirty-pound note and bid me change
            it.                                   --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To change a horse, or To change hand} (Man.), to turn or
      bear the horse's head from one hand to the other, from the
      left to right, or from the right to the left.

   {To change hands}, to change owners.

   {To change one's tune}, to become less confident or boastful.
      [Colloq.]

   {To change step}, to take a break in the regular succession
      of steps, in marching or walking, as by bringing the
      hollow of one foot against the heel of the other, and then
      stepping off with the foot which is in advance.

   Syn: To alter; vary; deviate; substitute; innovate;
        diversify; shift; veer; turn. See {Alter}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>change</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Change \Change\, v. i.
   1. To be altered; to undergo variation; as, men sometimes
      change for the better.
      [1913 Webster]

            For I am Lord, I change not.          --Mal. iii. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pass from one phase to another; as, the moon changes
      to-morrow night.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>change</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Change \Change\, n. [F. change, fr. changer. See {Change}. v.
   t.]
   1. Any variation or alteration; a passing from one state or
      form to another; as, a change of countenance; a change of
      habits or principles.
      [1913 Webster]

            Apprehensions of a change of dynasty. --Hallam.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the days of my appointed time will I wait, till
            my change come.                       --Job xiv. 14.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A succesion or substitution of one thing in the place of
      another; a difference; novelty; variety; as, a change of
      seasons.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our fathers did for change to France repair.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ringing grooves of change.        --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A passing from one phase to another; as, a change of the
      moon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Alteration in the order of a series; permutation.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which makes a variety, or may be substituted for
      another.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thirty change (R.V. changes) of garments. --Judg.
                                                  xiv. 12.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Small money; the money by means of which the larger coins
      and bank bills are made available in small dealings;
      hence, the balance returned when payment is tendered by a
      coin or note exceeding the sum due.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. [See {Exchange}.] A place where merchants and others meet
      to transact business; a building appropriated for
      mercantile transactions. [Colloq. for Exchange.]
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A public house; an alehouse. [Scot.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They call an alehouse a change.       --Burt.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mus.) Any order in which a number of bells are struck,
      other than that of the diatonic scale.
      [1913 Webster]

            Four bells admit twenty-four changes in ringing.
                                                  --Holder.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Change of life}, the period in the life of a woman when
      menstruation and the capacity for conception cease,
      usually occurring between forty-five and fifty years of
      age.

   {Change ringing}, the continual production, without
      repetition, of changes on bells, See def. 9. above.

   {Change wheel} (Mech.), one of a set of wheels of different
      sizes and number of teeth, that may be changed or
      substituted one for another in machinery, to produce a
      different but definite rate of angular velocity in an
      axis, as in cutting screws, gear, etc.

   {To ring the changes on}, to present the same facts or
      arguments in variety of ways.

   Syn: Variety; variation; alteration; mutation; transition;
        vicissitude; innovation; novelty; transmutation;
        revolution; reverse.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>change</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>change
     n 1: an event that occurs when something passes from one state or
          phase to another; "the change was intended to increase
          sales"; "this storm is certainly a change for the
          worse"; "the neighborhood had undergone few
          modifications since his last visit years ago" [syn: {alteration},
           {modification}]
     2: a relational difference between states; especially between
        states before and after some event; "he attributed the
        change to their marriage"
     3: the action of changing something; "the change of government
        had no impact on the economy"; "his change on abortion
        cost him the election"
     4: the result of alteration or modification; "there were marked
        changes in the lining of the lungs"; "there had been no
        change in the mountains"
     5: the balance of money received when the amount you tender is
        greater than the amount due; "I paid with a twenty and
        pocketed the change"
     6: a thing that is different; "he inspected several changes
        before selecting one"
     7: a different or fresh set of clothes; "she brought a change
        in her overnight bag"
     8: coins of small denomination regarded collectively; "he had a
        pocketful of change"
     9: money received in return for its equivalent in a larger
        denomination or a different currency; "he got change for a
        twenty and used it to pay the taxi driver"
     10: a difference that is usually pleasant; "he goes to France
         for variety"; "it is a refreshing change to meet a woman
         mechanic" [syn: {variety}]
     v 1: undergo a change; become different in essence; losing one's
          or its original nature; "She changed completely as she
          grew older"; "The weather changed last night" [ant: {stay}]
     2: cause to change; make different; cause a transformation;
        "The advent of the automobile may have altered the growth
        pattern of the city"; "The discussion has changed my
        thinking about the issue" [syn: {alter}, {modify}]
     3: make or become different in some particular way, without
        permanently losing one's or its former characteristics or
        essence; "her mood changes in accordance with the
        weather"; "The supermarket's selection of vegetables
        varies according to the season" [syn: {alter}, {vary}]
     4: lay aside, abandon, or leave for another; "switch to a
        different brand of beer"; "She switched psychiatrists";
        "The car changed lanes" [syn: {switch}, {shift}]
     5: change clothes; put on different clothes; "Change before you
        go to the opera"
     6: exchange or replace with another, usually of the same kind
        or category; "Could you convert my dollars into pounds?";
        "He changed his name"; "convert centimeters into inches";
        "convert holdings into shares" [syn: {exchange}, {commute},
         {convert}]
     7: give to, and receive from, one another; "Would you change
        places with me?"; "We have been exchanging letters for a
        year" [syn: {exchange}, {interchange}]
     8: change from one vehicle or transportation line to another;
        "She changed in Chicago on her way to the East coast"
        [syn: {transfer}]
     9: become deeper in tone; "His voice began to change when he
        was 12 years old"; "Her voice deepened when she whispered
        the password" [syn: {deepen}]
     10: remove or replace the coverings of; "Father had to learn how
         to change the baby"; "After each guest we changed the bed
         linens"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
