<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>changing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>changing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Change \Change\ (ch[=a]nj), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Changed}
   (ch[=a]njd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Changing}.] [F. changer, fr.
   LL. cambiare, to exchange, barter, L. cambire. Cf.
   {Cambial}.]
   1. To alter; to make different; to cause to pass from one
      state to another; as, to change the position, character,
      or appearance of a thing; to change the countenance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore will I change their glory into shame.
                                                  --Hosea. iv.
                                                  7.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To alter by substituting something else for, or by giving
      up for something else; as, to change the clothes; to
      change one's occupation; to change one's intention.
      [1913 Webster]

            They that do change old love for new,
            Pray gods, they change for worse!     --Peele.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give and take reciprocally; to exchange; -- followed by
      with; as, to change place, or hats, or money, with
      another.
      [1913 Webster]

            Look upon those thousands with whom thou wouldst
            not, for any interest, change thy fortune and
            condition.                            --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically: To give, or receive, smaller denominations
      of money (technically called change) for; as, to change a
      gold coin or a bank bill.
      [1913 Webster]

            He pulled out a thirty-pound note and bid me change
            it.                                   --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To change a horse, or To change hand} (Man.), to turn or
      bear the horse's head from one hand to the other, from the
      left to right, or from the right to the left.

   {To change hands}, to change owners.

   {To change one's tune}, to become less confident or boastful.
      [Colloq.]

   {To change step}, to take a break in the regular succession
      of steps, in marching or walking, as by bringing the
      hollow of one foot against the heel of the other, and then
      stepping off with the foot which is in advance.

   Syn: To alter; vary; deviate; substitute; innovate;
        diversify; shift; veer; turn. See {Alter}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>changing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>changing
     adj : marked by continuous change or effective action [syn: {ever-changing}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
