<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>chaos</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chaos</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>chaos
     
        A property of some non-linear dynamic systems which exhibit
        sensitive dependence on initial conditions.  This means that
        there are initial states which evolve within some finite time
        to states whose separation in one or more dimensions of state
        space depends, in an average sense, exponentially on their
        initial separation.  Such systems may still be completely
        {deterministic} in that any future state of the system depends
        only on the initial conditions and the equations describing
        the change of the system with time.  It may, however, require
        arbitrarily high precision to actually calculate a future
        state to within some finite precision.
     
        ["On defining chaos", R. Glynn Holt
        &lt;rgholt@voyager.jpl.nasa.gov&gt; and D. Lynn Holt
        &lt;lholt@seraph1.sewanee.edu&gt;.
       
     {(ftp://mrcnext.cso.uiuc.edu/pub/etext/ippe/preprints/Phil_of_Science/Holt_and_Holt.On_Defining_Chaos)}]
     
        Fixed precision {floating-point} arithmetic, as used by most
        computers, may actually introduce chaotic dependence on
        initial conditions due to the accumulation of rounding errors
        (which constitutes a non-linear system).
     
        (1995-02-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chaos</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chaos \Cha"os\ (k[=a]"[o^]s), n. [L. chaos chaos (in senses 1 &amp;
   2), Gr. cha`os, fr. cha`inein (root cha) to yawn, to gape, to
   open widely. Cf. {Chasm}.]
   1. An empty, immeasurable space; a yawning chasm. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Between us and there is fixed a great chaos. --Luke
                                                  xvi. 26
                                                  (Rhemish
                                                  Trans.).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The confused, unorganized condition or mass of matter
      before the creation of distinct and orderly forms.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any confused or disordered collection or state of things;
      a confused mixture; confusion; disorder.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chaos</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>chaos
     n 1: a state of extreme confusion and disorder [syn: {pandemonium},
           {bedlam}, {topsy-turvydom}, {topsy-turvyness}]
     2: the formless and disordered state of matter before the
        creation of the cosmos
     3: (Greek mythology) the most ancient of gods; the
        personification of the infinity of space preceding
        creation of the universe
     4: (physics) a dynamical system that is extremely sensitive to
        its initial conditions
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
