<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>chapel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chapel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chapel
   a holy place or sanctuary, occurs only in Amos 7:13, where one
   of the idol priests calls Bethel "the king's chapel."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chapel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chapel \Chap"el\, v. t.
   1. To deposit or inter in a chapel; to enshrine. [Obs.]
      --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) To cause (a ship taken aback in a light breeze) so
      to turn or make a circuit as to recover, without bracing
      the yards, the same tack on which she had been sailing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chapel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chapel \Chap"el\, n. [OF. chapele, F. chapelle, fr. LL. capella,
   orig., a short cloak, hood, or cowl; later, a reliquary,
   sacred vessel, chapel; dim. of cappa, capa, cloak, cape,
   cope; also, a covering for the head. The chapel where St.
   Martin's cloak was preserved as a precious relic, itself came
   to be called capella, whence the name was applied to similar
   paces of worship, and the guardian of this cloak was called
   capellanus, or chaplain. See {Cap}, and cf. {Chaplain}.,
   {Chaplet}.]
   1. A subordinate place of worship; as,
      (a) a small church, often a private foundation, as for a
          memorial;
      (b) a small building attached to a church;
      (c) a room or recess in a church, containing an altar.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: In Catholic churches, and also in cathedrals and abbey
         churches, chapels are usually annexed in the recesses
         on the sides of the aisles. --Gwilt.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A place of worship not connected with a church; as, the
      chapel of a palace, hospital, or prison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. In England, a place of worship used by dissenters from the
      Established Church; a meetinghouse.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A choir of singers, or an orchestra, attached to the court
      of a prince or nobleman.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Print.)
      (a) A printing office, said to be so called because
          printing was first carried on in England in a chapel
          near Westminster Abbey.
      (b) An association of workmen in a printing office.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Chapel of ease}.
      (a) A chapel or dependent church built for the ease or a
          accommodation of an increasing parish, or for
          parishioners who live at a distance from the principal
          church.
      (b) A privy. (Law)

   {Chapel master}, a director of music in a chapel; the
      director of a court or orchestra.

   {To build a chapel} (Naut.), to chapel a ship. See {Chapel},
      v. t., 2.

   {To hold a chapel}, to have a meeting of the men employed in
      a printing office, for the purpose of considering
      questions affecting their interests.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chapel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>chapel
     n 1: a place of worship that has its own altar
     2: a service conducted in a chapel; "he was late for chapel"
        [syn: {chapel service}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
