<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>charging</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>charging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Charge \Charge\ (ch[aum]rj), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Charged}
   (ch[aum]rjd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Charging}.] [OF. chargier, F.
   charger, fr. LL. carricare, fr. L. carrus wagon. Cf. {Cargo},
   {Caricature}, {Cark}, and see {Car}.]
   1. To lay on or impose, as a load, tax, or burden; to load;
      to fill.
      [1913 Webster]

            A carte that charged was with hay.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The charging of children's memories with rules.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay on or impose, as a task, duty, or trust; to
      command, instruct, or exhort with authority; to enjoin; to
      urge earnestly; as, to charge a jury; to charge the clergy
      of a diocese; to charge an agent.
      [1913 Webster]

            Moses . . . charged you to love the Lord your God.
                                                  --Josh. xxii.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cromwell, I charge thee, fling away ambition.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To lay on, impose, or make subject to or liable for.
      [1913 Webster]

            When land shall be charged by any lien. --Kent.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To fix or demand as a price; as, he charges two dollars a
      barrel for apples.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To place something to the account of as a debt; to debit,
      as, to charge one with goods. Also, to enter upon the
      debit side of an account; as, to charge a sum to one.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To impute or ascribe; to lay to one's charge.
      [1913 Webster]

            No more accuse thy pen, but charge the crime
            On native sloth and negligence of time. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To accuse; to make a charge or assertion against (a person
      or thing); to lay the responsibility (for something said
      or done) at the door of.
      [1913 Webster]

            If he did that wrong you charge him with.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To place within or upon any firearm, piece of apparatus or
      machinery, the quantity it is intended and fitted to hold
      or bear; to load; to fill; as, to charge a gun; to charge
      an electrical machine, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their battering cannon charged to the mouths.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To ornament with or cause to bear; as, to charge an
      architectural member with a molding.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Her.) To assume as a bearing; as, he charges three roses
       or; to add to or represent on; as, he charges his shield
       with three roses or.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To call to account; to challenge. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

             To charge me to an answer.           --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To bear down upon; to rush upon; to attack.
       [1913 Webster]

             Charged our main battle's front.     --Shak.

   Syn: To intrust; command; exhort; instruct; accuse; impeach;
        arraign. See {Accuse}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
