<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>charity</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>charity</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Charity
   (1 Cor. 13), the rendering in the Authorized Version of the word
   which properly denotes love, and is frequently so rendered
   (always so in the Revised Version). It is spoken of as the
   greatest of the three Christian graces (1 Cor. 12:31-13:13).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>charity</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CHARITY
     
        &lt;language&gt; A {functional language} based purely on {category
        theory} by Cockett, Spencer, and Fukushima, 1990-1991.
     
        A version for {Sun-4} is available from Tom Fukushima
        &lt;fukushim@ucalgary.ca&gt;.
     
        ["About Charity", J.R.B. Cockett, U. Calgary, Canada, et al].
     
        (2000-10-30)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>charity</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Charity \Char"i*ty\, n.; pl. {Charities}. [F. charit['e] fr. L.
   caritas dearness, high regard, love, from carus dear, costly,
   loved; asin to Skr. kam to wish, love, cf. Ir. cara a friend,
   W. caru to love. Cf. {Caress}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Love; universal benevolence; good will.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now abideth faith, hope, charity, three; but the
            greatest of these is charity.         --1. Cor.
                                                  xiii. 13.
      [1913 Webster]

            They, at least, are little to be envied, in whose
            hearts the great charities . . . lie dead. --Ruskin.
      [1913 Webster]

            With malice towards none, with charity for all.
                                                  --Lincoln.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Liberality in judging of men and their actions; a
      disposition which inclines men to put the best
      construction on the words and actions of others.
      [1913 Webster]

            The highest exercise of charity is charity towards
            the uncharitable.                     --Buckminster.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Liberality to the poor and the suffering, to benevolent
      institutions, or to worthy causes; generosity.
      [1913 Webster]

            The heathen poet, in commending the charity of Dido
            to the Trojans, spake like a Christian. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Whatever is bestowed gratuitously on the needy or
      suffering for their relief; alms; any act of kindness.
      [1913 Webster]

            She did ill then to refuse her a charity.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A charitable institution, or a gift to create and support
      such an institution; as, Lady Margaret's charity.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. pl. (Law) Eleemosynary appointments [grants or devises]
      including relief of the poor or friendless, education,
      religious culture, and public institutions.
      [1913 Webster]

            The charities that soothe, and heal, and bless,
            Are scattered at the feet of man like flowers.
                                                  --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Sisters of Charity} (R. C. Ch.), a sisterhood of religious
      women engaged in works of mercy, esp. in nursing the sick;
      -- a popular designation. There are various orders of the
      Sisters of Charity.

   Syn: Love; benevolence; good will; affection; tenderness;
        beneficence; liberality; almsgiving.
        [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>charity</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>charity
     n 1: a foundation created to promote the public good (not for
          assistance to any particular individuals)
     2: a kindly and lenient attitude toward people [syn: {brotherly
        love}]
     3: an activity or gift that benefits the public at large
     4: pinnate-leaved European perennial having bright blue or
        white flowers [syn: {Jacob's ladder}, {Greek valerian}, {Polemonium
        caeruleum}, {Polemonium van-bruntiae}, {Polymonium
        caeruleum van-bruntiae}]
     5: an institution set up to provide help to the needy
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
