<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>chase</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chase, AK (CDP, FIPS 12350)
  Location: 62.44907 N, 150.10176 W
  Population (1990): 38 (54 housing units)
  Area: 93.5 sq km (land), 2.5 sq km (water)
Chase, KS (city, FIPS 12650)
  Location: 38.35567 N, 98.34840 W
  Population (1990): 577 (285 housing units)
  Area: 0.8 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 67524
Chase, MI
  Zip code(s): 49623
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chase \Chase\, n. [Cf. F. chasse, fr. chasser. See {Chase}, v.]
   1. Vehement pursuit for the purpose of killing or capturing,
      as of an enemy, or game; an earnest seeking after any
      object greatly desired; the act or habit of hunting; a
      hunt. ``This mad chase of fame.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            You see this chase is hotly followed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is pursued or hunted.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nay, Warwick, seek thee out some other chase,
            For I myself must hunt this deer to death. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An open hunting ground to which game resorts, and which is
      private properly, thus differing from a forest, which is
      not private property, and from a park, which is inclosed.
      Sometimes written chace. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Court Tennis) A division of the floor of a gallery,
      marked by a figure or otherwise; the spot where a ball
      falls, and between which and the dedans the adversary must
      drive his ball in order to gain a point.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Chase gun} (Naut.), a cannon placed at the bow or stern of
      an armed vessel, and used when pursuing an enemy, or in
      defending the vessel when pursued.

   {Chase port} (Naut.), a porthole from which a chase gun is
      fired.

   {Stern chase} (Naut.), a chase in which the pursuing vessel
      follows directly in the wake of the vessel pursued.

   {cut to the chase} (Film), a term used in action movies
      meaning, to shift the scene to the most exciting part,
      where someone is being chased. It is used metaphorically
      to mean ``get to the main point''.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chase \Chase\ (ch[=a]s), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Chased}
   (ch[=a]st); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Chasing}.] [OF. chacier, F.
   chasser, fr. (assumed) LL. captiare, fr. L. captare to strive
   to seize. See {Catch}.]
   1. To pursue for the purpose of killing or taking, as an
      enemy, or game; to hunt.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are those which chased you from the field.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Philologists, who chase
            A panting syllable through time and place. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To follow as if to catch; to pursue; to compel to move on;
      to drive by following; to cause to fly; -- often with away
      or off; as, to chase the hens away.
      [1913 Webster]

            Chased by their brother's endless malice from prince
            to prince and from place to place.    --Knolles.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pursue eagerly, as hunters pursue game.
      [1913 Webster]

            Chasing each other merrily.           --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chase \Chase\, v. i.
   To give chase; to hunt; as, to chase around after a doctor.
   [Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chase \Chase\, n. [F. ch['a]se, fr. L. capsa box, case. See
   {Case} a box.] (Print.)
   1. A rectangular iron frame in which pages or columns of type
      are imposed.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) The part of a cannon from the re["e]nforce or the
      trunnions to the swell of the muzzle. See {Cannon}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A groove, or channel, as in the face of a wall; a trench,
      as for the reception of drain tile.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Shipbuilding) A kind of joint by which an overlap joint
      is changed to a flush joint, by means of a gradually
      deepening rabbet, as at the ends of clinker-built boats.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chase \Chase\, v. t. [A contraction of enchase.]
   1. To ornament (a surface of metal) by embossing, cutting
      away parts, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cut, so as to make a screw thread.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>chase
     n : the act of pursuing in an effort to overtake or capture;
         "the culprit started to run and the cop took off in
         pursuit" [syn: {pursuit}, {following}]
     v 1: go after with the intent to catch; "The policeman chased the
          mugger down the alley"; "the dog chased the rabbit"
          [syn: {chase after}, {trail}, {tail}, {tag}, {give chase},
           {dog}, {go after}, {track}]
     2: pursue someone sexually or romantically [syn: {chase after}]
     3: cut a groove into; "chase silver"
     4: cut a furrow into a columns [syn: {furrow}, {chamfer}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
