<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>checking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>checking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Check \Check\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Checked} (ch[e^]kt); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {checking}.]
   1. (Chess) To make a move which puts an adversary's piece,
      esp. his king, in check; to put in check.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put a sudden restraint upon; to stop temporarily; to
      hinder; to repress; to curb. Hence, (Ice Hockey) To
      obstruct the motion of an opposing player by contacting
      him with one's body.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            So many clogs to check and retard the headlong
            course of violence and oppression.    --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To verify, to guard, to make secure, by means of a mark,
      token, or other check; to distinguish by a check; to put a
      mark against (an item) after comparing with an original or
      a counterpart in order to secure accuracy. Hence, To
      compare with an original or with some standard, to insure
      correctness; as, to check an account; to check with a
      supervisor about procedures.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. To chide, rebuke, or reprove.
      [1913 Webster]

            The good king, his master, will check him for it.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) To slack or ease off, as a brace which is too
      stiffly extended.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To make checks or chinks in; to cause to crack; as, the
      sun checks timber.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To leave (something) in the temporary custody of another;
      as, to check baggage; to check one's firearms at the door;
      to check one's coat at the cloakroom.
      [PJC]

   8. To accept (something) for temporary custody from another;
      as, to check a customer's baggage; to check a customer's
      coat.
      [PJC]

   9. To make a checkered pattern upon.
      [PJC]

   Syn: To restrain; curb; bridle; repress; control; hinder;
        impede; obstruct; interrupt; tally; rebuke; reprove;
        rebuff.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
