<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>check</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>check</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Check \Check\ (ch[e^]k), n. [OE. chek, OF. eschec, F. ['e]chec,
   a stop, hindrance, orig. check in the game of chess, pl.
   ['e]checs chess, through Ar., fr. Pers. sh[=a]h king. See
   {Shah}, and cf. {Checkmate}, {Chess}, {Checker}.]
   1. (Chess) A word of warning denoting that the king is in
      danger; such a menace of a player's king by an adversary's
      move as would, if it were any other piece, expose it to
      immediate capture. A king so menaced is said to be in
      check, and must be made safe at the next move.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A condition of interrupted or impeded progress; arrest;
      stop; delay; as, to hold an enemy in check.
      [1913 Webster]

            Which gave a remarkable check to the first progress
            of Christianity.                      --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            No check, no stay, this streamlet fears.
                                                  --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Whatever arrests progress, or limits action; an obstacle,
      guard, restraint, or rebuff.
      [1913 Webster]

            Useful check upon the administration of government.
                                                  --Washington.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man whom no check could abash.      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A mark, certificate, or token, by which, errors may be
      prevented, or a thing or person may be identified; as,
      checks placed against items in an account; a check given
      for baggage; a return check on a railroad.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A written order directing a bank or banker to pay money as
      therein stated. See {Bank check}, below.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A woven or painted design in squares resembling the patten
      of a checkerboard; one of the squares of such a design;
      also, cloth having such a figure.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Falconry) The forsaking by a hawk of its proper game to
      follow other birds.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Small chick or crack.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bank check}, a written order on a banker or broker to pay
      money in his keeping belonging to the signer.

   {Check book}, a book containing blank forms for checks upon a
      bank.

   {Check hook}, a hook on the saddle of a harness, over which a
      checkrein is looped.

   {Check list}, a list or catalogue by which things may be
      verified, or on which they may be checked.

   {Check nut} (Mech.), a secondary nut, screwing down upon the
      primary nut to secure it. --Knight.

   {Check valve} (Mech.), a valve in the feed pipe of a boiler,
      or other conduit, to prevent the return of the feed water
      or other fluid.

   {To take check}, to take offense. [Obs.] --Dryden.

   Syn: Hindrance; setback; interruption; obstruction;
        reprimand; censure; rebuke; reproof; repulse; rebuff;
        tally; counterfoil; counterbalance; ticket; draft.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>check</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Check \Check\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Checked} (ch[e^]kt); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {checking}.]
   1. (Chess) To make a move which puts an adversary's piece,
      esp. his king, in check; to put in check.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put a sudden restraint upon; to stop temporarily; to
      hinder; to repress; to curb. Hence, (Ice Hockey) To
      obstruct the motion of an opposing player by contacting
      him with one's body.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            So many clogs to check and retard the headlong
            course of violence and oppression.    --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To verify, to guard, to make secure, by means of a mark,
      token, or other check; to distinguish by a check; to put a
      mark against (an item) after comparing with an original or
      a counterpart in order to secure accuracy. Hence, To
      compare with an original or with some standard, to insure
      correctness; as, to check an account; to check with a
      supervisor about procedures.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. To chide, rebuke, or reprove.
      [1913 Webster]

            The good king, his master, will check him for it.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) To slack or ease off, as a brace which is too
      stiffly extended.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To make checks or chinks in; to cause to crack; as, the
      sun checks timber.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To leave (something) in the temporary custody of another;
      as, to check baggage; to check one's firearms at the door;
      to check one's coat at the cloakroom.
      [PJC]

   8. To accept (something) for temporary custody from another;
      as, to check a customer's baggage; to check a customer's
      coat.
      [PJC]

   9. To make a checkered pattern upon.
      [PJC]

   Syn: To restrain; curb; bridle; repress; control; hinder;
        impede; obstruct; interrupt; tally; rebuke; reprove;
        rebuff.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>check</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Check \Check\ (ch[e^]k), v. i.
   To make a stop; to pause; -- with at.
   [1913 Webster]

         The mind, once jaded by an attempt above its power,
         either is disabled for the future, or else checks at
         any vigorous undertaking ever after.     --Locke.
   [1913 Webster]

   2. To clash or interfere. [R.] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To act as a curb or restraint.
      [1913 Webster]

            It [his presence] checks too strong upon me.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To crack or gape open, as wood in drying; or to crack in
      small checks, as varnish, paint, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Falconry) To turn, when in pursuit of proper game, and
      fly after other birds.
      [1913 Webster]

            And like the haggard, check at every feather
            That comes before his eye.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>check</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Check \Check\, a.
   Checkered; designed in checks.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>check</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>check n. A hardware-detected error condition, most commonly used to
   refer to actual hardware failures rather than software-induced traps.
   E.g., a `parity check' is the result of a hardware-detected parity
   error. Recorded here because the word often humorously extended to
   non-technical problems. For example, the term `child check' has been
   used to refer to the problems caused by a small child who is curious to
   know what happens when s/he presses all the cute buttons on a computer's
   console (of course, this particular problem could have been prevented
   with {molly-guard}s).


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>check</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>check
     n 1: a written order directing a bank to pay money; "he paid all
          his bills by check" [syn: {bank check}, {cheque}]
     2: an appraisal of the state of affairs; "they made an assay of
        the contents"; "a check on its dependability under stress"
        [syn: {assay}]
     3: the bill in a restaurant; "he asked the waiter for the
        check" [syn: {chit}, {tab}]
     4: the state of inactivity following an interruption; "the
        negotiations were in arrest"; "held them in check";
        "during the halt he got some lunch"; "the momentary stay
        enabled him to escape the blow"; "he spent the entire stop
        in his seat" [syn: {arrest}, {halt}, {hitch}, {stay}, {stop},
         {stoppage}]
     5: additional proof that something that was believed (some fact
        or hypothesis or theory) is correct; "fossils provided
        further confirmation of the evolutionary theory" [syn: {confirmation},
         {verification}, {substantiation}]
     6: the act of inspecting or verifying; "they made a check of
        their equipment"; "the pilot ran through the check-out
        procedure" [syn: {checkout}, {check-out procedure}]
     7: a mark indicating that something has been noted or completed
        etc.; "as he called the role he put a check mark by each
        student's name" [syn: {check mark}, {tick}]
     8: something immaterial that interferes with or delays action
        or progress [syn: {hindrance}, {deterrent}, {impediment},
        {balk}, {baulk}, {handicap}]
     9: a mark left after a small piece has been chopped or broken
        off of something [syn: {chip}]
     10: a textile pattern of squares or crossed lines (resembling a
         checkerboard); "she wore a skirt with checks"
     11: the act of restraining power or action or limiting excess;
         "his common sense is a bridle to his quick temper" [syn:
         {bridle}, {curb}]
     12: obstructing an opponent in ice hockey
     13: (chess) a direct attack on an opponent's king
     v 1: examine so as to determine accuracy, quality, or condition;
          "check the brakes"; "Check out the engine" [syn: {check
          up on}, {look into}, {check out}, {suss out}, {check
          over}, {go over}, {check into}]
     2: make an examination or investigation; "check into the
        rumor"; "check the time of the class"
     3: be careful or certain to do something; make certain of
        something; "He verified that the valves were closed"; "See
        that the curtains are closed"; "control the quality of the
        product" [syn: {see}, {insure}, {see to it}, {ensure}, {control},
         {ascertain}, {assure}]
     4: lessen the intensity of; temper; hold in restraint; hold or
        keep within limits; "moderate your alcohol intake"; "hold
        your tongue"; "hold your temper"; "control your anger"
        [syn: {control}, {hold in}, {hold}, {contain}, {curb}, {moderate}]
     5: stop for a moment, as if out of uncertainty or caution; "She
        checked for an instant and missed a step"
     6: put a check mark on or next to; "Please check each name on
        the list"; "tick off the items" [syn: {check off}, {mark},
         {mark off}, {tick off}, {tick}]
     7: slow the growth or development of; "The brain damage will
        retard the child's language development" [syn: {retard}, {delay}]
     8: be verified or confirmed; pass inspection; "These stories
        don't check!" [syn: {check out}]
     9: be compatible, similar or consistent; coincide in their
        characteristics; "The two stories don't agree in many
        details"; "The handwriting checks with the signature on
        the check"; "The suspect's fingerprints don't match those
        on the gun" [syn: {match}, {fit}, {correspond}, {jibe}, {gibe},
         {tally}, {agree}] [ant: {disagree}]
     10: block or impede (a player from the opposing team) in ice
         hockey
     11: train by instruction and practice; especially to teach
         self-control; "Parents must discipline their children";
         "Is this dog trained?" [syn: {discipline}, {train}, {condition}]
     12: consign for shipment on a vehicle; "check your luggage
         before boarding"
     13: hand over something to somebody as for temporary
         safekeeping; "Check your coat at the door"
     14: abandon the intended prey, turn, and pursue an inferior
         prey, of falcons
     15: stop in a chase especially when scent is lost; "The dog
         checked"
     16: mark into squares or draw squares on; draw crossed lines on
         [syn: {checker}, {chequer}]
     17: decline to initiate betting
     18: hold back, as of a danger or an enemy; check the expansion
         or influence of; "Arrest the downward trend"; "Check the
         growth of communism in Sout East Asia"; "Contain the
         rebel movement"; "Turn back the tide of communism" [syn:
         {turn back}, {arrest}, {stop}, {contain}, {hold back}]
     19: place into check; "He checked my kings"
     20: write out a check on a bank account
     21: find out, learn, or determine with certainty, usually by
         making an inquiry or other effort; "I want to see whether
         she speaks French"; "See whether it works"; "find out if
         he speaks Russian"; "Check whether the train leaves on
         time" [syn: {determine}, {find out}, {see}, {ascertain},
         {watch}, {learn}]
     22: verify by consulting a source or authority; "check the
         spelling of this word"; "check your facts"
     23: arrest the motion (of something) abruptly; "He checked the
         flow of water by shutting off the main valve"
     24: make cracks or chinks in; "The heat checked the paint" [syn:
          {chink}]
     25: become fractured; break or crack on the surface only; "The
         glass cracked when it was heated" [syn: {crack}, {break}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
