<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>chess</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chess</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>chess
     
        &lt;games&gt; A two-player {game} with {perfect information}.
     
        {Usenet} newsgroup: {news:rec.games.chess}.
     
        See also {Internet Chess Server}.
     
        (1995-03-25)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chess</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cheat \Cheat\, n. [rob. an abbrevation of escheat, lands or
   tenements that fall to a lord or to the state by forfeiture,
   or by the death of the tenant without heirs; the meaning
   being explained by the frauds, real or supposed, that were
   resorted to in procuring escheats. See {Escheat}.]
   1. An act of deception or fraud; that which is the means of
      fraud or deception; a fraud; a trick; imposition;
      imposture.
      [1913 Webster]

            When I consider life, 'tis all a cheat. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who cheats or deceives; an impostor; a deceiver; a
      cheater.
      [1913 Webster]

            Airy wonders, which cheats interpret. --Johnson
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) A troublesome grass, growing as a weed in grain
      fields; -- called also {chess}. See {Chess}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) The obtaining of property from another by an
      intentional active distortion of the truth.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When cheats are effected by deceitful or illegal
         symbols or tokens which may affect the public at large
         and against which common prudence could not have
         guarded, they are indictable at common law. --Wharton.

   Syn: Deception; imposture; fraud; delusion; artifice; trick;
        swindle; deceit; guile; finesse; stratagem.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chess</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chess \Chess\, n. (Bot.)
   A species of brome grass ({Bromus secalinus}) which is a
   troublesome weed in wheat fields, and is often erroneously
   regarded as degenerate or changed wheat; it bears a very
   slight resemblance to oats, and if reaped and ground up with
   wheat, so as to be used for food, is said to produce narcotic
   effects; -- called also {cheat} and {Willard's bromus}. [U.
   S.]
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Other species of brome grass are called {upright
         chess}, {soft chess}, etc.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chess</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Chess \Chess\ (ch[e^]s), n. [OE. ches, F. ['e]checs, prop. pl.
   of ['e]chec check. See 1st {Check}.]
   A game played on a chessboard, by two persons, with two
   differently colored sets of men, sixteen in each set. Each
   player has a king, a queen, two bishops, two knights, two
   castles or rooks, and eight pawns.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>chess</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>chess
     n 1: weedy annual native to Europe but widely distributed as a
          weed especially in wheat [syn: {cheat}, {Bromus
          secalinus}]
     2: a game for two players who move their 16 pieces according to
        specific rules; the object is to checkmate the opponent's
        king [syn: {chess game}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
