<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>circuit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circuit
   the apparent diurnal revolution of the sun round the earth (Ps.
   19:6), and the changes of the wind (Eccl. 1:6). In Job 22:14,
   "in the circuit of heaven" (R.V. marg., "on the vault of
   heaven") means the "arch of heaven," which seems to be bent over
   our heads.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>circuit
     
        1. &lt;communications&gt; A communications path in a {circuit
        switching} network.
     
        2. &lt;electronics&gt; A complete path through which an electric
        current can flow.
     
        The term is used loosely for any device or subsystem using
        electrical or electronic components.  E.g. "That lightning
        bolt fried the circuits in my GPS receiver".  An {integrated
        circuit} (IC) contains components built on a Silicon {die}.
     
        (2002-07-15)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circuit \Cir"cuit\, n. [F. circuit, fr. L. circuitus, fr.
   circuire or circumire to go around; circum around + ire to
   go.]
   1. The act of moving or revolving around, or as in a circle
      or orbit; a revolution; as, the periodical circuit of the
      earth round the sun. --Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The circumference of, or distance round, any space; the
      measure of a line round an area.
      [1913 Webster]

            The circuit or compass of Ireland is 1,800 miles.
                                                  --J. Stow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which encircles anything, as a ring or crown.
      [1913 Webster]

            The golden circuit on my head.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The space inclosed within a circle, or within limits.
      [1913 Webster]

            A circuit wide inclosed with goodliest trees.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A regular or appointed journeying from place to place in
      the exercise of one's calling, as of a judge, or a
      preacher.
      [1913 Webster]

   6.
      (a) (Law) A certain division of a state or country,
          established by law for a judge or judges to visit, for
          the administration of justice. --Bouvier.
      (b) (Methodist Church) A district in which an itinerant
          preacher labors.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. Circumlocution. [Obs.] ``Thou hast used no circuit of
      words.'' --Huloet.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Circuit court} (Law), a court which sits successively in
      different places in its circuit (see {Circuit}, 6). In the
      United States, the federal circuit courts are commonly
      presided over by a judge of the supreme court, or a
      special circuit judge, together with the judge of the
      district court. They have jurisdiction within statutory
      limits, both in law and equity, in matters of federal
      cognizance. Some of the individual States also have
      circuit courts, which have general statutory jurisdiction
      of the same class, in matters of State cognizance.

   {Circuit of action} or {Circuity of action} (Law), a longer
      course of proceedings than is necessary to attain the
      object in view.

   {To make a circuit}, to go around; to go a roundabout way.

   {Voltaic circle} or {Galvanic circle} or {Voltaic circuit} or
   {Galvanic circuit}, a continous electrical communication
      between the two poles of a battery; an arrangement of
      voltaic elements or couples with proper conductors, by
      which a continuous current of electricity is established.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circuit \Cir"cuit\, v. i.
   To move in a circle; to go round; to circulate. [Obs.] --J.
   Philips.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circuit \Cir"cuit\, v. t.
   To travel around. [Obs.] ``Having circuited the air.'' --T.
   Warton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>circuit
     n 1: an electrical device that provides a path for electrical
          current to flow [syn: {electrical circuit}, {electric
          circuit}]
     2: a journey or route all the way around a particular place or
        area; "they took an extended tour of Europe"; "we took a
        quick circuit of the park"; "a ten-day coach circuit of
        the island" [syn: {tour}]
     3: an established itinerary of venues or events that a
        particular group of people travel to; "she's a familiar
        name on the club circuit"; "on the lecture circuit"; "the
        judge makes a circuit of the courts in his district"; "the
        international tennis circuit"
     4: (law) a judicial division of a state or the United States
        (so-called because originally judges traveled and held
        court in different locations); one of the twelve groups of
        states in the United States that is covered by a
        particular circuit court of appeals
     5: a racetrack for automobile races [syn: {racing circuit}]
     6: movement once around a course; "he drove an extra lap just
        for insurance" [syn: {lap}, {circle}]
     v : make a circuit; "They were circuiting about the state"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
