<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>circle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circle, AK (CDP, FIPS 14880)
  Location: 65.82454 N, 144.08262 W
  Population (1990): 73 (31 housing units)
  Area: 11.8 sq km (land), 2.9 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 99733
Circle, MT (town, FIPS 14950)
  Location: 47.41749 N, 105.58614 W
  Population (1990): 805 (399 housing units)
  Area: 2.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 59215
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circle \Cir"cle\ (s[~e]r"k'l), n. [OE. cercle, F. cercle, fr. L.
   circulus (Whence also AS. circul), dim. of circus circle,
   akin to Gr. kri`kos, ki`rkos, circle, ring. Cf. {Circus},
   {Circum-}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A plane figure, bounded by a single curve line called its
      circumference, every part of which is equally distant from
      a point within it, called the center.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The line that bounds such a figure; a circumference; a
      ring.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Astron.) An instrument of observation, the graduated limb
      of which consists of an entire circle.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When it is fixed to a wall in an observatory, it is
         called a {mural circle}; when mounted with a telescope
         on an axis and in Y's, in the plane of the meridian, a
         {meridian circle} or {transit circle}; when involving
         the principle of reflection, like the sextant, a
         {reflecting circle}; and when that of repeating an
         angle several times continuously along the graduated
         limb, a {repeating circle}.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. A round body; a sphere; an orb.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is he that sitteth upon the circle of the earth.
                                                  --Is. xi. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Compass; circuit; inclosure.
      [1913 Webster]

            In the circle of this forest.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A company assembled, or conceived to assemble, about a
      central point of interest, or bound by a common tie; a
      class or division of society; a coterie; a set.
      [1913 Webster]

            As his name gradually became known, the circle of
            his acquaintance widened.             --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A circular group of persons; a ring.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A series ending where it begins, and repeating itself.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus in a circle runs the peasant's pain. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Logic) A form of argument in which two or more unproved
      statements are used to prove each other; inconclusive
      reasoning.
      [1913 Webster]

            That heavy bodies descend by gravity; and, again,
            that gravity is a quality whereby a heavy body
            descends, is an impertinent circle and teaches
            nothing.                              --Glanvill.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Indirect form of words; circumlocution. [R.]
       [1913 Webster]

             Has he given the lie,
             In circle, or oblique, or semicircle. --J.
                                                  Fletcher.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A territorial division or district.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note:

   {The Circles of the Holy Roman Empire}, ten in number, were
      those principalities or provinces which had seats in the
      German Diet.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Azimuth circle}. See under {Azimuth}.

   {Circle of altitude} (Astron.), a circle parallel to the
      horizon, having its pole in the zenith; an almucantar.

   {Circle of curvature}. See {Osculating circle of a curve}
      (Below).

   {Circle of declination}. See under {Declination}.

   {Circle of latitude}.
       (a) (Astron.) A great circle perpendicular to the plane
           of the ecliptic, passing through its poles.
       (b) (Spherical Projection) A small circle of the sphere
           whose plane is perpendicular to the axis.

   {Circles of longitude}, lesser circles parallel to the
      ecliptic, diminishing as they recede from it.

   {Circle of perpetual apparition}, at any given place, the
      boundary of that space around the elevated pole, within
      which the stars never set. Its distance from the pole is
      equal to the latitude of the place.

   {Circle of perpetual occultation}, at any given place, the
      boundary of the space around the depressed pole, within
      which the stars never rise.

   {Circle of the sphere}, a circle upon the surface of the
      sphere, called a great circle when its plane passes
      through the center of the sphere; in all other cases, a
      small circle.

   {Diurnal circle}. See under {Diurnal}.

   {Dress circle}, a gallery in a theater, generally the one
      containing the prominent and more expensive seats.

   {Druidical circles} (Eng. Antiq.), a popular name for certain
      ancient inclosures formed by rude stones circularly
      arranged, as at Stonehenge, near Salisbury.

   {Family circle}, a gallery in a theater, usually one
      containing inexpensive seats.

   {Horary circles} (Dialing), the lines on dials which show the
      hours.

   {Osculating circle of a curve} (Geom.), the circle which
      touches the curve at some point in the curve, and close to
      the point more nearly coincides with the curve than any
      other circle. This circle is used as a measure of the
      curvature of the curve at the point, and hence is called
      circle of curvature.

   {Pitch circle}. See under {Pitch}.

   {Vertical circle}, an azimuth circle.

   {Voltaic circuit} or {Voltaic circle}. See under {Circuit}.
      

   {To square the circle}. See under {Square}.

   Syn: Ring; circlet; compass; circuit; inclosure.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circle \Cir"cle\, v. i.
   To move circularly; to form a circle; to circulate.
   [1913 Webster]

         Thy name shall circle round the gaping through.
                                                  --Byron.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circle \Cir"cle\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Circled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Circling}.] [OE. cerclen, F. cercler, fr. L. circulare to
   make round. See {Circle}, n., and cf. {Circulate}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To move around; to revolve around.
      [1913 Webster]

            Other planets circle other suns.      --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To encompass, as by a circle; to surround; to inclose; to
      encircle. --Prior. Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their heads are circled with a short turban.
                                                  --Dampier.
      [1913 Webster]

            So he lies, circled with evil.        --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To circle in}, to confine; to hem in; to keep together; as,
      to circle bodies in. --Sir K. Digby.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>circle
     n 1: ellipse in which the two axes are of equal length; a plane
          curve generated by one point moving at a constant
          distance from a fixed point; "he calculated the
          circumference of the circle"
     2: an unofficial association of people or groups; "the smart
        set goes there"; "they were an angry lot" [syn: {set}, {band},
         {lot}]
     3: something approximating the shape of a circle; "the chairs
        were arranged in a circle"
     4: movement once around a course; "he drove an extra lap just
        for insurance" [syn: {lap}, {circuit}]
     5: a road junction at which traffic streams circularly around a
        central island; "the accident blocked all traffic at the
        rotary" [syn: {traffic circle}, {rotary}, {roundabout}]
     6: street names for flunitrazepan [syn: {R-2}, {Mexican valium},
         {rophy}, {rope}, {roofy}, {roach}, {forget me drug}]
     7: a curved section or tier of seats in a hall or theater or
        opera house; usually the first tier above the orchestra;
        "they had excellent seats in the dress circle" [syn: {dress
        circle}]
     8: any circular or rotating mechanism; "the machine punched out
        metal circles" [syn: {round}]
     v 1: travel around something; "circle the globe"
     2: move in circles [syn: {circulate}]
     3: be around; "Developments surround the town"; "The river
        encircles the village" [syn: {surround}, {environ}, {encircle},
         {round}, {ring}]
     4: form a circle around; "encircle the errors" [syn: {encircle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
