<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>circus</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CIRCUS, n.  A place where horses, ponies and elephants are permitted
to see men, women and children acting the fool.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Circus \Cir"cus\, n.; pl. {Circuses}. [L. circus circle, ring,
   circus (in sense 1). See {Circle}, and cf. {Cirque}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Roman Antiq.) A level oblong space surrounded on three
      sides by seats of wood, earth, or stone, rising in tiers
      one above another, and divided lengthwise through the
      middle by a barrier around which the track or course was
      laid out. It was used for chariot races, games, and public
      shows.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The Circus Maximus at Rome could contain more than
         100,000 spectators. --Harpers' Latin Dict.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A circular inclosure for the exhibition of feats of
      horsemanship, acrobatic displays, etc. Also, the company
      of performers, with their equipage.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Circuit; space; inclosure. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The narrow circus of my dungeon wall. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>circus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>circus
     n 1: a travelling company of entertainers; including trained
          animals; "he ran away from home to join the circus"
     2: performance given by a traveling company of acrobats clowns
        and trained animals; "the children always love to go to
        the circus"
     3: a frenetic disorganized (and often comic) disturbance
        suggestive of a circus or carnival; "it was so funny it
        was a circus"; "the whole occasion had a carnival
        atmosphere" [syn: {carnival}]
     4: (antiquity) an open-air stadium for chariot races and
        gladiatorial games
     5: an arena consisting of an oval or circular area enclosed by
        tiers of seats and usually covered by a tent; "they used
        the elephants to help put up the circus"
     6: a genus of haws comprising the harriers [syn: {genus Circus}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
