<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>civil</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>civil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Civil \Civ"il\, a. [L. civilis, fr. civis citizen: cf. F. civil.
   See {City}.]
   1. Pertaining to a city or state, or to a citizen in his
      relations to his fellow citizens or to the state; within
      the city or state.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Subject to government; reduced to order; civilized; not
      barbarous; -- said of the community.
      [1913 Webster]

            England was very rude and barbarous; for it is but
            even the other day since England grew civil.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Performing the duties of a citizen; obedient to
      government; -- said of an individual.
      [1913 Webster]

            Civil men come nearer the saints of God than others;
            they come within a step or two of heaven. --Preston
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Having the manners of one dwelling in a city, as opposed
      to those of savages or rustics; polite; courteous;
      complaisant; affable.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: ``A civil man now is one observant of slight external
         courtesies in the mutual intercourse between man and
         man; a civil man once was one who fulfilled all the
         duties and obligations flowing from his position as a
         'civis' and his relations to the other members of that
         'civitas.''' --Trench
         [1913 Webster]

   5. Pertaining to civic life and affairs, in distinction from
      military, ecclesiastical, or official state.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Relating to rights and remedies sought by action or suit
      distinct from criminal proceedings.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Civil action}, an action to enforce the rights or redress
      the wrongs of an individual, not involving a criminal
      proceeding.

   {Civil architecture}, the architecture which is employed in
      constructing buildings for the purposes of civil life, in
      distinction from military and naval architecture, as
      private houses, palaces, churches, etc.

   {Civil death}. (Law.) See under {Death}.

   {Civil engineering}. See under {Engineering}.

   {Civil law}. See under {Law}.

   {Civil list}. See under {List}.

   {Civil remedy} (Law), that given to a person injured, by
      action, as opposed to a criminal prosecution.

   {Civil service}, all service rendered to and paid for by the
      state or nation other than that pertaining to naval or
      military affairs.

   {Civil service reform}, the substitution of business
      principles and methods for the spoils system in the
      conduct of the civil service, esp. in the matter of
      appointments to office.

   {Civil state}, the whole body of the laity or citizens not
      included under the military, maritime, and ecclesiastical
      states.

   {Civil suit}. Same as {Civil action}.

   {Civil war}. See under {War}.

   {Civil year}. See under {Year}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>civil</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>civil
     adj 1: applying to ordinary citizens; "civil law"; "civil
            authorities"
     2: not rude; marked by satisfactory (or especially minimal)
        adherence to social usages and sufficient but not
        noteworthy consideration for others; "even if he didn't
        like them he should have been civil"- W.S. Maugham [syn: {polite}]
        [ant: {uncivil}]
     3: of or occurring within the state or between or among
        citizens of the state; "civil affairs"; "civil strife";
        "civil disobediece"; "civil branches of government"
     4: of or relating to or befitting citizens as individuals;
        "civil rights"; "civil liberty"; "civic duties"; "civic
        pride" [syn: {civic}]
     5: (of divisions of time) legally recognized in ordinary
        affairs of life; "the civil calendar"; "a civil day begins
        at mean midnight" [ant: {sidereal}]
     6: of or in a condition of social order; "civil peoples"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
