<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>classic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>classic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>classic
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; An adjective used before or after a noun to describe
        the original version of something.  This construction is
        especially used of product series in which the newer versions
        are considered worse than the older ones.
     
        Examples include "Star Trek Classic" - the original TV series
        as opposed to the films, ST The Next Generation or any of the
        other spin-offs and follow-ups; or "PC Classic" - {IBM}'s
        {ISA}-bus computers as opposed to the {PS/2} series.
     
        (1996-10-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>classic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Classic \Clas"sic\, n.
   1. A work of acknowledged excellence and authority, or its
      author; -- originally used of Greek and Latin works or
      authors, but now applied to authors and works of a like
      character in any language.
      [1913 Webster]

            In is once raised him to the rank of a legitimate
            English classic.                      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One learned in the literature of Greece and Rome, or a
      student of classical literature.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>classic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Classic \Clas"sic\ (kl[a^]s"s[i^]k), Classical \Clas"sic*al\, a.
   [L. classicus relating to the classes of the Roman people,
   and especially to the frist class; hence, of the first rank,
   superior, from classis class: cf. F. classique. See {Class},
   n.]
   1. Of or relating to the first class or rank, especially in
      literature or art.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give, as thy last memorial to the age,
            One classic drama, and reform the stage. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mr. Greaves may justly be reckoned a classical
            author on this subject [Roman weights and coins].
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of or pertaining to the ancient Greeks and Romans, esp. to
      Greek or Roman authors of the highest rank, or of the
      period when their best literature was produced; of or
      pertaining to places inhabited by the ancient Greeks and
      Romans, or rendered famous by their deeds.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though throned midst Latium's classic plains. --Mrs.
                                                  Hemans.
      [1913 Webster]

            The epithet classical, as applied to ancient
            authors, is determined less by the purity of their
            style than by the period at which they wrote.
                                                  --Brande &amp; C.
      [1913 Webster]

            He [Atterbury] directed the classical studies of the
            undergraduates of his college.        --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Conforming to the best authority in literature and art;
      chaste; pure; refined; as, a classical style.
      [1913 Webster]

            Classical, provincial, and national synods.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Classicals orders}. (Arch.) See under {Order}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>classic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>classic
     adj 1: characteristic of the classical artistic and literary
            traditions
     2: adhering to established standards and principles; "a classic
        proof"
     n 1: a creation of the highest excellence
     2: an artist who has created classic works
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
