<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>clock</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CLOCK, n.  A machine of great moral value to man, allaying his concern
for the future by reminding him what a lot of time remains to him.

    A busy man complained one day:
    "I get no time!"  "What's that you say?"
    Cried out his friend, a lazy quiz;
    "You have, sir, all the time there is.
    There's plenty, too, and don't you doubt it --
    We're never for an hour without it."
                                                          Purzil Crofe


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clock
     
        A processor's clock or one {cycle} thereof.  The relative
        execution times of instructions on a computer are usually
        measured by number of clock cycles rather than seconds.  One
        good reason for this is that {clock rate}s for various models
        of the computer may increase as technology improves, and it is
        usually the relative times one is interested in when
        discussing the {instruction set}.
     
        (1994-12-16)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clock \Clock\ (kl[o^]k), n. [AS. clucge bell; akin to D. klok
   clock, bell, G. glocke, Dan. klokke, Sw. klocka, Icel. klukka
   bell, LL. clocca, cloca (whence F. cloche); al perh. of
   Celtic origin; cf. Ir. &amp; Gael. clog bell, clock, W. cloch
   bell. Cf. {Cloak}.]
   1. A machine for measuring time, indicating the hour and
      other divisions; in ordinary mechanical clocks for
      domestic or office use the time is indicated on a
      typically circular face or dial plate containing two
      hands, pointing to numbers engraved on the periphery of
      the face, thus showing the hours and minutes. The works of
      a mechanical clock are moved by a weight or a spring, and
      it is often so constructed as to tell the hour by the
      stroke of a hammer on a bell. In electrical or electronic
      clocks, the time may be indicated, as on a mechanical
      clock, by hands, but may also be indicated by direct
      digital readout, with the hours and minutes in normal
      Arabic numerals. The readout using hands is often called
      analog to distinguish it from the digital readout. Some
      clocks also indicate the seconds. Clocks are not adapted,
      like the watch, to be carried on the person. Specialized
      clocks, such as {atomic clocks}, may be constructed on
      different principles, and may have a very high precision
      for use in scientific observations.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. A watch, esp. one that strikes. [Obs.] --Walton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The striking of a clock. [Obs.] --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A figure or figured work on the ankle or side of a
      stocking. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The phrases what o'clock? it is nine o'clock, etc., are
         contracted from what of the clock? it is nine of the
         clock, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Alarm clock}. See under {Alarm}.

   {Astronomical clock}.
      (a) A clock of superior construction, with a compensating
          pendulum, etc., to measure time with great accuracy,
          for use in astronomical observatories; -- called a
          regulator when used by watchmakers as a standard for
          regulating timepieces.
      (b) A clock with mechanism for indicating certain
          astronomical phenomena, as the phases of the moon,
          position of the sun in the ecliptic, equation of time,
          etc.

   {Electric clock}.
      (a) A clock moved or regulated by electricity or
          electro-magnetism.
      (b) A clock connected with an electro-magnetic recording
          apparatus.

   {Ship's clock} (Naut.), a clock arranged to strike from one
      to eight strokes, at half hourly intervals, marking the
      divisions of the ship's watches.

   {Sidereal clock}, an astronomical clock regulated to keep
      sidereal time.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clock \Clock\ (kl[o^]k), v. t.
   To ornament with figured work, as the side of a stocking.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clock \Clock\, v. t. &amp; i.
   To call, as a hen. See {Cluck}. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clock \Clock\, n. (Zo["o]l.)
   A large beetle, esp. the European dung beetle ({Scarab[ae]us
   stercorarius}).
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clock 1. n 1. [techspeak] The master oscillator that steps a CPU or
   other digital circuit through its paces. This has nothing to do with the
   time of day, although the software counter that keeps track of the
   latter may be derived from the former. 2. vt. To run a CPU or other
   digital circuit at a particular rate. "If you clock it at 100MHz, it
   gets warm.". See {overclock}. 3. vt. To force a digital circuit from one
   state to the next by applying a single clock pulse. "The data must be
   stable 10ns before you clock the latch."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clock
     n : a timepiece that shows the time of day
     v : measure the time or duration of an event or action or the
         person who performs an action in a certain period of
         time; "he clocked the runners" [syn: {time}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
