<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>clone</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clone
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; 1. An exact copy of a product, made legally or
        illegally, from {documentation} or by {reverse engineering},
        and usually cheaper.
     
        E.g. "PC clone": a PC-BUS/{ISA}, {EISA}, {VESA}, or {PCI}
        compatible {x86}-based {microcomputer} (this use is sometimes
        misspelled "klone" or "PClone").  These invariably have much more
        bang per buck than the {IB PCM} they resemble.
     
        E.g. "Unix clone": An {operating system} designed to deliver a
        {Unix}-like environment without Unix licence fees or with
        additional "mission-critical" features such as support for
        {real-time} programming.
     
        2. &lt;chat&gt; A {clonebot}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2000-06-15)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clone \clone\ (kl[=o]n), n.
   1. (Biol.) a group of organisms derived from a single
      individual by some kind of asexual reproduction; -- used
      mostly of microorganisms such as bacteria and yeast.

   Syn: clon.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. (Biol.) an individual organism containing a genetic
      complement identical to that of another organism, produced
      by using the genetic material from the second animal in a
      non-sexual reproduction process.
      [PJC]

   3. something virtually identical to another object.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clone \clone\ v. t.
   1. (Biol.) to make a clone from; to make identical copies of
      an organism by a non-sexual process of reproduction.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   2. (Microbiol.) to grow colonies of a microorganism by
      spreading a suspension of the microorganism onto a solid
      growth medium (such as in a Petri dish), at a
      concentration such that individual colonies will grow from
      single cells sufficiently well separated from other
      colonies so that pure cultures derived from a single
      organism can be isolated.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   3. (Biochem.) to make large quantities of a segment of DNA by
      inserting it, using biochemical techniques, into the DNA
      of a microorganism, and growing that microorganism in
      large numbers; as, to clone the gene for growth hormone.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clone n. 1. An exact duplicate: "Our product is a clone of their
   product." Implies a legal reimplementation from documentation or by
   reverse-engineering. Also connotes lower price. 2. A shoddy, spurious
   copy: "Their product is a clone of our product." 3. A blatant ripoff,
   most likely violating copyright, patent, or trade secret protections:
   "Your product is a clone of my product." This use implies legal action
   is pending. 4. [obs] `PC clone:' a PC-BUS/ISA or EISA-compatible
   80x86-based microcomputer (this use is sometimes spelled `klone' or
   `PClone'). These invariably have much more bang for the buck than the
   IBM archetypes they resemble. This term fell out of use in the 1990s;
   the class of machines it describes are now simply `PCs' or `Intel
   machines'. 5. [obs.] In the construction `Unix clone': An OS designed to
   deliver a Unix-lookalike environment without Unix license fees, or with
   additional `mission-critical' features such as support for real-time
   programming. {Linux} and the free BSDs killed off this product category
   and the term with it. 6. v. To make an exact copy of something. "Let me
   clone that" might mean "I want to borrow that paper so I can make a
   photocopy" or "Let me get a copy of that file before you {mung} it".


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clone
     n 1: a person who is almost identical to another [syn: {ringer},
          {dead ringer}]
     2: a group of genetically identical cells or organisms derived
        from a single cell or individual by some kind of asexual
        reproduction [syn: {clon}]
     3: an unauthorized copy or imitation [syn: {knockoff}]
     v : make multiple identical copies of; "people can clone a sheep
         nowadays"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
