<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>closer</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>closer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Close \Close\ (kl[=o]s), a. [Compar. {Closer} (kl[=o]"s[~e]r);
   superl. {Closest}.] [Of. &amp; F. clos, p. p. of clore. See
   {Close}, v. t.]
   1. Shut fast; closed; tight; as, a close box.
      [1913 Webster]

            From a close bower this dainty music flowed.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Narrow; confined; as, a close alley; close quarters. ``A
      close prison.'' --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Oppressive; without motion or ventilation; causing a
      feeling of lassitude; -- said of the air, weather, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            If the rooms be low-roofed, or full of windows and
            doors, the one maketh the air close, . . . and the
            other maketh it exceeding unequal.    --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Strictly confined; carefully quarded; as, a close
      prisoner.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Out of the way observation; secluded; secret; hidden. ``He
      yet kept himself close because of Saul.'' --1 Chron. xii.
      1
      [1913 Webster]

            ``Her close intent.''                 --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Disposed to keep secrets; secretive; reticent. ``For
      secrecy, no lady closer.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Having the parts near each other; dense; solid; compact;
      as applied to bodies; viscous; tenacious; not volatile, as
      applied to liquids.
      [1913 Webster]

            The golden globe being put into a press, . . . the
            water made itself way through the pores of that very
            close metal.                          --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Concise; to the point; as, close reasoning. ``Where the
      original is close no version can reach it in the same
      compass.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Adjoining; near; either in space; time, or thought; --
      often followed by to.
      [1913 Webster]

            Plant the spring crocuses close to a wall.
                                                  --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The thought of the Man of sorrows seemed a very
            close thing -- not a faint hearsay.   --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Short; as, to cut grass or hair close.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Intimate; familiar; confidential.
       [1913 Webster]

             League with you I seek
             And mutual amity, so strait, so close,
             That I with you must dwell, or you with me.
                                                  --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Nearly equal; almost evenly balanced; as, a close vote.
       ``A close contest.'' --Prescott.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Difficult to obtain; as, money is close. --Bartlett.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Parsimonious; stingy. ``A crusty old fellow, as close as
       a vise.'' --Hawthorne.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. Adhering strictly to a standard or original; exact;
       strict; as, a close translation. --Locke.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. Accurate; careful; precise; also, attentive; undeviating;
       strict; not wandering; as, a close observer.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Phon.) Uttered with a relatively contracted opening of
       the mouth, as certain sounds of e and o in French,
       Italian, and German; -- opposed to open.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Close borough}. See under {Borough}.

   {Close breeding}. See under {Breeding}.

   {Close communion}, communion in the Lord's supper, restricted
      to those who have received baptism by immersion.

   {Close corporation}, a body or corporation which fills its
      own vacancies.

   {Close fertilization}. (Bot.) See {Fertilization}.

   {Close harmony} (Mus.), compact harmony, in which the tones
      composing each chord are not widely distributed over
      several octaves.

   {Close time}, a fixed period during which killing game or
      catching certain fish is prohibited by law.

   {Close vowel} (Pron.), a vowel which is pronounced with a
      diminished aperture of the lips, or with contraction of
      the cavity of the mouth.

   {Close to the wind} (Naut.), directed as nearly to the point
      from which the wind blows as it is possible to sail;
      closehauled; -- said of a vessel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>closer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Closer \Clos"er\, n.
   1. One who, or that which, closes; specifically, a boot
      closer. See under {Boot}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A finisher; that which finishes or terminates.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Masonry) The last stone in a horizontal course, if of a
      less size than the others, or a piece of brick finishing a
      course. --Gwilt.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>closer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>closer
     n 1: a person who closes something; "whoever is the closer has to
          turn out the lights and lock up"
     2: (baseball) a relief pitcher who can protect a lead in the
        last inning or two of the game [syn: {finisher}]
     adv : (comparative of `near' or `close') within a shorter
           distance; "come closer, my dear!"; "they drew nearer";
           "getting nearer to the true explanation" [syn: {nearer},
            {nigher}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
