<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>clothes</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clothes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cloth \Cloth\ (kl[o^]th; 115), n.; pl. {Cloths} (kl[o^][th]z;
   115), except in the sense of garments, when it is {Clothes}
   (kl[=o]thz or kl[=o]z). [OE. clath cloth, AS. cl[=a][thorn]
   cloth, garment; akin to D. kleed, Icel. kl[ae][eth]i, Dan.
   kl[ae]de, cloth, Sw. kl["a]de, G. kleid garment, dress.]
   1. A fabric made of fibrous material (or sometimes of wire,
      as in wire cloth); commonly, a woven fabric of cotton,
      woolen, or linen, adapted to be made into garments;
      specifically, woolen fabrics, as distinguished from all
      others.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The dress; raiment. [Obs.] See {Clothes}.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll ne'er distust my God for cloth and bread.
                                                  --Quarles.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The distinctive dress of any profession, especially of the
      clergy; hence, the clerical profession.
      [1913 Webster]

            Appeals were made to the priesthood. Would they
            tamely permit so gross an insult to be offered to
            their cloth?                          --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cloth, the clergy, are constituted for
            administering and for giving the best possible
            effect to . . . every axiom.          --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Body cloth}. See under {Body}.

   {Cloth of gold}, a fabric woven wholly or partially of
      threads of gold.

   {Cloth measure}, the measure of length and surface by which
      cloth is measured and sold. For this object the standard
      yard is usually divided into quarters and nails.

   {Cloth paper}, a coarse kind of paper used in pressing and
      finishing woolen cloth. -- Cloth

   {shearer}, one who shears cloth and frees it from superfluous
      nap.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clothes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clothes \Clothes\ (kl[=o][th]z or kl[=o]z; 277), n. pl. [From
   {Cloth}.]
   1. Covering for the human body; dress; vestments; vesture; --
      a general term for whatever covering is worn, or is made
      to be worn, for decency or comfort.
      [1913 Webster]

            She . . . speaks well, and has excellent good
            clothes.                              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If I may touch but his clothes, I shall be whole.
                                                  --Mark. v. 28.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The covering of a bed; bedclothes.
      [1913 Webster]

            She turned each way her frighted head,
            Then sunk it deep beneath the clothes. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Body clothes}. See under {Body}.

   {Clothes moth} (Zo["o]l.), a small moth of the genus {Tinea}.
      The most common species ({Tinea flavifrontella}) is
      yellowish white. The larv[ae] eat woolen goods, furs,
      feathers, etc. They live in tubular cases made of the
      material upon which they feed, fastened together with
      silk.

   Syn: Garments; dress; clothing; apparel; attire; vesture;
        raiment; garb; costume; habit; habiliments.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clothes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clothes
     n : clothing in general; "she was refined in her choice of
         apparel"; "he always bought his clothes at the same
         store"; "fastidious about his dress" [syn: {apparel}, {wearing
         apparel}, {dress}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
