<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cloud</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cloud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cloud
   The Hebrew so rendered means "a covering," because clouds cover
   the sky. The word is used as a symbol of the Divine presence, as
   indicating the splendour of that glory which it conceals (Ex.
   16:10; 33:9; Num. 11:25; 12:5; Job 22:14; Ps. 18:11). A "cloud
   without rain" is a proverbial saying, denoting a man who does
   not keep his promise (Prov. 16:15; Isa. 18:4; 25:5; Jude 1:12).
   A cloud is the figure of that which is transitory (Job 30:15;
   Hos. 6:4). A bright cloud is the symbolical seat of the Divine
   presence (Ex.29:42, 43; 1 Kings 8:10; 2 Chr. 5:14; Ezek. 43:4),
   and was called the Shechinah (q.v.). Jehovah came down upon
   Sinai in a cloud (Ex. 19:9); and the cloud filled the court
   around the tabernacle in the wilderness so that Moses could not
   enter it (Ex. 40:34, 35). At the dedication of the temple also
   the cloud "filled the house of the Lord" (1 Kings 8:10). Thus in
   like manner when Christ comes the second time he is described as
   coming "in the clouds" (Matt. 17:5; 24:30; Acts 1:9, 11). False
   teachers are likened unto clouds carried about with a tempest (2
   Pet. 2:17). The infirmities of old age, which come one after
   another, are compared by Solomon to "clouds returning after the
   rain" (Eccl. 12:2). The blotting out of sins is like the sudden
   disappearance of threatening clouds from the sky (Isa. 44:22).
   
     Cloud, the pillar of, was the glory-cloud which indicated
   God's presence leading the ransomed people through the
   wilderness (Ex. 13:22; 33:9, 10). This pillar preceded the
   people as they marched, resting on the ark (Ex. 13:21; 40:36).
   By night it became a pillar of fire (Num. 9:17-23).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cloud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cloud \Cloud\ (kloud), n. [Prob. fr. AS. cl[=u]d a rock or
   hillock, the application arising from the frequent
   resemblance of clouds to rocks or hillocks in the sky or
   air.]
   1. A collection of visible vapor, or watery particles,
      suspended in the upper atmosphere.
      [1913 Webster]

            I do set my bow in the cloud.         --Gen. ix. 13.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A classification of clouds according to their chief
         forms was first proposed by the meteorologist Howard,
         and this is still substantially employed. The following
         varieties and subvarieties are recognized:
      (a) {Cirrus}. This is the most elevated of all the forms
          of clouds; is thin, long-drawn, sometimes looking like
          carded wool or hair, sometimes like a brush or room,
          sometimes in curl-like or fleecelike patches. It is
          the cat's-tail of the sailor, and the mare's-tail of
          the landsman.
      (b) {Cumulus}. This form appears in large masses of a
          hemispherical form, or nearly so, above, but flat
          below, one often piled above another, forming great
          clouds, common in the summer, and presenting the
          appearance of gigantic mountains crowned with snow. It
          often affords rain and thunder gusts.
      (c) {Stratus}. This form appears in layers or bands
          extending horizontally.
      (d) {Nimbus}. This form is characterized by its uniform
          gray tint and ragged edges; it covers the sky in
          seasons of continued rain, as in easterly storms, and
          is the proper rain cloud. The name is sometimes used
          to denote a raining cumulus, or cumulostratus.
      (e) {Cirro-cumulus}. This form consists, like the cirrus,
          of thin, broken, fleecelice clouds, but the parts are
          more or less rounded and regulary grouped. It is
          popularly called mackerel sky.
      (f) {Cirro-stratus}. In this form the patches of cirrus
          coalesce in long strata, between cirrus and stratus.
      (g) {Cumulo-stratus}. A form between cumulus and stratus,
          often assuming at the horizon a black or bluish tint.
          -- {Fog}, cloud, motionless, or nearly so, lying near
          or in contact with the earth's surface. -- {Storm
          scud}, cloud lying quite low, without form, and driven
          rapidly with the wind.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A mass or volume of smoke, or flying dust, resembling
      vapor. ``A thick cloud of incense.'' --Ezek. viii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A dark vein or spot on a lighter material, as in marble;
      hence, a blemish or defect; as, a cloud upon one's
      reputation; a cloud on a title.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which has a dark, lowering, or threatening aspect;
      that which temporarily overshadows, obscures, or
      depresses; as, a cloud of sorrow; a cloud of war; a cloud
      upon the intellect.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A great crowd or multitude; a vast collection. ``So great
      a cloud of witnesses.'' --Heb. xii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A large, loosely-knitted scarf, worn by women about the
      head.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cloud on a} (or the) {title} (Law), a defect of title,
      usually superficial and capable of removal by release,
      decision in equity, or legislation.

   {To be under a cloud}, to be under suspicion or in disgrace;
      to be in disfavor.

   {In the clouds}, in the realm of facy and imagination; beyond
      reason; visionary.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cloud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cloud \Cloud\ (kloud), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Clouded}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Clouding}.]
   1. To overspread or hide with a cloud or clouds; as, the sky
      is clouded.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To darken or obscure, as if by hiding or enveloping with a
      cloud; hence, to render gloomy or sullen.
      [1913 Webster]

            One day too late, I fear me, noble lord,
            Hath clouded all thy happy days on earth. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Be not disheartened, then, nor cloud those looks.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing clouds men's minds and impairs their honesty
            like prejudice.                       --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To blacken; to sully; to stain; to tarnish; to damage; --
      esp. used of reputation or character.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would not be a stander-by to hear
            My sovereign mistress clouded so, without
            My present vengeance taken.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To mark with, or darken in, veins or sports; to variegate
      with colors; as, to cloud yarn.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the nice conduct of a clouded cane. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cloud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cloud \Cloud\, v. i.
   To grow cloudy; to become obscure with clouds; -- often used
   with up.
   [1913 Webster]

         Worthies, away! The scene begins to cloud. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cloud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cloud
     n 1: any collection of particles (e.g., smoke or dust) or gases
          that is visible
     2: a visible mass of water or ice particles suspended at a
        considerable altitude
     3: out of touch with reality; "his head was in the clouds"
     4: a cause of worry or gloom or trouble; "the only cloud on the
        horizon was the possibility of dissent by the French"
     5: suspicion affecting your reputation; "after that mistake he
        was under a cloud"
     6: a group of many insects; "a swarm of insects obscured the
        light"; "a cloud of butterflies" [syn: {swarm}]
     v 1: make overcast or cloudy; "Fall weather often overcasts our
          beaches" [syn: {overcast}] [ant: {clear up}]
     2: make less visible or unclear; "The stars are obscured by the
        clouds" [syn: {obscure}, {befog}, {becloud}, {obnubilate},
         {haze over}, {fog}, {mist}]
     3: billow up in the form of a cloud; "The smoke clouded above
        the houses"
     4: make gloomy or depressed; "Their faces were clouded with
        sadness"
     5: place under suspicion or cast doubt upon; "sully someone's
        reputation" [syn: {defile}, {sully}, {corrupt}, {taint}]
     6: colour with streaks or blotches of different shades [syn: {mottle},
         {dapple}]
     7: make milky or dull; "The chemical clouded the liquid to
        which it was added"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
