<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>club</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>club</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Club \Club\ (kl[u^]b), n. [Cf. Icel. klubba, klumba, club,
   klumbuf[=o]ir a clubfoot, SW. klubba club, Dan. klump lump,
   klub a club, G. klumpen clump, kolben club, and E. clump.]
   1. A heavy staff of wood, usually tapering, and wielded with
      the hand; a weapon; a cudgel.
      [1913 Webster]

            But make you ready your stiff bats and clubs;
            Rome and her rats are at the point of battle.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [Cf. the Spanish name bastos, and Sp. baston staff, club.]
      Any card of the suit of cards having a figure like the
      trefoil or clover leaf. (pl.) The suit of cards having
      such figure.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An association of persons for the promotion of some common
      object, as literature, science, politics, good fellowship,
      etc.; esp. an association supported by equal assessments
      or contributions of the members.
      [1913 Webster]

            They talked
            At wine, in clubs, of art, of politics. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            He [Goldsmith] was one of the nine original members
            of that celebrated fraternity which has sometimes
            been called the Literary Club, but which has always
            disclaimed that epithet, and still glories in the
            simple name of the Club.              --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A joint charge of expense, or any person's share of it; a
      contribution to a common fund.
      [1913 Webster]

            They laid down the club.              --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            We dined at a French house, but paid ten shillings
            for our part of the club.             --Pepys.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Club law}, government by violence; lynch law; anarchy.
      --Addison. 
      [1913 Webster]

   {Club root} (Bot.), a disease of cabbages, by which the roots
      become distorted and the heads spoiled.

   {Club topsail} (Naut.), a kind of gaff topsail, used mostly
      by yachts having a fore-and-aft rig. It has a short
      ``club'' or ``jack yard'' to increase its spread.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>club</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Club \Club\, v. i.
   1. To form a club; to combine for the promotion of some
      common object; to unite.
      [1913 Webster]

            Till grosser atoms, tumbling in the stream
            Of fancy, madly met, and clubbed into a dream.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pay on equal or proportionate share of a common charge
      or expense; to pay for something by contribution.
      [1913 Webster]

            The owl, the raven, and the bat,
            Clubbed for a feather to his hat.     --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) To drift in a current with an anchor out.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>club</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Club \Club\ (kl[u^]b), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Clubbed} (kl[u^]bd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Clubbing}.]
   1. To beat with a club.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) To throw, or allow to fall, into confusion.
      [1913 Webster]

            To club a battalion implies a temporary inability in
            the commanding officer to restore any given body of
            men to their natural front in line or column.
                                                  --Farrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To unite, or contribute, for the accomplishment of a
      common end; as, to club exertions.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To raise, or defray, by a proportional assesment; as, to
      club the expense.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To club a musket} (Mil.), to turn the breach uppermost, so
      as to use it as a club.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>club</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>club
     n 1: a team of professional baseball players who play and travel
          together; "each club played six home games with teams in
          its own division" [syn: {baseball club}, {ball club}, {nine}]
     2: a formal association of people with similar interests; "he
        joined a golf club"; "they formed a small lunch society";
        "men from the fraternal order will staff the soup kitchen
        today" [syn: {society}, {guild}, {gild}, {lodge}, {order}]
     3: stout stick that is larger at one end; "he carried a club in
        self defense"; "he felt as if he had been hit with a club"
     4: a building occupied by a club; "the clubhouse needed a new
        roof" [syn: {clubhouse}]
     5: golf equipment used by a golfer to hit a golf ball [syn: {golf
        club}, {golf-club}]
     6: a playing card in the minor suit of clubs (having one or
        more black trefoils on it); "he led a small club"; "clubs
        were trumps"
     7: a spot that is open late at night and that provides
        entertainment (as singers or dancers) as well as dancing
        and food and drink; "don't expect a good meal at a
        cabaret"; "the gossip columnist got his information by
        visiting nightclubs every night"; "he played the drums at
        a jazz club" [syn: {cabaret}, {nightclub}, {nightspot}]
     v 1: unite with a common purpose; "The two men clubbed together"
     2: gather and spend time together; "They always club together"
     3: strike with a club or a bludgeon [syn: {bludgeon}]
     [also: {clubbing}, {clubbed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
