<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>clue</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clue \Clue\ (kl[=u]), n. [See {Clew}, n.]
   A ball of thread; a thread or other means of guidance. Same
   as {Clew}.
   [1913 Webster]

         You have wound a goodly clue.            --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         This clue once found unravels all the rest. --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]

         Serve as clues to guide us into further knowledge.
                                                  --Locke.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clew \Clew\ (kl[=u]), Clue \Clue\, n. [OE. clewe, clowe, clue,
   AS. cleowen, cliwen, clywe ball of thread; akin to D. kluwen,
   OHG. chliwa, chliuwa, G. dim. kleuel, kn["a]uel, and perch.
   to L. gluma hull, husk, Skr. glaus sort of ball or tumor.
   Perch. akin to E. claw. [root]26. Cf. {Knawel}.]
   1. A ball of thread, yarn, or cord; also, The thread itself.
      [1913 Webster]

            Untwisting his deceitful clew.        --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which guides or directs one in anything of a doubtful
      or intricate nature; that which gives a hint in the
      solution of a mystery.
      [1913 Webster]

            The clew, without which it was perilous to enter the
            vast and intricate maze of countinental politics,
            was in his hands.                     --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.)
      (a.) A lower corner of a square sail, or the after corner
           of a fore-and-aft sail.
      (b.) A loop and thimbles at the corner of a sail.
      (c.) A combination of lines or nettles by which a hammock
           is suspended.
           [1913 Webster]

   {Clew garnet} (Naut.), one of the ropes by which the clews of
      the courses of square-rigged vessels are drawn up to the
      lower yards.

   {Clew line} (Naut.), a rope by which a clew of one of the
      smaller square sails, as topsail, topgallant sail, or
      royal, is run up to its yard.

   {Clew-line block} (Naut.), The block through which a clew
      line reeves. See Illust. of {Block}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>clue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>clue
     n 1: a slight indication [syn: {hint}]
     2: evidence that helps to solve a problem [syn: {clew}, {cue}]
     v : roll into a ball [syn: {clew}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
