<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>coat</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Coat
   the tunic worn like the shirt next the skin (Lev. 16:4; Cant.
   5:3; 2 Sam. 15:32; Ex. 28:4; 29:5). The "coats of skins"
   prepared by God for Adam and Eve were probably nothing more than
   aprons (Gen. 3:21). This tunic was sometimes woven entire
   without a seam (John 19:23); it was also sometimes of "many
   colours" (Gen. 37:3; R.V. marg., "a long garment with sleeves").
   The "fisher's coat" of John 21:7 was obviously an outer garment
   or cloak, as was also the "coat" made by Hannah for Samuel (1
   Sam. 2:19). (See {DRESS}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Coat \Coat\ (k[=o]t; 110), n. [OF. cote, F. cotte, petticoat,
   cotte d'armes coat of arms, cotte de mailles coat of mail,
   LL. cota, cotta, tunic, prob. of German origin; cf. OHG.
   chozzo coarse mantle, G. klotze, D. kot, hut, E. cot. Cf.
   {Cot} a hut.]
   1. An outer garment fitting the upper part of the body;
      especially, such a garment worn by men.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let each
            His adamantine coat gird well.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A petticoat. [Obs.] ``A child in coats.'' --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The habit or vesture of an order of men, indicating the
      order or office; cloth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men of his coat should be minding their prayers.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            She was sought by spirits of richest coat. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An external covering like a garment, as fur, skin, wool,
      husk, or bark; as, the horses coats were sleek.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fruit of all kinds, in coat
            Rough or smooth rined, or bearded husk, or shell.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A layer of any substance covering another; a cover; a
      tegument; as, the coats of the eye; the coats of an onion;
      a coat of tar or varnish.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Same as Coat of arms. See below.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hark, countrymen! either renew the fight,
            Or tear the lions out of England's coat. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A coat card. See below. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Here's a trick of discarded cards of us! We were
            ranked with coats as long as old master lived.
                                                  --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Coat armor}. See under {Armor}.

   {Coat of arms} (Her.), a translation of the French cotte
      d'armes, a garment of light material worn over the armor
      in the 15th and 16th centuries. This was often charged
      with the heraldic bearings of the wearer. Hence, an
      heraldic achievement; the bearings of any person, taken
      together.

   {Coat card}, a card bearing a coated figure; the king, queen,
      or knave of playing cards. ```I am a coat card indeed.'
      `Then thou must needs be a knave, for thou art neither
      king nor queen.''' --Rowley.

   {Coat link}, a pair of buttons or studs joined by a link, to
      hold together the lappels of a double-breasted coat; or a
      button with a loop for a single-breasted coat.

   {Coat of mail}, a defensive garment of chain mail. See {Chain
      mail}, under {Chain}.

   {Mast coat} (Naut.), a piece of canvas nailed around a mast,
      where it passes through the deck, to prevent water from
      getting below.

   {Sail coat} (Naut.), a canvas cover laced over furled sails,
      and the like, to keep them dry and clean.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Coat \Coat\ (k[=o]t), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Coated}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Coating}.]
   1. To cover with a coat or outer garment.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover with a layer of any substance; as, to coat a jar
      with tin foil; to coat a ceiling.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>coat
     n 1: an outer garment that has sleeves and covers the body from
          shoulder down; worn outdoors
     2: a thin layer covering something; "a second coat of paint"
        [syn: {coating}]
     3: growth of hair or wool or fur covering the body of an animal
        [syn: {pelage}]
     v 1: put a coat on; cover the surface of; furnish with a surface;
          "coat the cake with chocolate" [syn: {surface}]
     2: cover or provide with a coat
     3: form a coat over; "Dirt had coated her face" [syn: {cake}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
