<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>coffee</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coffee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Coffee \Cof"fee\ (k[add]"f[-e]; k[o^]f"f[-e]; 115), n. [Turk.
   qahveh, Ar. qahuah wine, coffee, a decoction of berries. Cf.
   {Caf['e]}.]
   1. The ``beans'' or ``berries'' (pyrenes) obtained from the
      drupes of a small evergreen tree of the genus {Coffea},
      growing in Abyssinia, Arabia, Persia, and other warm
      regions of Asia and Africa, and also in tropical America.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. The coffee tree.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: There are several species of the coffee tree, as,
         {Coffea Arabica}, {Coffea canephora}, {Coffea
         occidentalis}, and {Coffea Liberica}. The white,
         fragrant flowers grow in clusters at the root of the
         leaves, and the fruit is a red or purple cherrylike
         drupe, with sweet pulp, usually containing two pyrenes,
         commercially called ``beans'' or ``berries''.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The beverage made by decoction of the roasted and ground
      berry of the coffee tree.
      [1913 Webster]

            They have in Turkey a drink called coffee. . . .
            This drink comforteth the brain and heart, and
            helpeth digestion.                    --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. a cup of coffee[3], especially one served in a restaurant;
      as, we each had two donuts and a coffee; three coffees to
      go.
      [PJC]

   5. a social gathering at which coffee is served, with
      optional other foods or refreshments.
      [PJC]

   6. a color ranging from medium brown to dark brown.
      [PJC]

   Note: The use of coffee is said to have been introduced into
         England about 1650, when coffeehouses were opened in
         Oxford and London.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Coffee bug} (Zo["o]l.), a species of scale insect ({Lecanium
      coff[ae]a}), often very injurious to the coffee tree.

   {Coffee rat} (Zo["o]l.) See {Musang}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coffee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>coffee
     n 1: a beverage consisting of an infusion of ground coffee beans;
          "he ordered a cup of coffee" [syn: {java}]
     2: any of several small trees and shrubs native to the tropical
        Old World yielding coffee beans [syn: {coffee tree}]
     3: a seed of the coffee tree; ground to make coffee [syn: {coffee
        bean}, {coffee berry}]
     4: a medium to dark brown color [syn: {chocolate}, {deep brown},
         {umber}, {burnt umber}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
