<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cohort</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cohort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Series \Se"ries\, n. [L. series, fr. serere, sertum, to join or
   bind together; cf. Gr. ??? to fasten, Skr. sarit thread. Cf.
   {Assert}, {Desert} a solitude, {Exert}, {Insert},
   {Seraglio}.]
   1. A number of things or events standing or succeeding in
      order, and connected by a like relation; sequence; order;
      course; a succession of things; as, a continuous series of
      calamitous events.
      [1913 Webster]

            During some years his life a series of triumphs.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Biol.) Any comprehensive group of animals or plants
      including several subordinate related groups.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sometimes a series includes several classes; sometimes
         only orders or families; in other cases only species.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) In Engler's system of plant classification, a group
      of families showing certain structural or morphological
      relationships. It corresponds to the {cohort} of some
      writers, and to the {order} of many modern systematists.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. (Math.) An indefinite number of terms succeeding one
      another, each of which is derived from one or more of the
      preceding by a fixed law, called the law of the series;
      as, an arithmetical series; a geometrical series.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Elec.) A mode of arranging the separate parts of a
      circuit by connecting them successively end to end to form
      a single path for the current; -- opposed to {parallel}.
      The parts so arranged are said to be

   {in series}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. (Com.) A parcel of rough diamonds of assorted qualities.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cohort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cohort \Co"hort\, n. [L. cohors, prop. an inclosure: cf. F.
   cohorte. See {Court}, n.]
   1. (Rom. Antiq.) A body of about five or six hundred
      soldiers; the tenth part of a legion.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any band or body of warriors.
      [1913 Webster]

            With him the cohort bright
            Of watchful cherubim.                 --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) A natural group of orders of plants, less
      comprehensive than a class.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cohort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cohort
     n 1: a company of companions or supporters
     2: a band of warriors (originally a unit of a Roman Legion)
     3: a group people having approximately the same age [syn: {age
        group}, {age bracket}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
