<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>college</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>college</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>College
   Heb. mishneh (2 Kings 22:14; 2 Chr. 34:22), rendered in Revised
   Version "second quarter", the residence of the prophetess
   Huldah. The Authorized Version followed the Jewish commentators,
   who, following the Targum, gave the Hebrew word its
   post-Biblical sense, as if it meant a place of instruction. It
   properly means the "second," and may therefore denote the lower
   city (Acra), which was built after the portion of the city on
   Mount Zion, and was enclosed by a second wall.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>college</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>College, AK (CDP, FIPS 16750)
  Location: 64.86954 N, 147.82340 W
  Population (1990): 11249 (4255 housing units)
  Area: 41.2 sq km (land), 0.9 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>college</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>College \Col"lege\, n. [F. coll[`e]ge, L. collegium, fr. collega
   colleague. See {Colleague}.]
   1. A collection, body, or society of persons engaged in
      common pursuits, or having common duties and interests,
      and sometimes, by charter, peculiar rights and privileges;
      as, a college of heralds; a college of electors; a college
      of bishops.
      [1913 Webster]

            The college of the cardinals.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then they made colleges of sufferers; persons who,
            to secure their inheritance in the world to come,
            did cut off all their portion in this. --Jer.
                                                  Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A society of scholars or friends of learning, incorporated
      for study or instruction, esp. in the higher branches of
      knowledge; as, the colleges of Oxford and Cambridge
      Universities, and many American colleges.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In France and some other parts of continental Europe,
         college is used to include schools occupied with
         rudimentary studies, and receiving children as pupils.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. A building, or number of buildings, used by a college.
      ``The gate of Trinity College.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Fig.: A community. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thick as the college of the bees in May. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {College of justice}, a term applied in Scotland to the
      supreme civil courts and their principal officers.

   {The sacred college}, the college or cardinals at Rome.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>college</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>college
     n 1: the body of faculty and students of a college
     2: an institution of higher education created to educate and
        grant degrees; often a part of a university
     3: British slang for prison
     4: a complex of buildings in which a college is housed
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
