<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>colony</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>colony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Colony
   The city of Philippi was a Roman colony (Acts 16:12), i.e., a
   military settlement of Roman soldiers and citizens, planted
   there to keep in subjection a newly-conquered district. A colony
   was Rome in miniature, under Roman municipal law, but governed
   by military officers (praetors and lictors), not by proconsuls.
   It had an independent internal government, the jus Italicum;
   i.e., the privileges of Italian citizens.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>colony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Colony, AL (town, FIPS 16684)
  Location: 33.94138 N, 86.90118 W
  Population (1990): 298 (106 housing units)
  Area: 5.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Colony, KS (city, FIPS 14950)
  Location: 38.07064 N, 95.36216 W
  Population (1990): 447 (197 housing units)
  Area: 1.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 66015
Colony, OK (town, FIPS 16400)
  Location: 35.34765 N, 98.67011 W
  Population (1990): 163 (78 housing units)
  Area: 2.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 73021
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>colony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Colony \Col"o*ny\ (k[o^]l"[-o]*n[y^]), n.; pl. {Colonies}
   (k[o^]l"[-o]*n[i^]z). [L. colonia, fr. colonus farmer, fr.
   colere to cultivate, dwell: cf. F. colonie. Cf. {Culture}.]
   1. A company of people transplanted from their mother country
      to a remote province or country, and remaining subject to
      the jurisdiction of the parent state; as, the British
      colonies in America.
      [1913 Webster]

            The first settlers of New England were the best of
            Englishmen, well educated, devout Christians, and
            zealous lovers of liberty. There was never a colony
            formed of better materials.           --Ames.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The district or country colonized; a settlement.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. a territory subject to the ruling governmental authority
      of another country and not a part of the ruling country.
      [PJC]

   4. A company of persons from the same country sojourning in a
      foreign city or land; as, the American colony in Paris.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Nat. Hist.) A number of animals or plants living or
      growing together, beyond their usual range.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Bot.) A cell family or group of common origin, mostly of
      unicellular organisms, esp. among the lower alg[ae]. They
      may adhere in chains or groups, or be held together by a
      gelatinous envelope.
      [PJC]

   7. (Zo["o]l.) A cluster or aggregation of zooids of any
      compound animal, as in the corals, hydroids, certain
      tunicates, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. (Zo["o]l.) A community of social insects, as ants, bees,
      etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Microbiology) a group of microorganisms originating as
      the descendents of one individual cell, growing on a
      gelled growth medium, as of gelatin or agar; especially,
      such a group that has grown to a sufficient number to be
      visible to the naked eye.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>colony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>colony
     n 1: a body of people who settle far from home but maintain ties
          with their homeland; inhabitants remain nationals of
          their home state but are not literally under the home
          state's system of government [syn: {settlement}]
     2: a group of animals of the same type living together
     3: one of the 13 British colonies that formed the original
        states of the United States
     4: a geographical area politically controlled by a distant
        country [syn: {dependency}]
     5: (microbiology) a group of organisms grown from a single
        parent cell
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
