<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>colored</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>colored</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Colored \Col"ored\, a.
   1. Having color; tinged; dyed; painted; stained.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lime rod, colored as the glede.   --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The colored rainbow arched wide.      --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specious; plausible; adorned so as to appear well; as, a
      highly colored description. --Sir G. C. Lewis.
      [1913 Webster]

            His colored crime with craft to cloke. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Of some other color than black or white.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Ethnol.) Of some other color than white; having a skin
      color darker than that of caucasian people; mostly applied
      to negroes or persons having negro blood; as, a colored
      man; the colored people. Opposite of {white} and
      {caucasian}.

   Syn: coloured, dark-skinned.
        [1913 Webster]

   5. (Bot.) Of some other color than green.
      [1913 Webster]

            Colored, meaning, as applied to foliage, of some
            other color than green.               --Gray.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In botany, green is not regarded as a color, but white
         is. --Wood.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>colored</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Color \Col"or\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Colored}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Coloring}.] [F. colorer.]
   1. To change or alter the hue or tint of, by dyeing,
      staining, painting, etc.; to dye; to tinge; to paint; to
      stain.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rays, to speak properly, are not colored; in
            them there is nothing else than a certain power and
            disposition to stir up a sensation of this or that
            color.                                --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To change or alter, as if by dyeing or painting; to give a
      false appearance to; usually, to give a specious
      appearance to; to cause to appear attractive; to make
      plausible; to palliate or excuse; as, the facts were
      colored by his prejudices.
      [1913 Webster]

            He colors the falsehood of [AE]neas by an express
            command from Jupiter to forsake the queen. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To hide. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            That by his fellowship he color might
            Both his estate and love from skill of any wight.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>colored</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>colored
     adj 1: having color or a certain color; sometimes used in
            combination; "colored crepe paper"; "the film was in
            color"; "amber-colored heads of grain" [syn: {coloured},
             {colorful}] [ant: {uncolored}]
     2: having skin rich in melanin pigments; "National Association
        for the Advancement of Colored People"; "the dark races";
        "dark-skinned peoples" [syn: {coloured}, {dark}, {dark-skinned}]
     3: favoring one person or side over another; "a biased account
        of the trial"; "a decision that was partial to the
        defendant" [syn: {biased}, {coloured}, {one-sided}, {slanted}]
     4: (used of color) artificially produced; not natural; "a
        bleached blonde" [syn: {bleached}, {coloured}, {dyed}]
     n : a United States term for Blacks that is now considered
         offensive [syn: {colored person}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
