<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>column</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>column</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Column \Col"umn\, n. [L. columna, fr. columen, culmen, fr.
   cellere (used only in comp.), akin to E. excel, and prob. to
   holm. See {Holm}, and cf. {Colonel}.]
   1. (Arch.) A kind of pillar; a cylindrical or polygonal
      support for a roof, ceiling, statue, etc., somewhat
      ornamented, and usually composed of base, shaft, and
      capital. See {Order}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything resembling, in form or position, a column in
      architecture; an upright body or mass; a shaft or obelisk;
      as, a column of air, of water, of mercury, etc.; the
      Column Vend[^o]me; the spinal column.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil.)
      (a) A body of troops formed in ranks, one behind the
          other; -- contradistinguished from {line}. Compare
          {Ploy}, and {Deploy}.
      (b) A small army.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Naut.) A number of ships so arranged as to follow one
      another in single or double file or in squadrons; -- in
      distinction from ``line'', where they are side by side.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Print.) A perpendicular set of lines, not extending
      across the page, and separated from other matter by a rule
      or blank space; as, a column in a newspaper.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Arith.) A perpendicular line of figures.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Bot.) The body formed by the union of the stamens in the
      Mallow family, or of the stamens and pistil in the
      orchids.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Print.) one of a series of articles written in a
      periodical, usually under the same title and at regular
      intervals; it may be written and signed by one or more
      authors, or may appear pseudonymously or anonymously, as
      an editorial column. ``Safire's weekly column On Language
      in the New York Times is usually more interesting (and
      probably more accurate) than his political column.'' --P.
      Cassidy
      [PJC]

   {Attached column}. See under {Attach}, v. t.

   {Clustered column}. See under {Cluster}, v. t.

   {Column rule}, a thin strip of brass separating columns of
      type in the form, and making a line between them in
      printing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>column</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>column
     n 1: a line of (usually military) units following one after
          another
     2: a vertical glass tube used in column chromatography; a
        mixture is poured in the top and washed through a
        stationary substance where components of the mixture are
        adsorbed selectively to form colored bands [syn: {chromatography
        column}]
     3: a linear array of numbers one above another
     4: anything tall and thin approximating the shape of a column
        or tower; "the test tube held a column of white powder";
        "a tower of dust rose above the horizon"; "a thin pillar
        of smoke betrayed their campsite" [syn: {tower}, {pillar}]
     5: an article giving opinions or perspectives [syn: {editorial},
         {newspaper column}]
     6: a vertical structure standing alone and not supporting
        anything (as a monument or a column of air) [syn: {pillar}]
     7: (architeture) a tall cylindrical vertical upright and used
        to support a structure [syn: {pillar}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
