<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>coma</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coma</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Envelope \En"vel*ope\ (?; 277), Envelop \En*vel"op\ (?; 277), n.
   [F. enveloppe.]
   1. That which envelops, wraps up, encases, or surrounds; a
      wrapper; an inclosing cover; esp., the cover or wrapper of
      a document, as of a letter.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Astron.) The nebulous covering of the head or nucleus of
      a comet; -- called also {coma}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Fort.) A work of earth, in the form of a single parapet
      or of a small rampart. It is sometimes raised in the ditch
      and sometimes beyond it. --Wilhelm.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Geom.) A curve or surface which is tangent to each member
      of a system of curves or surfaces, the form and position
      of the members of the system being allowed to vary
      according to some continuous law. Thus, any curve is the
      envelope of its tangents.

   4. A set of limits for the performance capabilities of some
      type of machine, originally used to refer to aircraft; --
      it is often described graphically as a two-dimensional
      graph of a function showing the maximum of one performance
      variable as a function of another. Now it is also used
      metaphorically to refer to capabilities of any system in
      general, including human organizations, esp. in the phrase
      push the envelope. It is used to refer to the maximum
      performance available at the current state of the
      technology, and therefore refers to a class of machines in
      general, not a specific machine.
      [PJC]

   {push the envelope} to increase the capability of some type
      of machine or system; -- usually by technological
      development.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coma</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Coma \Co"ma\ (k[=o]"m[.a]), n. [NL., fr. Gr. kw^ma lethargy, fr.
   koima^n to put to sleep. See {Cemetery}.]
   A state of profound insensibility from which it is difficult
   or impossible to rouse a person. See {Carus}.
   [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coma</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Coma \Co"ma\, n. [L., hair, fr. Gr. ko`mh.]
   1. (Astron.) The envelope of a comet; a nebulous covering,
      which surrounds the nucleus or body of a comet.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) A tuft or bunch, -- as the assemblage of branches
      forming the head of a tree; or a cluster of bracts when
      empty and terminating the inflorescence of a plant; or a
      tuft of long hairs on certain seeds.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Coma Berenices}[L.] (Astron.), a small constellation north
      of Virgo; -- called also {Berenice's Hair}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coma</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>COMA
     Cache Only Memory Architecture (SMP)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>coma</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>coma
     n 1: a state of deep and often prolonged unconsciousness; usually
          the result of disease or injury [syn: {comatoseness}]
     2: a usually terminal tuft of hairs especially on a seed
     3: (astronomy) the luminous cloud of particles surrounding the
        frozen nucleus of a comet; forms as the comet approaches
        the sun and is warmed
     [also: {comae} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
