<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>comfort</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>comfort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>COMFORT, n.  A state of mind produced by contemplation of a neighbor's
uneasiness.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>comfort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Comfort, TX (CDP, FIPS 16228)
  Location: 29.97233 N, 98.90281 W
  Population (1990): 1477 (646 housing units)
  Area: 8.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 78013
Comfort, WV
  Zip code(s): 25049
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>comfort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Comfort \Com"fort\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Comforted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Comforting.}] [F. conforter, fr. L. confortare to
   strengthen much; con- + fortis strong. See {Fort}.]
   1. To make strong; to invigorate; to fortify; to corroborate.
      [Obs.] --Wyclif.
      [1913 Webster]

            God's own testimony . . . doth not a little comfort
            and confirm the same.                 --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To assist or help; to aid. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I . . . can not help the noble chevalier:
            God comfort him in this necessity!    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To impart strength and hope to; to encourage; to relieve;
      to console; to cheer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Light excelleth in comforting the spirits of men.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            That we may be able to comfort them that are in any
            affliction.                           --2 Cor. i. 4
                                                  (Rev. Ver.).
      [1913 Webster]

            A perfect woman, nobly planned,
            To warn, to comfort, and command.     --Wordsworth.

   Syn: To cheer; solace; console; revive; encourage; enliven;
        invigorate; inspirit; gladden; recreate; exhilarate;
        refresh; animate; confirm; strengthen.

   Usage: {To Comfort}, {Console}, {Solace}. These verbs all
          suppose some antecedent state of suffering or sorrow.
          Console is confined to the act giving sympathetic
          relief to the mind under affliction or sorrow, and
          points to some definite source of that relief; as, the
          presence of his friend consoled him; he was much
          consoled by this intelligence. The act of consoling
          commonly implies the inculcation of resignation.
          Comfort points to relief afforded by the communication
          of positive pleasure, hope, and strength, as well as
          by the diminution of pain; as, ``They brought the
          young man alive, and were not a little comforted.''
          --Acts xx. 12. Solace is from L. solacium, which means
          according to Dumesnil, consolation inwardly felt or
          applied to the case of the sufferer. Hence, the verb
          to solace denotes the using of things for the purpose
          of affording relief under sorrow or suffering; as, to
          solace one's self with reflections, with books, or
          with active employments.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>comfort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Comfort \Com"fort\, n. [OF. confort, fr. conforter.]
   1. Assistance; relief; support. [Obs. except in the phrase
      ``aid and comfort.'' See 5 below.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Encouragement; solace; consolation in trouble; also, that
      which affords consolation.
      [1913 Webster]

            In comfort of her mother's fears.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cheer thy spirit with this comfort.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Speaking words of endearment where words of comfort
            availed not.                          --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A state of quiet enjoyment; freedom from pain, want, or
      anxiety; also, whatever contributes to such a condition.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had much joy and comfort in thy love. --Phil. 7
                                                  (Rev. Ver.).
      [1913 Webster]

            He had the means of living in comfort. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A wadded bedquilt; a comfortable. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) Unlawful support, countenance, or encouragement; as,
      to give aid and comfort to the enemy.

   Syn: {Comfort}, {Consolation}.

   Usage: Comfort has two meanings:

   1. Strength and relief received under affliction;

   2. Positive enjoyment, of a quiet, permanent nature, together
      with the sources thereof; as, the comfort of love;
      surrounded with comforts; but it is with the former only
      that the word consolation is brought into comparison. As
      thus compared, consolation points to some specific source
      of relief for the afflicted mind; as, the consolations of
      religion. Comfort supposes the relief to be afforded by
      imparting positive enjoyment, as well as a diminution of
      pain. ``Consolation, or comfort, signifies some
      alleviation to that pain to which it is not in our power
      to afford the proper and adequate remedy; they imply
      rather an augmentation of the power of bearing, than a
      diminution of the burden.'' --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>comfort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>comfort
     n 1: a state of being relaxed and feeling no pain; "he is a man
          who enjoys his comfort"; "she longed for the
          comfortableness of her armchair" [syn: {comfortableness}]
          [ant: {discomfort}]
     2: a feeling of freedom from worry or disappointment
     3: the act of consoling; giving relief in affliction; "his
        presence was a consolation to her" [syn: {consolation}, {solace}]
     4: a freedom from financial difficulty that promotes a
        comfortable state; "a life of luxury and ease"; "he had
        all the material comforts of this world" [syn: {ease}]
     v 1: give moral or emotional strength to [syn: {soothe}, {console},
           {solace}]
     2: lessen pain or discomfort; alleviate; "ease the pain in your
        legs" [syn: {ease}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
