<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>command</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>command</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>command
     
        &lt;operating system&gt; A character string which tells a program to
        perform a specific action.  Most commands take {arguments}
        which either modify the action performed or supply it with
        input.  Commands may be typed by the user or read from a file
        by a {command interpreter}.  It is also common to refer to
        menu items as commands.
     
        (1997-06-21)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>command</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Command \Com*mand"\ (?; 61), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Commanded}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Commanding}.] [OE. comaunden, commanden, OF.
   comander, F. commander, fr. L. com- + mandare to commit to,
   to command. Cf. {Commend}, {Mandate}.]
   1. To order with authority; to lay injunction upon; to
      direct; to bid; to charge.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are commanded to forgive our enemies, but you
            never read that we are commanded to forgive our
            friends.                              --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go to your mistress:
            Say, I command her come to me.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To exercise direct authority over; to have control of; to
      have at one's disposal; to lead.
      [1913 Webster]

            Monmouth commanded the English auxiliaries.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Such aid as I can spare you shall command. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To have within a sphere of control, influence, access, or
      vision; to dominate by position; to guard; to overlook.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bridges commanded by a fortified house. --Motley.
      [1913 Webster]

            Up to the eastern tower,
            Whose height commands as subject all the vale.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            One side commands a view of the finest garden.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To have power or influence of the nature of authority
      over; to obtain as if by ordering; to receive as a due; to
      challenge; to claim; as, justice commands the respect and
      affections of the people; the best goods command the best
      price.
      [1913 Webster]

            'Tis not in mortals to command success. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To direct to come; to bestow. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I will command my blessing upon you.  --Lev. xxv.
                                                  21.

   Syn: To bid; order; direct; dictate; charge; govern; rule;
        overlook.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>command</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Command \Com*mand"\, n.
   1. An authoritative order requiring obedience; a mandate; an
      injunction.
      [1913 Webster]

            Awaiting what command their mighty chief
            Had to impose.                        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The possession or exercise of authority.
      [1913 Webster]

            Command and force may often create, but can never
            cure, an aversion.                    --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Authority; power or right of control; leadership; as, the
      forces under his command.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Power to dominate, command, or overlook by means of
      position; scope of vision; survey.
      [1913 Webster]

            The steepy stand
            Which overlooks the vale with wide command.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Control; power over something; sway; influence; as, to
      have command over one's temper or voice; the fort has
      command of the bridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            He assumed an absolute command over his readers.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A body of troops, or any naval or military force or post,
      or the whole territory under the authority or control of a
      particular officer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Word of command} (Mil.), a word or phrase of definite and
      established meaning, used in directing the movements of
      soldiers; as, {aim}; {fire}; {shoulder arms}, etc.

   Syn: Control; sway; power; authority; rule; dominion;
        sovereignty; mandate; order; injunction; charge; behest.
        See {Direction}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>command</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Command \Com*mand"\, v. i.
   1. To have or to exercise direct authority; to govern; to
      sway; to influence; to give an order or orders.
      [1913 Webster]

            And reigned, commanding in his monarchy. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            For the king had so commanded concerning [Haman].
                                                  --Esth. iii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To have a view, as from a superior position.
      [1913 Webster]

            Far and wide his eye commands.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>command</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>command
     n 1: an authoritative direction or instruction to do something
          [syn: {bid}, {bidding}, {dictation}]
     2: a military unit or region under the control of a single
        officer
     3: the power or authority to command; "an admiral in command"
     4: availability for use; "the materials at the command of the
        potters grew"
     5: a position of highest authority; "the corporation has just
        undergone a change in command"
     6: great skillfulness and knowledge of some subject or
        activity; "a good command of French" [syn: {control}, {mastery}]
     7: (computer science) a line of code written as part of a
        computer program [syn: {instruction}, {statement}, {program
        line}]
     v 1: be in command of; "The general commanded a huge army"
     2: make someone do something [syn: {require}, {compel}]
     3: demand as one's due; "This speaker commands a high fee";
        "The author commands a fair hearing from his readers"
     4: look down on; "The villa dominates the town" [syn: {dominate},
         {overlook}, {overtop}]
     5: exercise authoritative control or power over; "control the
        budget"; "Command the military forces" [syn: {control}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
