<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>compare</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compare \Com*pare"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Compared}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Comparing}.] [L.comparare, fr. compar like or equal
   to another; com- + par equal: cf. F. comparer. See {Pair},
   {Peer} an equal, and cf. {Compeer}.]
   1. To examine the character or qualities of, as of two or
      more persons or things, for the purpose of discovering
      their resemblances or differences; to bring into
      comparison; to regard with discriminating attention.
      [1913 Webster]

            Compare dead happiness with living woe. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The place he found beyond expression bright,
            Compared with aught on earth.         --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Compare our faces and be judge yourself. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To compare great things with small.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To represent as similar, for the purpose of illustration;
      to liken.
      [1913 Webster]

            Solon compared the people unto the sea, and orators
            and counselors to the winds; for that the sea would
            be calm and quiet if the winds did not trouble it.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Gram.) To inflect according to the degrees of comparison;
      to state positive, comparative, and superlative forms of;
      as, most adjectives of one syllable are compared by
      affixing ``- er'' and ``-est'' to the positive form; as,
      black, blacker, blackest; those of more than one syllable
      are usually compared by prefixing ``more'' and ``most'',
      or ``less'' and ``least'', to the positive; as, beautiful,
      more beautiful, most beautiful.

   Syn: To {Compare}, {Compare with}, {Compare to}.

   Usage: Things are compared with each other in order to learn
          their relative value or excellence. Thus we compare
          Cicero with Demosthenes, for the sake of deciding
          which was the greater orator. One thing is compared to
          another because of a real or fanciful likeness or
          similarity which exists between them. Thus it has been
          common to compare the eloquence of Demosthenes to a
          thunderbolt, on account of its force, and the
          eloquence of Cicero to a conflagration, on account of
          its splendor. Burke compares the parks of London to
          the lungs of the human body.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compare \Com*pare"\, v. i.
   1. To be like or equal; to admit, or be worthy of,
      comparison; as, his later work does not compare with his
      earlier.
      [1913 Webster]

            I should compare with him in excellence. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To vie; to assume a likeness or equality.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shall pack horses . . . compare with C[ae]sars?
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compare \Com*pare"\, n.
   1. Comparison. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            His mighty champion, strong beyond compare.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their small galleys may not hold compare
            With our tall ships.                  --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Illustration by comparison; simile. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Rhymes full of protest, of oath, and big compare.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Beyond compare}. See {Beyond comparison}, under
      {Comparison}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compare \Com*pare"\, v. t. [L. comparare to prepare, procure;
   com- + parare. See {Prepare}, {Parade}.]
   To get; to procure; to obtain; to acquire [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         To fill his bags, and richesse to compare. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>compare
     n : qualities that are comparable; "no comparison between the
         two books"; "beyond compare" [syn: {comparison}, {equivalence},
          {comparability}]
     v 1: examine and note the similarities or differences of; "John
          compared his haircut to his friend's"; "We compared
          notes after we had both seen the movie"
     2: be comparable; "This car does not compare with our line of
        Mercedes"
     3: consider or describe as similar, equal, or analogous; "We
        can compare the Han dynasty to the Romans"; "You cannot
        equate success in financial matters with greed" [syn: {liken},
         {equate}]
     4: to form the comparative or superlative form on an adjective
        or adverb
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
