<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>compensation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compensation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compensation \Com`pen*sa"tion\, n. [L. compensatio a weighing, a
   balancing of accounts.]
   1. The act or principle of compensating. --Emerson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which constitutes, or is regarded as, an equivalent;
      that which makes good the lack or variation of something
      else; that which compensates for loss or privation;
      amends; remuneration; recompense.
      [1913 Webster]

            The parliament which dissolved the monastic
            foundations . . . vouchsafed not a word toward
            securing the slightest compensation to the
            dispossessed owners.                  --Hallam.
      [1913 Webster]

            No pecuniary compensation can possibly reward them.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law)
      (a) The extinction of debts of which two persons are
          reciprocally debtors by the credits of which they are
          reciprocally creditors; the payment of a debt by a
          credit of equal amount; a set-off. --Bouvier.
          --Wharton.
      (b) A recompense or reward for some loss or service.
      (c) An equivalent stipulated for in contracts for the sale
          of real estate, in which it is customary to provide
          that errors in description, etc., shall not avoid, but
          shall be the subject of compensation.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Compensation balance}, or {Compensated balance}, a kind of
      balance wheel for a timepiece. The rim is usually made of
      two different metals having different expansibility under
      changes of temperature, so arranged as to counteract each
      other and preserve uniformity of movement.

   {Compensation pendulum}. See {Pendulum}.

   Syn: Recompense; reward; indemnification; consideration;
        requital; satisfaction; set-off.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compensation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>compensation
     n 1: something (such as money) given or received as payment or
          reparation (as for a service or loss or injury)
     2: (psychiatry) a defense mechanism that conceals your
        undesirable shortcomings by exaggerating desirable
        behaviors
     3: the act of compensating for service or loss or injury [syn:
        {recompense}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
