<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>compromise</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compromise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>COMPROMISE, n.  Such an adjustment of conflicting interests as gives
each adversary the satisfaction of thinking he has got what he ought
not to have, and is deprived of nothing except what was justly his
due.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compromise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compromise \Com"pro*mise\, n. [F. compromis, fr. L. compromissum
   a mutual promise to abide by the decision of an arbiter, fr.
   compromittere to make such a promise; com- + promittere to
   promise. See {Promise}.]
   1. A mutual agreement to refer matters in dispute to the
      decision of arbitrators. [Obs.] --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A settlement by arbitration or by mutual consent reached
      by concession on both sides; a reciprocal abatement of
      extreme demands or rights, resulting in an agreement.
      [1913 Webster]

            But basely yielded upon compromise
            That which his noble ancestors achieved with blows.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All government, indeed every human benefit and
            enjoyment, every virtue and every prudent act, is
            founded on compromise and barter.     --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

            An abhorrence of concession and compromise is a
            never failing characteristic of religious factions.
                                                  --Hallam.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A committal to something derogatory or objectionable; a
      prejudicial concession; a surrender; as, a compromise of
      character or right.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was determined not to accept any fine speeches, to
            the compromise of that sex the belonging to which
            was, after all, my strongest claim and title to
            them.                                 --Lamb.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compromise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compromise \Com"pro*mise\, v. i.
   1. To agree; to accord. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make concession for conciliation and peace.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compromise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compromise \Com"pro*mise\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Compromised}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Compromising}.] [From {Compromise}, n.; cf.
   {Compromit}.]
   1. To bind by mutual agreement; to agree. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Laban and himself were compromised
            That all the eanlings which were streaked and pied
            Should fall as Jacob's hire.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To adjust and settle by mutual concessions; to compound.
      [1913 Webster]

            The controversy may easily be compromised. --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pledge by some act or declaration; to endanger the
      life, reputation, etc., of, by some act which can not be
      recalled; to expose to suspicion.
      [1913 Webster]

            To pardon all who had been compromised in the late
            disturbances.                         --Motley.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>compromise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>compromise
     n 1: a middle way between two extremes [syn: {via media}]
     2: an accommodation in which both sides make concessions; "the
        newly elected congressmen rejected a compromise because
        they considered it `business as usual'"
     v 1: make a compromise; arrive at a compromise; "nobody will get
          everything he wants; we all must compromise"
     2: settle by concession
     3: expose or make liable to danger, suspicion, or disrepute;
        "The nuclear secrets of the state were compromised by the
        spy"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
