<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>companies</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>companies</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Company \Com"pa*ny\ (k[u^]m"p[.a]*n[y^]), n.; pl. {Companies}
   (k[u^]m"p[.a]*n[i^]z). [F. compagnie, fr. OF. compaing. See
   {Companion}.]
   1. The state of being a companion or companions; the act of
      accompanying; fellowship; companionship; society; friendly
      intercourse. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Evil company doth corrupt good manners. --1 Cor. xv.
                                                  33. (Rev.
                                                  Ver.).
      [1913 Webster]

            Brethren, farewell: your company along
            I will not wish.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A companion or companions.
      [1913 Webster]

            To thee and thy company I bid
            A hearty welcome.                     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An assemblage or association of persons, either permanent
      or transient.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt meet a company of prophets. --1 Sam. x.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Guests or visitors, in distinction from the members of a
      family; as, to invite company to dine.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Society, in general; people assembled for social
      intercourse.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nature has left every man a capacity of being
            agreeable, though not of shining in company.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An association of persons for the purpose of carrying on
      some enterprise or business; a corporation; a firm; as,
      the East India Company; an insurance company; a
      joint-stock company.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Partners in a firm whose names are not mentioned in its
      style or title; -- often abbreviated in writing; as,
      Hottinguer &amp; Co.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mil.) A subdivision of a regiment of troops under the
      command of a captain, numbering in the United States (full
      strength) 100 men.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) The crew of a ship, including the officers; as, a
      whole ship's company.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The body of actors employed in a theater or in the
       production of a play.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To keep company with}. See under {Keep}, v. t.

   Syn: Assemblage; assembly; society; group; circle; crowd;
        troop; crew; gang; corporation; association; fraternity;
        guild; partnership; copartnery; union; club; party;
        gathering.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
