<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>conclude</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conclude</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Conclude \Con*clude"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Concluded}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Concluding}.] [L. concludere, conclusum; con- +
   claudere to shut. See {Close}, v. t.]
   1. To shut up; to inclose. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The very person of Christ [was] concluded within the
            grave.                                --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To include; to comprehend; to shut up together; to
      embrace. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            For God hath concluded all in unbelief. --Rom. xi.
                                                  32.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Scripture hath concluded all under sin. --Gal.
                                                  iii. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To reach as an end of reasoning; to infer, as from
      premises; to close, as an argument, by inferring; --
      sometimes followed by a dependent clause.
      [1913 Webster]

            No man can conclude God's love or hatred to any
            person by anything that befalls him.  --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore we conclude that a man is justified by
            faith.                                --Rom. iii.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make a final determination or judgment concerning; to
      judge; to decide.
      [1913 Webster]

            But no frail man, however great or high,
            Can be concluded blest before he die. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Is it concluded he shall be protector? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To bring to an end; to close; to finish.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will conclude this part with the speech of a
            counselor of state.                   --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To bring about as a result; to effect; to make; as, to
      conclude a bargain. ``If we conclude a peace.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To shut off; to restrain; to limit; to estop; to bar; --
      generally in the passive; as, the defendant is concluded
      by his own plea; a judgment concludes the introduction of
      further evidence argument.
      [1913 Webster]

            If therefore they will appeal to revelation for
            their creation they must be concluded by it. --Sir
                                                  M. Hale.

   Syn: To infer; decide; determine; settle; close; finish;
        terminate; end.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conclude</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Conclude \Con*clude"\, v. i.
   1. To come to a termination; to make an end; to close; to
      end; to terminate.
      [1913 Webster]

            A train of lies,
            That, made in lust, conclude in perjuries. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            And, to conclude,
            The victory fell on us.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form a final judgment; to reach a decision.
      [1913 Webster]

            Can we conclude upon Luther's instability? --Bp.
                                                  Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

            Conclude and be agreed.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conclude</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>conclude
     v 1: decide by reasoning; draw or come to a conclusion; "We
          reasoned that it was cheaper to rent than to buy a
          house" [syn: {reason}, {reason out}]
     2: bring to a close; "The committee concluded the meeting"
     3: reach a conclusion after a discussion or deliberation [syn:
        {resolve}]
     4: come to a close; "The concert closed with a nocturne by
        Chopin" [syn: {close}]
     5: reach agreement on; "They concluded an economic agreement";
        "We concluded a cease-fire"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
