<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>conception</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conception</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Conception, MO
  Zip code(s): 64433
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conception</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Conception \Con*cep"tion\, n. [F. conception, L. conceptio, fr.
   concipere to conceive. See {Conceive}.]
   1. The act of conceiving in the womb; the initiation of an
      embryonic animal life.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will greaty multiply thy sorrow and thy
            conception.                           --Gen. iii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being conceived; beginning.
      [1913 Webster]

            Joy had the like conception in our eyes. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The power or faculty of apprehending of forming an idea in
      the mind; the power of recalling a past sensation or
      perception.
      [1913 Webster]

            Under the article of conception, I shall confine
            myself to that faculty whose province it is to
            enable us to form a notion of our past sensations,
            or of the objects of sense that we have formerly
            perceived.                            --Stewart.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The formation in the mind of an image, idea, or notion,
      apprehension.
      [1913 Webster]

            Conception consists in a conscious act of the
            understanding, bringing any given object or
            impression into the same class with any number of
            other objects or impression, by means of some
            character or characters common to them all.
                                                  --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The image, idea, or notion of any action or thing which is
      formed in the mind; a concept; a notion; a universal; the
      product of a rational belief or judgment. See {Concept}.
      [1913 Webster]

            He [Herodotus] says that the sun draws or attracts
            the water; a metaphorical term obviously intended to
            denote some more general and abstract conception
            than that of the visible operation which the word
            primarily signifies.                  --Whewell.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Idea; purpose; design.
      [1913 Webster]

            Note this dangerous conception.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Conceit; affected sentiment or thought. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . is full of conceptions, points of epigram,
            and witticism.                        --Dryden.

   Syn: Idea; notion; perception; apprehemsion; comprehension.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conception</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>conception
     n 1: an abstract or general idea inferred or derived from
          specific instances [syn: {concept}, {construct}] [ant: {misconception}]
     2: the act of becoming pregnant; fertilization of an ovum by a
        spermatozoon
     3: the event that occurred at the beginning of something; "from
        its creation the plan was doomed to failure" [syn: {creation}]
     4: the creation of something in the mind [syn: {invention}, {innovation},
         {excogitation}, {design}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
