<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>condensation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condensation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Condensation \Con`den*sa"tion\, n. [L. condensatio: cf. F.
   condensation.]
   1. The act or process of condensing or of being condensed;
      the state of being condensed.
      [1913 Webster]

            He [Goldsmith] was a great and perhaps an unequaled
            master of the arts of selection and condensation.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Physics) The act or process of reducing, by depression of
      temperature or increase of pressure, etc., to another and
      denser form, as gas to the condition of a liquid or steam
      to water.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Chem.) A rearrangement or concentration of the different
      constituents of one or more substances into a distinct and
      definite compound of greater complexity and molecular
      weight, often resulting in an increase of density, as the
      condensation of oxygen into ozone, or of acetone into
      mesitylene.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Condensation product} (Chem.), a substance obtained by the
      polymerization of one substance, or by the union of two or
      more, with or without separation of some unimportant side
      products.

   {Surface condensation}, the system of condensing steam by
      contact with cold metallic surfaces, in distinction from
      condensation by the injection of cold water.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condensation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>condensation
     n 1: (psychoanalysis) an unconscious process whereby two ideas or
          images combine into a single symbol; especially in
          dreams
     2: the process of changing from a gaseous to a liquid or solid
        state
     3: atmospheric moisture that has condensed because of cold
        [syn: {condensate}]
     4: the process or result of becoming smaller or pressed
        together; "the contraction of a gas on cooling" [syn: {compression},
         {contraction}]
     5: a shortened version of a written work [syn: {abridgement}, {abridgment},
         {capsule}]
     6: the act of increasing the density of something [syn: {condensing}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
