<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>condition</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Condition \Con*di"tion\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Conditioned}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Conditioning}.]
   1. To make terms; to stipulate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pay me back my credit,
            And I'll condition with ye.           --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Metaph.) To impose upon an object those relations or
      conditions without which knowledge and thought are alleged
      to be impossible.
      [1913 Webster]

            To think of a thing is to condition.  --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Condition \Con*di"tion\, n. [F., fr. L. conditio (better
   condicio) agreement, compact, condition; con- + a root
   signifying to show, point out, akin to dicere to say, dicare
   to proclaim, dedicate. See {Teach}, {Token}.]
   1. Mode or state of being; state or situation with regard to
      external circumstances or influences, or to physical or
      mental integrity, health, strength, etc.; predicament;
      rank; position, estate.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am in my condition
            A prince, Miranda; I do think, a king. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And O, what man's condition can be worse
            Than his whom plenty starves and blessings curse?
                                                  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

            The new conditions of life.           --Darwin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Essential quality; property; attribute.
      [1913 Webster]

            It seemed to us a condition and property of divine
            powers and beings to be hidden and unseen to others.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Temperament; disposition; character. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The condition of a saint and the complexion of a
            devil.                                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which must exist as the occasion or concomitant of
      something else; that which is requisite in order that
      something else should take effect; an essential
      qualification; stipulation; terms specified.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had as lief take her dowry with this condition, to
            be whipped at the high cross every morning. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many are apt to believe remission of sins, but they
            believe it without the condition of repentance.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) A clause in a contract, or agreement, which has for
      its object to suspend, to defeat, or in some way to
      modify, the principal obligation; or, in case of a will,
      to suspend, revoke, or modify a devise or bequest. It is
      also the case of a future uncertain event, which may or
      may not happen, and on the occurrence or non-occurrence of
      which, the accomplishment, recission, or modification of
      an obligation or testamentary disposition is made to
      depend. --Blount. Tomlins. Bouvier. Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Equation of condition}. (Math.) See under {Equation}.

   {On condition} or {Upon condition} (that), used for {if} in
      introducing conditional sentences. ``Upon condition thou
      wilt swear to pay him tribute . . . thou shalt be placed
      as viceroy under him.'' --Shak.

   {Conditions of sale}, the terms on which it is proposed to
      sell property by auction; also, the instrument containing
      or expressing these terms.

   Syn: State; situation; circumstances; station; case; mode;
        plight; predicament; stipulation; qualification;
        requisite; article; provision; arrangement. See {State}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Condition \Con*di"tion\, v. t. [Cf. LL. conditionare. See
   {Condition}, n.]
   1. To invest with, or limit by, conditions; to burden or
      qualify by a condition; to impose or be imposed as the
      condition of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Seas, that daily gain upon the shore,
            Have ebb and flow conditioning their march.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To contract; to stipulate; to agree.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was conditioned between Saturn and Titan, that
            Saturn should put to death all his male children.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Raleigh.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (U. S. Colleges) To put under conditions; to require to
      pass a new examination or to make up a specified study, as
      a condition of remaining in one's class or in college; as,
      to condition a student who has failed in some branch of
      study.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To test or assay, as silk (to ascertain the proportion of
      moisture it contains). --McElrath.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>condition
     n 1: a state at a particular time; "a condition (or state) of
          disrepair"; "the current status of the arms
          negotiations" [syn: {status}]
     2: a mode of being or form of existence of a person or thing;
        "the human condition"
     3: an assumption on which rests the validity or effect of
        something else [syn: {precondition}, {stipulation}]
     4: (usually plural) a statement of what is required as part of
        an agreement; "the contract set out the conditions of the
        lease"; "the terms of the treaty were generous" [syn: {term}]
     5: the state of (good) health (especially in the phrases `in
        condition' or `in shape' or `out of condition' or `out of
        shape') [syn: {shape}]
     6: information that should be kept in mind when making a
        decision; "another consideration is the time it would
        take" [syn: {circumstance}, {consideration}]
     7: the procedure that is varied in order to estimate a
        variable's effect by comparison with a control condition
        [syn: {experimental condition}]
     v 1: establish a conditioned response
     2: train by instruction and practice; especially to teach
        self-control; "Parents must discipline their children";
        "Is this dog trained?" [syn: {discipline}, {train}, {check}]
     3: specify as a condition or requirement in a contract or
        agreement; make an express demand or provision in an
        agreement; "The will stipulates that she can live in the
        house for the rest of her life"; "The contract stipulates
        the dates of the payments" [syn: {stipulate}, {qualify}, {specify}]
     4: put into a better state; "he conditions old cars"
     5: apply conditioner to in order to make smooth and shiny; "I
        condition my hair after washing it"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
