<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>condemn</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condemn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Condemn \Con*demn"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Condemned}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Condemning} (? or ?).] [L. condemnare; con- + damnare
   to condemn: cf. F. condamner. See {Damn}.]
   1. To pronounce to be wrong; to disapprove of; to censure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Condemn the fault, and not the actor of it!
            Why, every fault's condemned ere it be done. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wilt thou condemn him that is most just? --Job
                                                  xxxiv. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To declare the guilt of; to make manifest the faults or
      unworthiness of; to convict of guilt.
      [1913 Webster]

            The queen of the south shall rise up in the judgment
            with this generation, and shall condemn it. --Matt.
                                                  xii. 42.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pronounce a judicial sentence against; to sentence to
      punishment, suffering, or loss; to doom; -- with to before
      the penalty.
      [1913 Webster]

            Driven out from bliss, condemned
            In this abhorred deep to utter woe.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            To each his sufferings; all are men,
            Condemned alike to groan.             --Gray.
      [1913 Webster]

            And they shall condemn him to death.  --Matt. xx.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

            The thief condemned, in law already dead. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            No flocks that range the valley free,
            To slaughter I condemn.               --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To amerce or fine; -- with in before the penalty.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king of Egypt . . . condemned the land in a
            hundred talents of silver.            --2 Cron.
                                                  xxxvi. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To adjudge or pronounce to be unfit for use or service; to
      adjudge or pronounce to be forfeited; as, the ship and her
      cargo were condemned.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law) To doom to be taken for public use, under the right
      of eminent domain.

   Syn: To blame; censure; reprove; reproach; upbraid;
        reprobate; convict; doom; sentence; adjudge.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>condemn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>condemn
     v 1: express strong disapproval of; "We condemn the racism in
          South Africa"; "These ideas were reprobated" [syn: {reprobate},
           {decry}, {objurgate}, {excoriate}]
     2: declare or judge unfit; "The building was condemned by the
        inspector"
     3: compel or force into a particular state or activity; "His
        devotion to his sick wife condemned him to a lonely
        existence"
     4: demonstrate the guilt of (someone); "Her strange behavior
        condemned her"
     5: pronounce a sentence on (somebody) in a court of law; "He
        was condemned to ten years in prison" [syn: {sentence}, {doom}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
