<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>conference</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conference</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Conference \Con"fer*ence\, n. [F. conf['e]rence. See {Confer}.]
   1. The act of comparing two or more things together;
      comparison. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Helps and furtherances which . . . the mutual
            conference of all men's collections and observations
            may afford.                           --Hocker.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of consulting together formally; serious
      conversation or discussion; interchange of views.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor with such free and friendly conference
            As he hath used of old.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A meeting for consultation, discussion, or an interchange
      of opinions.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A meeting of the two branches of a legislature, by their
      committees, to adjust between them.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Methodist Church) A stated meeting of preachers and
      others, invested with authority to take cognizance of
      ecclesiastical matters.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A voluntary association of Congregational churches of a
      district; the district in which such churches are.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Conference meeting}, a meeting for conference. Specifically,
      a meeting conducted (usually) by laymen, for conference
      and prayer. [U. S.]

   {Conference room}, a room for conference and prayer, and for
      the pastor's less formal addresses. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conference</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>League \League\ (l[=e]g), n. [F. ligue, LL. liga, fr. L. ligare
   to bind; cf. Sp. liga. Cf. {Ally} a confederate, {Ligature}.]
   1. An alliance or combination of two or more nations,
      parties, organizations, or persons, for the accomplishment
      of a purpose which requires a continued course of action,
      as for mutual defense, or for furtherance of commercial,
      religious, or political interests, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            And let there be
            'Twixt us and them no league, nor amity. --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically: (Sports) An association of sports teams that
      establishes rules of play, decides questions of membership
      in the league, and organizes matches between the member
      teams. In some cases a sports league is called a
      {conference}, as in the {National Football Conference}.
      [PJC]

   Note: A league may be offensive or defensive, or both;
         offensive, when the parties agree to unite in attacking
         a common enemy; defensive, when they agree to a mutual
         defense of each other against an enemy.
         [1913 Webster]

   {The Holy League}, an alliance of Roman Catholics formed in
      1576 by influence of the Duke of Guise for the exclusion
      of Protestants from the throne of France.

   {Solemn League and Covenant}. See {Covenant},2.

   {The land league}, an association, organized in Dublin in
      1879, to promote the interests of the Irish tenantry, its
      avowed objects being to secure fixity of tenure, fair
      rent, and free sale of the tenants' interest. It was
      declared illegal by Parliament, but vigorous prosecutions
      have failed to suppress it.

   Syn: Alliance; confederacy; confederation; coalition;
        combination; compact; co["o]peration.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conference</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>conference
     n 1: a prearranged meeting for consultation or exchange of
          information or discussion (especially one with a formal
          agenda)
     2: an association of sports teams that organizes matches for
        its members [syn: {league}]
     3: a discussion among participants who have an agreed (serious)
        topic [syn: {group discussion}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
