<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>confirmation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>confirmation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Confirmation \Con`fir*ma"tion\, n. [F. confirmation, L.
   confirmatio.]
   1. The act of confirming or strengthening; the act of
      establishing, ratifying, or sanctioning; as, the
      confirmation of an appointment.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their blood is shed
            In confirmation of the noblest claim. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which confirms; that which gives new strength or
      assurance; as to a statement or belief; additional
      evidence; proof; convincing testimony.
      [1913 Webster]

            Trifles light as air
            Are to the jealous confirmations strong
            As proofs of holy writ.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Eccl.) A rite supplemental to baptism, by which a person
      is admitted, through the laying on of the hands of a
      bishop, to the full privileges of the church, as in the
      Roman Catholic, the Episcopal Church, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            This ordinance is called confirmation, because they
            who duly receive it are confirmed or strengthened
            for the fulfillment of their Christian duties, by
            the grace therein bestowed upon them. --Hook.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) A conveyance by which a voidable estate is made sure
      and not voidable, or by which a particular estate is
      increased; a contract, express or implied, by which a
      person makes that firm and binding which was before
      voidable.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>confirmation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>confirmation
     n 1: additional proof that something that was believed (some fact
          or hypothesis or theory) is correct; "fossils provided
          further confirmation of the evolutionary theory" [syn: {verification},
           {check}, {substantiation}]
     2: information that confirms or verifies
     3: making something valid by formally ratifying or confirming
        it; "the ratification of the treaty"; "confirmation of the
        appointment" [syn: {ratification}]
     4: a ceremony held in the synagogue (usually at Pentecost) to
        admit as adult members of the Jewish community young men
        and women who have successfully completed a course of
        study in Judaism
     5: a sacrament admitting a baptized person to full
        participation in the church
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
