<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>connection</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>connection</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Connection \Con*nec"tion\, n. [Cf. {Connexion}.]
   1. The act of connecting, or the state of being connected;
      the act or process of bringing two things into contact;
      junction; union; as, the connection between church and
      state is inescapable; the connection of pipes of different
      diameters requires an adapter.

   Syn: link, connectedness.
        [1913 Webster]

   2. That which connects or joins together; bond; tie.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. any relationship between things or events; association;
      alliance; as, a causal connection between interest rates
      and stock prices.

   Syn: relation.
        [PJC]

              He [Algazel] denied the possibility of a known
              connection between cause and effect. --Whewell.
        [1913 Webster]

              The eternal and inseparable connection between
              virtue and happiness.               --Atterbury.
        [1913 Webster]

              Any sort of connection which is perceived or
              imagined between two or more things. --I. Taylor.
        [1913 Webster]

   4. A relation; esp. a person connected with another by
      marriage rather than by blood; -- used in a loose and
      indefinite, and sometimes a comprehensive, sense.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The persons or things that are connected; as, a business
      connection; the Methodist connection.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men elevated by powerful connection.  --Motley.
      [1913 Webster]

            At the head of a strong parliamentary connection.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whose names, forces, connections, and characters
            were perfectly known to him.          --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. something that connects other objects.

   Syn: connexion, connector, connecter, connective.
        [PJC]

   6. (usually plural) an acquaintance or acquaintances who are
      influential or in a position of power and to whom you are
      connected in some way (as by family or friendship); as, he
      has powerful connections.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   7. a communications channel; as, my cell phone had a bad
      connection.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   8. (Transportation) a vehicle in which one may continue a
      journey after debarking from another vehicle; the
      departing vehicle of a {connection[9]}; as, my connection
      leaves four hours after my arrival; I missed my
      connection.

   Note: A connection may be more specifically referred to as a
         {connecting flight}, a {connecting train}, etc.
         [PJC]

   9. (Transportation) the scheduled arrival of one vehicle and
      departure of a second, sufficiently close in time and
      place to allow the departing vehicle serve as a means of
      continuing a journey begun or continued in the first
      vehicle; as, we can get a connection at Newark to continue
      on to Paris; -- most commonly used of airplanes, trains,
      and buses arriving and departing at the same terminal.
      [PJC]

   10. (Transportation) the transfer of a passenger from one
       vehicle to another to continue a journey; as, the
       connection was made in Copenhagen; -- most commonly of
       scheduled transportation on common carriers.
       [PJC]

   11. (Commerce) a vendor who can supply desired materials at a
       favorable price, or under conditions when other sources
       are unavailable; as, to get a bargain from one's
       connection in the jewelry trade; to have connections for
       the purchase of marijuana; -- often used in the pl..
       [PJC]

   12. (Psychol.) the process of bringing ideas or events
       together in memory or imagination.

   Syn: association, connection, connexion.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   {In this connection}, in connection with this subject.

   Note: [A phrase objected to by some writers.]
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: This word was formerly written, as by Milton, with x
         instead of t in the termination, connexion, and the
         same thing is true of the kindred words inflexion,
         reflexion, and the like. But the general usage at
         present is to spell them connection, inflection,
         reflection, etc.

   Syn: Union; coherence; continuity; junction; association;
        dependence; intercourse; commerce; communication;
        affinity; relationship.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>connection</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>connection
     n 1: a relation between things or events (as in the case of one
          causing the other or sharing features with it); "there
          was a connection between eating that pickle and having
          that nightmare" [syn: {connexion}, {connectedness}]
          [ant: {unconnectedness}]
     2: the state of being connected; "the connection between church
        and state is inescapable" [syn: {link}, {connectedness}]
        [ant: {disjunction}]
     3: an instrumentality that connects; "he soldered the
        connection"; "he didn't have the right connector between
        the amplifier and the speakers" [syn: {connexion}, {connector},
         {connecter}, {connective}]
     4: (usually plural) a person who is influential and to whom you
        are connected in some way (as by family or friendship);
        "he has powerful connections"
     5: the process of bringing ideas or events together in memory
        or imagination; "conditioning is a form of learning by
        association" [syn: {association}, {connexion}]
     6: a connecting shape [syn: {connexion}, {link}]
     7: a supplier (especially of narcotics)
     8: shifting from one form of transportation to another; "the
        plane was late and he missed his connection in Atlanta"
        [syn: {connexion}]
     9: the act of bringing two things into contact (especially for
        communication); "the joining of hands around the table";
        "there was a connection via the internet" [syn: {joining},
         {connexion}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
