<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>console</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>console</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>console
     
        1. The operator's station of a {mainframe}.  In times past,
        this was a privileged location that conveyed godlike powers to
        anyone with fingers on its keys.  Under {Unix} and other
        modern {time-sharing} {operating system}s, such privileges are
        guarded by passwords instead, and the console is just the
        {tty} the system was booted from.  Some of the mystique
        remains, however, and it is traditional for {sysadmin}s to
        post urgent messages to all users from the console (on Unix,
        /dev/console).
     
        2. On {microcomputer} {Unix} boxes, the main screen and
        keyboard (as opposed to character-only terminals talking to a
        {serial port}).  Typically only the console can do real
        graphics or run {X}.  See also {CTY}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>console</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Console \Con*sole"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Consoled}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Consoling}.] [L. consolari,. p. p. consolatus; con- +
   solari to console, comfort: cf. F. consoler. See {Solace}.]
   To cheer in distress or depression; to alleviate the grief
   and raise the spirits of; to relieve; to comfort; to soothe.
   [1913 Webster]

         And empty heads console with empty sound. --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]

         I am much consoled by the reflection that the religion
         of Christ has been attacked in vain by all the wits and
         philosophers, and its triumph has been complete. --P.
                                                  Henry.

   Syn: To comfort; solace; soothe; cheer; sustain; encourage;
        support. See {Comfort}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>console</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Console \Con"sole\, n. [F.]
   1. (Arch.)
      (a) A bracket whose projection is not more than half its
          height.
      (b) Any small bracket; also, a console table.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. (Computers) The keyboard and monitor of a computer
      considered together.
      [GG]

   3. (Engineering) The controlling portion of an electrical,
      electronic, or mechanical device or system, from which the
      operator may observe the state of the system as indicated
      by gauges or on some form of {display[n3]}, and may direct
      or control the action of the system.
      [GG +PJC]

   4. the desklike controlling unit of an organ containing the
      keyboard, pedals, stops, etc. by means of which the organ
      is played.
      [PJC]

   5. a home entertainment device such as a television, radio,
      phonograph, CD player, or combination of these, designed
      as a piece of furniture, to stand on the floor rather than
      on a table or in a separate cabinet; -- also used
      attributively in the phrase {console model}.
      [PJC]

   {Console table}, a table whose top is supported by two or
      more consoles instead of legs.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>console</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>console n. 1. The operator's station of a {mainframe}. In times past,
   this was a privileged location that conveyed godlike powers to anyone
   with fingers on its keys. Under Unix and other modern timesharing OSes,
   such privileges are guarded by passwords instead, and the console is
   just the {tty} the system was booted from. Some of the mystique remains,
   however, and it is traditional for sysadmins to post urgent messages to
   all users from the console (on Unix, /dev/console). 2. On microcomputer
   Unix boxes, the main screen and keyboard (as opposed to character-only
   terminals talking to a serial port). Typically only the console can do
   real graphics or run {X}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>console</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>console
     n 1: a small table fixed to a wall or designed to stand against a
          wall [syn: {console table}]
     2: a scientific instrument consisting of displays and an input
        device that an operator can use to monitor and control a
        system (especially a computer system)
     3: an ornamental scroll-shaped bracket (especially one used to
        support a wall fixture); "the bust of Napoleon stood on a
        console"
     4: housing for electronic instruments, as radio or television
        [syn: {cabinet}]
     v : give moral or emotional strength to [syn: {comfort}, {soothe},
          {solace}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
