<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>constitution</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>constitution</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Constitution \Con`sti*tu"tion\ (k[o^]n`st[ict]*t[=u]"sh[u^]n),
   n. [F. constitution, L. constitutio.]
   1. The act or process of constituting; the action of
      enacting, establishing, or appointing; enactment;
      establishment; formation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being; that form of being, or structure and
      connection of parts, which constitutes and characterizes a
      system or body; natural condition; structure; texture;
      conformation.
      [1913 Webster]

            The physical constitution of the sun. --Sir J.
                                                  Herschel.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The aggregate of all one's inherited physical qualities;
      the aggregate of the vital powers of an individual, with
      reference to ability to endure hardship, resist disease,
      etc.; as, a robust constitution.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our constitutions have never been enfeebled by the
            vices or luxuries of the old world.   --Story.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The aggregate of mental qualities; temperament.
      [1913 Webster]

            He defended himself with . . . less passion than was
            expected from his constitution.       --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The fundamental, organic law or principles of government
      of men, embodied in written documents, or implied in the
      institutions and usages of the country or society; also, a
      written instrument embodying such organic law, and laying
      down fundamental rules and principles for the conduct of
      affairs.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our constitution had begun to exist in times when
            statesmen were not much accustomed to frame exact
            definitions.                          --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In England the constitution is unwritten, and may be
         modified from time to time by act of Parliament. In the
         United States a constitution cannot ordinarily be
         modified, exept through such processes as the
         constitution itself ordains.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. An authoritative ordinance, regulation or enactment;
      especially, one made by a Roman emperor, or one affecting
      ecclesiastical doctrine or discipline; as, the
      constitutions of Justinian.
      [1913 Webster]

            The positive constitutions of our own churches.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            A constitution of Valentinian addressed to Olybrius,
            then prefect of Rome, for the regulation of the
            conduct of advocates.                 --George Long.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Apostolic constitutions}. See under {Apostolic}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>constitution</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>constitution
     n 1: law determining the fundamental political principles of a
          government [syn: {fundamental law}, {organic law}]
     2: the act of forming something; "the constitution of a PTA
        group last year"; "it was the establishment of his
        reputation"; "he still remembers the organization of the
        club" [syn: {establishment}, {formation}, {organization},
        {organisation}]
     3: the way in which someone or something is composed [syn: {composition},
         {makeup}]
     4: United States 44-gun frigate that was one of the first three
        naval ships built by the United States; it won brilliant
        victories over British frigates during the War of 1812 and
        is without doubt the most famous ship in the history of
        the United States Navy; it has been rebuilt and is
        anchored in the Charlestown Navy Yard in Boston [syn: {Old
        Ironsides}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
