<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>consistency</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>consistency</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Consistence \Con*sist"ence\, Consistency \Con*sist"en*cy\, n.
   [Cf. F. consistance.]
   1. The condition of standing or adhering together, or being
      fixed in union, as the parts of a body; existence;
      firmness; coherence; solidity.
      [1913 Webster]

            Water, being divided, maketh many circles, till it
            restore itself to the natural consistence. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are as water, weak, and of no consistence. --Jer.
                                                  Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The same form, substance, and consistency. --T.
                                                  Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A degree of firmness, density, viscosity, or spissitude; a
      measure of the ability to hold together when manipulated.

   Syn: body.
        [1913 Webster]

              Let the expressed juices be boiled into the
              consistence of a sirup.             --Arbuthnot.
        [1913 Webster]

   3. That which stands together as a united whole; a
      combination.
      [1913 Webster]

            The church of God, as meaning the whole consistence
            of orders and members.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Firmness of constitution or character; substantiality;
      durability; persistency.
      [1913 Webster]

            His friendship is of a noble make and a lasting
            consistency.                          --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Agreement or harmony of all parts of a complex thing among
      themselves, or of the same thing with itself at different
      times; the harmony of conduct with profession; congruity;
      correspondence; as, the consistency of laws, regulations,
      or judicial decisions; consistency of opinions;
      consistency of conduct or of character.
      [1913 Webster]

            That consistency of behavior whereby he inflexibly
            pursues those measures which appear the most just.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Consistency, thou art a jewel.        --Popular
                                                  Saying.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>consistency</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>consistency
     n 1: the property of holding together and retaining its shape;
          "when the dough has enough consistency it is ready to
          bake" [syn: {consistence}, {body}]
     2: a harmonious uniformity or agreement among things or parts
        [syn: {consistence}] [ant: {inconsistency}]
     3: logical coherence and accordance with the facts; "a rambling
        argument that lacked any consistency"
     4: (logic) an attribute of a logical system that is so
        constituted that none of the propositions deducible from
        the axioms contradict one another
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
