<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>consist</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>consist</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Consist \Con*sist"\ (k[o^]n*s[i^]st"), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Consisted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Consisting}.] [L. consistere to
   stand still or firm; con- + sistere to stand, cause to stand,
   stare to stand: cf. F. consister. See {Stand}.]
   1. To stand firm; to be in a fixed or permanent state, as a
      body composed of parts in union or connection; to hold
      together; to be; to exist; to subsist; to be supported and
      maintained.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is before all things, and by him all things
            consist.                              --Col. i. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be composed or made up; -- followed by of.
      [1913 Webster]

            The land would consist of plains and valleys. --T.
                                                  Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To have as its substance or character, or as its
      foundation; to be; -- followed by in.
      [1913 Webster]

            If their purgation did consist in words. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man's life consisteth not in the abundance of the
            things which he possesseth.           --Luke xii.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be consistent or harmonious; to be in accordance; --
      formerly used absolutely, now followed by with.
      [1913 Webster]

            This was a consisting story.          --Bp. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

            Health consists with temperance alone. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            For orders and degrees
            Jar not with liberty, but well consist. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To insist; -- followed by on. [Obs.] --Shak.

   Syn: {To Consist}, {Consist of}, {Consist in}.

   Usage: The verb consist is employed chiefly for two purposes,
          which are marked and distinguished by the prepositions
          used. When we wish to indicate the parts which unite
          to compose a thing, we use of; as when we say,
          ``Macaulay's Miscellanies consist chiefly of articles
          which were first published in the Edinburgh Review.''
          When we wish to indicate the true nature of a thing,
          or that on which it depends, we use in; as, ``There
          are some artists whose skill consists in a certain
          manner which they have affected.'' ``Our safety
          consists in a strict adherence to duty.''
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>consist</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>consist
     v 1: originate (in); "The problems dwell in the social injustices
          in this country" [syn: {dwell}, {lie}, {belong}, {lie in}]
     2: have its essential character; be comprised or contained in;
        be embodied in; "The payment consists in food"; "What does
        love consist in?"
     3: be consistent in form, tenor, or character; be congruous;
        "Desires are to be satisfied only so far as consists with
        an approved end"
     4: be composed of; "The land he conquered comprised several
        provinces"; "What does this dish consist of?" [syn: {comprise}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
