<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>constellation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>constellation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Constellation
   a cluster of stars, or stars which appear to be near each other
   in the heavens, and which astronomers have reduced to certain
   figures (as the "Great Bear," the "Bull," etc.) for the sake of
   classification and of memory. In Isa. 13:10, where this word
   only occurs, it is the rendering of the Hebrew _kesil_, i.e.,
   "fool." This was the Hebrew name of the constellation Orion (Job
   9:9; 38:31), a constellation which represented Nimrod, the
   symbol of folly and impiety. The word some interpret by "the
   giant" in this place, "some heaven-daring rebel who was chained
   to the sky for his impiety."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>constellation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Constellation \Con`stel*la"tion\, n. [F. constellation, L.
   constellatio.]
   1. A cluster or group of fixed stars, or division of the
      heavens, designated in most cases by the name of some
      animal, or of some mythologial personage, within whose
      imaginary outline, as traced upon the heavens, the group
      is included.
      [1913 Webster]

            The constellations seem to have been almost
            purposely named and delineated to cause as much
            confusion and inconvenience as possible. --Sir J.
                                                  Herschel.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In each of the constellations now recognized by
         astronomers (about 90 in number) the brightest stars,
         both named and unnamed, are designated nearly in the
         order of brilliancy by the letters of the Greek
         alphabet; as, [alpha] Tauri (Aldebaran) is the first
         star of Taurus, [gamma] Orionis (Bellatrix) is the
         third star of Orion.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. An assemblage of splendors or excellences.
      [1913 Webster]

            The constellations of genius had already begun to
            show itself . . . which was to shed a glory over the
            meridian and close of Philip's reign. --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fortune; fate; destiny. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            It is constellation, which causeth all that a man
            doeth.                                --Gower.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>constellation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>constellation
     n 1: an arrangement of parts or elements; "the outcome depends on
          the configuration of influences at the time" [syn: {configuration}]
     2: a configuration of stars as seen from the earth
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
