<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>contact</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>contact</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Contact \Con"tact\ (k[o^]n"t[a^]kt), n. [L. contactus, fr.
   contingere, -tactum, to touch on all sides. See
   {Contingent}.]
   1. A close union or junction of bodies; a touching or
      meeting.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geom.) The property of two curves, or surfaces, which
      meet, and at the point of meeting have a common direction.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mining) The plane between two adjacent bodies of
      dissimilar rock. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Electricity) A metallic conducting component of an
      electrical device connected to a circuit within and so
      situated that it may form a conducting pathway to an
      external power source or device when contacted by another
      conductor; as, the contact on a standard light bulb has
      the shape of a screw for easy insertion into the socket.
      [PJC]

   5. A person who serves to commmunicate information to or from
      one group to another, whether formally or informally; as,
      a good Washington reporter has contacts in the White
      House.
      [PJC]

   {Contact level}, a delicate level so pivoted as to tilt when
      two parts of a measuring apparatus come into contact with
      each other; -- used in precise determinations of lengths
      and in the accurate graduation of instruments.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>contact</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>contact
     n 1: close interaction; "they kept in daily contact"; "they
          claimed that they had been in contact with
          extraterrestrial beings"
     2: the state or condition of touching or of being in immediate
        proximity; "litmus paper turns red on contact with an
        acid"
     3: the act of touching physically; "her fingers came in contact
        with the light switch"
     4: the physical coming together of two or more things; "contact
        with the pier scraped paint from the hull" [syn: {impinging},
         {striking}]
     5: a person who is in a position to give you special
        assistance; "he used his business contacts to get an
        introduction to the governor" [syn: {middleman}]
     6: a channel for communication between groups; "he provided a
        liaison with the guerrillas" [syn: {liaison}, {link}, {inter-group
        communication}]
     7: (electronics) a junction where things (as two electrical
        conductors) touch or are in physical contact; "they forget
        to solder the contacts" [syn: {tangency}]
     8: a communicative interaction; "the pilot made contact with
        the base"; "he got in touch with his colleagues" [syn: {touch}]
     9: a thin curved glass or plastic lens designed to fit over the
        cornea in order to correct vision or to deliver medication
        [syn: {contact lens}]
     v 1: be in or establish communication with; "Our advertisements
          reach millions"; "He never contacted his children after
          he emigrated to Australia" [syn: {reach}, {get through},
           {get hold of}]
     2: be in direct physical contact with; make contact; "The two
        buildings touch"; "Their hands touched"; "The wire must
        not contact the metal cover"; "The surfaces contact at
        this point" [syn: {touch}, {adjoin}, {meet}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
