<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>contrast</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>contrast</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Contrast \Con*trast"\, v. t.
   1. To set in opposition, or over against, in order to show
      the differences between, or the comparative excellences
      and defects of; to compare by difference or contrariety of
      qualities; as, to contrast the present with the past.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Fine Arts) To give greater effect to, as to a figure or
      other object, by putting it in some relation of opposition
      to another figure or object.
      [1913 Webster]

            the figures of the groups must not be all on side .
            . . but must contrast each other by their several
            position.                             --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>contrast</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Contrast \Con*trast"\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Contrasted}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Contrasting}.] [F. contraster, LL. contrastare to
   resist, withstand, fr. L. contra + stare to stand. See
   {Stand}.]
   To stand in opposition; to exhibit difference, unlikeness, or
   opposition of qualities.
   [1913 Webster]

         The joints which divide the sandstone contrast finely
         with the divisional planes which separate the basalt
         into pillars.                            --Lyell.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>contrast</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Contrast \Con"trast\ (k[o^]n"tr[.a]st), n. [F. contraste: cf.
   It. contrasto.]
   1. The act of contrasting, or the state of being contrasted;
      comparison by contrariety of qualities.
      [1913 Webster]

            place the prospect of the soul
            In sober contrast with reality.       --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Opposition or dissimilitude of things or qualities;
      unlikeness, esp. as shown by juxtaposition or comparison.
      [1913 Webster]

            The contrasts and resemblances of the seasons.
                                                  --Whewell.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Fine Arts) The opposition of varied forms, colors, etc.,
      which by such juxtaposition more vividly express each
      other's peculiarities.                      --Fairholt.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>contrast</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>contrast
     n 1: the opposition or dissimilarity of things that are compared;
          "in contrast to", "by contrast" [syn: {direct contrast}]
     2: the act of distinguishing by comparing differences
     3: a conceptual separation or demarcation; "there is a narrow
        line between sanity and insanity" [syn: {line}, {dividing
        line}, {demarcation}]
     4: the perceptual effect of the juxtaposition of very different
        colors
     5: the range of optical density and tone on a photographic
        negative or print (or the extent to which adjacent areas
        on a television screen differ in brightness)
     v 1: put in opposition to show or emphasize differences; "The
          middle school teacher contrasted her best student's work
          with that of her weakest student"
     2: to show differences when compared; be different; "the
        students contrast considerably in their artistic
        abilities" [syn: {counterpoint}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
