<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>control</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>control</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>control
     
        &lt;character&gt; (Or "ctrl", "^") One (or a pair) of {modifier
        keys} found on all modern {keyboards}.  If the control key is
        held down while pressing and releasing certain other keys then
        a "{control character}" is generated, e.g. holding control and
        hitting "A" generates control-A ({ASCII} code 1).  The ASCII
        code for the control character is generally 64 less than that
        for the unmodified character.
     
        The control key does not generate any character on its own but
        most modern keyboards and {operating systems} allow a program
        to tell whether each of the individual keys on the keyboard
        (including modifier keys) is pressed at any time.
     
        Control characters mostly have some kind of "non-printing"
        effect on the output such as ringing the bell (Control-G) or
        advancing to the next line (Control-J).  Most have alternative
        names suggesting these functions (Bell, Line Feed, etc.).
     
        See {ASCII character table}.
     
        (1997-07-10)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>control</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Control \Con*trol"\, n. [F. contr[^o]le a counter register,
   contr. fr. contr-r[^o]le; contre (L. contra) + r[^o]le roll,
   catalogue. See {Counter} and {Roll}, and cf. {Counterroll}.]
   1. A duplicate book, register, or account, kept to correct or
      check another account or register; a counter register.
      [Obs.] --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which serves to check, restrain, or hinder;
      restraint. ``Speak without control.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Power or authority to check or restrain; restraining or
      regulating influence; superintendence; government; as,
      children should be under parental control.
      [1913 Webster]

            The House of Commons should exercise a control over
            all the departments of the executive administration.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mach.) The complete apparatus used to control a mechanism
      or machine in operation, as a flying machine in flight;
      specifically (A["e]ronautics), the mechanism controlling
      the rudders and ailerons.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   5. (Climatology) Any of the physical factors determining the
      climate of any particular place, as latitude,distribution
      of land and water, altitude, exposure, prevailing winds,
      permanent high- or low-barometric-pressure areas, ocean
      currents, mountain barriers, soil, and vegetation.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. (Technology) in research, an object or subject used in an
      experimental procedure, which is treated identically to
      the primary subject of the experiment, except for the
      omission of the specific treatment or conditions whose
      effect is being investigated. If the control is a group of
      living organisms, as is common in medical research, it is
      called the

   {control group}.

   Note: For most experimental procedures, the results are not
         considered valid and reliable unless a proper control
         experiment is performed. There are various types of
         control used in experimental science, and often several
         groups of subjects serve as controls, being subjected
         to different variations of the experimental procedure,
         or controlling for several variables being tested. When
         the effects caused by an experimental treatment are not
         consistent and obvious, statistical analysis of the
         results is typically used to determine if there are any
         significant differences between the effects of
         different experimental conditions.
         [PJC]

   7. (Technology) the part of an experimental procedure in
      which the controls[6] are subjected to the experimental
      conditions.
      [PJC]

   8. the group of technical specialists exercising control by
      remote communications over a distant operation, such as a
      space flight; as, the American Mission Control for manned
      flights is located in Houston.
      [PJC]

   {Board of control}. See under {Board}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>control</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Control \Con*trol"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Controlled}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Controlling}.] [F. contr[^o]ler, fr. contr[^o]le.]
   [Formerly written {comptrol} and {controul}.]
   1. To check by a counter register or duplicate account; to
      prove by counter statements; to confute. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This report was controlled to be false. --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To exercise restraining or governing influence over; to
      check; to counteract; to restrain; to regulate; to govern;
      to overpower.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give me a staff of honor for mine age,
            But not a scepter to control the world. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I feel my virtue struggling in my soul:
            But stronger passion does its power control.
                                                  --Dryden.

   3. to assure the validity of an experimental procedure by
      using a {control[7]}.
      [PJC]

   Syn: To restrain; rule; govern; manage; guide; regulate;
        hinder; direct; check; curb; counteract; subdue.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>control</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>control
     n 1: power to direct or determine; "under control"
     2: a relation of constraint of one entity (thing or person or
        group) by another; "measures for the control of disease";
        "they instituted controls over drinking on campus"
     3: (physiology) regulation or maintenance of a function or
        action or reflex etc; "the timing and control of his
        movements were unimpaired"; "he had lost control of his
        sphincters"
     4: a standard against which other conditions can be compared in
        a scientific experiment; "the control condition was
        inappropriate for the conclusions he wished to draw" [syn:
         {control condition}]
     5: the activity of managing or exerting control over something;
        "the control of the mob by the police was admirable"
     6: the state that exists when one person or group has power
        over another; "her apparent dominance of her husband was
        really her attempt to make him pay attention to her" [syn:
         {dominance}, {ascendance}, {ascendence}, {ascendancy}, {ascendency}]
     7: discipline in personal and social activities; "he was a
        model of polite restraint"; "she never lost control of
        herself" [syn: {restraint}] [ant: {unrestraint}]
     8: great skillfulness and knowledge of some subject or
        activity; "a good command of French" [syn: {command}, {mastery}]
     9: the economic policy of controlling or limiting or curbing
        prices or wages etc.; "they wanted to repeal all the
        legislation that imposed economic controls"
     10: a mechanism that controls the operation of a machine; "the
         speed control on his turntable was not working properly";
         "I turned the controls over to her" [syn: {controller}]
     11: a spiritual agency that is assumed to assist the medium
         during a seance
     v 1: exercise authoritative control or power over; "control the
          budget"; "Command the military forces" [syn: {command}]
     2: lessen the intensity of; temper; hold in restraint; hold or
        keep within limits; "moderate your alcohol intake"; "hold
        your tongue"; "hold your temper"; "control your anger"
        [syn: {hold in}, {hold}, {contain}, {check}, {curb}, {moderate}]
     3: handle and cause to function; "do not operate machinery
        after imbibing alcohol"; "control the lever" [syn: {operate}]
     4: control (others or oneself) or influence skillfully, usually
        to one's advantage; "She manipulates her boss"; "She is a
        very controlling mother and doesn't let her children grow
        up"; "The teacher knew how to keep the class in line";
        "she keeps in line" [syn: {manipulate}, {keep in line}]
     5: verify or regulate by conducting a parallel experiment or
        comparing with another standard, of scientific
        experiments; "Are you controlling for the temperature?"
        [syn: {verify}]
     6: verify by using a duplicate register for comparison;
        "control an account"
     7: be careful or certain to do something; make certain of
        something; "He verified that the valves were closed"; "See
        that the curtains are closed"; "control the quality of the
        product" [syn: {see}, {check}, {insure}, {see to it}, {ensure},
         {ascertain}, {assure}]
     8: have a firm understanding or knowledge of; be on top of; "Do
        you control these data?" [syn: {master}]
     [also: {controlling}, {controlled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
