<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>containment</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>containment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Containment \Con*tain"ment\, n.
   1. That which is contained; the extent; the substance. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The containment of a rich man's estate. --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. the act of containing.
      [PJC]

   3. (Diplomacy) the act or policy of restricting the influence
      or territorial growth of a hostile nation.

   Note: The policy of containment is employed when the defeat
         of a hostile nation or overthrow of its government is
         considered impractical or too costly.
         [PJC]

   4. the act of restricting some deleterious substance within a
      confined space, especially when such material is released
      unintentionally or by accident; as, containment of nuclear
      waste; containment of an oil spill. Also used
      attributively, as a containment boom.
      [PJC]

   5. a structure surrounding a nuclear power plant designed to
      prevent release of radioactive materials into the
      environment in the event of an accident.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>containment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>containment
     n 1: a policy of creating strategic alliances in order to check
          the expansion of a hostile power or ideology or to force
          it to negotiate pecefully; "containment of communist
          expansion was a central principle of United States'
          foreign policy from 1947 to the 1975"
     2: (physics) a system designed to prevent the accidental
        release of radioactive material from a reactor
     3: (military) the act of containing something or someone;
        keeping it from spreading; "the army was charged with the
        containment of the rebel forces"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
