<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>converted</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>converted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Convert \Con*vert"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Converted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Converting}.] [L. convertere, -versum; con- + vertere
   to turn: cf. F. convertir. See {Verse}.]
   1. To cause to turn; to turn. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            O, which way shall I first convert myself? --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To change or turn from one state or condition to another;
      to alter in form, substance, or quality; to transform; to
      transmute; as, to convert water into ice.
      [1913 Webster]

            If the whole atmosphere were converted into water.
                                                  --T. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

            That still lessens
            The sorrow, and converts it nigh to joy. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To change or turn from one belief or course to another, as
      from one religion to another or from one party or sect to
      another.
      [1913 Webster]

            No attempt was made to convert the Moslems.
                                                  --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To produce the spiritual change called conversion in (any
      one); to turn from a bad life to a good one; to change the
      heart and moral character of (any one) from the
      controlling power of sin to that of holiness.
      [1913 Webster]

            He which converteth the sinner from the error of his
            way shall save a soul from death.     --Lames v. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To apply to any use by a diversion from the proper or
      intended use; to appropriate dishonestly or illegally.
      [1913 Webster]

            When a bystander took a coin to get it changed, and
            converted it, [it was] held no larceny. --Cooley.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To exchange for some specified equivalent; as, to convert
      goods into money.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Logic) To change (one proposition) into another, so that
      what was the subject of the first becomes the predicate of
      the second.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To turn into another language; to translate. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Which story . . . Catullus more elegantly converted.
                                                  --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Converted guns}, cast-iron guns lined with wrought-iron or
      steel tubes. --Farrow.

   {Converting furnace} (Steel Manuf.), a furnace in which
      wrought iron is converted into steel by cementation.

   Syn: To change; turn; transmute; appropriate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>converted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>converted \converted\ adj.
   spiritually reborn or converted; as, a converted sinner.

   Syn: born-again, reborn.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>converted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>converted
     adj : spiritually reborn or converted; "a born-again Christian";
           "a converted sinner" [syn: {born-again}, {reborn}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
