<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>conversion</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conversion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Conversion
   the turning of a sinner to God (Acts 15:3). In a general sense
   the heathen are said to be "converted" when they abandon
   heathenism and embrace the Christian faith; and in a more
   special sense men are converted when, by the influence of divine
   grace in their souls, their whole life is changed, old things
   pass away, and all things become new (Acts 26:18). Thus we speak
   of the conversion of the Philippian jailer (16:19-34), of Paul
   (9:1-22), of the Ethiopian treasurer (8:26-40), of Cornelius
   (10), of Lydia (16:13-15), and others. (See {REGENERATION}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conversion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Conversion \Con*ver"sion\, n. [L. conversio: cf. F. conversion.
   See {Convert}.]
   1. The act of turning or changing from one state or condition
      to another, or the state of being changed; transmutation;
      change.
      [1913 Webster]

            Artificial conversion of water into ice. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The conversion of the aliment into fat. --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of changing one's views or course, as in passing
      from one side, party, or from of religion to another;
      also, the state of being so changed. ``Conversion to
      Christianity.'' --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) An appropriation of, and dealing with the property
      of another as if it were one's own, without right; as, the
      conversion of a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            Or bring my action of conversion
            And trover for my goods.              --Hudibras.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Logic) The act of interchanging the terms of a
      proposition, as by putting the subject in the place of the
      predicate, or the contrary.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) A change or reduction of the form or value of a
      proposition; as, the conversion of equations; the
      conversion of proportions.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mil.)
      (a) A change of front, as a body of troops attacked in the
          flank.
      (b) A change of character or use, as of smoothbore guns
          into rifles.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. (Theol.) A spiritual and moral change attending a change
      of belief with conviction; a change of heart; a change
      from the service of the world to the service of God; a
      change of the ruling disposition of the soul, involving a
      transformation of the outward life.
      [1913 Webster]

            He oft
            Frequented their assemblies, . . . and to them
            preached
            Conversion and repentance, as to souls
            In prison under judgments imminent.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>conversion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>conversion
     n 1: an event that results in a transformation [syn: {transition},
           {changeover}]
     2: a change in the units or form of an expression: "conversion
        from Fahrenheit to Centigrade"
     3: a successful free throw or try for point after a touchdown
     4: a spiritual enlightenment causing a person to lead a new
        life [syn: {rebirth}, {spiritual rebirth}]
     5: (psychiatry) a defense mechanism represses emotional
        conflicts which are then converted into physical symptoms
        that have no organic basis
     6: a change of religion; "his conversion to the Catholic faith"
     7: interchange of subject and predicate of a proposition
     8: act of exchanging one type of money or security for another
     9: the act of changing from one use or function or purpose to
        another
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
