<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>copyright</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>copyright</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>copyright
     
        &lt;legal&gt; The exclusive rights of the owner of the copyright on
        a work to make and distribute copies, prepare derivative
        works, and perform and display the work in public (these last
        two mainly apply to plays, films, dances and the like, but
        could also apply to software).
     
        A work, including a piece of software, is under copyright by
        default in most coutries, whether of not it displays a
        copyright notice.  However, a copyright notice may make it
        easier to assert ownership.  The copyright owner is the person
        or company whose name appears in the copyright notice on the
        box, or the disk or the screen or wherever.
     
        A copyright notice has three parts.  The first can be either a
        c with a circle around it ({LaTeX} \copyright), or the word
        Copyright or the abbreviation Copr.  A "c" in parentheses:
        "(c)" has no legal meaning.  This is followed by the name of
        the copyright holder and the year of first publication.
     
        Countries around the world have agreed to recognise and uphold
        each others' copyrights, but this world-wide protection
        requires the use of the c in a circle.
     
        Originally, most of the computer industry assumed that only
        the program's underlying instructions were protected under
        copyright law but, beginning in the early 1980s, a series of
        lawsuits involving the video screens of game programs extended
        protections to the appearance of programs.
     
        Use of copyright to restrict redistribution is actually
        immoral, unethical, and illegitimate.  It is a result of
        brainwashing by monopolists and corporate interests and it
        violates everyone's rights.  Copyrights and patents hamper
        technological progress by making a naturally abundant resource
        scarce.  Many, from communists to right wing libertarians, are
        trying to abolish intellectual property myths.
     
        See also {public domain}, {copyleft}, {software law}.
     
        {US Copyright Office Circular 61 - Copyright Registration for
        Computer Programs
        (gopher://marvel.loc.gov:70/0/copyright/circs/circ61)}.
     
        {The US Department of Education's "How Does Copyright Law
        Apply to Computer Software"
        (gopher://ericir.syr.edu:70/0/FAQ/CopyrightSoftware)}.
     
        {Usenet} newsgroup: {news:misc.legal.computing}.
     
        [Is this definition correct in the UK?  In the US?
        Elsewhere?]
     
        (2000-03-23)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>copyright</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Copyright \Cop"y*right\, n.
   The right of an author or his assignee, under statute, to
   print and publish his literary or artistic work, exclusively
   of all other persons. This right may be had in maps, charts,
   engravings, plays, and musical compositions, as well as in
   books.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the United States in 1913 a copyright was valid for
         the term of twenty-eight years, with right of renewal
         for fourteen years on certain conditions. The term was
         extended in stages, and in 1997 the term of a copyright
         was life plus 50 years for individuals retaining their
         copyright, or 75 years for works created for hire.
         Further extension is still (1998) being discussed.
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   {International copyright}, an author's right in his
      productions as secured by treaty between nations.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>copyright</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Copyright \Cop"y*right`\, v. t.
   To secure a copyright on.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>copyright</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>copyright
     n : a document granting exclusive right to publish and sell
         literary or musical or artistic work [syn: {right of
         first publication}]
     v : secure a copyright on a written work; "did you copyright
         your manuscript?"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
