<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cord</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cord
   frequently used in its proper sense, for fastening a tent (Ex.
   35:18; 39:40), yoking animals to a cart (Isa. 5:18), binding
   prisoners (Judg. 15:13; Ps. 2:3; 129:4), and measuring ground (2
   Sam. 8;2; Ps. 78:55). Figuratively, death is spoken of as the
   giving way of the tent-cord (Job 4:21. "Is not their tent-cord
   plucked up?" R.V.). To gird one's self with a cord was a token
   of sorrow and humiliation. To stretch a line over a city meant
   to level it with the ground (Lam. 2:8). The "cords of sin" are
   the consequences or fruits of sin (Prov. 5:22). A "threefold
   cord" is a symbol of union (Eccl. 4:12). The "cords of a man"
   (Hos. 11:4) means that men employ, in inducing each other,
   methods such as are suitable to men, and not "cords" such as
   oxen are led by. Isaiah (5:18) says, "Woe unto them that draw
   iniquity with cords of vanity, and sin as it were with a cart
   rope." This verse is thus given in the Chaldee paraphrase: "Woe
   to those who begin to sin by little and little, drawing sin by
   cords of vanity: these sins grow and increase till they are
   strong and are like a cart rope." This may be the true meaning.
   The wicked at first draw sin with a slender cord; but by-and-by
   their sins increase, and they are drawn after them by a cart
   rope. Henderson in his commentary says: "The meaning is that the
   persons described were not satisfied with ordinary modes of
   provoking the Deity, and the consequent ordinary approach of his
   vengeance, but, as it were, yoked themselves in the harness of
   iniquity, and, putting forth all their strength, drew down upon
   themselves, with accelerated speed, the load of punishment which
   their sins deserved."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cord, AR
  Zip code(s): 72524
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cord \Cord\ (k[^o]rd), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Corded}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Cording}.]
   1. To bind with a cord; to fasten with cords; to connect with
      cords; to ornament or finish with a cord or cords, as a
      garment.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To arrange (wood, etc.) in a pile for measurement by the
      cord.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cord \Cord\ (k[^o]rd), n. [F. corde, L. chorda catgut, chord,
   cord, fr. Gr. chordh`; cf. chola`des intestines, L. haruspex
   soothsayer (inspector of entrails), Icel. g["o]rn, pl. garnir
   gut, and E. yarn. Cf. {Chord}, {Yarn}.]
   1. A string, or small rope, composed of several strands
      twisted together.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A solid measure, equivalent to 128 cubic feet; a pile of
      wood, or other coarse material, eight feet long, four feet
      high, and four feet broad; -- originally measured with a
      cord or line.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fig.: Any moral influence by which persons are caught,
      held, or drawn, as if by a cord; an enticement; as, the
      cords of the wicked; the cords of sin; the cords of
      vanity.
      [1913 Webster]

            The knots that tangle human creeds,
            The wounding cords that bind and strain
            The heart until it bleeds.            --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Anat.) Any structure having the appearance of a cord,
      esp. a tendon or a nerve. See under {Spermatic}, {Spinal},
      {Umbilical}, {Vocal}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.) See {Chord}. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cord wood}, wood for fuel cut to the length of four feet
      (when of full measure).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Core \Core\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cord} (k?rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Coring}.]
   1. To take out the core or inward parts of; as, to core an
      apple.
      [1913 Webster]

            He's like a corn upon my great toe . . . he must be
            cored out.                            --Marston.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form by means of a core, as a hole in a casting.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To extract a cylindrical sample from, with a boring
      device. See {core[8]}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cord
     n 1: a line made of twisted fibers or threads; "the bundle was
          tied with a cord"
     2: a unit of amount of wood cut for burning; 128 cubic feet
     3: a light insulated conductor for household use [syn: {electric
        cord}]
     4: a cut pile fabric with vertical ribs; usually made of cotton
        [syn: {corduroy}]
     v 1: stack in cords; "cord firewood"
     2: bind or tie with a cord
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
