<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>corn</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Corn
   The word so rendered (dagan) in Gen. 27:28, 37, Num. 18:27,
   Deut. 28:51, Lam. 2:12, is a general term representing all the
   commodities we usually describe by the words corn, grain, seeds,
   peas, beans. With this corresponds the use of the word in John
   12:24.
   
     In Gen. 41:35, 49, Prov. 11:26, Joel 2:24 ("wheat"), the word
   thus translated (bar; i.e., "winnowed") means corn purified from
   chaff. With this corresponds the use of the word in the New
   Testament (Matt. 3:12; Luke 3:17; Acts 7:12). In Ps. 65:13 it
   means "growing corn."
   
     In Gen. 42:1, 2, 19, Josh. 9:14, Neh. 10:31 ("victuals"), the
   word (sheber; i.e., "broken," i.e., grist) denotes generally
   victuals, provisions, and corn as a principal article of food.
   
     From the time of Solomon, corn began to be exported from
   Palestine (Ezek. 27:17; Amos 8:5). "Plenty of corn" was a part
   of Issac's blessing conferred upon Jacob (Gen. 27:28; comp. Ps.
   65:13).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Corn, OK (town, FIPS 17300)
  Location: 35.37887 N, 98.78131 W
  Population (1990): 548 (228 housing units)
  Area: 0.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 73024
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Indian corn \Indian corn\ (Bot.),
   A cereal plant of the genus {Zea} ({Zea Mays}), also simply
   called {corn}, used widely as a food; the maize, a native
   plant of America; more specifically: a primitive variety of
   {Zea Mays} having variegated kernels on each cob, in
   distinction from the more commonly used {yellow corn}; it is
   often used as decoration at Thanksgiving time. See {Corn},
   and {Maize}.
   [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: In modern American usage, the word corn when unmodified
         usually refers to yellow corn, and Indian corn refers
         to the variegated variety.
         [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Maize \Maize\ (m[=a]z), n. [Sp. maiz. fr. mahiz or mahis, is the
   language of the Island of Haiti.] (Bot.)
   A large species of American grass of the genus {Zea} ({Zea
   Mays}), widely cultivated as a forage and food plant; Indian
   corn, commonly called {corn}. Also, its seed, growing on
   cobs, and used as food for men and animals.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Maize eater} (Zo["o]l.), a South American bird of the genus
      {Pseudoleistes}, allied to the troupials.

   {Maize yellow}, a delicate pale yellow.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Corn \Corn\ (k[^o]rn), n. [L. cornu horn: cf. F. corne horn,
   hornlike excrescence. See {Horn}.]
   A thickening of the epidermis at some point, esp. on the
   toes, by friction or pressure. It is usually painful and
   troublesome.
   [1913 Webster]

         Welcome, gentlemen! Ladies that have their toes
         Unplagued with corns, will have a bout with you.
                                                  --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The substance of a corn usually resembles horn, but
         where moisture is present, as between the toes, it is
         white and sodden, and is called a {soft corn}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Corn \Corn\, n. [AS. corn; akin to OS. korn, D. koren, G., Dan.,
   Sw., &amp; Icel. korn, Goth. ka['u]rn, L. granum, Russ. zerno.
   Cf. {Grain}, {Kernel}.]
   1. A single seed of certain plants, as wheat, rye, barley,
      and maize; a grain.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The various farinaceous grains of the cereal grasses used
      for food, as wheat, rye, barley, maize, oats.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In Scotland, corn is generally restricted to oats, in
         the United States, to maize, or {Indian corn} (see
         sense 3), and in England to wheat.
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. a tall cereal plant ({Zea mays}) bearing its seeds as
      large kernels in multiple rows on the surface of a hard
      cylindrical ear, the core of which (the cob) is not
      edible; -- also called {Indian corn} and, in technical
      literature, {maize}. There are several kinds; as, {yellow
      corn}, which grows chiefly in the Northern States, and is
      yellow when ripe; {white corn} or {southern corn}, which
      grows to a great height, and has long white kernels;
      {sweet corn}, comprising a number of sweet and tender
      varieties, grown chiefly at the North, some of which have
      kernels that wrinkle when ripe and dry; {pop corn}, any
      small variety, used for popping. Corn seeds may be cooked
      while on the ear and eaten directly, or may be stripped
      from the ear and cooked subsequently. The term {Indian
      corn} is often used to refer to a primitive type of corn
      having kernels of varied color borne on the same cob; it
      is used for decoration, especially in the fall.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. The plants which produce corn, when growing in the field;
      the stalks and ears, or the stalks, ears, and seeds, after
      reaping and before thrashing.
      [1913 Webster]

            In one night, ere glimpse of morn,
            His shadowy flail had thrashed the corn. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A small, hard particle; a grain. ``Corn of sand.'' --Bp.
      Hall. ``A corn of powder.'' --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Corn ball}, a ball of popped corn stuck together with soft
      candy from molasses or sugar.

   {Corn bread}, bread made of Indian meal.

   {Corn cake}, a kind of corn bread; johnny cake; hoecake.

   {Corn cockle} (Bot.), a weed ({Agrostemma Githago} syn.
      {Lychnis Githago}), having bright flowers, common in grain
      fields.

   {Corn flag} (Bot.), a plant of the genus {Gladiolus}; --
      called also {sword lily}.

   {Corn fly}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A small fly which, in the larval state, is injurious
          to grain, living in the stalk, and causing the disease
          called ``gout,'' on account of the swelled joints. The
          common European species is {Chlorops t[ae]niopus}.
      (b) A small fly ({Anthomyia ze}) whose larva or maggot
          destroys seed corn after it has been planted.

   {Corn fritter}, a fritter having green Indian corn mixed
      through its batter. [U. S.]

   {Corn laws}, laws regulating trade in corn, especially those
      in force in Great Britain till 1846, prohibiting the
      importation of foreign grain for home consumption, except
      when the price rose above a certain rate.

   {Corn marigold}. (Bot.) See under {Marigold}.

   {Corn oyster}, a fritter containing grated green Indian corn
      and butter, the combined taste resembling that of oysters.
      [U.S.]

   {Corn parsley} (Bot.), a plant of the parsley genus
      ({Petroselinum segetum}), a weed in parts of Europe and
      Asia.

   {Corn popper}, a utensil used in popping corn.

   {Corn poppy} (Bot.), the red poppy ({Papaver Rh[oe]as}),
      common in European cornfields; -- also called {corn rose}.
      

   {Corn rent}, rent paid in corn.

   {Corn rose}. See {Corn poppy}.

   {Corn salad} (Bot.), a name given to several species of
      {Valerianella}, annual herbs sometimes used for salad.
      {Valerianella olitoria} is also called {lamb's lettuce}.
      

   {Corn stone}, red limestone. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Corn violet} (Bot.), a species of {Campanula}.

   {Corn weevil}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A small weevil which causes great injury to grain.
      (b) In America, a weevil ({Sphenophorus ze[ae]}) which
          attacks the stalk of maize near the root, often doing
          great damage. See {Grain weevil}, under {Weevil}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Corn \Corn\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Corned} (k?rnd); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Corning}.]
   1. To preserve and season with salt in grains; to sprinkle
      with salt; to cure by salting; now, specifically, to salt
      slightly in brine or otherwise; as, to corn beef; to corn
      a tongue.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form into small grains; to granulate; as, to corn
      gunpowder.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To feed with corn or (in Sctland) oats; as, to corn
      horses. --Jamieson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To render intoxicated; as, ale strong enough to corn one.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Corning house}, a house or place where powder is corned or
      granulated.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>corn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>corn
     n 1: tall annual cereal grass bearing kernels on large ears:
          widely cultivated in America in many varieties; the
          principal cereal in Mexico and Central and South America
          since pre-Columbian times [syn: {maize}, {Indian corn},
          {Zea mays}]
     2: the dried grains or kernels or corn used as animal feed or
        ground for meal
     3: ears of corn grown for human food [syn: {edible corn}]
     4: a hard thickening of the skin (especially on the top or
        sides of the toes) caused by the pressure of ill-fitting
        shoes [syn: {clavus}]
     5: annual or biennial grass having erect flower spikes and
        light brown grains [syn: {wheat}]
     6: whiskey distilled from a mash of not less than 80 percent
        corn [syn: {corn whiskey}, {corn whisky}]
     7: something sentimental or trite; "that movie was pure corn"
     v 1: feed (cattle) with corn
     2: preserve with salt; "corned beef"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
