<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>couch</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>couch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Couch
   (Gen. 49:4; 1 Chr. 5:1; Job 7:13; Ps. 6:6, etc.), a seat for
   repose or rest. (See {BED}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>couch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Couch, MO
  Zip code(s): 65690
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>couch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Couch \Couch\, v. i.
   1. To lie down or recline, as on a bed or other place of
      rest; to repose; to lie.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where souls do couch on flowers, we 'll hand in
            hand.                                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If I court moe women, you 'll couch with moe men.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lie down for concealment; to hide; to be concealed; to
      be included or involved darkly.
      [1913 Webster]

            We 'll couch in the castle ditch, till we see the
            light of our fairies.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The half-hidden, hallf-revealed wonders, that yet
            couch beneath the words of the Scripture. --I.
                                                  Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bend the body, as in reverence, pain, labor, etc.; to
      stoop; to crouch. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            An aged squire
            That seemed to couch under his shield three-square.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>couch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Couch \Couch\ (kouch), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Couched} (koucht);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Couching}.] [F. coucher to lay down, lie
   down, OF. colchier, fr. L. collocare to lay, put, place; col-
   + locare to place, fr. locus place. See {Locus}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To lay upon a bed or other resting place.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where unbruised youth, with unstuffed brain,
            Does couch his limbs, there golden sleep doth reign.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To arrange or dispose as in a bed; -- sometimes followed
      by the reflexive pronoun.
      [1913 Webster]

            The waters couch themselves as may be to the center
            of this globe, in a spherical convexity. --T.
                                                  Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To lay or deposit in a bed or layer; to bed.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is at this day in use at Gaza, to couch
            potsherds, or vessels of earth, in their walls.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Paper Making) To transfer (as sheets of partly dried
      pulp) from the wire cloth mold to a felt blanket, for
      further drying.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To conceal; to include or involve darkly.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is all this, and more, that lies naturally
            couched under this allegory.          --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To arrange; to place; to inlay. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To put into some form of language; to express; to phrase;
      -- used with in and under.
      [1913 Webster]

            A well-couched invective.             --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had received a letter from Flora couched in rather
            cool terms.                           --Blackw. Mag.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Med.) To treat by pushing down or displacing the opaque
      lens with a needle; as, to couch a cataract.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To couch a spear} or {To couch a lance}, to lower to the
      position of attack; to place in rest.
      [1913 Webster]

            He stooped his head, and couched his spear,
            And spurred his steed to full career. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To couch malt}, to spread malt on a floor. --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>couch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Couch \Couch\, n. [F. couche, OF. colche, culche, fr. colchier.
   See {Couch}, v. t. ]
   1. A bed or place for repose or sleep; particularly, in the
      United States, a lounge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gentle sleep . . . why liest thou with the vile
            In loathsome beds, and leavest the kingly couch?
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like one that wraps the drapery of his couch
            About him, and lies down to pleasant dreams.
                                                  --Bryant.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any place for repose, as the lair of a beast, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A mass of steeped barley spread upon a floor to germinate,
      in malting; or the floor occupied by the barley; as, couch
      of malt.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Painting &amp; Gilding) A preliminary layer, as of color,
      size, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>couch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Coach \Coach\ (k[=o]ch; 224), n. [F. coche, fr. It. cocchio,
   dim. of cocca little boat, fr. L. concha mussel, mussel
   shell, Gr. ?, akin to Skr. [,c]ankha. Cf. {Conch},
   {Cockboat}, {Cockle}.]
   1. A large, closed, four-wheeled carriage, having doors in
      the sides, and generally a front and back seat inside,
      each for two persons, and an elevated outside seat in
      front for the driver.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Coaches have a variety of forms, and differ in respect
         to the number of persons they can carry. Mail coaches
         and tallyho coaches often have three or more seats
         inside, each for two or three persons, and seats
         outside, sometimes for twelve or more.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A special tutor who assists in preparing a student for
      examination. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Wareham was studying for India with a Wancester
            coach.                                --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) A cabin on the after part of the quarter-deck,
      usually occupied by the captain. [Written also {couch}.]
      [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The commanders came on board and the council sat in
            the coach.                            --Pepys.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Railroad) A first-class passenger car, as distinguished
      from a drawing-room car, sleeping car, etc. It is
      sometimes loosely applied to any passenger car.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. One who coaches; specif. (sports), a trainer; one who
      assists in training individual athletes or the members of
      a sports team, or who performs other ancillary functions
      in sports; as, a third base coach.
      [+PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>couch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>couch
     n 1: an upholstered seat for more than one person [syn: {sofa}, {lounge}]
     2: a flat coat of paint or varnish used by artists as a primer
     3: a narrow bed on which a patient lies during psychiatric or
        psychoanalytic treatment
     v : formulate in a particular style or language; "I wouldn't put
         it that way"; "She cast her request in very polite
         language" [syn: {frame}, {redact}, {cast}, {put}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
