<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>could</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>could</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Could \Could\ (k??d), imp. of {Can}. [OF. coude. The l was
   inserted by mistake, under the influence of should and
   would.]
   Was, should be, or would be, able, capable, or susceptible.
   Used as an auxiliary, in the past tense or in the conditional
   present.
   [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>could</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Can \Can\, v. t. &amp; i.

   Note: [The transitive use is obsolete.] [imp. {Could}.] [OE.
         cunnen, cannen (1st sing. pres. I can), to know, know
         how, be able, AS. cunnan, 1st sing. pres. ic cann or
         can, pl. cunnon, 1st sing. imp. c[=u][eth]e (for
         cun[eth]e); p. p. c[=u][eth] (for cun[eth]); akin to
         OS. Kunnan, D. Kunnen, OHG. chunnan, G. k["o]nnen,
         Icel. kunna, Goth. Kunnan, and E. ken to know. The
         present tense I can (AS. ic cann) was originally a
         preterit, meaning I have known or Learned, and hence I
         know, know how. [root]45. See {Ken}, {Know}; cf. {Con},
         {Cunning}, {Uncouth}.]
   1. To know; to understand. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I can rimes of Rodin Hood.            --Piers
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            I can no Latin, quod she.             --Piers
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let the priest in surplice white,
            That defunctive music can.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be able to do; to have power or influence. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The will of Him who all things can.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            For what, alas, can these my single arms? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            M[ae]c[ae]nas and Agrippa, who can most with
            C[ae]sar.                             --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be able; -- followed by an infinitive without to; as, I
      can go, but do not wish to.

   Syn: {Can but}, {Can not but}. It is an error to use the
        former of these phrases where the sens requires the
        latter. If we say, ``I can but perish if I go,'' ``But''
        means only, and denotes that this is all or the worst
        that can happen. When the apostle Peter said. ``We can
        not but speak of the things which we have seen and
        heard.'' he referred to a moral constraint or necessety
        which rested upon him and his associates; and the
        meaning was, We cannot help speaking, We cannot refrain
        from speaking. This idea of a moral necessity or
        constraint is of frequent occurrence, and is also
        expressed in the phrase, ``I can not help it.'' Thus we
        say. ``I can not but hope,'' ``I can not but believe,''
        ``I can not but think,'' ``I can not but remark,'' etc.,
        in cases in which it would be an error to use the phrase
        can but.
        [1913 Webster]

              Yet he could not but acknowledge to himself that
              there was something calculated to impress awe, . .
              . in the sudden appearances and vanishings . . .
              of the masque                       --De Quincey.
        [1913 Webster]

              Tom felt that this was a rebuff for him, and could
              not but understand it as a left-handed hit at his
              employer.                           --Dickens.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
