<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>county</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>county</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>County \Coun"ty\ (koun"t[y^]), n.; pl. {Counties} (-t[i^]z). [F.
   comt['e], fr. LL. comitatus. See {Count}.]
   1. An earldom; the domain of a count or earl. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A circuit or particular portion of a state or kingdom,
      separated from the rest of the territory, for certain
      purposes in the administration of justice and public
      affairs; -- called also a {shire}. See {Shire}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every county, every town, every family, was in
            agitation.                            --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A count; an earl or lord. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {County commissioners}. See {Commissioner}.

   {County corporate}, a city or town having the privilege to be
      a county by itself, and to be governed by its own sheriffs
      and other magistrates, irrespective of the officers of the
      county in which it is situated; as London, York, Bristol,
      etc. [Eng.] --Mozley &amp; W.

   {County court}, a court whose jurisdiction is limited to
      county.

   {County palatine}, a county distinguished by particular
      privileges; -- so called a palatio (from the palace),
      because the owner had originally royal powers, or the same
      powers, in the administration of justice, as the king had
      in his palace; but these powers are now abridged. The
      counties palatine, in England, are Lancaster, Chester, and
      Durham.

   {County rates}, rates levied upon the county, and collected
      by the boards of guardians, for the purpose of defraying
      the expenses to which counties are liable, such as
      repairing bridges, jails, etc. [Eng.]

   {County seat}, a county town. [U.S.]

   {County sessions}, the general quarter sessions of the peace
      for each county, held four times a year. [Eng.]

   {County town}, the town of a county, where the county
      business is transacted; a shire town.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>county</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>county
     n 1: a region created by territorial division for the purpose of
          local government; "the county has a population of 12,345
          people"
     2: the largest administrative district within a state; "the
        county plans to build a new road"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
