<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>countries</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>countries</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Country \Coun"try\ (k?n"tr?), n.; pl. {Countries} (-tr?z). [F.
   contr['e]e, LL. contrata, fr. L. contra over against, on the
   opposite side. Cf. {Counter}, adv., {Contra}.]
   1. A tract of land; a region; the territory of an independent
      nation; (as distinguished from any other region, and with
      a personal pronoun) the region of one's birth, permanent
      residence, or citizenship.
      [1913 Webster]

            Return unto thy country, and to thy kindred. --Gen.
                                                  xxxxii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            I might have learned this by my last exile,
            that change of countries cannot change my state.
                                                  --Stirling.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many a famous realm
            And country, whereof here needs no account --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Rural regions, as opposed to a city or town.
      [1913 Webster]

            As they walked, on their way into the country.
                                                  --Mark xvi. 12
                                                  (Rev. Ver. ).
      [1913 Webster]

            God made the covatry, and man made the town.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

            Only very great men were in the habit of dividing
            the year between town and country.    --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The inhabitants or people of a state or a region; the
      populace; the public. Hence:
      (a) One's constituents.
      (b) The whole body of the electors of state; as, to
          dissolve Parliament and appeal to the country.
          [1913 Webster]

                All the country in a general voice
                Cried hate upon him.              --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law)
      (a) A jury, as representing the citizens of a country.
      (b) The inhabitants of the district from which a jury is
          drawn.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mining.) The rock through which a vein runs.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Conclusion to the country}. See under {Conclusion}.

   {To put one's self upon the country}, or {To throw one's self
   upon the country}, to appeal to one's constituents; to stand
      trial before a jury.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
