<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>count</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>count</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Count \Count\ (kount), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Counted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Counting}.] [OF. conter, and later (etymological
   spelling) compter, in modern French thus distinguished;
   conter to relate (cf. {Recount}, {Account}), compter to
   count; fr. L. computuare to reckon, compute; com- + putare to
   reckon, settle, order, prune, orig., to clean. See {Pure},
   and cf. {Compute}.]
   1. To tell or name one by one, or by groups, for the purpose
      of ascertaining the whole number of units in a collection;
      to number; to enumerate; to compute; to reckon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who can count the dust of Jacob?      --Num. xxiii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

            In a journey of forty miles, Avaux counted only
            three miserable cabins.               --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To place to an account; to ascribe or impute; to consider
      or esteem as belonging.
      [1913 Webster]

            Abracham believed God, and it was counted unto him
            for righteousness.                    --Rom. iv. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To esteem; to account; to reckon; to think, judge, or
      consider.
      [1913 Webster]

            I count myself in nothing else so happy
            As in a soul remembering my good friends. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To count out}.
      (a) To exclude (one) from consideration; to be assured
          that (one) will not participate or cannot be depended
          upon.
      (b) (House of Commons) To declare adjourned, as a sitting
          of the House, when it is ascertained that a quorum is
          not present.
      (c) To prevent the accession of (a person) to office, by a
          fraudulent return or count of the votes cast; -- said
          of a candidate really elected. [Colloq.]

   Syn: To calculate; number; reckon; compute; enumerate. See
        {Calculate}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>count</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Count \Count\, n. [F. conte, fr. L. comes, comitis, associate,
   companion, one of the imperial court or train, properly, one
   who goes with another; com- + ire to go, akin to Skr. i to
   go.]
   A nobleman on the continent of Europe, equal in rank to an
   English earl.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Though the tittle Count has never been introduced into
         Britain, the wives of Earls have, from the earliest
         period of its history, been designated as Countesses.
         --Brande &amp; C.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Count palatine}.
   (a) Formerly, the proprietor of a county who possessed royal
       prerogatives within his county, as did the Earl of
       Chester, the Bishop of Durham, and the Duke of Lancaster.
       [Eng.] See {County palatine}, under {County}.
   (b) Originally, a high judicial officer of the German
       emperors; afterward, the holder of a fief, to whom was
       granted the right to exercise certain imperial powers
       within his own domains. [Germany]
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>count</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Count \Count\, n. [F. conte and compte, with different meanings,
   fr. L. computus a computation, fr. computare. See {Count}, v.
   t.]
   1. The act of numbering; reckoning; also, the number
      ascertained by counting.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of blessed saints for to increase the count.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            By this count, I shall be much in years. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An object of interest or account; value; estimation.
      [Obs.] ``All his care and count.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) A formal statement of the plaintiff's case in court;
      in a more technical and correct sense, a particular
      allegation or charge in a declaration or indictment,
      separately setting forth the cause of action or
      prosecution. --Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the old law books, count was used synonymously with
         declaration. When the plaintiff has but a single cause
         of action, and makes but one statement of it, that
         statement is called indifferently count or declaration,
         most generally, however, the latter. But where the suit
         embraces several causes, or the plaintiff makes several
         different statements of the same cause of action, each
         statement is called a count, and all of them combined,
         a declaration. --Bouvier. Wharton.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>count</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Count \Count\, v. i.
   1. To number or be counted; to possess value or carry weight;
      hence, to increase or add to the strength or influence of
      some party or interest; as, every vote counts; accidents
      count for nothing.
      [1913 Webster]

            This excellent man . . . counted among the best and
            wisest of English statesmen.          --J. A.
                                                  Symonds.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To reckon; to rely; to depend; -- with on or upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was brewer to the palace; and it was apprehended
            that the government counted on his voice.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            I think it a great error to count upon the genius of
            a nation as a standing argument in all ages.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To take account or note; -- with of. [Obs.] ``No man
      counts of her beauty.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Eng. Law) To plead orally; to argue a matter in court; to
      recite a count. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>count</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>count
     n 1: the total number counted; "a blood count"
     2: the act of counting; "the counting continued for several
        hours" [syn: {counting}, {numeration}, {enumeration}, {reckoning},
         {tally}]
     3: a nobleman (in various countries) having rank equal to a
        British earl
     v 1: determine the number or amount of; "Can you count the books
          on your shelf?"; "Count your change" [syn: {number}, {enumerate},
           {numerate}]
     2: have weight; have import, carry weight; "It does not matter
        much" [syn: {matter}, {weigh}]
     3: show consideration for; take into account; "You must
        consider her age"; "The judge considered the offender's
        youth and was lenient" [syn: {consider}, {weigh}]
     4: name or recite the numbers; "The toddler could count to 100"
     5: put into a group; "The academy counts several Nobel Prize
        winners among its members" [syn: {number}]
     6: include as if by counting; "I can count my colleagues in the
        opposition"
     7: have faith or confidence in; "you can count on me to help
        you any time"; "Look to your friends for support"; "You
        can bet on that!"; "Depend on your family in times of
        crisis" [syn: {bet}, {depend}, {look}, {calculate}, {reckon}]
     8: take account of; "You have to reckon with our opponents";
        "Count on the monsoon" [syn: {reckon}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
