<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>counted</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>counted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>counted
     
        &lt;mathematics&gt; A term describing a {set} with an explicit
        {isomorphism} to the {natural numbers}.
     
        Compare: {countable}.
     
        (1995-04-13)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>counted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Count \Count\ (kount), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Counted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Counting}.] [OF. conter, and later (etymological
   spelling) compter, in modern French thus distinguished;
   conter to relate (cf. {Recount}, {Account}), compter to
   count; fr. L. computuare to reckon, compute; com- + putare to
   reckon, settle, order, prune, orig., to clean. See {Pure},
   and cf. {Compute}.]
   1. To tell or name one by one, or by groups, for the purpose
      of ascertaining the whole number of units in a collection;
      to number; to enumerate; to compute; to reckon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who can count the dust of Jacob?      --Num. xxiii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

            In a journey of forty miles, Avaux counted only
            three miserable cabins.               --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To place to an account; to ascribe or impute; to consider
      or esteem as belonging.
      [1913 Webster]

            Abracham believed God, and it was counted unto him
            for righteousness.                    --Rom. iv. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To esteem; to account; to reckon; to think, judge, or
      consider.
      [1913 Webster]

            I count myself in nothing else so happy
            As in a soul remembering my good friends. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To count out}.
      (a) To exclude (one) from consideration; to be assured
          that (one) will not participate or cannot be depended
          upon.
      (b) (House of Commons) To declare adjourned, as a sitting
          of the House, when it is ascertained that a quorum is
          not present.
      (c) To prevent the accession of (a person) to office, by a
          fraudulent return or count of the votes cast; -- said
          of a candidate really elected. [Colloq.]

   Syn: To calculate; number; reckon; compute; enumerate. See
        {Calculate}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
