<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>courage</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>courage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Courage \Cour"age\ (k[u^]r"[asl]j; 48), n. [OE. corage heart,
   mind, will, courage, OF. corage, F. courage, fr. a LL.
   derivative of L. cor heart. See {Heart}.]
   1. The heart; spirit; temper; disposition. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            So priketh hem nature in here corages. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            My lord, cheer up your spirits; our foes are nigh,
            and this soft courage makes your followers faint.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Heart; inclination; desire; will. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'd such a courage to do him good.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That quality of mind which enables one to encounter danger
      and difficulties with firmness, or without fear, or
      fainting of heart; valor; boldness; resolution.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king-becoming graces . . .
            Devotion, patience, courage, fortitude,
            I have no relish of them.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Courage that grows from constitution often forsakes
            a man when he has occasion for it.    --Addison.

   Syn: Heroism; bravery; intrepidity; valor; gallantry; daring;
        firmness; hardihood; boldness; dauntlessness;
        resolution.

   Usage: See {Heroism}. -- {Courage}, {Bravery}, {Fortitude},
          {Intrepidity}, {Gallantry}, {Valor}. Courage is that
          firmness of spirit and swell of soul which meets
          danger without fear. Bravery is daring and impetuous
          courage, like that of one who has the reward
          continually in view, and displays his courage in
          daring acts. Fortitude has often been styled ``passive
          courage,'' and consist in the habit of encountering
          danger and enduring pain with a steadfast and unbroken
          spirit. Valor is courage exhibited in war, and can not
          be applied to single combats; it is never used
          figuratively. Intrepidity is firm, unshaken courage.
          Gallantry is adventurous courage, which courts danger
          with a high and cheerful spirit. A man may show
          courage, fortitude, or intrepidity in the common
          pursuits of life, as well as in war. Valor, bravery,
          and gallantry are displayed in the contest of arms.
          Valor belongs only to battle; bravery may be shown in
          single combat; gallantry may be manifested either in
          attack or defense; but in the latter case, the defense
          is usually turned into an attack.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>courage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Courage \Cour"age\, v. t.
   To inspire with courage; to encourage. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Paul writeth unto Timothy . . . to courage him.
                                                  --Tyndale.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>courage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>courage
     n : a quality of spirit that enables you to face danger of pain
         without showing fear [syn: {courageousness}, {bravery}]
         [ant: {cowardice}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
