<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>course</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>course</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Course \Course\ (k[=o]rs), n. [F. cours, course, L. cursus, fr.
   currere to run. See {Current}.]
   1. The act of moving from one point to another; progress;
      passage.
      [1913 Webster]

            And when we had finished our course from Tyre, we
            came to Ptolemais.                    --Acts xxi. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The ground or path traversed; track; way.
      [1913 Webster]

            The same horse also run the round course at
            Newmarket.                            --Pennant.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Motion, considered as to its general or resultant
      direction or to its goal; line progress or advance.
      [1913 Webster]

            A light by which the Argive squadron steers
            Their silent course to Ilium's well known shore.
                                                  --Dennham.
      [1913 Webster]

            Westward the course of empire takes its way.
                                                  --Berkeley.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Progress from point to point without change of direction;
      any part of a progress from one place to another, which is
      in a straight line, or on one direction; as, a ship in a
      long voyage makes many courses; a course measured by a
      surveyor between two stations; also, a progress without
      interruption or rest; a heat; as, one course of a race.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Motion considered with reference to manner; or derly
      progress; procedure in a certain line of thought or
      action; as, the course of an argument.
      [1913 Webster]

            The course of true love never did run smooth.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Customary or established sequence of events; recurrence of
      events according to natural laws.
      [1913 Webster]

            By course of nature and of law.       --Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

            Day and night,
            Seedtime and harvest, heat and hoary frost,
            Shall hold their course.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Method of procedure; manner or way of conducting; conduct;
      behavior.
      [1913 Webster]

            My lord of York commends the plot and the general
            course of the action.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            By perseverance in the course prescribed.
                                                  --Wodsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

            You hold your course without remorse. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A series of motions or acts arranged in order; a
      succession of acts or practices connectedly followed; as,
      a course of medicine; a course of lectures on chemistry.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The succession of one to another in office or duty; order;
      turn.
      [1913 Webster]

            He appointed . . . the courses of the priests --2
                                                  Chron. viii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. That part of a meal served at one time, with its
       accompaniments.
       [1913 Webster]

             He [Goldsmith] wore fine clothes, gave dinners of
             several courses, paid court to venal beauties.
                                                  --Macaulay.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Arch.) A continuous level range of brick or stones of
       the same height throughout the face or faces of a
       building. --Gwilt.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Naut.) The lowest sail on any mast of a square-rigged
       vessel; as, the fore course, main course, etc.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. pl. (Physiol.) The menses.
       [1913 Webster]

   {In course}, in regular succession.

   {Of course}, by consequence; as a matter of course; in
      regular or natural order.

   {In the course of}, at same time or times during. ``In the
      course of human events.'' --T. Jefferson.

   Syn: Way; road; route; passage; race; series; succession;
        manner; method; mode; career; progress.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>course</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Course \Course\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Coursed} (k?rst)); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Coursing}.]
   1. To run, hunt, or chase after; to follow hard upon; to
      pursue.
      [1913 Webster]

            We coursed him at the heels.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to chase after or pursue game; as, to course
      greyhounds after deer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To run through or over.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bounding steed courses the dusty plain. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>course</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Course \Course\, v. i.
   1. To run as in a race, or in hunting; to pursue the sport of
      coursing; as, the sportsmen coursed over the flats of
      Lancashire.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move with speed; to race; as, the blood courses through
      the veins. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>course</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>course
     n 1: education imparted in a series of lessons or class meetings;
          "he took a course in basket weaving"; "flirting is not
          unknown in college classes" [syn: {course of study}, {course
          of instruction}, {class}]
     2: a connected series of events or actions or developments;
        "the government took a firm course"; "historians can only
        point out those lines for which evidence is available"
        [syn: {line}]
     3: facility consisting of a circumscribed area of land or water
        laid out for a sport; "the course had only nine holes";
        "the course was less than a mile"
     4: a mode of action; "if you persist in that course you will
        surely fail"; "once a nation is embarked on a course of
        action it becomes extremely difficult for any retraction
        to take place" [syn: {course of action}]
     5: a line or route along which something travels or moves; "the
        hurricane demolished houses in its path"; "the track of an
        animal"; "the course of the river" [syn: {path}, {track}]
     6: general line of orientation; "the river takes a southern
        course"; "the northeastern trend of the coast" [syn: {trend}]
     7: part of a meal served at one time; "she prepared a three
        course meal"
     8: (construction) a layer of masonry; "a course of bricks"
        [syn: {row}]
     adv : as might be expected; "naturally, the lawyer sent us a huge
           bill" [syn: {naturally}, {of course}] [ant: {unnaturally}]
     v 1: move swiftly through or over; "ships coursing the Atlantic"
     2: move along, of liquids; "Water flowed into the cave"; "the
        Missouri feeds into the Mississippi" [syn: {run}, {flow},
        {feed}]
     3: hunt with hounds; "He often courses hares"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
