<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>covered</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covered</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cover \Cov"er\ (k?v"?r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Covered} (-?rd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Covering}.] [OF. covrir, F. couvrir, fr. L.
   cooperire; co- + operire to cover; probably fr. ob towards,
   over + the root appearing in aperire to open. Cf. {Aperient},
   {Overt}, {Curfew}.]
   1. To overspread the surface of (one thing) with another; as,
      to cover wood with paint or lacquer; to cover a table with
      a cloth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To envelop; to clothe, as with a mantle or cloak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And with the majesty of darkness round
            Covers his throne.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            All that beauty than doth cover thee. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To invest (one's self with something); to bring upon
      (one's self); as, he covered himself with glory.
      [1913 Webster]

            The powers that covered themselves with everlasting
            infamy by the partition of Poland.    --Brougham.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To hide sight; to conceal; to cloak; as, the enemy were
      covered from our sight by the woods.
      [1913 Webster]

            A cloud covered the mount.            --Exod. xxiv.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

            In vain shou striv'st to cover shame with shame.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To brood or sit on; to incubate.
      [1913 Webster]

            While the hen is covering her eggs, the male . . .
            diverts her with his songs.           --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To overwhelm; to spread over.
      [1913 Webster]

            The waters returned and covered the chariots and the
            horsemen.                             --Ex. xiv. 28.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To shelter, as from evil or danger; to protect; to defend;
      as, the cavalry covered the retreat.
      [1913 Webster]

            His calm and blameless life
            Does with substantial blessedness abound,
            And the soft wings of peace cover him round.
                                                  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To remove from remembrance; to put away; to remit.
      ``Blessed is he whose is covered.'' --Ps. xxxii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To extend over; to be sufficient for; to comprehend,
      include, or embrace; to account for or solve; to
      counterbalance; as, a mortgage which fully covers a sum
      loaned on it; a law which covers all possible cases of a
      crime; receipts than do not cover expenses.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To put the usual covering or headdress on.
       [1913 Webster]

             Cover thy head . . .; nay, prithee, be covered.
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To copulate with (a female); to serve; as, a horse covers
       a mare; -- said of the male.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To cover ground} or {To cover distance}, to pass over; as,
      the rider covered the ground in an hour.

   {To cover one's short contracts} (Stock Exchange), to buy
      stock when the market rises, as a dealer who has sold
      short does in order to protect himself.

   {Covering party} (Mil.), a detachment of troops sent for the
      protection of another detachment, as of men working in the
      trenches.

   {To cover into}, to transfer to; as, to cover into the
      treasury.

   Syn: To shelter; screen; shield; hide; overspread.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covered</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Covered \Cov"ered\ (k?v"?rd), a.
   Under cover; screened; sheltered; not exposed; hidden.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Covered way} (Fort.), a corridor or banquette along the top
      of the counterscarp and covered by an embankment whose
      slope forms the glacis. It gives the garrison an open line
      of communication around the works, and a standing place
      beyond the ditch. See Illust. of {Ravelin}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covered</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Covet \Cov"et\ (k?v"?t), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Covered}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Coveting}.] [OF. coveitier, covoitier, F. convoiter,
   from a derivative fr. L. cupere to desire; cf. Skr. kup to
   become excited. Cf. {Cupidity}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To wish for with eagerness; to desire possession of; --
      used in a good sense.
      [1913 Webster]

            Covet earnestly the best gifts.       --1. Cor.
                                                  xxii. 31.
      [1913 Webster]

            If it be a sin to covet honor,
            I am the most offending soul alive.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To long for inordinately or unlawfully; to hanker after
      (something forbidden).
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's house. --Ex. xx.
                                                  17.

   Syn: To long for; desire; hanker after; crave.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covered</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>covered
     adj 1: overlaid or spread or topped with or enclosed within
            something; sometimes used as a combining form; "women
            with covered faces"; "covered wagons"; "a covered
            balcony" [ant: {uncovered}]
     2: having the head and face covered; "the bride's veiled head";
        "veiled Muslim women"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
