<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>covenant</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covenant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Covenant
   a contract or agreement between two parties. In the Old
   Testament the Hebrew word _berith_ is always thus translated.
   _Berith_ is derived from a root which means "to cut," and hence
   a covenant is a "cutting," with reference to the cutting or
   dividing of animals into two parts, and the contracting parties
   passing between them, in making a covenant (Gen. 15; Jer. 34:18,
   19).
   
     The corresponding word in the New Testament Greek is
   _diatheke_, which is, however, rendered "testament" generally in
   the Authorized Version. It ought to be rendered, just as the
   word _berith_ of the Old Testament, "covenant."
   
     This word is used (1) of a covenant or compact between man and
   man (Gen. 21:32), or between tribes or nations (1 Sam. 11:1;
   Josh. 9:6, 15). In entering into a convenant, Jehovah was
   solemnly called on to witness the transaction (Gen. 31:50), and
   hence it was called a "covenant of the Lord" (1 Sam. 20:8). The
   marriage compact is called "the covenant of God" (Prov. 2:17),
   because the marriage was made in God's name. Wicked men are
   spoken of as acting as if they had made a "covenant with death"
   not to destroy them, or with hell not to devour them (Isa.
   28:15, 18).
   
     (2.) The word is used with reference to God's revelation of
   himself in the way of promise or of favour to men. Thus God's
   promise to Noah after the Flood is called a covenant (Gen. 9;
   Jer. 33:20, "my covenant"). We have an account of God's
   covernant with Abraham (Gen. 17, comp. Lev. 26:42), of the
   covenant of the priesthood (Num. 25:12, 13; Deut. 33:9; Neh.
   13:29), and of the covenant of Sinai (Ex. 34:27, 28; Lev.
   26:15), which was afterwards renewed at different times in the
   history of Israel (Deut. 29; Josh. 1:24; 2 Chr. 15; 23; 29; 34;
   Ezra 10; Neh. 9). In conformity with human custom, God's
   covenant is said to be confirmed with an oath (Deut. 4:31; Ps.
   89:3), and to be accompanied by a sign (Gen. 9; 17). Hence the
   covenant is called God's "counsel," "oath," "promise" (Ps. 89:3,
   4; 105:8-11; Heb. 6:13-20; Luke 1:68-75). God's covenant
   consists wholly in the bestowal of blessing (Isa. 59:21; Jer.
   31:33, 34).
   
     The term covenant is also used to designate the regular
   succession of day and night (Jer. 33:20), the Sabbath (Ex.
   31:16), circumcision (Gen. 17:9, 10), and in general any
   ordinance of God (Jer. 34:13, 14).
   
     A "covenant of salt" signifies an everlasting covenant, in the
   sealing or ratifying of which salt, as an emblem of perpetuity,
   is used (Num. 18:19; Lev. 2:13; 2 Chr. 13:5).
   
     COVENANT OF WORKS, the constitution under which Adam was
   placed at his creation. In this covenant, (1.) The contracting
   parties were (a) God the moral Governor, and (b) Adam, a free
   moral agent, and representative of all his natural posterity
   (Rom. 5:12-19). (2.) The promise was "life" (Matt. 19:16, 17;
   Gal. 3:12). (3.) The condition was perfect obedience to the law,
   the test in this case being abstaining from eating the fruit of
   the "tree of knowledge," etc. (4.) The penalty was death (Gen.
   2:16, 17).
   
     This covenant is also called a covenant of nature, as made
   with man in his natural or unfallen state; a covenant of life,
   because "life" was the promise attached to obedience; and a
   legal covenant, because it demanded perfect obedience to the
   law.
   
     The "tree of life" was the outward sign and seal of that life
   which was promised in the covenant, and hence it is usually
   called the seal of that covenant.
   
     This covenant is abrogated under the gospel, inasmuch as
   Christ has fulfilled all its conditions in behalf of his people,
   and now offers salvation on the condition of faith. It is still
   in force, however, as it rests on the immutable justice of God,
   and is binding on all who have not fled to Christ and accepted
   his righteousness.
   
     CONVENANT OF GRACE, the eternal plan of redemption entered
   into by the three persons of the Godhead, and carried out by
   them in its several parts. In it the Father represented the
   Godhead in its indivisible sovereignty, and the Son his people
   as their surety (John 17:4, 6, 9; Isa. 42:6; Ps. 89:3).
   
     The conditions of this covenant were, (1.) On the part of the
   Father (a) all needful preparation to the Son for the
   accomplishment of his work (Heb. 10:5; Isa. 42:1-7); (b) support
   in the work (Luke 22:43); and (c) a glorious reward in the
   exaltation of Christ when his work was done (Phil. 2:6-11), his
   investiture with universal dominion (John 5:22; Ps. 110:1), his
   having the administration of the covenant committed into his
   hands (Matt. 28:18; John 1:12; 17:2; Acts 2:33), and in the
   final salvation of all his people (Isa. 35:10; 53:10, 11; Jer.
   31:33; Titus 1:2). (2.) On the part of the Son the conditions
   were (a) his becoming incarnate (Gal. 4:4, 5); and (b) as the
   second Adam his representing all his people, assuming their
   place and undertaking all their obligations under the violated
   covenant of works; (c) obeying the law (Ps. 40:8; Isa. 42:21;
   John 9:4, 5), and (d) suffering its penalty (Isa. 53; 2 Cor.
   5:21; Gal. 3:13), in their stead.
   
     Christ, the mediator of, fulfils all its conditions in behalf
   of his people, and dispenses to them all its blessings. In Heb.
   8:6; 9:15; 12:24, this title is given to Christ. (See {DISPENSATION}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covenant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Covenant \Cov"e*nant\ (k?v"?-nant), n. [OF. covenant, fr. F. &amp;
   OF. convenir to agree, L. convenire. See {Convene}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A mutual agreement of two or more persons or parties, or
      one of the stipulations in such an agreement.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then Jonathan and David made a covenant. --1 Sam.
                                                  xviiii. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let there be covenants drawn between us. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If we conclude a peace,
            It shall be with such strict and severe covenants
            As little shall the Frenchmen gain thereby. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Eccl. Hist.) An agreement made by the Scottish Parliament
      in 1638, and by the English Parliament in 1643, to
      preserve the reformed religion in Scotland, and to
      extirpate popery and prelacy; -- usually called the
      ``Solemn League and Covenant.''
      [1913 Webster]

            He [Wharton] was born in the days of the Covenant,
            and was the heir of a covenanted house. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Theol.) The promises of God as revealed in the
      Scriptures, conditioned on certain terms on the part of
      man, as obedience, repentance, faith, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will establish my covenant between me and thee and
            thy seed after thee in their generations for an
            everlasting covenant, to be a God unto thee, and to
            thy seed after thee.                  --Gen. xvii.
                                                  7.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A solemn compact between members of a church to maintain
      its faith, discipline, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law)
      (a) An undertaking, on sufficient consideration, in
          writing and under seal, to do or to refrain from some
          act or thing; a contract; a stipulation; also, the
          document or writing containing the terms of agreement.
      (b) A form of action for the violation of a promise or
          contract under seal.

   Syn: Agreement; contract; compact; bargain; arrangement;
        stipulation.

   Usage: {Covenant}, {Contract}, {Compact}, {Stipulation}.
          These words all denote a mutual agreement between two
          parties. Covenant is frequently used in a religious
          sense; as, the covenant of works or of grace; a church
          covenant; the Solemn League and Covenant. Contract is
          the word most used in the business of life. Crabb and
          Taylor are wrong in saying that a contract must always
          be in writing. There are oral and implied contracts as
          well as written ones, and these are equally enforced
          by law. In legal usage, the word covenant has an
          important place as connected with contracts. A compact
          is only a stronger and more solemn contract. The term
          is chiefly applied to political alliances. Thus, the
          old Confederation was a compact between the States.
          Under the present Federal Constitution, no individual
          State can, without consent of Congress, enter into a
          compact with any other State or foreign power. A
          stipulation is one of the articles or provisions of a
          contract.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covenant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Covenant \Cov"e*nant\, v. t.
   To grant or promise by covenant.
   [1913 Webster]

         My covenant of peace that I covenanted with you.
                                                  --Wyclif.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covenant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Covenant \Cov"e*nant\ (k?v"?-n?nt), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Covenanted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Covenanting}.]
   To agree (with); to enter into a formal agreement; to bind
   one's self by contract; to make a stipulation.
   [1913 Webster]

         Jupiter covenanted with him, that it should be hot or
         cold, wet or dry, . . . as the tenant should direct.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
   [1913 Webster]

         And they covenanted with him for thyrty pieces of
         silver.                                  --Matt. xxvi.
                                                  15.

   Syn: To agree; contract; bargain; stipulate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>covenant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>covenant
     n 1: a signed written agreement between two or more parties
          (nations) to perform some action [syn: {compact}, {concordat}]
     2: (Bible) an agreement between God and his people in which God
        makes certain promises and requires certain behavior from
        them in return
     v 1: enter into a covenenant
     2: enter into a covenant or formal agreement; "They covenanted
        with Judas for 30 pieces of silver"; "The nations
        covenanted to fight terrorism around the world"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
