<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>crack</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crack \Crack\, n.
   1. A partial separation of parts, with or without a
      perceptible opening; a chink or fissure; a narrow breach;
      a crevice; as, a crack in timber, or in a wall, or in
      glass.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Rupture; flaw; breach, in a moral sense.
      [1913 Webster]

            My love to thee is sound, sans crack or flaw.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sharp, sudden sound or report; the sound of anything
      suddenly burst or broken; as, the crack of a falling
      house; the crack of thunder; the crack of a whip.
      [1913 Webster]

            Will the stretch out to the crack of doom? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The tone of voice when changed at puberty.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though now our voices
            Have got the mannish crack.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Mental flaw; a touch of craziness; partial insanity; as,
      he has a crack.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A crazy or crack-brained person. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I . . . can not get the Parliament to listen to me,
            who look upon me as a crack and a projector.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A boast; boasting. [Obs.] ``Crack and brags.'' --Burton.
      ``Vainglorius cracks.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Breach of chastity. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A boy, generally a pert, lively boy. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Val. 'T is a noble child. Vir. A crack, madam.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A brief time; an instant; as, to be with one in a crack.
       [Eng. &amp; Scot. Colloq.]
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Free conversation; friendly chat. [Scot.]
       [1913 Webster]

             What is crack in English? . . . A crack is . . . a
             chat with a good, kindly human heart in it. --P. P.
                                                  Alexander.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. a witty remark; a wisecrack.
       [PJC]

   13. a chance or opportunity to do something; an attempt; as,
       I'll take a crack at it.
       [PJC]

   14. a form of cocaine, highly purified and prepared as small
       pellets, especially suitable for smoking; -- also called
       {rock}. Used in this form it appears to be more addicting
       than cocaine powder. [slang]
       [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crack \Crack\, v. i.
   1. To burst or open in chinks; to break, with or without
      quite separating into parts.
      [1913 Webster]

            By misfortune it cracked in the coling. --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mirror cracked from side to side. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be ruined or impaired; to fail. [Collog.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The credit . . . of exchequers cracks, when little
            comes in and much goes out.           --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To utter a loud or sharp, sudden sound.
      [1913 Webster]

            As thunder when the clouds in autumn crack. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To utter vain, pompous words; to brag; to boast; -- with
      of. [Archaic.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Ethoipes of their sweet complexion crack. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crack \Crack\ (kr[a^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cracked}
   (kr[a^]kt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Cracking}.] [OE. cracken,
   craken, to crack, break, boast, AS. cracian, cearcian, to
   crack; akin to D. kraken, G. krachen; cf. Skr. garj to
   rattle, or perh. of imitative origin. Cf. {Crake},
   {Cracknel}, {Creak}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To break or burst, with or without entire separation of
      the parts; as, to crack glass; to crack nuts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To rend with grief or pain; to affect deeply with sorrow;
      hence, to disorder; to distract; to craze.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, madam, my old heart is cracked.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He thought none poets till their brains were
            cracked.                              --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to sound suddenly and sharply; to snap; as, to
      crack a whip.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To utter smartly and sententiously; as, to crack a joke.
      --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cry up; to extol; -- followed by up. [Low]
      [1913 Webster]

   {To crack a bottle}, to open the bottle and drink its
      contents.

   {To crack a crib}, to commit burglary. [Slang]

   {To crack on}, to put on; as, to crack on more sail, or more
      steam. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crack \Crack\, a.
   Of superior excellence; having qualities to be boasted of;
   as, a crack shot. [Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]

         One of our crack speakers in the Commons. --Dickens.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cocaine \Co"ca*ine\, n. (Chem.)
   A powerful narcotic alkaloid, {C17H21NO4}, obtained from the
   leaves of coca. It is a bitter, white, crystalline substance,
   and is remarkable for producing local insensibility to pain.
   It is classified as addictive and is not available in the U.
   S. without a prescription, but is nevertheless one of the
   most widespread illegal drugs of abuse. It is used in several
   forms, including small pellets of free base, called {crack}.
   Most of the cacaine illegally used in the U.S. is imported.
   [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crack [warez d00dz] 1. v. To break into a system (compare {cracker}).
   2. v. Action of removing the copy protection from a commercial program.
   People who write cracks consider themselves challenged by the copy
   protection measures. They will often do it as much to show that they are
   smarter than the developer who designed the copy protection scheme than
   to actually copy the program. 3. n. A program, instructions or patch
   used to remove the copy protection of a program or to uncripple features
   from a demo/time limited program. 4. An {exploit}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crack
     adj : of the highest quality; "an ace reporter"; "a crack shot";
           "a first-rate golfer"; "a super party"; "played
           top-notch tennis"; "an athlete in tiptop condition";
           "she is absolutely tops" [syn: {ace}, {A-one}, {first-rate},
            {super}, {tiptop}, {topnotch}, {tops(p)}]
     n 1: a long narrow opening [syn: {cleft}, {crevice}, {fissure}, {scissure}]
     2: a narrow opening; "he opened the window a crack" [syn: {gap}]
     3: a long narrow depression in a surface [syn: {crevice}, {cranny},
         {fissure}, {chap}]
     4: a sudden sharp noise; "the crack of a whip"; "he heard the
        cracking of the ice"; "he can hear the snap of a twig"
        [syn: {cracking}, {snap}]
     5: a chance to do something; "he wanted a shot at the champion"
        [syn: {shot}]
     6: witty remark [syn: {wisecrack}, {sally}, {quip}]
     7: a blemish resulting from a break without complete separation
        of the parts; "there was a crack in the mirror"
     8: a purified and potent form of cocaine that is smoked rather
        than snorted [syn: {tornado}]
     9: a usually brief attempt; "he took a crack at it"; "I gave it
        a whirl" [syn: {fling}, {go}, {pass}, {whirl}, {offer}]
     10: the act of cracking something [syn: {fracture}, {cracking}]
     v 1: become fractured; break or crack on the surface only; "The
          glass cracked when it was heated" [syn: {check}, {break}]
     2: make a very sharp explosive sound; "His gun cracked"
     3: make a sharp sound; "his fingers snapped" [syn: {snap}]
     4: hit forcefully; deal a hard blow, making a cracking noise;
        "The teacher cracked him across the face with a ruler"
     5: pass through (a barrier); "Registrations cracked through the
        30,000 mark in the county" [syn: {break through}]
     6: break partially but keep its integrity; "The glass cracked"
     7: break suddenly and abruptly, as under tension; "The rope
        snapped" [syn: {snap}]
     8: suffer a nervous breakdown [syn: {crack up}, {crock up}, {break
        up}, {collapse}]
     9: tell spontaneously; "crack a joke"
     10: cause to become cracked; "heat and light cracked the back of
         the leather chair"
     11: reduce (petroleum) to a simpler compound by cracking
     12: break into simpler molecules by means of heat; "The
         petroleum cracked"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
