<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cramp</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cramp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cramp \Cramp\ (kr[a^]mp), n. [OE. crampe, craumpe; akin to D. &amp;
   Sw. kramp, Dan. krampe, G. krampf (whence F. crampe), Icel.
   krappr strait, narrow, and to E. crimp, crumple; cf. cram.
   See {Grape}.]
   1. That which confines or contracts; a restraint; a shackle;
      a hindrance.
      [1913 Webster]

            A narrow fortune is a cramp to a great mind.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            Crippling his pleasures with the cramp of fear.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Masonry) A device, usually of iron bent at the ends, used
      to hold together blocks of stone, timbers, etc.; a cramp
      iron.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Carp.) A rectangular frame, with a tightening screw, used
      for compressing the joints of framework, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A piece of wood having a curve corresponding to that of
      the upper part of the instep, on which the upper leather
      of a boot is stretched to give it the requisite shape.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Med.) A spasmodic and painful involuntary contraction of
      a muscle or muscles, as of the leg.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cramp, divers nights, gripeth him in his legs.
                                                  --Sir T. More.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Med.) A paralysis of certain muscles due to excessive
      use; as, writer's cramp; milker's cramp, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Cramp bone}, the patella of a sheep; -- formerly used as a
      charm for the cramp. --Halliwell. ``He could turn cramp
      bones into chess men.'' --Dickens.

   {Cramp ring}, a ring formerly supposed to have virtue in
      averting or curing cramp, as having been consecrated by
      one of the kings of England on Good Friday.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cramp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cramp \Cramp\, a. [See {Cramp}, n.]
   Knotty; difficult. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Care being taken not to add any of the cramp reasons
         for this opinion.                        --Coleridge.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cramp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cramp \Cramp\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cramped} (kr[a^]mt; 215); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Cramping}.]
   1. To compress; to restrain from free action; to confine and
      contract; to hinder.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mind my be as much cramped by too much knowledge
            as by ignorance.                      --Layard.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fasten or hold with, or as with, a cramp.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, to bind together; to unite.
      [1913 Webster]

            The . . . fabric of universal justic is well cramped
            and bolted together in all its parts. --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To form on a cramp; as, to cramp boot legs.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To afflict with cramp.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the gout cramps my joints.       --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To cramp the wheels of wagon}, to turn the front wheels out
      of line with the hind wheels, so that one of them shall be
      against the body of the wagon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cramp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cramp
     n 1: a painful and involuntary muscular contraction [syn: {spasm},
           {muscle spasm}]
     2: a clamp for holding pieces of wood together while they are
        glued
     3: a strip of metal with ends bent at right angles; used to
        hold masonry together [syn: {cramp iron}]
     v 1: secure with a cramp; "cramp the wood"
     2: prevent the progress or free movement of; "He was hampered
        in his efforts by the bad weather"; "the imperilist nation
        wanted to strangle the free trade between the two small
        countries" [syn: {hamper}, {halter}, {strangle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
