<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>creation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>creation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Creation
   "In the beginning" God created, i.e., called into being, all
   things out of nothing. This creative act on the part of God was
   absolutely free, and for infinitely wise reasons. The cause of
   all things exists only in the will of God. The work of creation
   is attributed (1) to the Godhead (Gen. 1:1, 26); (2) to the
   Father (1 Cor. 8:6); (3) to the Son (John 1:3; Col. 1:16, 17);
   (4) to the Holy Spirit (Gen. 1:2; Job 26:13; Ps. 104:30). The
   fact that he is the Creator distinguishes Jehovah as the true
   God (Isa. 37:16; 40:12, 13; 54:5; Ps. 96:5; Jer. 10:11, 12). The
   one great end in the work of creation is the manifestation of
   the glory of the Creator (Col. 1:16; Rev. 4:11; Rom. 11:36).
   God's works, equally with God's word, are a revelation from him;
   and between the teachings of the one and those of the other,
   when rightly understood, there can be no contradiction.
   
     Traditions of the creation, disfigured by corruptions, are
   found among the records of ancient Eastern nations. (See {ACCAD}.) A peculiar interest belongs to the traditions of the
   Accadians, the primitive inhabitants of the plains of Lower
   Mesopotamia. These within the last few years have been brought
   to light in the tablets and cylinders which have been rescued
   from the long-buried palaces and temples of Assyria. They bear a
   remarkable resemblance to the record of Genesis.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>creation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Creation \Cre*a"tion\ (kr?-A"sh?n), n. [L. creatio: cf. F.
   cr?ation. See {Create}.]
   1. The act of creating or causing to exist. Specifically, the
      act of bringing the universe or this world into existence.
      [1913 Webster]

            From the creation to the general doom. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            As when a new particle of matter dotn begin to
            exist, in rerum natura, which had before no being;
            and this we call creation.            --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is created; that which is produced or caused to
      exist, as the world or some original work of art or of the
      imagination; nature.
      [1913 Webster]

            We know that the whole creation groaneth. --Rom.
                                                  viii. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

            A dagger of the mind, a false creation. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Choice pictures and creations of curious art.
                                                  --Beaconsfield.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The act of constituting or investing with a new character;
      appointment; formation.
      [1913 Webster]

            An Irish peer of recent creation.     --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>creation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>creation
     n 1: the human act of creating [syn: {creative activity}]
     2: an artifact that has been brought into existence by someone
     3: the event that occurred at the beginning of something; "from
        its creation the plan was doomed to failure" [syn: {conception}]
     4: the act of starting something for the first time;
        introducing something new; "she looked forward to her
        initiation as an adult"; "the foundation of a new
        scientific society"; "he regards the fork as a modern
        introduction" [syn: {initiation}, {founding}, {foundation},
         {institution}, {origination}, {innovation}, {introduction},
         {instauration}]
     5: (theology) God's act of bringing the universe into existence
     6: everything that exists anywhere; "they study the evolution
        of the universe"; "the biggest tree in existence" [syn: {universe},
         {existence}, {world}, {cosmos}, {macrocosm}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
