<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>credit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>credit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Credit \Cred"it\ (kr[e^]d"[i^]t), n. [F. cr['e]dit (cf. It.
   credito), L. creditum loan, prop. neut. of creditus, p. p. of
   credere to trust, loan, believe. See {Creed}.]
   1. Reliance on the truth of something said or done; belief;
      faith; trust; confidence.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Jonathan and the people heard these words they
            gave no credit unto them, nor received them. --1
                                                  Macc. x. 46.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Reputation derived from the confidence of others; esteem;
      honor; good name; estimation.
      [1913 Webster]

            John Gilpin was a citizen
            Of credit and renown.                 --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A ground of, or title to, belief or confidence; authority
      derived from character or reputation.
      [1913 Webster]

            The things which we properly believe, be only such
            as are received on the credit of divine testimony.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which tends to procure, or add to, reputation or
      esteem; an honor.
      [1913 Webster]

            I published, because I was told I might please such
            as it was a credit to please.         --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Influence derived from the good opinion, confidence, or
      favor of others; interest.
      [1913 Webster]

            Having credit enough with his master to provide for
            his own interest.                     --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Com.) Trust given or received; expectation of future
      playment for property transferred, or of fulfillment or
      promises given; mercantile reputation entitling one to be
      trusted; -- applied to individuals, corporations,
      communities, or nations; as, to buy goods on credit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Credit is nothing but the expectation of money,
            within some limited time.             --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The time given for payment for lands or goods sold on
      trust; as, a long credit or a short credit.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Bookkeeping) The side of an account on which are entered
      all items reckoned as values received from the party or
      the category named at the head of the account; also, any
      one, or the sum, of these items; -- the opposite of
      {debit}; as, this sum is carried to one's credit, and that
      to his debit; A has several credits on the books of B.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bank credit}, or {Cash credit}. See under {Cash}.

   {Bill of credit}. See under {Bill}.

   {Letter of credit}, a letter or notification addressed by a
      banker to his correspondent, informing him that the person
      named therein is entitled to draw a certain sum of money;
      when addressed to several different correspondents, or
      when the money can be drawn in fractional sums in several
      different places, it is called a {circular letter of
      credit}.

   {Public credit}.
      (a) The reputation of, or general confidence in, the
          ability or readiness of a government to fulfill its
          pecuniary engagements.
      (b) The ability and fidelity of merchants or others who
          owe largely in a community.
          [1913 Webster]

                He touched the dead corpse of Public Credit, and
                it sprung upon its feet.          --D. Webster.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>credit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Credit \Cred"it\ (kr[e^]d"[i^]t), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Credited}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Crediting}.]
   1. To confide in the truth of; to give credence to; to put
      trust in; to believe.
      [1913 Webster]

            How shall they credit
            A poor unlearned virgin?              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring honor or repute upon; to do credit to; to raise
      the estimation of.
      [1913 Webster]

            You credit the church as much by your government as
            you did the school formerly by your wit. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bookkeeping) To enter upon the credit side of an account;
      to give credit for; as, to credit the amount paid; to set
      to the credit of; as, to credit a man with the interest
      paid on a bond.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To credit with}, to give credit for; to assign as justly due
      to any one.
      [1913 Webster]

            Crove, Helmholtz, and Meyer, are more than any
            others to be credited with the clear enunciation of
            this doctrine.                        --Newman.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>credit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>credit
     n 1: approval; "give her recognition for trying"; "he was given
          credit for his work"; "give her credit for trying"; "the
          credits were given at the end of the film" [syn: {recognition}]
     2: money available for a client to borrow
     3: an accounting entry acknowledging income or capital items
        [syn: {credit entry}] [ant: {debit}]
     4: used in the phrase `to your credit' in order to indicate an
        achievement deserving praise; "she already had several
        performances to her credit";
     5: arrangement for deferred payment for goods and services
        [syn: {deferred payment}] [ant: {cash}]
     6: recognition by a college or university that a course of
        studies has been successfully completed; typically
        measured in semester hours [syn: {course credit}]
     7: a short note recognizing a source of information or of a
        quoted passage; "the student's essay failed to list
        several important citations"; "the acknowledgments are
        usually printed at the front of a book"; "the article
        includes mention of similar clinical cases" [syn: {citation},
         {acknowledgment}, {reference}, {mention}, {quotation}]
     8: an entry on a list of persons who contributed to a film or
        written work
     v 1: give someone credit for something; "We credited her for
          saving our jobs"
     2: give credit for; "She was not properly credited in the
        program" [syn: {accredit}]
     3: accounting: enter as credit; "We credit your account with
        $100" [ant: {debit}]
     4: have trust in; trust in the truth or veracity of
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
