<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cries</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cries</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cry \Cry\ (kr?), n.; pl. {Cries} (kr?z). [F. cri, fr. crier to
   cry. See {Cry}, v. i. ]
   1. A loud utterance; especially, the inarticulate sound
      produced by one of the lower animals; as, the cry of
      hounds; the cry of wolves. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Outcry; clamor; tumult; popular demand.
      [1913 Webster]

            Again that cry was found to have been as
            unreasonable as ever.                 --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any expression of grief, distress, etc., accompanied with
      tears or sobs; a loud sound, uttered in lamentation.
      [1913 Webster]

            There shall be a great cry throughout all the land.
                                                  --Ex. xi. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            An infant crying in the night,
            An infant crying for the light;
            And with no language but a cry.       --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Loud expression of triumph or wonder or of popular
      acclamation or favor. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cry went once on thee.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Importunate supplication.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, the most piteous cry of the poor souls. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Public advertisement by outcry; proclamation, as by
      hawkers of their wares.
      [1913 Webster]

            The street cries of London.           --Mayhew.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Common report; fame.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cry goes that you shall marry her. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A word or phrase caught up by a party or faction and
      repeated for effect; as, the party cry of the Tories.
      [1913 Webster]

            All now depends upon a good cry.      --Beaconsfield.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A pack of hounds. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            A cry more tunable
            Was never hollaed to, nor cheered with horn. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A pack or company of persons; -- in contempt.
       [1913 Webster]

             Would not this . . . get me a fellowship in a cry
             of players?                          --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. The crackling noise made by block tin when it is bent
       back and forth.
       [1913 Webster]

   {A far cry}, a long distance; -- in allusion to the sending
      of criers or messengers through the territory of a
      Scottish clan with an announcement or summons.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
