<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cross</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CROSS, n.  An ancient religious symbol erroneously supposed to owe its
significance to the most solemn event in the history of Christianity,
but really antedating it by thousands of years.  By many it has been
believed to be identical with the _crux ansata_ of the ancient phallic
worship, but it has been traced even beyond all that we know of that,
to the rites of primitive peoples.  We have to-day the White Cross as
a symbol of chastity, and the Red Cross as a badge of benevolent
neutrality in war.  Having in mind the former, the reverend Father
Gassalasca Jape smites the lyre to the effect following:

    "Be good, be good!" the sisterhood
        Cry out in holy chorus,
    And, to dissuade from sin, parade
        Their various charms before us.

    But why, O why, has ne'er an eye
        Seen her of winsome manner
    And youthful grace and pretty face
        Flaunting the White Cross banner?

    Now where's the need of speech and screed
        To better our behaving?
    A simpler plan for saving man
        (But, first, is he worth saving?)

    Is, dears, when he declines to flee
        From bad thoughts that beset him,
    Ignores the Law as 't were a straw,
        And wants to sin -- don't let him.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross
   in the New Testament the instrument of crucifixion, and hence
   used for the crucifixion of Christ itself (Eph. 2:16; Heb. 12:2;
   1 Cor. 1:17, 18; Gal. 5:11; 6:12, 14; Phil. 3:18). The word is
   also used to denote any severe affliction or trial (Matt. 10:38;
   16:24; Mark 8:34; 10:21).
   
     The forms in which the cross is represented are these:
   
     1. The crux simplex (I), a "single piece without transom."
   
     2. The crux decussata (X), or St. Andrew's cross.
   
     3. The crux commissa (T), or St. Anthony's cross.
   
     4. The crux immissa (t), or Latin cross, which was the kind of
   cross on which our Saviour died. Above our Lord's head, on the
   projecting beam, was placed the "title." (See {CRUCIFIXION}.)
   
     After the conversion, so-called, of Constantine the Great
   (B.C. 313), the cross first came into use as an emblem of
   Christianity. He pretended at a critical moment that he saw a
   flaming cross in the heavens bearing the inscription, "In hoc
   signo vinces", i.e., By this sign thou shalt conquer, and that
   on the following night Christ himself appeared and ordered him
   to take for his standard the sign of this cross. In this form a
   new standard, called the Labarum, was accordingly made, and
   borne by the Roman armies. It remained the standard of the Roman
   army till the downfall of the Western empire. It bore the
   embroidered monogram of Christ, i.e., the first two Greek
   letters of his name, X and P (chi and rho), with the Alpha and
   Omega. (See {A}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross, SC
  Zip code(s): 29436
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ordinary \Or"di*na*ry\, n.; pl. {Ordinaries} (-r[i^]z).
   1. (Law)
      (a) (Roman Law) An officer who has original jurisdiction
          in his own right, and not by deputation.
      (b) (Eng. Law) One who has immediate jurisdiction in
          matters ecclesiastical; an ecclesiastical judge; also,
          a deputy of the bishop, or a clergyman appointed to
          perform divine service for condemned criminals and
          assist in preparing them for death.
      (c) (Am. Law) A judicial officer, having generally the
          powers of a judge of probate or a surrogate.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. The mass; the common run. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I see no more in you than in the ordinary
            Of nature's salework.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is so common, or continued, as to be considered
      a settled establishment or institution. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Spain had no other wars save those which were grown
            into an ordinary.                     --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything which is in ordinary or common use.
      [1913 Webster]

            Water buckets, wagons, cart wheels, plow socks, and
            other ordinaries.                     --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A dining room or eating house where a meal is prepared for
      all comers, at a fixed price for the meal, in distinction
      from one where each dish is separately charged; a table
      d'h[^o]te; hence, also, the meal furnished at such a
      dining room. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the odd words they have picked up in a
            coffeehouse, or a gaming ordinary, are produced as
            flowers of style.                     --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            He exacted a tribute for licenses to hawkers and
            peddlers and to ordinaries.           --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Her.) A charge or bearing of simple form, one of nine or
      ten which are in constant use. The {bend}, {chevron},
      {chief}, {cross}, {fesse}, {pale}, and {saltire} are
      uniformly admitted as ordinaries. Some authorities include
      bar, bend sinister, pile, and others. See {Subordinary}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In ordinary}.
      (a) In actual and constant service; statedly attending and
          serving; as, a physician or chaplain in ordinary. An
          ambassador in ordinary is one constantly resident at a
          foreign court.
      (b) (Naut.) Out of commission and laid up; -- said of a
          naval vessel.

   {Ordinary of the Mass} (R. C. Ch.), the part of the Mass
      which is the same every day; -- called also the {canon of
      the Mass}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross \Cross\ (kr[o^]s; 115), n. [OE. crois, croys, cros; the
   former fr. OF. crois, croiz, F. croix, fr. L. crux; the
   second is perh. directly fr. Prov. cros, crotz. fr. the same
   L. crux; cf. Icel. kross. Cf. {Crucial}, {Crusade}, {Cruise},
   {Crux}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A gibbet, consisting of two pieces of timber placed
      transversely upon one another, in various forms, as a T,
      or +, with the horizontal piece below the upper end of the
      upright, or as an X. It was anciently used in the
      execution of criminals.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nailed to the cross
            By his own nation.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The sign or mark of the cross, made with the finger, or in
      ink, etc., or actually represented in some material; the
      symbol of Christ's death; the ensign and chosen symbol of
      Christianity, of a Christian people, and of Christendom.
      [1913 Webster]

            The custom of making the sign of the cross with the
            hand or finger, as a means of conferring blessing or
            preserving from evil, is very old.    --Schaff-Herzog
                                                  Encyc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Before the cross has waned the crescent's ray. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tis where the cross is preached.      --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Affiction regarded as a test of patience or virtue; trial;
      disappointment; opposition; misfortune.
      [1913 Webster]

            Heaven prepares a good man with crosses. --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A piece of money stamped with the figure of a cross, also,
      that side of such a piece on which the cross is stamped;
      hence, money in general.
      [1913 Webster]

            I should bear no cross if I did bear you; for I
            think you have no money in your purse. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An appendage or ornament or anything in the form of a
      cross; a badge or ornamental device of the general shape
      of a cross; hence, such an ornament, even when varying
      considerably from that form; thus, the Cross of the
      British Order of St. George and St. Michael consists of a
      central medallion with seven arms radiating from it.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Arch.) A monument in the form of a cross, or surmounted
      by a cross, set up in a public place; as, a market cross;
      a boundary cross; Charing Cross in London.
      [1913 Webster]

            Dun-Edin's Cross, a pillared stone,
            Rose on a turret octagon.             --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Her.) A common heraldic bearing, of which there are many
      varieties. See the Illustration, above.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. The crosslike mark or symbol used instead of a signature
      by those unable to write.
      [1913 Webster]

            Five Kentish abbesses . . . .subscribed their names
            and crosses.                          --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Church lands. [Ireland] [Obs.] --Sir J. Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A line drawn across or through another line.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Hence: A mixing of breeds or stock, especially in cattle
       breeding; or the product of such intermixture; a hybrid
       of any kind.
       [1913 Webster]

             Toning down the ancient Viking into a sort of a
             cross between Paul Jones and Jeremy Diddler. --Lord
                                                  Dufferin.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Surveying) An instrument for laying of offsets
       perpendicular to the main course.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Mech.) A pipe-fitting with four branches the axes of
       which usually form's right angle.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Cross and pile}, a game with money, at which it is put to
      chance whether a coin shall fall with that side up which
      bears the cross, or the other, which is called pile, or
      reverse; the game called {heads or tails}.

   {Cross bottony} or

   {Cross botton['e]}. See under {Bottony}.

   {Cross estoil['e]} (Her.). a cross, each of whose arms is
      pointed like the ray of a star; that is, a star having
      four long points only.

   {Cross of Calvary}. See {Calvary}, 3.

   {Southern cross}. (Astron.) See under {Southern}.

   {To do a thing on the cross}, to act dishonestly; -- opposed
      to acting on the square. [Slang]

   {To take up the cross}, to bear troubles and afflictions with
      patience from love to Christ.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross \Cross\ (kr[o^]s), a.
   1. Not parallel; lying or falling athwart; transverse;
      oblique; intersecting.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cross refraction of the second prism. --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not accordant with what is wished or expected;
      interrupting; adverse; contrary; thwarting; perverse. ``A
      cross fortune.'' --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cross and unlucky issue of my design.
                                                  --Glanvill.
      [1913 Webster]

            The article of the resurrection seems to lie
            marvelously cross to the common experience of
            mankind.                              --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are both love's captives, but with fates so
            cross,
            One must be happy by the other's loss. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Characterized by, or in a state of, peevishness,
      fretfulness, or ill humor; as, a cross man or woman.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had received a cross answer from his mistress.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Made in an opposite direction, or an inverse relation;
      mutually inverse; interchanged; as, cross interrogatories;
      cross marriages, as when a brother and sister marry
      persons standing in the same relation to each other.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cross action} (Law), an action brought by a party who is
      sued against the person who has sued him, upon the same
      subject matter, as upon the same contract. --Burrill.

   {Cross aisle} (Arch.), a transept; the lateral divisions of a
      cruciform church.

   {Cross axle}.
      (a) (Mach.) A shaft, windlass, or roller, worked by levers
          at opposite ends, as in the copperplate printing
          press.
      (b) A driving axle, with cranks set at an angle of 90[deg]
          with each other.

   {Cross bedding} (Geol.), oblique lamination of horizontal
      beds.

   {Cross bill}. See in the Vocabulary.

   {Cross bitt}. Same as {Crosspiece}.

   {Cross bond}, a form of bricklaying, in which the joints of
      one stretcher course come midway between those of the
      stretcher courses above and below, a course of headers and
      stretchers intervening. See {Bond}, n., 8.

   {Cross breed}. See in the Vocabulary.

   {Cross breeding}. See under {Breeding}.

   {Cross buttock}, a particular throw in wrestling; hence, an
      unexpected defeat or repulse. --Smollet.

   {Cross country}, across the country; not by the road. ``The
      cross-country ride.'' --Cowper.

   {Cross fertilization}, the fertilization of the female
      products of one physiological individual by the male
      products of another, -- as the fertilization of the ovules
      of one plant by pollen from another. See {Fertilization}.
      

   {Cross file}, a double convex file, used in dressing out the
      arms or crosses of fine wheels.

   {Cross fire} (Mil.), lines of fire, from two or more points
      or places, crossing each other.

   {Cross forked}. (Her.) See under {Forked}.

   {Cross frog}. See under {Frog}.

   {Cross furrow}, a furrow or trench cut across other furrows
      to receive the water running in them and conduct it to the
      side of the field.

   {Cross handle}, a handle attached transversely to the axis of
      a tool, as in the augur. --Knight.

   {Cross lode} (Mining), a vein intersecting the true or
      principal lode.

   {Cross purpose}. See {Cross-purpose}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Cross reference}, a reference made from one part of a book
      or register to another part, where the same or an allied
      subject is treated of.

   {Cross sea} (Naut.), a chopping sea, in which the waves run
      in contrary directions.

   {Cross stroke}, a line or stroke across something, as across
      the letter t.

   {Cross wind}, a side wind; an unfavorable wind.

   {Cross wires}, fine wires made to traverse the field of view
      in a telescope, and moved by a screw with a graduated
      head, used for delicate astronomical observations; spider
      lines. Fixed cross wires are also used in microscopes,
      etc.

   Syn: Fretful; peevish. See {Fretful}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross \Cross\, prep.
   Athwart; across. [Archaic or Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]

         A fox was taking a walk one night cross a village.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To go cross lots}, to go across the fields; to take a short
      cut. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross \Cross\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Crossed} (kr[o^]st; 115); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Crossing}.]
   1. To put across or athwart; to cause to intersect; as, to
      cross the arms.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay or draw something, as a line, across; as, to cross
      the letter t.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass from one side to the other of; to pass or move
      over; to traverse; as, to cross a stream.
      [1913 Webster]

            A hunted hare . . . crosses and confounds her former
            track.                                -- I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To pass, as objects going in an opposite direction at the
      same time. ``Your kind letter crossed mine.'' --J. D.
      Forbes.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To run counter to; to thwart; to obstruct; to hinder; to
      clash or interfere with.
      [1913 Webster]

            In each thing give him way; cross him in nothing.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            An oyster may be crossed in love.     -- Sheridan.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To interfere and cut off; to debar. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To cross me from the golden time I look for. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To make the sign of the cross upon; -- followed by the
      reflexive pronoun; as, he crossed himself.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To cancel by marking crosses on or over, or drawing a line
      across; to erase; -- usually with out, off, or over; as,
      to cross out a name.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To cause to interbreed; -- said of different stocks or
      races; to mix the breed of.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To cross a check} (Eng. Banking), to draw two parallel
      transverse lines across the face of a check, with or
      without adding between them the words ``and company'',
      with or without the words ``not negotiable'', or to draw
      the transverse lines simply, with or without the words
      ``not negotiable'' (the check in any of these cases being
      crossed generally). Also, to write or print across the
      face of a check the name of a banker, with or without the
      words ``not negotiable'' (the check being then crossed
      specially). A check crossed generally is payable only when
      presented through a bank; one crossed specially, only when
      presented through the bank mentioned. [Webster 1913
      Suppl.]

   {To cross one's path}, to oppose one's plans. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross \Cross\, v. i.
   1. To lie or be athwart.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move or pass from one side to the other, or from place
      to place; to make a transit; as, to cross from New York to
      Liverpool.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be inconsistent. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Men's actions do not always cross with reason. --Sir
                                                  P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To interbreed, as races; to mix distinct breeds.
      [1913 Webster]

            If two individuals of distinct races cross, a third
            is invariably produced different from either.
                                                  --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cross</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cross
     adj 1: extending or lying across; in a crosswise direction; at
            right angles to the long axis; "cross members should
            be all steel"; "from the transverse hall the stairway
            ascends gracefully"; "transversal vibrations";
            "transverse colon" [syn: {cross(a)}, {transverse}, {transversal},
             {thwartwise}]
     2: perversely irritable [syn: {crabbed}, {crabby}, {fussy}, {grouchy},
         {grumpy}, {bad-tempered}, {ill-tempered}]
     n 1: a wooden structure consisting of an upright post with a
          transverse piece
     2: marking consisting of crossing lines [syn: {crisscross}, {mark}]
     3: a cross as an emblem of Christianity; used in heraldry
     4: any affliction that causes great suffering; "that is his
        cross to bear"; "he bears his afflictions like a crown of
        thorns" [syn: {crown of thorns}]
     5: an organism that is the offspring of genetically dissimilar
        parents or stock; especially offspring produced by
        breeding plants or animals of different varieties or
        breeds or species; "a mule is a cross between a horse and
        a donkey" [syn: {hybrid}, {crossbreed}]
     6: (genetics) the act of mixing different species or varieties
        of animals or plants and thus to produce hybrids [syn: {hybridization},
         {hybridisation}, {crossbreeding}, {crossing}, {interbreeding},
         {hybridizing}]
     v 1: travel across or pass over; "The caravan covered almost 100
          miles each day" [syn: {traverse}, {track}, {cover}, {pass
          over}, {get over}, {get across}, {cut through}, {cut
          across}]
     2: meet at a point [syn: {intersect}]
     3: hinder or prevent (the efforts, plans, or desires) of; "What
        ultimately frustrated every challenger was Ruth's amazing
        September surge"; "foil your opponent" [syn: {thwart}, {queer},
         {spoil}, {scotch}, {foil}, {frustrate}, {baffle}, {bilk}]
     4: fold so as to resemble a cross; "she crossed her legs" [ant:
         {uncross}]
     5: to cover or extend over an area or time period; "Rivers
        traverse the valley floor", "The parking lot spans 3
        acres"; "The novel spans three centuries" [syn: {traverse},
         {span}, {sweep}]
     6: meet and pass; "the trains crossed"
     7: trace a line through or across; "cross your `t'"
     8: breed animals or plants using parents of different races and
        varieties; "cross a horse and a donkey"; "Mendel tried
        crossbreeding"; "these species do not interbreed" [syn: {crossbreed},
         {hybridize}, {hybridise}, {interbreed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
