<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>crossing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crossing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cross \Cross\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Crossed} (kr[o^]st; 115); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Crossing}.]
   1. To put across or athwart; to cause to intersect; as, to
      cross the arms.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay or draw something, as a line, across; as, to cross
      the letter t.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass from one side to the other of; to pass or move
      over; to traverse; as, to cross a stream.
      [1913 Webster]

            A hunted hare . . . crosses and confounds her former
            track.                                -- I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To pass, as objects going in an opposite direction at the
      same time. ``Your kind letter crossed mine.'' --J. D.
      Forbes.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To run counter to; to thwart; to obstruct; to hinder; to
      clash or interfere with.
      [1913 Webster]

            In each thing give him way; cross him in nothing.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            An oyster may be crossed in love.     -- Sheridan.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To interfere and cut off; to debar. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To cross me from the golden time I look for. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To make the sign of the cross upon; -- followed by the
      reflexive pronoun; as, he crossed himself.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To cancel by marking crosses on or over, or drawing a line
      across; to erase; -- usually with out, off, or over; as,
      to cross out a name.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To cause to interbreed; -- said of different stocks or
      races; to mix the breed of.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To cross a check} (Eng. Banking), to draw two parallel
      transverse lines across the face of a check, with or
      without adding between them the words ``and company'',
      with or without the words ``not negotiable'', or to draw
      the transverse lines simply, with or without the words
      ``not negotiable'' (the check in any of these cases being
      crossed generally). Also, to write or print across the
      face of a check the name of a banker, with or without the
      words ``not negotiable'' (the check being then crossed
      specially). A check crossed generally is payable only when
      presented through a bank; one crossed specially, only when
      presented through the bank mentioned. [Webster 1913
      Suppl.]

   {To cross one's path}, to oppose one's plans. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crossing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crossing \Cross"ing\, n. [See {Cross}, v. t. ]
   1. The act by which anything is crossed; as, the crossing of
      the ocean.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of making the sign of the cross. --Bp. Hall.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The act of interbreeding; a mixing of breeds.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Intersection, as of two paths or roads.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A place where anything (as a stream) is crossed; a paved
      walk across a street, or a set of marks across the street
      pavement indicating that this is a designated location for
      pedestrians to cross.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   6. Contradiction; thwarting; obstruction.
      [1913 Webster]

            I do not bear these crossings.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crossing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crossing
     n 1: traveling across
     2: a shallow area in a stream that can be forded [syn: {ford}]
     3: a point where two lines (paths or arcs etc.) intersect
     4: a junction where one street or road crosses another [syn: {intersection},
         {crossroad}, {crossway}, {carrefour}]
     5: a path (often marked) where something (as a street or
        railroad) can be crossed to get from one side to the other
        [syn: {crosswalk}, {crossover}]
     6: (genetics) the act of mixing different species or varieties
        of animals or plants and thus to produce hybrids [syn: {hybridization},
         {hybridisation}, {crossbreeding}, {cross}, {interbreeding},
         {hybridizing}]
     7: a voyage across a body of water (usually across the Atlantic
        Ocean)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
