<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>crunch</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crunch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crunch
     
        1. &lt;jargon&gt; To process, usually in a time-consuming or
        complicated way.  Connotes an essentially trivial operation
        that is nonetheless painful to perform.  The pain may be due
        to the triviality's being embedded in a loop from 1 to
        1,000,000,000.  "Fortran programs do mostly {number
        crunching}."
     
        2. &lt;compression&gt; To reduce the size of a file without losing
        information by a complicated scheme that produces bit
        configurations completely unrelated to the original data, such
        as by a {Huffman} code.  Since such {compression} usually
        takes more computations than simpler methods such as
        {run-length encoding}, the term is doubly appropriate.  (This
        meaning is usually used in the construction "file crunching"
        to distinguish it from {number crunching}.)  Use of {crunch}
        itself in this sense is rare among {Unix} hackers.
     
        3. The {hash character}.  Used at {XEROX} and {CMU}, among
        other places.
     
        4. To squeeze program source to the minimum size that will
        still compile or execute.  The term came from a {BBC
        Microcomputer} program that crunched {BBC BASIC} {source} in
        order to make it run more quickly (apart from storing
        {keywords} as byte codes, the language was wholly interpreted,
        so the number of characters mattered).  {Obfuscated C Contest}
        entries are often crunched; see the first example under that
        entry.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2002-03-14)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crunch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crunch \Crunch\ (kr[u^]nch), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Crunched}
   (kr[u^]ncht); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Crunching}.] [Prob. of
   imitative origin; or cf. D. schransen to eat heartily, or E.
   scrunch.]
   1. To chew with force and noise; to craunch.
      [1913 Webster]

            And their white tusks crunched o'er the whiter
            skull.                                --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To grind or press with violence and noise.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ship crunched through the ice.    --Kane.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To emit a grinding or craunching noise.
      [1913 Webster]

            The crunching and ratting of the loose stones. --H.
                                                  James.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crunch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crunch \Crunch\, v. t.
   To crush with the teeth; to chew with a grinding noise; to
   craunch; as, to crunch a biscuit.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crunch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crunch 1. vi. To process, usually in a time-consuming or complicated
   way. Connotes an essentially trivial operation that is nonetheless
   painful to perform. The pain may be due to the triviality's being
   embedded in a loop from 1 to 1,000,000,000. "FORTRAN programs do mostly
   {number-crunching}." 2. vt. To reduce the size of a file by a
   complicated scheme that produces bit configurations completely unrelated
   to the original data, such as by a Huffman code. (The file ends up
   looking something like a paper document would if somebody crunched the
   paper into a wad.) Since such compression usually takes more
   computations than simpler methods such as run-length encoding, the term
   is doubly appropriate. (This meaning is usually used in the construction
   `file crunch(ing)' to distinguish it from {number-crunching}.) See
   {compress}. 3. n. The character `#'. Used at XEROX and CMU, among other
   places. See {{ASCII}}. 4. vt. To squeeze program source into a
   minimum-size representation that will still compile or execute. The term
   came into being specifically for a famous program on the BBC micro that
   crunched BASIC source in order to make it run more quickly (it was a
   wholly interpretive BASIC, so the number of characters mattered).
   {Obfuscated C Contest} entries are often crunched; see the first example
   under that entry.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crunch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crunch
     n 1: the sound of something crunching; "he heard the crunch of
          footsteps on the gravel path"
     2: a critical situation that arises because of a shortage (as a
        shortage of time or money or resources); "an end-of-the
        year crunch"; "a financial crunch"
     3: the act of crushing [syn: {crush}, {compaction}]
     v 1: make crunching noises; "his shoes were crunching on the
          gravel" [syn: {scranch}, {scraunch}, {crackle}]
     2: press or grind with a crunching noise [syn: {cranch}, {craunch},
         {grind}]
     3: chew noisily; "The children crunched the celery sticks"
        [syn: {munch}]
     4: reduce to small pieces or particles by pounding or abrading;
        "grind the spices in a mortar"; "mash the garlic" [syn: {grind},
         {mash}, {bray}, {comminute}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
