<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>crutch</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crutch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crutch \Crutch\, v. t.
   To support on crutches; to prop up. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Two fools that crutch their feeble sense on verse.
                                                  --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crutch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crutch \Crutch\ (kr[u^]ch; 224), n.; pl. {Crutches} (-[e^]z).
   [OE. crucche, AS. crycc, cricc; akin to D. kruk, G.
   kr["u]cke, Dan. krykke, Sw. krycka, and to E. crook. See
   {Crook}, and cf. {Cricket} a low stool.]
   1. A staff with a crosspiece at the head, to be placed under
      the arm or shoulder, to support the lame or infirm in
      walking.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll lean upon one crutch, and fight with the other.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rhyme is a crutch that lifts the weak alone. --H.
                                                  Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A form of pommel for a woman's saddle, consisting of a
      forked rest to hold the leg of the rider.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.)
      (a) A knee, or piece of knee timber.
      (b) A forked stanchion or post; a crotch. See {Crotch}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crutch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crotch \Crotch\ (kr[o^]ch; 224), n.; pl. {Crotches}
   (kr[o^]ch"[e^]z). [Cf. {Crotchet}, {Crutch}.]
   1. The angle formed by the parting of two legs or branches; a
      fork; the point where a trunk divides; as, the crotch of a
      tree. more specifically, the space on the human torso
      between the two legs; also, the corresponding part between
      the legs of a pair of pants, which is in contact with the
      crotch of the wearer; as, pants with a tight crotch have
      become very popular.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. (Naut.) A stanchion or post of wood or iron, with two arms
      for supporting a boom, spare yards, etc.; -- called also
      {crane} and {crutch}. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Billiards) In the three-ball carom game, a small space at
      each corner of the table. See {Crotched}, below.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crutch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crutch
     n 1: a wooden or metal staff that fits under the armpit and
          reaches to the ground; used by disabled person while
          walking
     2: anything that serves as an expedient; "he uses drugs as a
        psychological crutch"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
