<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>crystallization</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crystallization</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crystallization \Crys`tal*li*za"tion\
   (kr[i^]s`tal*l[i^]*z[=a]"sh[u^]n), n. [Cf. F.
   cristallization.]
   1. (Chem. &amp; Min.) The act or process by which a substance in
      solidifying assumes the form and structure of a crystal,
      or becomes crystallized; the formation of crystals.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The body formed by crystallizing; as, silver on
      precipitation forms arborescent crystallizations.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The systems of crystallization are the several classes
         to which the forms are mathematically referable. They
         are most simply described according to the relative
         lengths and inclinations of certain assumed lines
         called axes; but the real distinction is the degree of
         symmetry characterizing them. 1. {The Isometric
         system}, or {The Monometric system} has the axes all
         equal, as in the cube, octahedron, etc. 2. {The
         Tetragonal system}, or {The Dimetric system} has a
         varying vertical axis, while the lateral are equal, as
         in the right square prism. 3. {The Orthorhombic
         system}, or {The Trimetric system} has the three axes
         unequal, as in the rectangular and rhombic prism. In
         this system, the lateral axes are called, respectively,
         macrodiagonal and brachydiagonal. -- The preceding are
         erect forms, the axes intersecting at right angles. The
         following are oblique. 4. {The Monoclinic system},
         having one of the intersections oblique, as in the
         oblique rhombic prism. In this system, the lateral axes
         are called respectively, clinodiagonal and
         orthodiagonal. 5. {The Triclinic system}, having all
         the three intersections oblique, as in the oblique
         rhomboidal prism. There is also: 6. {The Hexagonal
         system} (one division of which is called Rhombohedral),
         in which there are three equal lateral axes, and a
         vertical axis of variable length, as in the hexagonal
         prism and the rhombohedron.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: The Diclinic system, sometimes recognized, with two
         oblique intersections, is only a variety of the
         Triclinic.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>crystallization</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>crystallization
     n 1: the formation of crystals [syn: {crystallisation}, {crystallizing}]
     2: a rock formed by the solidification of a substance; has
        regularly repeating internal structure; external plane
        faces [syn: {crystal}]
     3: a mental synthesis that becomes fixed or concrete by a
        process resembling crystal formation
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
