<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cup</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cup
   a wine-cup (Gen. 40:11, 21), various forms of which are found on
   Assyrian and Egyptian monuments. All Solomon's drinking vessels
   were of gold (1 Kings 10: 21). The cups mentioned in the New
   Testament were made after Roman and Greek models, and were
   sometimes of gold (Rev. 17:4).
   
     The art of divining by means of a cup was practiced in Egypt
   (Gen. 44:2-17), and in the East generally.
   
     The "cup of salvation" (Ps. 116:13) is the cup of thanksgiving
   for the great salvation. The "cup of consolation" (Jer. 16:7)
   refers to the custom of friends sending viands and wine to
   console relatives in mourning (Prov. 31:6). In 1 Cor. 10:16, the
   "cup of blessing" is contrasted with the "cup of devils" (1 Cor.
   10:21). The sacramental cup is the "cup of blessing," because of
   blessing pronounced over it (Matt. 26:27; Luke 22:17). The
   "portion of the cup" (Ps. 11:6; 16:5) denotes one's condition of
   life, prosperous or adverse. A "cup" is also a type of sensual
   allurement (Jer. 51:7; Prov. 23:31; Rev. 17:4). We read also of
   the "cup of astonishment," the "cup of trembling," and the "cup
   of God's wrath" (Ps. 75:8; Isa. 51:17; Jer. 25:15; Lam. 4:21;
   Ezek. 23:32; Rev. 16:19; comp. Matt. 26:39, 42; John 18:11). The
   cup is also the symbol of death (Matt. 16:28; Mark 9:1; Heb.
   2:9).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trophy \Tro"phy\, n.; pl. {Trophies}. [F. troph['e]e (cf. It. &amp;
   Sp. trofeo), L. tropaeum, trophaeum, Gr. ?, strictly, a
   monument of the enemy's defeat, fr.? a turn, especially, a
   turning about of the enemy, a putting to flight or routing
   him, fr. ? to turn. See {Trope}.]
   1. (Gr. &amp; Rom. Antiq.) A sign or memorial of a victory raised
      on the field of battle, or, in case of a naval victory, on
      the nearest land. Sometimes trophies were erected in the
      chief city of the conquered people.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A trophy consisted originally of some of the armor,
         weapons, etc., of the defeated enemy fixed to the trunk
         of a tree or to a post erected on an elevated site,
         with an inscription, and a dedication to a divinity.
         The Romans often erected their trophies in the Capitol.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The representation of such a memorial, as on a medal; esp.
      (Arch.), an ornament representing a group of arms and
      military weapons, offensive and defensive.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything taken from an enemy and preserved as a memorial
      of victory, as arms, flags, standards, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Around the posts hung helmets, darts, and spears,
            And captive chariots, axes, shields, and bars,
            And broken beaks of ships, the trophies of their
            wars.                                 --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any evidence or memorial of victory or conquest; as, every
      redeemed soul is a trophy of grace.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An object memorializing a victory in a sporting contest.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Some trophies(5) are unique, temporary possession of
         the same object passing to the new victors of some
         periodic contest in subsequent occurrences. Others are
         objects of little inherent worth, given by the
         authority sponsoring the contest to the victor. A
         trophy is sometimes shaped like a cup, and in such
         cases may be called a {cup}, as the {America's Cup} (in
         Yacht racing). --&gt;
         [1913 Webster]

   {Trophy money}, a duty paid formerly in England, annually, by
      housekeepers, toward providing harness, drums, colors, and
      the like, for the militia.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crater \Cra"ter\ (kr[=a]"t[~e]r), n. [L. crater, cratera, a
   mixing vessel, the mouth of a volcano, Gr. krath`r, fr.
   keranny`nai to mix; cf. Skr. [,c]r[imac] to mix, [,c]ir to
   cook, [,c]r[=a] to cook. Cf. {Grail}, in Holy Grail.]
   1. The basinlike opening or mouth of a volcano, through which
      the chief eruption comes; similarly, the mouth of a
      geyser, about which a cone of silica is often built up.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) The pit left by the explosion of a bomb, shell, or
      mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Astron.) A constellation of the southen hemisphere; --
      called also the {Cup}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cup \Cup\ (k[u^]p), n. [AS. cuppe, LL. cuppa cup; cf. L. cupa
   tub, cask; cf. also Gr. ky`ph hut, Skr. k[=u]pa pit, hollow,
   OSlav. kupa cup. Cf. {Coop}, {Cupola}, {Cowl} a water vessel,
   and {Cob}, {Coif}, {Cop}.]
   1. A small vessel, used commonly to drink from; as, a tin
      cup, a silver cup, a wine cup; especially, in modern
      times, the pottery or porcelain vessel, commonly with a
      handle, used with a saucer in drinking tea, coffee, and
      the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The contents of such a vessel; a cupful.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give me a cup of sack, boy.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. Repeated potations; social or excessive indulgence in
      intoxicating drinks; revelry.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thence from cups to civil broils.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is to be received or indured; that which is
      allotted to one; a portion.
      [1913 Webster]

            O my Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass
            from me.                              --Matt. xxvi.
                                                  39.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Anything shaped like a cup; as, the cup of an acorn, or of
      a flower.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cowslip's golden cup no more I see. --Shenstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Med.) A cupping glass or other vessel or instrument used
      to produce the vacuum in cupping.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cup and ball}, a familiar toy of children, having a cup on
      the top of a piece of wood to which, a ball is attached by
      a cord; the ball, being thrown up, is to be caught in the
      cup; bilboquet. --Milman.

   {Cup and can}, familiar companions.

   {Dry cup}, {Wet cup} (Med.), a cup used for dry or wet
      cupping. See under {Cupping}.

   {To be in one's cups}, to be drunk.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cup \Cup\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cupped} (k[u^]pt); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Cupping}.]
   1. To supply with cups of wine. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Cup us, till the world go round.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Surg.) To apply a cupping apparatus to; to subject to the
      operation of cupping. See {Cupping}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mech.) To make concave or in the form of a cup; as, to
      cup the end of a screw.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>CUP
     Competitive UPgrade (MS)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cup
     n 1: a United States liquid unit equal to 8 fluid ounces
     2: the quantity a cup will hold; "he drank a cup of coffee";
        "he borrowed a cup of sugar" [syn: {cupful}]
     3: a small open container usually used for drinking; usually
        has a handle; "he put the cup back in the saucer"; "the
        handle of the cup was missing"
     4: a large metal vessel with two handles that is awarded as a
        trophy to the winner of a competition; "the school kept
        the cups is a special glass case" [syn: {loving cup}]
     5: any cup-shaped concavity; "bees filled the waxen cups with
        honey"; "he wore a jock strap with a metal cup"; "the cup
        of her bra"
     6: the hole (or metal container in the hole) on a golf green;
        "he swore as the ball rimmed the cup and rolled away";
        "put the flag back in the cup"
     7: a punch served in a pitcher instead of a punch bowl
     8: cup-shaped plant organ
     v 1: form into the shape of a cup; "She cupped her hands"
     2: put into a cup; "cup the milk"
     3: treat by applying evacuated cups to the patient's skin [syn:
         {transfuse}]
     [also: {cupping}, {cupped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
