<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>curb</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curb \Curb\ (k[^u]rb), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Curbed} (k[^u]rbd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Curbing}.] [F. courber to bend, curve,
   L.curvare, fr. curvus bent, curved; cf. Gr. kyrto`s curved.
   Cf. {Curve}.]
   1. To bend or curve. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Crooked and curbed lines.             --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To guide and manage, or restrain, as with a curb; to bend
      to one's will; to subject; to subdue; to restrain; to
      confine; to keep in check.
      [1913 Webster]

            Part wield their arms, part curb the foaming steed.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where pinching want must curb thy warm desires.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To furnish with a curb, as a well; also, to restrain by a
      curb, as a bank of earth.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curb \Curb\, v. i.
   To bend; to crouch; to cringe. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Virtue itself of vice must pardon beg,
         Yea, curb and woo for leave to do him good. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curb \Curb\, n.
   1. That which curbs, restrains, or subdues; a check or
      hindrance; esp., a chain or strap attached to the upper
      part of the branches of a bit, and capable of being drawn
      tightly against the lower jaw of the horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that before ran in the pastures wild
            Felt the stiff curb control his angry jaws.
                                                  --Drayton.
      [1913 Webster]

            By these men, religion,that should be
            The curb, is made the spur of tyranny. --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) An assemblage of three or more pieces of timber,
      or a metal member, forming a frame around an opening, and
      serving to maintain the integrity of that opening; also, a
      ring of stone serving a similar purpose, as at the eye of
      a dome.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A frame or wall round the mouth of a well; also, a frame
      within a well to prevent the earth caving in.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A curbstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Far.) A swelling on the back part of the hind leg of a
      horse, just behind the lowest part of the hock joint,
      generally causing lameness. --James Law.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Curb bit}, a stiff bit having branches by which a leverage
      is obtained upon the jaws of horse. --Knight.

   {Curb pins} (Horology), the pins on the regulator which
      restrain the hairspring.

   {Curb plate} (Arch.), a plate serving the purpose of a curb.
      

   {Deck curb}. See under {Deck}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>curb
     n 1: an edge between a sidewalk and a roadway consisting of a
          line of curbstones (usually forming part of a gutter)
          [syn: {curbing}, {kerb}]
     2: a horse's bit with an attached chain or strap to check the
        horse [syn: {curb bit}]
     3: a stock exchange in New York [syn: {American Stock Exchange},
         {AMEX}]
     4: the act of restraining power or action or limiting excess;
        "his common sense is a bridle to his quick temper" [syn: {bridle},
         {check}]
     v 1: lessen the intensity of; temper; hold in restraint; hold or
          keep within limits; "moderate your alcohol intake";
          "hold your tongue"; "hold your temper"; "control your
          anger" [syn: {control}, {hold in}, {hold}, {contain}, {check},
           {moderate}]
     2: to put down by force or authority; "suppress a nascent
        uprising"; "stamp down on littering"; "conquer one's
        desires" [syn: {suppress}, {stamp down}, {inhibit}, {subdue},
         {conquer}]
     3: keep to the curb; "curb your dogs"
     4: place restrictions on; "curtail drinking in school" [syn: {restrict},
         {curtail}, {cut back}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
