<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cure</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cure \Cure\ (k[=u]r), n. [OF, cure care, F., also, cure,
   healing, cure of souls, L. cura care, medical attendance,
   cure; perh. akin to cavere to pay heed, E. cution. Cure is
   not related to care.]
   1. Care, heed, or attention. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Of study took he most cure and most heed. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Vicarages of greatcure, but small value. --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Spiritual charge; care of soul; the office of a parish
      priest or of a curate; hence, that which is committed to
      the charge of a parish priest or of a curate; a curacy;
      as, to resign a cure; to obtain a cure.
      [1913 Webster]

            The appropriator was the incumbent parson, and had
            the cure of the souls of the parishioners.
                                                  --Spelman.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Medical or hygienic care; remedial treatment of disease; a
      method of medical treatment; as, to use the water cure.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Act of healing or state of being healed; restoration to
      health from disease, or to soundness after injury.
      [1913 Webster]

            Past hope! pastcure! past help.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I do cures to-day and to-morrow.      --Luke xii.
                                                  32.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Means of the removal of disease or evil; that which heals;
      a remedy; a restorative.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cold, hunger, prisons, ills without a cure.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The proper cure of such prejudices.   --Bp. Hurd.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cure \Cure\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cured} (k[=u]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Curing}.] [OF. curer to take care, to heal, F., only, to
   cleanse, L. curare to take care, to heal, fr. cura. See
   {Cure},.]
   1. To heal; to restore to health, soundness, or sanity; to
      make well; -- said of a patient.
      [1913 Webster]

            The child was cured from that very hour. --Matt.
                                                  xvii. 18.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To subdue or remove by remedial means; to remedy; to
      remove; to heal; -- said of a malady.
      [1913 Webster]

            To cure this deadly grief.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then he called his twelve disciples together, and
            gave them power . . . to cure diseases. --Luke ix.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To set free from (something injurious or blameworthy), as
      from a bad habit.
      [1913 Webster]

            I never knew any man cured of inattention. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To prepare for preservation or permanent keeping; to
      preserve, as by drying, salting, etc.; as, to cure beef or
      fish; to cure hay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cure \Cure\, v. i.
   1. To pay heed; to care; to give attention. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To restore health; to effect a cure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whose smile and frown, like to Achilles' spear,
            Is able with the change to kill and cure. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To become healed.
      [1913 Webster]

            One desperate grief cures with another's languish.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cur'e \Cu`r['e]"\ (k[.u]`r[asl]"), n. [F., fr. LL. curatus. See
   {Curate}.]
   A curate; a pardon.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cure
     n : a medicine or therapy that cures disease or relieve pain
         [syn: {remedy}, {curative}]
     v 1: provide a cure for, make healthy again; "The treatment cured
          the boy's acne"; "The quack pretended to heal patients
          but never managed to" [syn: {bring around}, {heal}]
     2: prepare by drying, salting, or chemical processing in order
        to preserve; "cure meats"; "cure pickles"
     3: make (substances) hard and improve their usability; "cure
        resin"
     4: be or become preserved; "the apricots cure in the sun"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
