<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>curling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curl \Curl\ (k[^u]rl), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Curled} (k[^u]rld);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Curling}.] [Akin to D. krullen, Dan.
   kr["o]lle, dial. Sw. krulla to curl, crisp; possibly akin to
   E. crook. Cf. {Curl}, n., {Cruller}.]
   1. To twist or form into ringlets; to crisp, as the hair.
      [1913 Webster]

            But curl their locks with bodkins and with braid.
                                                  --Cascoigne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To twist or make onto coils, as a serpent's body.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of his tortuous train,
            Curled many a wanton wreath in sight of Eve.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To deck with, or as with, curls; to ornament.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thicker than the snaky locks
            That curledMeg[ae]ra.                 --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Curling with metaphors a plain intention. --Herbert.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To raise in waves or undulations; to ripple.
      [1913 Webster]

            Seas would be pools without the brushing air
            To curl the waves.                    --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Hat Making) To shape (the brim) into a curve.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curling \Curl"ing\, n.
   1. The act or state of that which curls; as, the curling of
      smoke when it rises; the curling of a ringlet; also, the
      act or process of one who curls something, as hair, or the
      brim of hats.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A scottish game in which heavy weights of stone or iron
      are propelled by hand over the ice towards a mark.
      [1913 Webster]

            Curling . . . is an amusement of the winter, and
            played on the ice, by sliding from one mark to
            another great stones of 40 to 70 pounds weight, of a
            hemispherical form, with an iron or wooden handle at
            top. The object of the player is to lay his stone as
            near to the mark as possible, to guard that of his
            partner, which has been well laid before, or to
            strike off that of his antagonist.    --Pennant
                                                  (Tour in
                                                  Scotland.
                                                  1772).
      [1913 Webster]

   {Curling irons}, {Curling tong}, an instrument for curling
      the hair; -- commonly heated when used. Called also
      {curler[4]}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>curling
     adj : having curls [syn: {curled}]
     n : a game played on ice; curling stones (heavy stones with
         handles) are slid toward a target
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
