<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>curtain</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curtain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curtain
   (1.) Ten curtains, each twenty-eight cubits long and four wide,
   made of fine linen, also eleven made of goat's hair, covered the
   tabernacle (Ex. 26:1-13; 36:8-17).
   
     (2.) The sacred curtain, separating the holy of holies from
   the sanctuary, is designated by a different Hebrew word
   (peroketh). It is described as a "veil of blue, and purple, and
   scarlet, and fine twined linen of cunning work" (Ex. 26:31; Lev.
   16:2; Num. 18:7).
   
     (3.) "Stretcheth out the heavens as a curtain" (Isa. 40:22),
   is an expression used with reference to the veil or awning which
   Orientals spread for a screen over their courts in summer.
   According to the prophet, the heavens are spread over our heads
   as such an awning. Similar expressions are found in Ps. 104:2l;
   comp. Isa. 44:24; Job 9:8.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curtain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curtain \Cur"tain\ (k[^u]r"t[i^]n; 48), n. [OE.cortin,
   curtin,fr. OF. cortine, curtine, F. courtine, LL. cortina,
   curtian (in senses 1 and 2), also, small court, small
   inclosure surrounded by walls, from cortis court. See
   {Court}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A hanging screen intended to darken or conceal, and
      admitting of being drawn back or up, and reclosed at
      pleasure; esp., drapery of cloth or lace hanging round a
      bed or at a window; in theaters, and like places, a
      movable screen for concealing the stage.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Fort.) That part of the rampart and parapet which is
      between two bastions or two gates. See Illustrations of
      {Ravelin} and {Bastion}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.) That part of a wall of a building which is between
      two pavilions, towers, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A flag; an ensign; -- in contempt. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Behind the curtain}, in concealment; in secret.

   {Curtain lecture}, a querulous lecture given by a wife to her
      husband within the bed curtains, or in bed. --Jerrold.
      [1913 Webster]

            A curtain lecture is worth all the sermons in the
            world for teaching the virtues of patience and
            long-suffering.                       --W. Irving.

   {The curtain falls}, the performance closes.

   {The curtain rises}, the performance begins.

   {To draw the curtain}, to close it over an object, or to
      remove it; hence:
      (a) To hide or to disclose an object.
      (b) To commence or close a performance.

   {To drop the curtain}, to end the tale, or close the
      performance.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curtain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Curtain \Cur"tain\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Curtained}
   (k[^u]r"t[i^]nd; 48); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Curtaining}.]
   To inclose as with curtains; to furnish with curtains.
   [1913 Webster]

         So when the sun in bed
         Curtained with cloudy red.               --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>curtain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>curtain
     n 1: hanging cloth used as a blind (especially for a window)
          [syn: {drape}, {drapery}, {mantle}, {pall}]
     2: any barrier to communication or vision; "a curtain of
        secrecy"; "a curtain of trees"
     v : provide with drapery; "curtain the bedrooms"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
