<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cutting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cutting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cutting
   the flesh in various ways was an idolatrous practice, a part of
   idol-worship (Deut. 14:1; 1 Kings 18:28). The Israelites were
   commanded not to imitate this practice (Lev. 19:28; 21:5; Deut.
   14:1). The tearing of the flesh from grief and anguish of spirit
   in mourning for the dead was regarded as a mark of affection
   (Jer. 16:6; 41:5; 48:37).
   
     Allusions are made in Revelation (13:16; 17:5; 19:20) to the
   practice of printing marks on the body, to indicate allegiance
   to a deity. We find also references to it, through in a
   different direction, by Paul (Gal. 6; 7) and by Ezekiel (9:4).
   (See {HAIR}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cutting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cut \Cut\ (k[u^]t), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cut}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Cutting}.] [OE. cutten, kitten, ketten; prob. of Celtic
   origin; cf. W. cwtau to shorten, curtail, dock, cwta
   bobtailed, cwt tail, skirt, Gael. cutaich to shorten,
   curtail, dock, cutach short, docked, cut a bobtail, piece,
   Ir. cut a short tail, cutach bobtailed. Cf. {Coot}.]
   1. To separate the parts of with, or as with, a sharp
      instrument; to make an incision in; to gash; to sever; to
      divide.
      [1913 Webster]

            You must cut this flesh from off his breast. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Before the whistling winds the vessels fly,
            With rapid swiftness cut the liquid way. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To sever and cause to fall for the purpose of gathering;
      to hew; to mow or reap.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy servants can skill to cut timer.  --2. Chron.
                                                  ii. 8
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To sever and remove by cutting; to cut off; to dock; as,
      to cut the hair; to cut the nails.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To castrate or geld; as, to cut a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To form or shape by cutting; to make by incision, hewing,
      etc.; to carve; to hew out.
      [1913 Webster]

            Why should a man. whose blood is warm within,
            Sit like his grandsire cut in alabaster? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Loopholes cut through thickest shade. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To wound or hurt deeply the sensibilities of; to pierce;
      to lacerate; as, sarcasm cuts to the quick.
      [1913 Webster]

            The man was cut to the heart.         --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To intersect; to cross; as, one line cuts another at right
      angles.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To refuse to recognize; to ignore; as, to cut a person in
      the street; to cut one's acquaintance. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To absent one's self from; as, to cut an appointment, a
      recitation. etc. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            An English tradesman is always solicitous to cut the
            shop whenever he can do so with impunity. --Thomas
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Cricket) To deflect (a bowled ball) to the off, with a
       chopping movement of the bat.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. (Billiards, etc.) To drive (an object ball) to either
       side by hitting it fine on the other side with the cue
       ball or another object ball.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. (Lawn Tennis, etc.) To strike (a ball) with the racket
       inclined or struck across the ball so as to put a certain
       spin on the ball.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   13. (Croquet) To drive (a ball) to one side by hitting with
       another ball.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To cut a caper}. See under {Caper}.

   {To cut the cards}, to divide a pack of cards into portions,
      in order to determine the deal or the trump, or to change
      the cards to be dealt.

   {To cut both ways}, to have effects both advantageous and
      disadvantageous.

   {To cut corners}, to deliberately do an incomplete or
      imperfect job in order to save time or money.

   {To cut a dash} or {To cut a figure}, to make a display of
      oneself; to give a conspicuous impression. [Colloq.]

   {To cut down}.
       (a) To sever and cause to fall; to fell; to prostrate.
           ``Timber . . . cut down in the mountains of
           Cilicia.'' --Knolles.
       (b) To put down; to abash; to humble. [Obs] ``So great is
           his natural eloquence, that he cuts down the finest
           orator.'' --Addison
       (c) To lessen; to retrench; to curtail; as, to cut down
           expenses.
       (d) (Naut.) To raze; as, to cut down a frigate into a
           sloop.

   {To cut the knot} or {To cut the Gordian knot}, to dispose of
      a difficulty summarily; to solve it by prompt, arbitrary
      action, rather than by skill or patience.

   {To cut lots}, to determine lots by cuttings cards; to draw
      lots.

   {To cut off}.
       (a) To sever; to separate.
           [1913 Webster +PJC]

                 I would to God, . . .
                 The king had cut off my brother's. --Shak.
       (b) To put an untimely death; to put an end to; to
           destroy. ``Iren[ae]us was likewise cut off by
           martyrdom.'' --Addison.
       (c) To interrupt; as, to cut off communication; to cut
           off (the flow of) steam from (the boiler to) a steam
           engine.
       (d) To intercept; as,, to cut off an enemy's retreat.
       (e) To end; to finish; as, to cut off further debate.

   {To cut out}.
       (a) To remove by cutting or carving; as, to cut out a
           piece from a board.
       (b) To shape or form by cutting; as, to cut out a
           garment. `` A large forest cut out into walks.''
           --Addison.
       (c) To scheme; to contrive; to prepare; as, to cut out
           work for another day. ``Every man had cut out a place
           for himself.'' --Addison.
       (d) To step in and take the place of; to supplant; as, to
           cut out a rival. [Colloq.]
       (e) To debar. ``I am cut out from anything but common
           acknowledgments.'' --Pope.
       (f) To seize and carry off (a vessel) from a harbor, or
           from under the guns of an enemy.
       (g) to separate from the midst of a number; as, to cut
           out a steer from a herd; to cut out a car from a
           train.
       (h) to discontinue; as, to cut out smoking.

   {To cut to pieces}.
       (a) To cut into pieces; as, to cut cloth to pieces.
       (b) To slaughter; as, to cut an army to pieces.

   {To cut a play} (Drama), to shorten it by leaving out
      passages, to adapt it for the stage.

   {To cut rates} (Railroads, etc.), to reduce the charges for
      transportation below the rates established between
      competing lines.

   {To cut short}, to arrest or check abruptly; to bring to a
      sudden termination. ``Achilles cut him short, and thus
      replied.'' --Dryden.

   {To cut stick}, to make off clandestinely or precipitately.
      [Slang]

   {To cut teeth}, to put forth teeth; to have the teeth pierce
      through the gum and appear.

   {To have cut one's eyeteeth}, to be sharp and knowing.
      [Colloq.]

   {To cut one's wisdom teeth}, to come to years of discretion.
      

   {To cut under}, to undersell; as, to cut under a competitor
      in trade; more commonly referred to as {undercut}.

   {To cut up}.
       (a) To cut to pieces; as, to cut up an animal, or bushes.
       (b) To damage or destroy; to injure; to wound; as, to cut
           up a book or its author by severe criticism. ``This
           doctrine cuts up all government by the roots.''
           --Locke.
       (c) To afflict; to discourage; to demoralize; as, the
           death of his friend cut him up terribly. [Colloq.]
           --Thackeray.
           [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cutting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cutting \Cut"ting\ (k[u^]t"t[i^]ng), n.
   1. The act or process of making an incision, or of severing,
      felling, shaping, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Something cut, cut off, or cut out, as a twig or scion cut
      off from a stock for the purpose of grafting or of rooting
      as an independent plant; something cut out of a newspaper;
      an excavation cut through a hill or elsewhere to make a
      way for a railroad, canal, etc.; a cut.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cutting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cutting \Cut"ting\, a.
   1. Adapted to cut; as, a cutting tool.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Chilling; penetrating; sharp; as, a cutting wind.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Severe; sarcastic; biting; as, a cutting reply; a cutting
      remark.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cutting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cutting
     See {cut}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cutting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cut
     adj 1: separated into parts or laid open or penetrated with a sharp
            edge or instrument; "the cut surface was mottled";
            "cut tobacco"; "blood from his cut forehead";
            "bandages on her cut wrists" [ant: {uncut}]
     2: fashioned or shaped by cutting; "a well-cut suit"; "cut
        diamonds"; "cut velvet" [ant: {uncut}]
     3: with parts removed; "the drastically cut film" [syn: {shortened}]
     4: made neat and tidy by trimming; "his neatly trimmed hair"
        [syn: {trimmed}] [ant: {untrimmed}]
     5: (used of grass or vegetation) cut down with a hand implement
        or machine; "the smell of new-mown hay" [syn: {mown}]
        [ant: {unmown}]
     6: (of pages of a book) having the folds of the leaves trimmed
        or slit; "the cut pages of the book" [ant: {uncut}]
     7: (of a male animal) having the testicles removed; "a cut
        horse" [syn: {emasculated}, {gelded}]
     8: having a long rip or tear; "a split lip" [syn: {split}]
     9: wounded by cutting deeply; "got a gashed arm in a knife
        fight"; "had a slashed cheek from the broken glass" [syn:
        {gashed}, {slashed}]
     10: cut down; "the tree is down" [syn: {cut down}, {down}]
     11: (used of rates or prices) reduced usually sharply; "the
         slashed prices attracted buyers" [syn: {slashed}]
     12: mixed with water; "sold cut whiskey"; "a cup of thinned
         soup" [syn: {thinned}, {weakened}]
     n 1: the act of reducing the amount or number; "the mayor
          proposed extensive cuts in the city budget"
     2: a wound made by cutting; "he put a bandage over the cut"
        [syn: {gash}, {slash}, {slice}]
     3: a piece of meat that has been cut from an animal carcass
        [syn: {cut of meat}]
     4: a distinct selection of music from a recording or a compact
        disc; "he played the first cut on the cd"; "the title
        track of the album" [syn: {track}]
     5: the act of penetrating or opening open with a sharp edge;
        "his cut in the lining revealed the hidden jewels" [syn: {cutting}]
     6: a share of the profits; "everyone got a cut of the earnings"
     7: a step on some scale; "he is a cut above the the rest"
     8: a trench resembling a furrow that was made by erosion or
        excavation [syn: {gash}]
     9: (film) an immediate transition from one shot to the next;
        "the cut from the accident scene to the hospital seemed
        too abrupt"
     10: the act of cutting something into parts; "his cuts were
         skillful"; "his cutting of the cake made a terrible mess"
         [syn: {cutting}]
     11: the omission that is made when an editorial change shortens
         a written passage; "an editor's deletions frequently
         upset young authors"; "both parties agreed on the
         excision of the proposed clause" [syn: {deletion}, {excision}]
     12: the style in which a garment is cut; "a dress of traditional
         cut"
     13: the act of shortening something by cutting off the ends;
         "the barber gave him a good cut" [syn: {cutting}, {cutting
         off}]
     14: in baseball; a batter's attempt to hit a pitched ball; "he
         took a vicious cut at the ball" [syn: {baseball swing}, {swing}]
     15: a remark capable of wounding mentally; "the unkindest cut of
         all" [syn: {stinger}]
     16: a canal made by erosion or excavation
     17: a refusal to recognize someone you know; "the snub was
         clearly intentional" [syn: {snub}, {cold shoulder}]
     18: (sports) a stroke that puts reverse spin on the ball; "cuts
         do not bother a good tennis player" [syn: {undercut}]
     19: the division of a deck of cards before dealing; "he insisted
         that we give him the last cut before every deal"; "the
         cutting of the cards soon became a ritual" [syn: {cutting}]
     20: an unexcused absence from class; "he was punished for taking
         too many cuts in his math class"
     v 1: separate with or as if with an instrument; "Cut the rope"
     2: cut down on; make a reduction in; "reduce your daily fat
        intake"; "The employer wants to cut back health benefits"
        [syn: {reduce}, {cut down}, {cut back}, {trim}, {trim down},
         {trim back}, {bring down}]
     3: turn sharply; change direction abruptly; "The car cut to the
        left at the intersection"; "The motorbike veered to the
        right" [syn: {swerve}, {sheer}, {curve}, {trend}, {veer},
        {slue}, {slew}]
     4: make an incision or separation; "cut along the dotted line"
     5: discharge from a group; "The coach cut two players from the
        team"
     6: form by probing, penetrating, or digging; "cut a hole"; "cut
        trenches"; "The sweat cut little rivulets into her face"
     7: style and tailor in a certain fashion; "cut a dress" [syn: {tailor}]
     8: hit (a ball) with a spin so that it turns in the opposite
        direction; "cut a pingpong ball"
     9: make out and issue; "write out a check"; "cut a ticket";
        "Please make the check out to me" [syn: {write out}, {issue},
         {make out}]
     10: cut and assemble the components of; "edit film"; "cut
         recording tape" [syn: {edit}, {edit out}]
     11: intentionally fail to attend; "cut class" [syn: {skip}]
     12: informal: be able to manage or manage successfully; "I can't
         hack it anymore"; "she could not cut the long days in the
         office" [syn: {hack}]
     13: give the appearance or impression of; "cut a nice figure"
     14: move (one's fist); "his opponent cut upward toward his chin"
     15: pass directly and often in haste; "We cut through the
         neighbor's yard to get home sooner"
     16: pass through or across; "The boat cut the water"
     17: make an abrupt change of image or sound; "cut from one scene
         to another"
     18: stop filming; "cut a movie scene"
     19: make a recording of; "cut the songs"; "She cut all of her
         major titles again"
     20: record a performance on (a medium); "cut a record"
     21: create by duplicating data; "cut a disk"; "burn a CD" [syn:
         {burn}]
     22: form or shape by cutting or incising; "cut paper dolls"
     23: perform or carry out; "cut a caper"
     24: function as a cutting instrument; "This knife cuts well"
     25: allow incision or separation; "This bread cuts easily"
     26: divide a deck of cards at random into two parts to make
         selection difficult; "Wayne cut"; "She cut the deck for a
         long time"
     27: cause to stop operating by disengaging a switch; "Turn off
         the stereo, please"; "cut the engine"; "turn out the
         lights" [syn: {switch off}, {turn off}, {turn out}] [ant:
          {switch on}]
     28: reap or harvest; "cut grain"
     29: fell by sawing; hew; "The Vietnamese cut a lot of timber
         while they occupied Cambodia"
     30: penetrate injuriously; "The glass from the shattered
         windshield cut into her forehead"
     31: refuse to acknowledge; "She cut him dead at the meeting"
         [syn: {ignore}, {disregard}, {snub}]
     32: shorten as if by severing the edges or ends of; "cut my
         hair"
     33: weed out unwanted or unnecessary things; "We had to lose
         weight, so we cut the sugar from our diet" [syn: {prune},
          {rationalize}, {rationalise}]
     34: dissolve by breaking down the fat of; "soap cuts grease"
     35: have a reducing effect; "This cuts into my earnings"
     36: cease, stop; "cut the noise"; "We had to cut short the
         conversation" [syn: {cut off}]
     37: reduce in scope while retaining essential elements; "The
         manuscript must be shortened" [syn: {abridge}, {foreshorten},
          {abbreviate}, {shorten}, {contract}, {reduce}] [ant: {elaborate}]
     38: lessen the strength or flavor of a solution or mixture; "cut
         bourbon" [syn: {dilute}, {thin}, {thin out}, {reduce}]
     39: have grow through the gums; "The baby cut a tooth"
     40: grow through the gums; "The new tooth is cutting"
     41: cut off the testicles (of male animals such as horses); "the
         vet gelded the young horse" [syn: {geld}]
     [also: {cutting}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cutting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cutting
     adj 1: (of speech) harsh or hurtful in tone or character; "cutting
            remarks"; "edged satire"; "a stinging comment" [syn: {edged},
             {stinging}]
     2: unpleasantly cold and damp; "bleak winds of the North
        Atlantic" [syn: {bleak}, {raw}]
     3: as physically painful as if caused by a sharp instrument; "a
        cutting wind"; "keen winds"; "knifelike cold"; "piercing
        knifelike pains"; "piercing cold"; "piercing criticism";
        "a stabbing pain"; "lancinating pain" [syn: {keen}, {knifelike},
         {piercing}, {stabbing}, {lancinate}, {lancinating}]
     4: suitable for cutting or severing; "a cutting tool"; "the
        cutting edge"
     n 1: the activity of selecting the scenes to be shown and putting
          them together to create a film [syn: {film editing}]
     2: a part (sometimes a root or leaf or bud) removed from a
        plant to propagate a new plant through rooting or grafting
        [syn: {slip}]
     3: the act of cutting something into parts; "his cuts were
        skillful"; "his cutting of the cake made a terrible mess"
        [syn: {cut}]
     4: a piece cut off from the main part of something
     5: an excerpt cut from a newspaper or magazine; "he searched
        through piles of letters and clippings" [syn: {clipping},
        {newspaper clipping}, {press clipping}, {press cutting}]
     6: cutting away parts to create a desired shape [syn: {carving}]
     7: the division of a deck of cards before dealing; "he insisted
        that we give him the last cut before every deal"; "the
        cutting of the cards soon became a ritual" [syn: {cut}]
     8: the act of penetrating or opening open with a sharp edge;
        "his cut in the lining revealed the hidden jewels" [syn: {cut}]
     9: the act of diluting something; "the cutting of whiskey with
        water"; "the thinning of paint with turpentine" [syn: {thinning}]
     10: the act of shortening something by cutting off the ends;
         "the barber gave him a good cut" [syn: {cut}, {cutting
         off}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
