<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>cycle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cycle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cycle
     
        &lt;unit&gt; A basic unit of computation, one period of a computer
        {clock}.
     
        Each {instruction} takes a number of clock cycles.  Often the
        computer can access its memory once on every clock cycle, and
        so one speaks also of "memory cycles".
     
        Every {hacker} wants more cycles (noted hacker {Bill Gosper}
        describes himself as a "cycle junkie").  There are only so
        many cycles per second, and when you are sharing a computer
        the cycles get divided up among the users.  The more cycles
        the computer spends working on your program rather than
        someone else's, the faster your program will run.  That's why
        every hacker wants more cycles: so he can spend less time
        waiting for the computer to respond.
     
        The use of the term "cycle" for a computer clock period can
        probably be traced back to the rotation of a generator
        generating alternating current though computers generally use
        a clock signal which is more like a {square wave}.
        Interestingly, the earliest mechanical calculators,
        e.g. Babbage's {Difference Engine}, really did have parts
        which rotated in true cycles.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1997-09-30)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cycle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cycle \Cy"cle\ (s?"k'l), n. [F. ycle, LL. cyclus, fr. Gr.
   ky`klos ring or circle, cycle; akin to Skr. cakra wheel,
   circle. See {Wheel}.]
   1. An imaginary circle or orbit in the heavens; one of the
      celestial spheres. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An interval of time in which a certain succession of
      events or phenomena is completed, and then returns again
      and again, uniformly and continually in the same order; a
      periodical space of time marked by the recurrence of
      something peculiar; as, the cycle of the seasons, or of
      the year.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wages . . . bear a full proportion . . . to the
            medium of provision during the last bad cycle of
            twenty years.                         --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An age; a long period of time.
      [1913 Webster]

            Better fifty years of Europe than a cycle of Cathay.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An orderly list for a given time; a calendar. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We . . . present our gardeners with a complete cycle
            of what is requisite to be done throughout every
            month of the year.                    --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The circle of subjects connected with the exploits of the
      hero or heroes of some particular period which have served
      as a popular theme for poetry, as the legend of Arthur and
      the knights of the Round Table, and that of Charlemagne
      and his paladins.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Bot.) One entire round in a circle or a spire; as, a
      cycle or set of leaves. --Gray.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A bicycle or tricycle, or other light velocipede.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A motorcycle.
      [PJC]

   9. (Thermodynamics) A series of operations in which heat is
      imparted to (or taken away from) a working substance which
      by its expansion gives up a part of its internal energy in
      the form of mechanical work (or being compressed increases
      its internal energy) and is again brought back to its
      original state.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. (Technology) A complete positive and negative, or forward
       and reverse, action of any periodic process, such as a
       vibration, an electric field oscillation, or a current
       alternation; one period. Hence: (Elec.) A complete
       positive and negative wave of an alternating current. The
       number of cycles (per second) is a measure of the
       frequency of an alternating current.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl. + PJC]

   {Calippic cycle}, a period of 76 years, or four Metonic
      cycles; -- so called from Calippus, who proposed it as an
      improvement on the Metonic cycle.

   {Cycle of eclipses}, a period of about 6,586 days, the time
      of revolution of the moon's node; -- called {Saros} by the
      Chaldeans.

   {Cycle of indiction}, a period of 15 years, employed in Roman
      and ecclesiastical chronology, not founded on any
      astronomical period, but having reference to certain
      judicial acts which took place at stated epochs under the
      Greek emperors.

   {Cycle of the moon}, or {Metonic cycle}, a period of 19
      years, after the lapse of which the new and full moon
      returns to the same day of the year; -- so called from
      Meton, who first proposed it.

   {Cycle of the sun}, {Solar cycle}, a period of 28 years, at
      the end of which time the days of the month return to the
      same days of the week. The dominical or Sunday letter
      follows the same order; hence the solar cycle is also
      called the {cycle of the Sunday letter}. In the Gregorian
      calendar the solar cycle is in general interrupted at the
      end of the century.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cycle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cycle \cy"cle\ (s?"k'l), v. t.
   To cause to pass through a cycle[2].
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cycle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cycle \Cy"cle\ (s?"k'l), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Cycled}. (-k'ld);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Cycling} (-kl?ng).]
   1. To pass through a cycle[2] of changes; to recur in cycles.
      --Tennyson. --Darwin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To ride a bicycle, tricycle, or other form of cycle.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cycle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cycle 1. n. The basic unit of computation. What every hacker wants more
   of (noted hacker Bill Gosper described himself as a "cycle junkie"). One
   can describe an instruction as taking so many `clock cycles'. Often the
   computer can access its memory once on every clock cycle, and so one
   speaks also of `memory cycles'. These are technical meanings of {cycle}.
   The jargon meaning comes from the observation that there are only so
   many cycles per second, and when you are sharing a computer the cycles
   get divided up among the users. The more cycles the computer spends
   working on your program rather than someone else's, the faster your
   program will run. That's why every hacker wants more cycles: so he can
   spend less time waiting for the computer to respond. 2. By extension, a
   notional unit of _human_ thought power, emphasizing that lots of things
   compete for the typical hacker's think time. "I refused to get involved
   with the Rubik's Cube back when it was big. Knew I'd burn too many
   cycles on it if I let myself." 3. vt. Syn. {bounce} (sense 4), {120
   reset}; from the phrase `cycle power'. "Cycle the machine again, that
   serial port's still hung."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>cycle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>cycle
     n 1: an interval during which a recurring sequence of events
          occurs; "the neverending cycle of the seasons" [syn: {rhythm},
           {round}]
     2: a series of poems or songs on the same theme; "schubert's
        song cycles"
     3: a periodically repeated sequence of events; "a cycle of
        reprisal and retaliation"
     4: the unit of frequency; one Hertz has a periodic interval of
        one second [syn: {Hertz}, {Hz}, {cycle per second}, {cycles/second},
         {cps}]
     5: a single complete execution of a periodically repeated
        phenomenon; "a year constitutes a cycle of the seasons"
        [syn: {oscillation}]
     6: a wheeled vehicle that has two wheels and is moved by foot
        pedals [syn: {bicycle}, {bike}, {wheel}]
     v 1: cause to go through a recurring sequence; "cycle thge
          laundry in this washing program"
     2: pass through a cycle; "This machine automatically cycles"
     3: ride a motorcycle [syn: {motorcycle}]
     4: ride a bicycle [syn: {bicycle}, {bike}, {pedal}, {wheel}]
     5: recur in repeating sequences
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
