<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>kill</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>KILL, v.t.  To create a vacancy without nominating a successor.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kill \Kill\ (k[i^]l), n.
   A kiln. [Obs.] --Fuller.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kill \Kill\, n. [D. kil.]
   A channel or arm of the sea; a river; a stream; as, the
   channel between Staten Island and Bergen Neck is the Kill van
   Kull, or the Kills; -- used also in composition; as,
   Schuylkill, Catskill, etc.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kill \Kill\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Killed} (k[i^]ld); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Killing}.] [OE. killen, kellen, cullen, to kill,
   strike; perh. the same word as cwellen, quellen, to kill (cf.
   {Quell}), or perh. rather akin to Icel. kolla to hit in the
   head, harm, kollr top, summit, head, Sw. kulle, D. kollen to
   kill with the ax.]
   1. To deprive of life, animal or vegetable, in any manner or
      by any means; to render inanimate; to put to death; to
      slay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ah, kill me with thy weapon, not with words !
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To destroy; to ruin; as, to kill one's chances; to kill
      the sale of a book. ``To kill thine honor.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her lively color kill'd with deadly cares. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to cease; to quell; to calm; to still; as, in
      seamen's language, a shower of rain kills the wind; new
      sound insultation killed the loud noises from outside.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Be comforted, good madam; the great rage,
            You see, is killed in him.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To destroy the effect of; to counteract; to neutralize;
      as, alkali kills acid.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To waste or spend unprofitably; -- usually used of time;
      as, he killed an hour waiting for the doctor to see him.
      [PJC]

   6. To cancel or forbid publication of (a report, article,
      etc.), after it has been written; as, they killed the
      article after getting threats of a lawsuit.
      [PJC]

   {To kill time}, to busy one's self with something which
      occupies the attention, or makes the time pass without
      tediousness.

   Syn: To murder; assassinate; slay; butcher; destroy. -- To
        {Kill}, {Murder}, {Assassinate}. To kill does not
        necessarily mean any more than to deprive of life. A man
        may kill another by accident or in self-defense, without
        the imputation of guilt. To murder is to kill with
        malicious forethought and intention. To assassinate is
        to murder suddenly and by stealth. The sheriff may kill
        without murdering; the duelist murders, but does not
        assassinate his antagonist; the assassin kills and
        murders.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kill \Kill\, n.
   1. The act of killing.

            ``There is none like to me!'' says the cub in the
            pride of his earliest kill.           --Kipling.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. An animal killed in the hunt, as by a beast of prey.

            If ye plunder his kill from a weaker, devour not all
            in thy pride.                         --Kipling.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>kill
     n 1: the act of terminating a life [syn: {killing}, {putting to
          death}]
     2: the destruction of an enemy plane or ship or tank or
        missile; "the pilot reported two kills during the mission"
     v 1: cause to die; put to death, usually intentionally or
          knowingly; "This man killed several people when he tried
          to rob a bank"; "The farmer killed a pig for the
          holidays"
     2: thwart the passage of; "kill a motion"; "he shot down the
        student's proposal" [syn: {shoot down}, {defeat}, {vote
        down}, {vote out}]
     3: cause the death of, without intention; "She was killed in
        the collision of three cars"
     4: end or extinguish by forceful means; "Stamp out poverty!"
        [syn: {stamp out}]
     5: be fatal; "cigarettes kill"; "drunken driving kills"
     6: be the source of great pain for; "These new shoes are
        killing me!"
     7: overwhelm with hilarity, pleasure, or admiration; "The
        comedian was so funny, he was killing me!"
     8: hit with so much force as to make a return impossible, in
        racket games; "She killed the ball"
     9: hit with great force; "He killed the ball"
     10: deprive of life; "AIDS has killed thousands in Africa"
     11: drink down entirely; "He downed three martinis before
         dinner"; "She killed a bottle of brandy that night";
         "They popped a few beer after work" [syn: {toss off}, {pop},
          {bolt down}, {belt down}, {pour down}, {down}, {drink
         down}]
     12: mark for deletion, rub off, or erase; "kill these lines in
         the President's speech" [syn: {obliterate}, {wipe out}]
     13: tire out completely; "The daily stress of her work is
         killing her"
     14: cause to cease operating; "kill the engine"
     15: destroy a vitally essential quality of or in; "Eating
         artichokes kills the taste of all other foods"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
