<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>killed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>killed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kill \Kill\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Killed} (k[i^]ld); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Killing}.] [OE. killen, kellen, cullen, to kill,
   strike; perh. the same word as cwellen, quellen, to kill (cf.
   {Quell}), or perh. rather akin to Icel. kolla to hit in the
   head, harm, kollr top, summit, head, Sw. kulle, D. kollen to
   kill with the ax.]
   1. To deprive of life, animal or vegetable, in any manner or
      by any means; to render inanimate; to put to death; to
      slay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ah, kill me with thy weapon, not with words !
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To destroy; to ruin; as, to kill one's chances; to kill
      the sale of a book. ``To kill thine honor.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her lively color kill'd with deadly cares. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to cease; to quell; to calm; to still; as, in
      seamen's language, a shower of rain kills the wind; new
      sound insultation killed the loud noises from outside.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Be comforted, good madam; the great rage,
            You see, is killed in him.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To destroy the effect of; to counteract; to neutralize;
      as, alkali kills acid.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To waste or spend unprofitably; -- usually used of time;
      as, he killed an hour waiting for the doctor to see him.
      [PJC]

   6. To cancel or forbid publication of (a report, article,
      etc.), after it has been written; as, they killed the
      article after getting threats of a lawsuit.
      [PJC]

   {To kill time}, to busy one's self with something which
      occupies the attention, or makes the time pass without
      tediousness.

   Syn: To murder; assassinate; slay; butcher; destroy. -- To
        {Kill}, {Murder}, {Assassinate}. To kill does not
        necessarily mean any more than to deprive of life. A man
        may kill another by accident or in self-defense, without
        the imputation of guilt. To murder is to kill with
        malicious forethought and intention. To assassinate is
        to murder suddenly and by stealth. The sheriff may kill
        without murdering; the duelist murders, but does not
        assassinate his antagonist; the assassin kills and
        murders.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
