<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>kit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>kit
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; ({Usenet}, possibly from {DEC}) Slang for a full
        software distribution, as opposed to a {patch} or upgrade.  A
        source software distribution that has been packaged in such a
        way that it can (theoretically) be unpacked and installed
        according to a series of steps using only standard {Unix}
        tools, and entirely documented by some reasonable chain of
        references from the top-level {README file}.  The more general
        term {distribution} may imply that special tools or more
        stringent conditions on the host environment are required.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1994-11-18)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kit \Kit\, (k[i^]t), v. t. [imp. {Kitte}.]
   To cut. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kit \Kit\, n. [See {Kitten}.]
   A kitten.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Kit fox} (Zo["o]l.), a small burrowing fox ({Vulpes velox}),
      inhabiting the region of the Rocky Mountains. It is
      brownish gray, reddish on the breast and flanks, and white
      below. Called also {swift fox}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kit \Kit\, n. [Gf. AS. cytere harp, L. cithara. Cf. {Guitar}.]
   A small violin. ``A dancing master's kit.'' --Grew.
   [1913 Webster]

         Prince Turveydrop then tinkled the strings of his kit
         with his fingers, and the young ladies stood up to
         dance.                                   --Dickens.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Kit \Kit\, n. [Cf. D. kit a large bottle, OD. kitte beaker,
   decanter.]
   1. A large bottle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A wooden tub or pail, smaller at the top than at the
      bottom; as, a kit of butter, or of mackerel. --Wright.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A straw or rush basket for fish; also, any kind of basket.
      [Prov. Eng.] --Halliwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A box for working implements.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence: A collection of tools or other objects to be used
      for a specific purpose, often contained in a box which may
      be carried conveniently; a working outfit, as of a
      workman, a soldier, and the like; as, a plumber's kit; a
      doctor's kit; a cosmetic kit; a first-aid kit.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   6. A group of separate parts, things, or individuals; -- used
      with whole, and generally contemptuously; as, the whole
      kit of them; the whole kit and kaboodle.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>kit n. [Usenet; poss. fr. {DEC} slang for a full software distribution,
   as opposed to a patch or upgrade] A source software distribution that
   has been packaged in such a way that it can (theoretically) be unpacked
   and installed according to a series of steps using only standard Unix
   tools, and entirely documented by some reasonable chain of references
   from the top-level {README file}. The more general term {distribution}
   may imply that special tools or more stringent conditions on the host
   environment are required.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>KIT
     Kernel software for Intelligent Terminals (T-Online, Telekom, BTX)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>kit
     n 1: a case for containing a set of articles
     2: gear consisting of a set of articles or tools for a
        specified purpose [syn: {outfit}]
     3: young of any of various fur-bearing animals; "a fox kit"
     v : supply with a set of articles or tools [syn: {kit out}, {kit
         up}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
