<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>kitt</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>kitt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sand \Sand\, n. [AS. sand; akin to D. zand, G. sand, OHG. sant,
   Icel. sandr, Dan. &amp; Sw. sand, Gr. ?.]
   1. Fine particles of stone, esp. of siliceous stone, but not
      reduced to dust; comminuted stone in the form of loose
      grains, which are not coherent when wet.
      [1913 Webster]

            That finer matter, called sand, is no other than
            very small pebbles.                   --Woodward.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A single particle of such stone. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The sand in the hourglass; hence, a moment or interval of
      time; the term or extent of one's life.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sands are numbered that make up my life. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. pl. Tracts of land consisting of sand, like the deserts of
      Arabia and Africa; also, extensive tracts of sand exposed
      by the ebb of the tide. ``The Libyan sands.'' --Milton.
      ``The sands o' Dee.'' --C. Kingsley.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Courage; pluck; grit. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Sand badger} (Zo["o]l.), the Japanese badger ({Meles
      ankuma}).

   {Sand bag}.
      (a) A bag filled with sand or earth, used for various
          purposes, as in fortification, for ballast, etc.
      (b) A long bag filled with sand, used as a club by
          assassins.

   {Sand ball}, soap mixed with sand, made into a ball for use
      at the toilet.

   {Sand bath}.
      (a) (Chem.) A vessel of hot sand in a laboratory, in which
          vessels that are to be heated are partially immersed.
      (b) A bath in which the body is immersed in hot sand.

   {Sand bed}, a thick layer of sand, whether deposited
      naturally or artificially; specifically, a thick layer of
      sand into which molten metal is run in casting, or from a
      reducing furnace.

   {Sand birds} (Zo["o]l.), a collective name for numerous
      species of limicoline birds, such as the sandpipers,
      plovers, tattlers, and many others; -- called also {shore
      birds}.

   {Sand blast}, a process of engraving and cutting glass and
      other hard substances by driving sand against them by a
      steam jet or otherwise; also, the apparatus used in the
      process.

   {Sand box}.
      (a) A box with a perforated top or cover, for sprinkling
          paper with sand.
      (b) A box carried on locomotives, from which sand runs on
          the rails in front of the driving wheel, to prevent
          slipping.

   {Sand-box tree} (Bot.), a tropical American tree ({Hura
      crepitans}). Its fruit is a depressed many-celled woody
      capsule which, when completely dry, bursts with a loud
      report and scatters the seeds. See Illust. of {Regma}.

   {Sand bug} (Zo["o]l.), an American anomuran crustacean
      ({Hippa talpoidea}) which burrows in sandy seabeaches. It
      is often used as bait by fishermen. See Illust. under
      {Anomura}.

   {Sand canal} (Zo["o]l.), a tubular vessel having a calcareous
      coating, and connecting the oral ambulacral ring with the
      madreporic tubercle. It appears to be excretory in
      function.

   {Sand cock} (Zo["o]l.), the redshank. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Sand collar}. (Zo["o]l.) Same as {Sand saucer}, below.

   {Sand crab}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The lady crab.
      (b) A land crab, or ocypodian.

   {Sand crack} (Far.), a crack extending downward from the
      coronet, in the wall of a horse's hoof, which often causes
      lameness.

   {Sand cricket} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      large terrestrial crickets of the genus {Stenophelmatus}
      and allied genera, native of the sandy plains of the
      Western United States.

   {Sand cusk} (Zo["o]l.), any ophidioid fish. See {Illust.}
      under {Ophidioid}.

   {Sand dab} (Zo["o]l.), a small American flounder ({Limanda
      ferruginea}); -- called also {rusty dab}. The name is also
      applied locally to other allied species.

   {Sand darter} (Zo["o]l.), a small etheostomoid fish of the
      Ohio valley ({Ammocrypta pellucida}).

   {Sand dollar} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of small
      flat circular sea urchins, which live on sandy bottoms,
      especially {Echinarachnius parma} of the American coast.
      

   {Sand drift}, drifting sand; also, a mound or bank of drifted
      sand.

   {Sand eel}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A lant, or launce.
      (b) A slender Pacific Ocean fish of the genus
          {Gonorhynchus}, having barbels about the mouth.

   {Sand flag}, sandstone which splits up into flagstones.

   {Sand flea}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any species of flea which inhabits, or breeds in,
          sandy places, especially the common dog flea.
      (b) The chigoe.
      (c) Any leaping amphipod crustacean; a beach flea, or
          orchestian. See {Beach flea}, under {Beach}.

   {Sand flood}, a vast body of sand borne along by the wind.
      --James Bruce.

   {Sand fluke}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The sandnecker.
      (b) The European smooth dab ({Pleuronectes
          microcephalus}); -- called also {kitt}, {marysole},
          {smear dab}, {town dab}.

   {Sand fly} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of small
      dipterous flies of the genus {Simulium}, abounding on
      sandy shores, especially {Simulium nocivum} of the United
      States. They are very troublesome on account of their
      biting habits. Called also {no-see-um}, {punky}, and
      {midge}.

   {Sand gall}. (Geol.) See {Sand pipe}, below.

   {Sand grass} (Bot.), any species of grass which grows in
      sand; especially, a tufted grass ({Triplasis purpurea})
      with numerous bearded joints, and acid awl-shaped leaves,
      growing on the Atlantic coast.

   {Sand grouse} (Zo["o]l.), any one of many species of Old
      World birds belonging to the suborder Pterocletes, and
      resembling both grouse and pigeons. Called also {rock
      grouse}, {rock pigeon}, and {ganga}. They mostly belong to
      the genus {Pterocles}, as the common Indian species ({P.
      exustus}). The large sand grouse ({P. arenarius}), the
      painted sand grouse ({P. fasciatus}), and the pintail sand
      grouse ({P. alchata}) are also found in India. See Illust.
      under {Pterocletes}.

   {Sand hill}, a hill of sand; a dune.

   {Sand-hill crane} (Zo["o]l.), the American brown crane ({Grus
      Mexicana}).

   {Sand hopper} (Zo["o]l.), a beach flea; an orchestian.

   {Sand hornet} (Zo["o]l.), a sand wasp.

   {Sand lark}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A small lark ({Alaudala raytal}), native of India.
      (b) A small sandpiper, or plover, as the ringneck, the
          sanderling, and the common European sandpiper.
      (c) The Australian red-capped dotterel ({[AE]gialophilus
          ruficapillus}); -- called also {red-necked plover}.

   {Sand launce} (Zo["o]l.), a lant, or launce.

   {Sand lizard} (Zo["o]l.), a common European lizard ({Lacerta
      agilis}).

   {Sand martin} (Zo["o]l.), the bank swallow.

   {Sand mole} (Zo["o]l.), the coast rat.

   {Sand monitor} (Zo["o]l.), a large Egyptian lizard ({Monitor
      arenarius}) which inhabits dry localities.

   {Sand mouse} (Zo["o]l.), the dunlin. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Sand myrtle}. (Bot.) See under {Myrtle}.

   {Sand partridge} (Zo["o]l.), either of two small Asiatic
      partridges of the genus {Ammoperdix}. The wings are long
      and the tarsus is spurless. One species ({A. Heeji})
      inhabits Palestine and Arabia. The other species ({A.
      Bonhami}), inhabiting Central Asia, is called also {seesee
      partridge}, and {teehoo}.

   {Sand picture}, a picture made by putting sand of different
      colors on an adhesive surface.

   {Sand pike}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The sauger.
      (b) The lizard fish.

   {Sand pillar}, a sand storm which takes the form of a
      whirling pillar in its progress in desert tracts like
      those of the Sahara and Mongolia.

   {Sand pipe} (Geol.), a tubular cavity, from a few inches to
      several feet in depth, occurring especially in calcareous
      rocks, and often filled with gravel, sand, etc.; -- called
      also {sand gall}.

   {Sand pride} (Zo["o]l.), a small British lamprey now
      considered to be the young of larger species; -- called
      also {sand prey}.

   {Sand pump}, in artesian well boring, a long, slender bucket
      with a valve at the bottom for raising sand from the well.
      

   {Sand rat} (Zo["o]l.), the pocket gopher.

   {Sand rock}, a rock made of cemented sand.

   {Sand runner} (Zo["o]l.), the turnstone.

   {Sand saucer} (Zo["o]l.), the mass of egg capsules, or
      o["o]thec[ae], of any mollusk of the genus {Natica} and
      allied genera. It has the shape of a bottomless saucer,
      and is coated with fine sand; -- called also {sand
      collar}.

   {Sand screw} (Zo["o]l.), an amphipod crustacean
      ({Lepidactylis arenarius}), which burrows in the sandy
      seabeaches of Europe and America.

   {Sand shark} (Zo["o]l.), an American shark ({Odontaspis
      littoralis}) found on the sandy coasts of the Eastern
      United States; -- called also {gray shark}, and {dogfish
      shark}. See Illust. under {Remora}.

   {Sand skink} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of Old
      World lizards belonging to the genus {Seps}; as, the
      ocellated sand skink ({Seps ocellatus}) of Southern
      Europe.

   {Sand skipper} (Zo["o]l.), a beach flea, or orchestian.

   {Sand smelt} (Zo["o]l.), a silverside.

   {Sand snake}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any one of several species of harmless burrowing
          snakes of the genus {Eryx}, native of Southern Europe,
          Africa, and Asia, especially {E. jaculus} of India and
          {E. Johnii}, used by snake charmers.
      (b) Any innocuous South African snake of the genus
          {Psammophis}, especially {P. sibilans}.

   {Sand snipe} (Zo["o]l.), the sandpiper.

   {Sand star} (Zo["o]l.), an ophiurioid starfish living on
      sandy sea bottoms; a brittle star.

   {Sand storm}, a cloud of sand driven violently by the wind.
      

   {Sand sucker}, the sandnecker.

   {Sand swallow} (Zo["o]l.), the bank swallow. See under
      {Bank}.

   {Sand trap}, (Golf) a shallow pit on a golf course having a
      layer of sand in it, usually located near a green, and
      designed to function as a hazard, due to the difficulty of
      hitting balls effectively from such a position.

   {Sand tube}, a tube made of sand. Especially:
      (a) A tube of vitrified sand, produced by a stroke of
          lightning; a fulgurite.
      (b) (Zo["o]l.) Any tube made of cemented sand.
      (c) (Zo["o]l.) In starfishes, a tube having calcareous
          particles in its wall, which connects the oral water
          tube with the madreporic plate.

   {Sand viper}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Hognose snake}.

   {Sand wasp} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      hymenopterous insects belonging to the families
      {Pompilid[ae]} and {Spherid[ae]}, which dig burrows in
      sand. The female provisions the nest with insects or
      spiders which she paralyzes by stinging, and which serve
      as food for her young.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
