<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sacred</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sacred</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SACRED, adj.  Dedicated to some religious purpose; having a divine
character; inspiring solemn thoughts or emotions; as, the Dalai Lama
of Thibet; the Moogum of M'bwango; the temple of Apes in Ceylon; the
Cow in India; the Crocodile, the Cat and the Onion of ancient Egypt;
the Mufti of Moosh; the hair of the dog that bit Noah, etc.

    All things are either sacred or profane.
    The former to ecclesiasts bring gain;
    The latter to the devil appertain.
                                                       Dumbo Omohundro


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sacred</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sacred
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; Reserved for exclusive use by something.  The term
        might mean only writable by whatever it is sacred to.
     
        For example, "Register 7 is sacred to the interrupt handler"
        would mean that if any other code changed the contents of
        register 7, dire consequences would ensue.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2002-12-30)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sacred</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sacred \Sa"cred\, a. [Originally p. p. of OE. sacren to
   consecrate, F. sacrer, fr. L. sacrare, fr. sacer sacred,
   holy, cursed. Cf. {Consecrate}, {Execrate}, {Saint},
   {Sexton}.]
   1. Set apart by solemn religious ceremony; especially, in a
      good sense, made holy; set apart to religious use;
      consecrated; not profane or common; as, a sacred place; a
      sacred day; sacred service.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Relating to religion, or to the services of religion; not
      secular; religious; as, sacred history.
      [1913 Webster]

            Smit with the love of sacred song.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Designated or exalted by a divine sanction; possessing the
      highest title to obedience, honor, reverence, or
      veneration; entitled to extreme reverence; venerable.
      [1913 Webster]

            Such neighbor nearness to our sacred [royal] blood
            Should nothing privilege him.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Poet and saint to thee alone were given,
            The two most sacred names of earth and heaven.
                                                  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, not to be profaned or violated; inviolable.
      [1913 Webster]

            Secrets of marriage still are sacred held. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Consecrated; dedicated; devoted; -- with to.
      [1913 Webster]

            A temple, sacred to the queen of love. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Solemnly devoted, in a bad sense, as to evil, vengeance,
      curse, or the like; accursed; baleful. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            But, to destruction sacred and devote. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Society of the Sacred Heart} (R.C. Ch.), a religious order
      of women, founded in France in 1800, and approved in 1826.
      It was introduced into America in 1817. The members of the
      order devote themselves to the higher branches of female
      education.

   {Sacred baboon}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Hamadryas}.

   {Sacred bean} (Bot.), a seed of the Oriental lotus ({Nelumbo
      speciosa} or {Nelumbium speciosum}), a plant resembling a
      water lily; also, the plant itself. See {Lotus}.

   {Sacred beetle} (Zo["o]l.) See {Scarab}.

   {Sacred canon}. See {Canon}, n., 3.

   {Sacred fish} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      fresh-water African fishes of the family {Mormyrid[ae]}.
      Several large species inhabit the Nile and were considered
      sacred by the ancient Egyptians; especially {Mormyrus
      oxyrhynchus}.

   {Sacred ibis}. See {Ibis}.

   {Sacred monkey}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any Asiatic monkey of the genus {Semnopithecus},
          regarded as sacred by the Hindoos; especially, the
          entellus. See {Entellus}.
      (b) The sacred baboon. See {Hamadryas}.
      (c) The bhunder, or rhesus monkey.

   {Sacred place} (Civil Law), the place where a deceased person
      is buried.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Holy; divine; hallowed; consecrated; dedicated; devoted;
        religious; venerable; reverend.
        [1913 Webster] -- {Sa"cred*ly}, adv. -- {Sa"cred*ness},
        n.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sacred</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sacred adj. Reserved for the exclusive use of something (an extension
   of the standard meaning). Often means that anyone may look at the sacred
   object, but clobbering it will screw whatever it is sacred to. The
   comment "Register 7 is sacred to the interrupt handler" appearing in a
   program would be interpreted by a hacker to mean that if any _other_
   part of the program changes the contents of register 7, dire
   consequences are likely to ensue.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sacred</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sacred
     adj 1: concerned with religion or religious purposes; "sacred
            texts"; "sacred rites"; "sacred music" [ant: {profane}]
     2: worthy of respect or dedication; "saw motherhood as woman's
        sacred calling"
     3: made or declared or believed to be holy; devoted to a deity
        or some religious ceremony or use; "a consecrated chursh";
        "the sacred mosque"; "sacred elephants"; "sacred bread and
        wine"; "sanctified wine" [syn: {consecrated}, {sanctified}]
     4: worthy of religious veneration; "the sacred name of Jesus";
        "Jerusalem's hallowed soil" [syn: {hallowed}]
     5: (often followed by `to') devoted exclusively to a single use
        or purpose or person; "a fund sacred to charity"; "a
        morning hour sacred to study"; "a private office sacred to
        the President"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
