<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>safe</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>safe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>safe
     
        A safe program analysis is one which will not reach invalid
        conclusions about the behaviour of the program.  This may
        involve making safe approximations to properties of parts of
        the program.  A safe approximation is one which gives less
        information.
     
        For example, strictness analysis aims to answer the question
        "will this function evaluate its argument"?.  The two possible
        results are "definitely" and "don't know".  A safe
        approximation for "definitely" is "don't know".  The two
        possible results correspond to the two sets: "the set of all
        functions which evaluate their argument" and "all functions".
        A set can be safely approximated by another which contains it.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>safe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Safe \Safe\, n.
   A place for keeping things in safety. Specifically:
   (a) A strong and fireproof receptacle (as a movable chest of
       steel, etc., or a closet or vault of brickwork) for
       containing money, valuable papers, or the like.
   (b) A ventilated or refrigerated chest or closet for securing
       provisions from noxious animals or insects.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>safe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Safe \Safe\, a. [Compar. {Safer}; superl. {Safest}.] [OE. sauf,
   F. sauf, fr. L. salvus, akin to salus health, welfare,
   safety. Cf. {Salute}, {Salvation}, {Sage} a plant, {Save},
   {Salvo} an exception.]
   1. Free from harm, injury, or risk; untouched or unthreatened
      by danger or injury; unharmed; unhurt; secure; whole; as,
      safe from disease; safe from storms; safe from foes. ``And
      ye dwelled safe.'' --1 Sam. xii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

            They escaped all safe to land.        --Acts xxvii.
                                                  44.
      [1913 Webster]

            Established in a safe, unenvied throne. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Conferring safety; securing from harm; not exposing to
      danger; confining securely; to be relied upon; not
      dangerous; as, a safe harbor; a safe bridge, etc. ``The
      man of safe discretion.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The King of heaven hath doomed
            This place our dungeon, not our safe retreat.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Incapable of doing harm; no longer dangerous; in secure
      care or custody; as, the prisoner is safe.
      [1913 Webster]

            But Banquo's safe?
            Ay, my good lord, safe in a ditch he bides. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Safe hit} (Baseball), a hit which enables the batter to get
      to first base even if no error is made by the other side.

   {safe house}, a residence where a person in hiding from the
      authorities or other persons may stay without being
      discovered.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Secure; unendangered; sure.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>safe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Safe \Safe\, v. t.
   To render safe; to make right. [Obs.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>safe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SAFE
     Security And Freedom through Encryption [law] (USA, cryptography)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>safe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>safe
     adj 1: free from danger or the risk of harm; "a safe trip"; "you
            will be safe here"; "a safe place"; "a safe bet" [ant:
             {dangerous}]
     2: of an undertaking
     3: having reached a base without being put out; "the runner was
        called safe when the baseman dropped the ball" [syn: {safe(p)}]
        [ant: {out(p)}]
     4: financially sound; "a good investment"; "a secure
        investment" [syn: {dependable}, {good}, {secure}]
     5: in safekeeping; "your secret is safe with me"
     n 1: strongbox where valuables can be kept safe
     2: a ventilated or refrigerated cupboard for securing
        provisions from pests
     3: contraceptive device consisting of a thin rubber or latex
        sheath worn over the penis during intercourse [syn: {condom},
         {rubber}, {safety}, {prophylactic}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
