<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sail</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SAIL
     
        1. &lt;body, education&gt; {Stanford Artificial Intelligence
        Laboratory}.
     
        2. &lt;language&gt; {Stanford Artificial Intelligence Language}.
     
        3. &lt;language&gt; An early system on the {Larc} computer.
     
        [Listed in CACM 2(5):16, May 1959].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2001-06-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sail \Sail\, n. [OE. seil, AS. segel, segl; akin to D. zeil,
   OHG. segal, G. &amp; Sw. segel, Icel. segl, Dan. seil. [root]
   153.]
   1. An extent of canvas or other fabric by means of which the
      wind is made serviceable as a power for propelling vessels
      through the water.
      [1913 Webster]

            Behoves him now both sail and oar.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything resembling a sail, or regarded as a sail.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A wing; a van. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Like an eagle soaring
            To weather his broad sails.           --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The extended surface of the arm of a windmill.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A sailing vessel; a vessel of any kind; a craft.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense, the plural has usually the same form as
         the singular; as, twenty sail were in sight.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. A passage by a sailing vessel; a journey or excursion upon
      the water.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sails are of two general kinds, {fore-and-aft sails},
         and {square sails}. Square sails are always bent to
         yards, with their foot lying across the line of the
         vessel. Fore-and-aft sails are set upon stays or gaffs
         with their foot in line with the keel. A fore-and-aft
         sail is triangular, or quadrilateral with the after
         leech longer than the fore leech. Square sails are
         quadrilateral, but not necessarily square. See Phrases
         under {Fore}, a., and {Square}, a.; also, {Bark},
         {Brig}, {Schooner}, {Ship}, {Stay}.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Sail burton} (Naut.), a purchase for hoisting sails aloft
      for bending.

   {Sail fluke} (Zo["o]l.), the whiff.

   {Sail hook}, a small hook used in making sails, to hold the
      seams square.

   {Sail loft}, a loft or room where sails are cut out and made.
      

   {Sail room} (Naut.), a room in a vessel where sails are
      stowed when not in use.

   {Sail yard} (Naut.), the yard or spar on which a sail is
      extended.

   {Shoulder-of-mutton sail} (Naut.), a triangular sail of
      peculiar form. It is chiefly used to set on a boat's mast.
      

   {To crowd sail}. (Naut.) See under {Crowd}.

   {To loose sails} (Naut.), to unfurl or spread sails.

   {To make sail} (Naut.), to extend an additional quantity of
      sail.

   {To set a sail} (Naut.), to extend or spread a sail to the
      wind.

   {To set sail} (Naut.), to unfurl or spread the sails; hence,
      to begin a voyage.

   {To shorten sail} (Naut.), to reduce the extent of sail, or
      take in a part.

   {To strike sail} (Naut.), to lower the sails suddenly, as in
      saluting, or in sudden gusts of wind; hence, to
      acknowledge inferiority; to abate pretension.

   {Under sail}, having the sails spread.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sail \Sail\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sailed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sailing}.] [AS. segelian, seglian. See {Sail}, n.]
   1. To be impelled or driven forward by the action of wind
      upon sails, as a ship on water; to be impelled on a body
      of water by the action of steam or other power.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move through or on the water; to swim, as a fish or a
      water fowl.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be conveyed in a vessel on water; to pass by water; as,
      they sailed from London to Canton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To set sail; to begin a voyage.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To move smoothly through the air; to glide through the air
      without apparent exertion, as a bird.
      [1913 Webster]

            As is a winged messenger of heaven, . . .
            When he bestrides the lazy pacing clouds,
            And sails upon the bosom of the air.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sail \Sail\, v. t.
   1. To pass or move upon, as in a ship, by means of sails;
      hence, to move or journey upon (the water) by means of
      steam or other force.
      [1913 Webster]

            A thousand ships were manned to sail the sea.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fly through; to glide or move smoothly through.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sublime she sails
            The a["e]rial space, and mounts the wing[`e]d gales.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To direct or manage the motion of, as a vessel; as, to
      sail one's own ship. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SAIL /sayl/, not /S-A-I-L/ n. 1. The Stanford Artificial Intelligence
   Lab. An important site in the early development of LISP; with the MIT AI
   Lab, BBN, CMU, XEROX PARC, and the Unix community, one of the major
   wellsprings of technical innovation and hacker-culture traditions (see
   the {{WAITS}} entry for details). The SAIL machines were shut down in
   late May 1990, scant weeks after the MIT AI Lab's ITS cluster was
   officially decommissioned. 2. The Stanford Artificial Intelligence
   Language used at SAIL (sense 1). It was an Algol-60 derivative with a
   coroutining facility and some new data types intended for building
   search trees and association lists.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SAIL
     Stanford Artificial Intelligence Laboratory [language] (USA)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sail
     n 1: a large piece of fabric (as canvas) by means of which wind
          is used to propel a sailing vessel [syn: {canvas}, {canvass},
           {sheet}]
     2: an ocean trip taken for pleasure [syn: {cruise}]
     v 1: traverse or travel by ship on (a body of water); "We sailed
          the Atlantic"; "He sailed the Pacific all alone"
     2: move with sweeping, effortless, gliding motions; "The diva
        swept into the room"; "Shreds of paper sailed through the
        air"; "The searchlights swept across the sky" [syn: {sweep}]
     3: travel in a boat propelled by wind; "I love sailing,
        especially on the open sea"
     4: travel by boat on a boat propelled by wind or by other
        means; "The QE2 will sail to Southampton tomorrow" [syn: {voyage},
         {navigate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
