<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sally</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sally</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sally \Sal"ly\ (s[a^]l"l[y^]), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sallied}
   (-l[i^]d); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Sallying}.] [F. saillir, fr. L.
   salire to leap, spring, akin to Gr. "a`llesqai; cf. Skr.
   s[.r] to go, to flow. Cf. {Salient}, {Assail}, {Assault},
   {Exult}, {Insult}, {Saltation}, {Saltire}.]
   To leap or rush out; to burst forth; to issue suddenly; as a
   body of troops from a fortified place to attack besiegers; to
   make a sally.
   [1913 Webster]

         They break the truce, and sally out by night. --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]

         The foe retires, -- she heads the sallying host.
                                                  --Byron.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sally</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sally \Sal"ly\, n.; pl. {Sallies}. [F. saillie, fr. saillir. See
   Sally, v.]
   1. A leaping forth; a darting; a spring.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A rushing or bursting forth; a quick issue; a sudden
      eruption; specifically, an issuing of troops from a place
      besieged to attack the besiegers; a sortie.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sallies were made by the Spaniards, but they were
            beaten in with loss.                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An excursion from the usual track; range; digression;
      deviation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every one shall know a country better that makes
            often sallies into it, and traverses it up and down,
            than he that . . . goes still round in the same
            track.                                --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A flight of fancy, liveliness, wit, or the like; a
      flashing forth of a quick and active mind.
      [1913 Webster]

            The unaffected mirth with which she enjoyed his
            sallies.                              --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Transgression of the limits of soberness or steadiness;
      act of levity; wild gayety; frolic; escapade.
      [1913 Webster]

            The excursion was esteemed but a sally of youth.
                                                  --Sir H.
                                                  Wotton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Sally port}.
      (a) (Fort.) A postern gate, or a passage underground, from
          the inner to the outer works, to afford free egress
          for troops in a sortie.
      (b) (Naval) A large port on each quarter of a fireship,
          for the escape of the men into boats when the train is
          fired; a large port in an old-fashioned three-decker
          or a large modern ironclad.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sally</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sally
     n 1: witty remark [syn: {wisecrack}, {crack}, {quip}]
     2: a military action in which besieged troops burst forth from
        their position [syn: {sortie}]
     3: a venture off the beaten path; "a sally into the wide world
        beyond his home" [syn: {sallying forth}]
     [also: {sallied}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
