<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>salt</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Salt
   used to season food (Job 6:6), and mixed with the fodder of
   cattle (Isa. 30:24, "clean;" in marg. of R.V. "salted"). All
   meat-offerings were seasoned with salt (Lev. 2:13). To eat salt
   with one is to partake of his hospitality, to derive subsistence
   from him; and hence he who did so was bound to look after his
   host's interests (Ezra 4:14, "We have maintenance from the
   king's palace;" A.V. marg., "We are salted with the salt of the
   palace;" R.V., "We eat the salt of the palace").
   
     A "covenant of salt" (Num. 18:19; 2 Chr. 13:5) was a covenant
   of perpetual obligation. New-born children were rubbed with salt
   (Ezek. 16:4). Disciples are likened unto salt, with reference to
   its cleansing and preserving uses (Matt. 5:13). When Abimelech
   took the city of Shechem, he sowed the place with salt, that it
   might always remain a barren soil (Judg. 9:45). Sir Lyon
   Playfair argues, on scientific grounds, that under the generic
   name of "salt," in certain passages, we are to understand
   petroleum or its residue asphalt. Thus in Gen. 19:26 he would
   read "pillar of asphalt;" and in Matt. 5:13, instead of "salt,"
   "petroleum," which loses its essence by exposure, as salt does
   not, and becomes asphalt, with which pavements were made.
   
     The Jebel Usdum, to the south of the Dead Sea, is a mountain
   of rock salt about 7 miles long and from 2 to 3 miles wide and
   some hundreds of feet high.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>salt
     
        A tiny bit of near-random data inserted where too much
        regularity would be undesirable; a data {frob} (sense 1).  For
        example, the Unix crypt(3) manual page mentions that "the salt
        string is used to perturb the DES algorithm in one of 4096
        different ways."
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SALT
     
        1. Symbolic Assembly Language Trainer.  Assembly-like language
        implemented in BASIC by Kevin Stock, now at Encore in France.
     
        2. Sam And Lincoln Threaded language.  A threaded extensible
        variant of BASIC.  "SALT", S.D. Fenster et al, BYTE (Jun 1985)
        p.147.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Salt \Salt\, n. [AS. sealt; akin to OS. &amp; OFries. salt, D. zout,
   G. salz, Icel., Sw., &amp; Dan. salt, L. sal, Gr. ?, Russ. sole,
   Ir. &amp; Gael. salann, W. halen, of unknown origin. Cf. {Sal},
   {Salad}, {Salary}, {Saline}, {Sauce}, {Sausage}.]
   1. The chloride of sodium, a substance used for seasoning
      food, for the preservation of meat, etc. It is found
      native in the earth, and is also produced, by evaporation
      and crystallization, from sea water and other water
      impregnated with saline particles.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, flavor; taste; savor; smack; seasoning.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though we are justices and doctors and churchmen . .
            . we have some salt of our youth in us. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, also, piquancy; wit; sense; as, Attic salt.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A dish for salt at table; a saltcellar.
      [1913 Webster]

            I out and bought some things; among others, a dozen
            of silver salts.                      --Pepys.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A sailor; -- usually qualified by old. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Around the door are generally to be seen, laughing
            and gossiping, clusters of old salts. --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Chem.) The neutral compound formed by the union of an
      acid and a base; thus, sulphuric acid and iron form the
      salt sulphate of iron or green vitriol.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Except in case of ammonium salts, accurately speaking,
         it is the acid radical which unites with the base or
         basic radical, with the elimination of hydrogen, of
         water, or of analogous compounds as side products. In
         the case of diacid and triacid bases, and of dibasic
         and tribasic acids, the mutual neutralization may vary
         in degree, producing respectively basic, neutral, or
         acid salts. See Phrases below.
         [1913 Webster]

   7. Fig.: That which preserves from corruption or error; that
      which purifies; a corrective; an antiseptic; also, an
      allowance or deduction; as, his statements must be taken
      with a grain of salt.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye are the salt of the earth.         --Matt. v. 13.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. pl. Any mineral salt used as an aperient or cathartic,
      especially Epsom salts, Rochelle salt, or Glauber's salt.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. pl. Marshes flooded by the tide. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Above the salt}, {Below the salt}, phrases which have
      survived the old custom, in the houses of people of rank,
      of placing a large saltcellar near the middle of a long
      table, the places above which were assigned to the guests
      of distinction, and those below to dependents, inferiors,
      and poor relations. See {Saltfoot}.
      [1913 Webster]

            His fashion is not to take knowledge of him that is
            beneath him in clothes. He never drinks below the
            salt.                                 --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Acid salt} (Chem.)
      (a) A salt derived from an acid which has several
          replaceable hydrogen atoms which are only partially
          exchanged for metallic atoms or basic radicals; as,
          acid potassium sulphate is an acid salt.
      (b) A salt, whatever its constitution, which merely gives
          an acid reaction; thus, copper sulphate, which is
          composed of a strong acid united with a weak base, is
          an acid salt in this sense, though theoretically it is
          a neutral salt.

   {Alkaline salt} (Chem.), a salt which gives an alkaline
      reaction, as sodium carbonate.

   {Amphid salt} (Old Chem.), a salt of the oxy type, formerly
      regarded as composed of two oxides, an acid and a basic
      oxide. [Obsolescent]

   {Basic salt} (Chem.)
      (a) A salt which contains more of the basic constituent
          than is required to neutralize the acid.
      (b) An alkaline salt.

   {Binary salt} (Chem.), a salt of the oxy type conveniently
      regarded as composed of two ingredients (analogously to a
      haloid salt), viz., a metal and an acid radical.

   {Double salt} (Chem.), a salt regarded as formed by the union
      of two distinct salts, as common alum, potassium aluminium
      sulphate. See under {Double}.

   {Epsom salts}. See in the Vocabulary.

   {Essential salt} (Old Chem.), a salt obtained by
      crystallizing plant juices.

   {Ethereal salt}. (Chem.) See under {Ethereal}.

   {Glauber's salt} or {Glauber's salts}. See in Vocabulary.

   {Haloid salt} (Chem.), a simple salt of a halogen acid, as
      sodium chloride.

   {Microcosmic salt}. (Chem.). See under {Microcosmic}.

   {Neutral salt}. (Chem.)
      (a) A salt in which the acid and base (in theory)
          neutralize each other.
      (b) A salt which gives a neutral reaction.

   {Oxy salt} (Chem.), a salt derived from an oxygen acid.

   {Per salt} (Old Chem.), a salt supposed to be derived from a
      peroxide base or analogous compound. [Obs.]

   {Permanent salt}, a salt which undergoes no change on
      exposure to the air.

   {Proto salt} (Chem.), a salt derived from a protoxide base or
      analogous compound.

   {Rochelle salt}. See under {Rochelle}.

   {Salt of amber} (Old Chem.), succinic acid.

   {Salt of colcothar} (Old Chem.), green vitriol, or sulphate
      of iron.

   {Salt of hartshorn}. (Old Chem.)
      (a) Sal ammoniac, or ammonium chloride.
      (b) Ammonium carbonate. Cf. {Spirit of hartshorn}, under
          {Hartshorn}.

   {Salt of lemons}. (Chem.) See {Salt of sorrel}, below.

   {Salt of Saturn} (Old Chem.), sugar of lead; lead acetate; --
      the alchemical name of lead being Saturn.

   {Salt of Seignette}. Same as {Rochelle salt}.

   {Salt of soda} (Old Chem.), sodium carbonate.

   {Salt of sorrel} (Old Chem.), acid potassium oxalate, or
      potassium quadroxalate, used as a solvent for ink stains;
      -- so called because found in the sorrel, or Oxalis. Also
      sometimes inaccurately called {salt of lemon}.

   {Salt of tartar} (Old Chem.), potassium carbonate; -- so
      called because formerly made by heating cream of tartar,
      or potassium tartrate. [Obs.]

   {Salt of Venus} (Old Chem.), blue vitriol; copper sulphate;
      -- the alchemical name of copper being Venus.

   {Salt of wisdom}. See {Alembroth}.

   {Sedative salt} (Old Med. Chem.), boric acid.

   {Sesqui salt} (Chem.), a salt derived from a sesquioxide base
      or analogous compound.

   {Spirit of salt}. (Chem.) See under {Spirit}.

   {Sulpho salt} (Chem.), a salt analogous to an oxy salt, but
      containing sulphur in place of oxygen.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Salt \Salt\, a. [Compar. {Salter}; superl. {Saltest}.] [AS.
   sealt, salt. See {Salt}, n.]
   1. Of or relating to salt; abounding in, or containing, salt;
      prepared or preserved with, or tasting of, salt; salted;
      as, salt beef; salt water. ``Salt tears.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Overflowed with, or growing in, salt water; as, a salt
      marsh; salt grass.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fig.: Bitter; sharp; pungent.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have a salt and sorry rheum offends me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Fig.: Salacious; lecherous; lustful. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Salt acid} (Chem.), hydrochloric acid.

   {Salt block}, an apparatus for evaporating brine; a salt
      factory. --Knight.

   {Salt bottom}, a flat piece of ground covered with saline
      efflorescences. [Western U.S.] --Bartlett.

   {Salt cake} (Chem.), the white caked mass, consisting of
      sodium sulphate, which is obtained as the product of the
      first stage in the manufacture of soda, according to
      Leblanc's process.

   {Salt fish}.
      (a) Salted fish, especially cod, haddock, and similar
          fishes that have been salted and dried for food.
      (b) A marine fish.

   {Salt garden}, an arrangement for the natural evaporation of
      sea water for the production of salt, employing large
      shallow basins excavated near the seashore.

   {Salt gauge}, an instrument used to test the strength of
      brine; a salimeter.

   {Salt horse}, salted beef. [Slang]

   {Salt junk}, hard salt beef for use at sea. [Slang]

   {Salt lick}. See {Lick}, n.

   {Salt marsh}, grass land subject to the overflow of salt
      water.

   {Salt-marsh caterpillar} (Zo["o]l.), an American bombycid
      moth ({Spilosoma acr[ae]a} which is very destructive to
      the salt-marsh grasses and to other crops. Called also
      {woolly bear}. See Illust. under {Moth}, {Pupa}, and
      {Woolly bear}, under {Woolly}.

   {Salt-marsh fleabane} (Bot.), a strong-scented composite herb
      ({Pluchea camphorata}) with rayless purplish heads,
      growing in salt marshes.

   {Salt-marsh hen} (Zo["o]l.), the clapper rail. See under
      {Rail}.

   {Salt-marsh terrapin} (Zo["o]l.), the diamond-back.

   {Salt mine}, a mine where rock salt is obtained.

   {Salt pan}.
      (a) A large pan used for making salt by evaporation; also,
          a shallow basin in the ground where salt water is
          evaporated by the heat of the sun.
      (b) pl. Salt works.

   {Salt pit}, a pit where salt is obtained or made.

   {Salt rising}, a kind of yeast in which common salt is a
      principal ingredient. [U.S.]

   {Salt raker}, one who collects salt in natural salt ponds, or
      inclosures from the sea.

   {Salt sedative} (Chem.), boracic acid. [Obs.]

   {Salt spring}, a spring of salt water.

   {Salt tree} (Bot.), a small leguminous tree ({Halimodendron
      argenteum}) growing in the salt plains of the Caspian
      region and in Siberia.

   {Salt water}, water impregnated with salt, as that of the
      ocean and of certain seas and lakes; sometimes, also,
      tears.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mine eyes are full of tears, I can not see;
            And yet salt water blinds them not so much
            But they can see a sort of traitors here. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Salt-water sailor}, an ocean mariner.

   {Salt-water tailor}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Bluefish}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Salt \Salt\, v. i.
   To deposit salt as a saline solution; as, the brine begins to
   salt.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Salt \Salt\, n. [L. saltus, fr. salire to leap.]
   The act of leaping or jumping; a leap. [Obs.] --B. Jonson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Salt \Salt\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Salted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Salting}.]
   1. To sprinkle, impregnate, or season with salt; to preserve
      with salt or in brine; to supply with salt; as, to salt
      fish, beef, or pork; to salt cattle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fill with salt between the timbers and planks, as a
      ship, for the preservation of the timber.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To salt a mine}, to artfully deposit minerals in a mine in
      order to deceive purchasers regarding its value. [Cant]

   {To salt away}, {To salt down}, to prepare with, or pack in,
      salt for preserving, as meat, eggs, etc.; hence,
      colloquially, to save, lay up, or invest sagely, as money.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>salt n. A tiny bit of near-random data inserted where too much
   regularity would be undesirable; a data {frob} (sense 1). For example,
   the Unix crypt(3) man page mentions that "the salt string is used to
   perturb the DES algorithm in one of 4096 different ways."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SALT
     Script Application Language for Telix
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SALT
     Suse Advanced Linux Technology (Suse, Linux)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>salt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>salt
     adj 1: containing or filled with salt; "salt water" [ant: {fresh}]
     2: of speech that is painful or bitter; "salt scorn"-
        Shakespeare; "a salt apology"
     3: one of the four basic taste sensations; like the taste of
        sea water [syn: {salty}]
     n 1: a compound formed by replacing hydrogen in an acid by a
          metal (or a radical that acts like a metal)
     2: white crystalline form of especially sodium chloride used to
        season and preserve food [syn: {table salt}, {common salt}]
     3: negotiations between the United States and the Union of
        Soviet Socialist Republics opened in 1969 in Helsinki
        designed to limit both countries' stock of nuclear weapons
        [syn: {Strategic Arms Limitation Talks}]
     4: the taste experience when salt is taken into the mouth [syn:
         {saltiness}, {salinity}]
     v 1: add salt to
     2: sprinkle as if with salt; "the rebels had salted the fields
        with mines and traps"
     3: add zest or liveliness to; "She salts her lectures with
        jokes"
     4: preserve with salt; "people used to salt meats on ships"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
