<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sanctuary</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sanctuary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sanctuary
   denotes, (1) the Holy Land (Ex. 15:17; comp. Ps. 114:2); (2) the
   temple (1 Chr. 22:19; 2 Chr. 29:21); (3) the tabernacle (Ex.
   25:8; Lev. 12:4; 21:12); (4) the holy place, the place of the
   Presence (Gr. hieron, the temple-house; not the _naos_, which is
   the temple area, with its courts and porches), Lev. 4:6; Eph.
   2:21, R.V., marg.; (5) God's holy habitation in heaven (Ps.
   102:19). In the final state there is properly "no sanctuary"
   (Rev. 21:22), for God and the Lamb "are the sanctuary" (R.V.,
   "temple"). All is there hallowed by the Divine Presence; all is
   sancturary.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sanctuary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sanctuary, TX (town, FIPS 65066)
  Location: 32.90870 N, 97.58391 W
  Population (1990): 234 (88 housing units)
  Area: 0.7 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sanctuary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sanctuary \Sanc"tu*a*ry\, n.; pl. {Sanctuaries}. [OE.
   seintuarie, OF. saintuaire, F. sanctuaire, fr. L.
   sanctuarium, from sanctus sacred, holy. See {Saint}.]
   A sacred place; a consecrated spot; a holy and inviolable
   site. Hence, specifically:
   (a) The most retired part of the temple at Jerusalem, called
       the Holy of Holies, in which was kept the ark of the
       covenant, and into which no person was permitted to enter
       except the high priest, and he only once a year, to
       intercede for the people; also, the most sacred part of
       the tabernacle; also, the temple at Jerusalem.
   (b) (Arch.) The most sacred part of any religious building,
       esp. that part of a Christian church in which the altar
       is placed.
   (c) A house consecrated to the worship of God; a place where
       divine service is performed; a church, temple, or other
       place of worship.
   (d) A sacred and inviolable asylum; a place of refuge and
       protection; shelter; refuge; protection.
       [1913 Webster]

             These laws, whoever made them, bestowed on temples
             the privilege of sanctuary.          --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

             The admirable works of painting were made fuel for
             the fire; but some relics of it took sanctuary
             under ground, and escaped the common destiny.
                                                  --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Wildlife sanctuary}, a tract of land set aside by law for
      the preservation of wildlife, in which no hunting is
      permitted.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sanctuary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sanctuary
     n 1: a consecrated place where sacred objects are kept
     2: a shelter from danger or hardship [syn: {refuge}, {asylum}]
     3: area around the altar of a church for the clergy and choir;
        often enclosed by a lattice or railing [syn: {chancel}, {bema}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
