<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>saved</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Save \Save\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Saved}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Saving}.] [OE. saven, sauven, salven, OF. salver, sauver, F.
   sauver, L. salvare, fr. salvus saved, safe. See {Safe}, a.]
   1. To make safe; to procure the safety of; to preserve from
      injury, destruction, or evil of any kind; to rescue from
      impending danger; as, to save a house from the flames.
      [1913 Webster]

            God save all this fair company.       --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            He cried, saying, Lord, save me.      --Matt. xiv.
                                                  30.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou hast . . . quitted all to save
            A world from utter loss.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Theol.) Specifically, to deliver from sin and its
      penalty; to rescue from a state of condemnation and
      spiritual death, and bring into a state of spiritual life.
      [1913 Webster]

            Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners.
                                                  --1 Tim. i.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To keep from being spent or lost; to secure from waste or
      expenditure; to lay up; to reserve.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now save a nation, and now save a groat. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To rescue from something undesirable or hurtful; to
      prevent from doing something; to spare.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll save you
            That labor, sir. All's now done.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To hinder from doing, suffering, or happening; to obviate
      the necessity of; to prevent; to spare.
      [1913 Webster]

            Will you not speak to save a lady's blush? --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To hold possession or use of; to escape loss of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Just saving the tide, and putting in a stock of
            merit.                                --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To save appearances}, to preserve a decent outside; to avoid
      exposure of a discreditable state of things.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To preserve; rescue; deliver; protect; spare; reserve;
        prevent.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>saved
     adj 1: rescued; especially from the power and consequences of sin;
            "a saved soul" [ant: {lost}]
     2: guarded from injury or destruction [syn: {protected}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
