<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>saw</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SAW, n.  A trite popular saying, or proverb.  (Figurative and
colloquial.)  So called because it makes its way into a wooden head. 
Following are examples of old saws fitted with new teeth.

        A penny saved is a penny to squander.

        A man is known by the company that he organizes.

        A bad workman quarrels with the man who calls him that.

        A bird in the hand is worth what it will bring.

        Better late than before anybody has invited you.

        Example is better than following it.

        Half a loaf is better than a whole one if there is much else.

        Think twice before you speak to a friend in need.

        What is worth doing is worth the trouble of asking somebody to
    do it.

        Least said is soonest disavowed.

        He laughs best who laughs least.

        Speak of the Devil and he will hear about it.

        Of two evils choose to be the least.

        Strike while your employer has a big contract.

        Where there's a will there's a won't.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Saw \Saw\, v. i.
   1. To use a saw; to practice sawing; as, a man saws well.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cut, as a saw; as, the saw or mill saws fast.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be cut with a saw; as, the timber saws smoothly.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Saw \Saw\, v. t. [imp. {Sawed}; p. p. {Sawed} or {Sawn}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Sawing}.]
   1. To cut with a saw; to separate with a saw; as, to saw
      timber or marble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form by cutting with a saw; as, to saw boards or
      planks, that is, to saw logs or timber into boards or
      planks; to saw shingles; to saw out a panel.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Also used figuratively; as, to saw the air.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Saw \Saw\ (s[add]),
   imp. of {See}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Saw \Saw\, n. [OE. sawe, AS. sagu; akin to secgan to say. See
   {Say}, v. t. and cf. {Saga}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Something said; speech; discourse. [Obs.] ``To hearken all
      his sawe.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A saying; a proverb; a maxim.
      [1913 Webster]

            His champions are the prophets and apostles,
            His weapons holy saws of sacred writ. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Dictate; command; decree. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            [Love] rules the creatures by his powerful saw.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Saw \Saw\, n. [OE. sawe, AS. sage; akin to D. zaag, G. s["a]ge,
   OHG. sega, saga, Dan. sav, Sw. s[*a]g, Icel. s["o]g, L.
   secare to cut, securis ax, secula sickle. Cf. {Scythe},
   {Sickle}, {Section}, {Sedge}.]
   An instrument for cutting or dividing substances, as wood,
   iron, etc., consisting of a thin blade, or plate, of steel,
   with a series of sharp teeth on the edge, which remove
   successive portions of the material by cutting and tearing.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Saw is frequently used adjectively, or as the first
         part of a compound.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Band saw}, {Crosscut saw}, etc. See under {Band},
      {Crosscut}, etc.

   {Circular saw}, a disk of steel with saw teeth upon its
      periphery, and revolved on an arbor.

   {Saw bench}, a bench or table with a flat top for for sawing,
      especially with a circular saw which projects above the
      table.

   {Saw file}, a three-cornered file, such as is used for
      sharpening saw teeth.

   {Saw frame}, the frame or sash in a sawmill, in which the
      saw, or gang of saws, is held.

   {Saw gate}, a saw frame.

   {Saw gin}, the form of cotton gin invented by Eli Whitney, in
      which the cotton fibers are drawn, by the teeth of a set
      of revolving circular saws, through a wire grating which
      is too fine for the seeds to pass.

   {Saw grass} (Bot.), any one of certain cyperaceous plants
      having the edges of the leaves set with minute sharp
      teeth, especially the {Cladium Mariscus} of Europe, and
      the {Cladium effusum} of the Southern United States. Cf.
      {Razor grass}, under {Razor}.

   {Saw log}, a log of suitable size for sawing into lumber.

   {Saw mandrel}, a mandrel on which a circular saw is fastened
      for running.

   {Saw pit}, a pit over which timbor is sawed by two men, one
      standing below the timber and the other above. --Mortimer.

   {Saw sharpener} (Zo["o]l.), the great titmouse; -- so named
      from its harsh call note. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Saw whetter} (Zo["o]l.), the marsh titmouse ({Parus
      palustris}); -- so named from its call note. [Prov. Eng.]
      

   {Scroll saw}, a ribbon of steel with saw teeth upon one edge,
      stretched in a frame and adapted for sawing curved
      outlines; also, a machine in which such a saw is worked by
      foot or power.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>See \See\ (s[=e]), v. t. [imp. {Saw} (s[add]); p. p. {Seen}
   (s[=e]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Seeing}.] [OE. seen, sen, seon,
   AS. se['o]n; akin to OFries. s[=i]a, D. zien, OS. &amp; OHG.
   sehan, G. sehen, Icel. sj[=a], Sw. se, Dan. see, Goth.
   sa['i]hwan, and probably to L. sequi to follow (and so
   originally meaning, to follow with the eyes). Gr. "e`pesqai,
   Skr. sac. Cf. {Sight}, {Sue} to follow.]
   1. To perceive by the eye; to have knowledge of the existence
      and apparent qualities of by the organs of sight; to
      behold; to descry; to view.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will now turn aside, and see this great sight.
                                                  --Ex. iii. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perceive by mental vision; to form an idea or
      conception of; to note with the mind; to observe; to
      discern; to distinguish; to understand; to comprehend; to
      ascertain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go, I pray thee, see whether it be well with thy
            brethren.                             --Gen. xxxvii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jesus saw that he answered discreetly. --Mark xii.
                                                  34.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who's so gross
            That seeth not this palpable device?  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To follow with the eyes, or as with the eyes; to watch; to
      regard attentively; to look after. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had a mind to see him out, and therefore did not
            care for contradicting him.           --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To have an interview with; especially, to make a call
      upon; to visit; as, to go to see a friend.
      [1913 Webster]

            And Samuel came no more to see Saul until the day of
            his death.                            --1 Sam. xv.
                                                  35.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To fall in with; to meet or associate with; to have
      intercourse or communication with; hence, to have
      knowledge or experience of; as, to see military service.
      [1913 Webster]

            Make us glad according to the days wherein thou hast
            afflicted us, and the years wherein we have seen
            evil.                                 --Ps. xc. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

            Verily, verily, I say unto you, if a man keep my
            saying, he shall never see death.     --John viii.
                                                  51.
      [1913 Webster]

            Improvement in wisdom and prudence by seeing men.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To accompany in person; to escort; to wait upon; as, to
      see one home; to see one aboard the cars.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. In poker and similar games at cards, to meet (a bet), or
      to equal the bet of (a player), by staking the same sum.
      ``I'll see you and raise you ten.''
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   {God you see} (or {God him see} or {God me see}, etc.), God
      keep you (him, me, etc.) in his sight; God protect you.
      [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {To see (anything) out}, to see (it) to the end; to be
      present at, work at, or attend, to the end.

   {To see stars}, to see flashes of light, like stars; --
      sometimes the result of concussion of the head. [Colloq.]
      

   {To see (one) through}, to help, watch, or guard (one) to the
      end of a course or an undertaking.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>saw
     n 1: a condensed but memorable saying embodying some important
          fact of experience that is taken as true by many people
          [syn: {proverb}, {adage}, {byword}]
     2: hand tool having a toothed blade for cutting
     3: a power tool for cutting wood [syn: {power saw}, {sawing
        machine}]
     v : cut with a saw; "saw wood for the fireplace"
     [also: {sawn}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>see
     n : the seat within a bishop's diocese where his cathedral is
         located
     adv : compare (used in texts to point the reader to another
           location in the text) [syn: {cf.}, {cf}, {confer}, {see
           also}]
     v 1: perceive by sight or have the power to perceive by sight;
          "You have to be a good observer to see all the details";
          "Can you see the bird in that tree?"; "He is blind--he
          cannot see"
     2: perceive (an idea or situation) mentally; "Now I see!"; "I
        just can't see your point"; "Does she realize how
        important this decision is?"; "I don't understand the
        idea" [syn: {understand}, {realize}, {realise}]
     3: perceive or be contemporaneous with; "We found Republicans
        winning the offices"; "You'll see a lot of cheating in
        this school"; "I want to see results"; "The 1960 saw the
        rebellion of the younger generation against established
        traditions"; "I want to see results" [syn: {witness}, {find}]
     4: imagine; conceive of; see in one's mind; "I can't see him on
        horseback!"; "I can see what will happen"; "I can see a
        risk in this strategy" [syn: {visualize}, {visualise}, {envision},
         {project}, {fancy}, {figure}, {picture}, {image}]
     5: deem to be; "She views this quite differently from me"; "I
        consider her to be shallow"; "I don't see the situation
        quite as negatively as you do" [syn: {consider}, {reckon},
         {view}, {regard}]
     6: get to know or become aware of, usually accidentally; "I
        learned that she has two grown-up children"; "I see that
        you have been promoted" [syn: {learn}, {hear}, {get word},
         {get wind}, {pick up}, {find out}, {get a line}, {discover}]
     7: see or watch; "view a show on television"; "This program
        will be seen all over the world"; "view an exhibition";
        "Catch a show on Broadway"; "see a movie" [syn: {watch}, {view},
         {catch}, {take in}]
     8: find out, learn, or determine with certainty, usually by
        making an inquiry or other effort; "I want to see whether
        she speaks French"; "See whether it works"; "find out if
        he speaks Russian"; "Check whether the train leaves on
        time" [syn: {determine}, {check}, {find out}, {ascertain},
         {watch}, {learn}]
     9: come together; "I'll probably see you at the meeting"; "How
        nice to see you again!" [syn: {meet}, {ran into}, {encounter},
         {run across}, {come across}]
     10: be careful or certain to do something; make certain of
         something; "He verified that the valves were closed";
         "See that the curtains are closed"; "control the quality
         of the product" [syn: {check}, {insure}, {see to it}, {ensure},
          {control}, {ascertain}, {assure}]
     11: go to see for professional or business reasons; "You should
         see a lawyer"; "We had to see a psychiatrist"
     12: go to see for a social visit; "I went to see my friend Mary
         the other day"
     13: visit a place, as for entertainment; "We went to see the
         Eiffel Tower in the morning" [syn: {visit}]
     14: take charge of or deal with; "Could you see about lunch?";
         "I must attend to this matter"; "She took care of this
         business" [syn: {attend}, {take care}, {look}]
     15: receive as a specified guest; "the doctor will see you now";
         "The minister doesn't see anybody before noon"
     16: date regularly; have a steady relationship with; "Did you
         know that she is seeing an older man?"; "He is dating his
         former wife again!" [syn: {go steady}, {go out}, {date}]
     17: see and understand, have a good eye; "The artist must first
         learn to see"
     18: deliberate or decide; "See whether you can come tomorrow";
         "let's see--which movie should we see tonight?"
     19: observe as if with an eye; "The camera saw the burglary and
         recorded it"
     20: observe, check out, and look over carefully or inspect; "The
         customs agent examined the baggage"; "I must see your
         passport before you can enter the country" [syn: {examine}]
     21: go or live through; "We had many trials to go through"; "he
         saw action in Viet Nam" [syn: {experience}, {undergo}, {go
         through}]
     22: accompany or escort; "I'll see you to the door" [syn: {escort}]
     23: match or meet; "I saw the bet of one of my fellow players"
     24: make sense of; assign a meaning to; "What message do you see
         in this letter?"; "How do you interpret his behavior?"
         [syn: {interpret}, {construe}]
     [also: {seen}, {saw}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>saw
     See {see}
     [also: {sawn}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
