<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>saying</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Saying \Say"ing\, n.
   That which is said; a declaration; a statement, especially a
   proverbial one; an aphorism; a proverb.
   [1913 Webster]

         Many are the sayings of the wise,
         In ancient and in modern books enrolled. --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Declaration; speech; adage; maxim; aphorism; apothegm;
        saw; proverb; byword.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Say \Say\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Said} (s[e^]d), contracted from
   sayed; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Saying}.] [OE. seggen, seyen, siggen,
   sayen, sayn, AS. secgan; akin to OS. seggian, D. zeggen, LG.
   seggen, OHG. sag[=e]n, G. sagen, Icel. segja, Sw. s["a]ga,
   Dan. sige, Lith. sakyti; cf. OL. insece tell, relate, Gr.
   'e`nnepe (for 'en-sepe), 'e`spete. Cf. {Saga}, {Saw} a
   saying.]
   1. To utter or express in words; to tell; to speak; to
      declare; as, he said many wise things.
      [1913 Webster]

            Arise, and say how thou camest here.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To repeat; to rehearse; to recite; to pronounce; as, to
      say a lesson.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of my instruction hast thou nothing bated
            In what thou hadst to say?            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            After which shall be said or sung the following
            hymn.                                 --Bk. of Com.
                                                  Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To announce as a decision or opinion; to state positively;
      to assert; hence, to form an opinion upon; to be sure
      about; to be determined in mind as to.
      [1913 Webster]

            But what it is, hard is to say.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To mention or suggest as an estimate, hypothesis, or
      approximation; hence, to suppose; -- in the imperative,
      followed sometimes by the subjunctive; as, he had, say
      fifty thousand dollars; the fox had run, say ten miles.
      [1913 Webster]

            Say, for nonpayment that the debt should double,
            Is twenty hundred kisses such a trouble? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {It is said}, or {They say}, it is commonly reported; it is
      rumored; people assert or maintain.

   {That is to say}, that is; in other words; otherwise.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>saying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>saying
     n : a word or phrase that particular people use in particular
         situations; "pardon the expression" [syn: {expression}, {locution}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
