<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>scale</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\ (sk[=a]l), n. [AS. sc[=a]le; perhaps influenced by
   the kindred Icel. sk[=a]l balance, dish, akin also to D.
   schaal a scale, bowl, shell, G. schale, OHG. sc[=a]la, Dan.
   skaal drinking cup, bowl, dish, and perh. to E. scale of a
   fish. Cf. {Scale} of a fish, {Skull} the brain case.]
   1. The dish of a balance; hence, the balance itself; an
      instrument or machine for weighing; as, to turn the scale;
      -- chiefly used in the plural when applied to the whole
      instrument or apparatus for weighing. Also used
      figuratively.
      [1913 Webster]

            Long time in even scale
            The battle hung.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The scales are turned; her kindness weighs no more
            Now than my vows.                     --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. (Astron.) The sign or constellation Libra.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Platform scale}. See under {Platform}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Scaled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Scaling}.]
   To weigh or measure according to a scale; to measure; also,
   to grade or vary according to a scale or system.
   [1913 Webster]

         Scaling his present bearing with his past. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To scale a debt, wages, etc.} or {To scale down a debt,
   wages, etc.}, to reduce a debt, etc., according to a fixed
      ratio or scale. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\, v. t.
   1. To strip or clear of scale or scales; as, to scale a fish;
      to scale the inside of a boiler.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take off in thin layers or scales, as tartar from the
      teeth; to pare off, as a surface. ``If all the mountains
      were scaled, and the earth made even.'' --T. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To scatter; to spread. [Scot. &amp; Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Gun.) To clean, as the inside of a cannon, by the
      explosion of a small quantity of powder. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\, n. [Cf. AS. scealu, scalu, a shell, parings; akin
   to D. schaal, G. schale, OHG. scala, Dan. &amp; Sw. skal a shell,
   Dan. ski[ae]l a fish scale, Goth. skalja tile, and E. shale,
   shell, and perhaps also to scale of a balance; but perhaps
   rather fr. OF. escale, escaile, F. ['e]caille scale of a
   fish, and ['e]cale shell of beans, pease, eggs, nuts, of
   German origin, and akin to Goth. skalja, G. schale. See
   {Shale}.]
   1. (Anat.) One of the small, thin, membranous, bony or horny
      pieces which form the covering of many fishes and
      reptiles, and some mammals, belonging to the dermal part
      of the skeleton, or dermoskeleton. See {Cycloid},
      {Ctenoid}, and {Ganoid}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fish that, with their fins and shining scales,
            Glide under the green wave.           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, any layer or leaf of metal or other material,
      resembling in size and thinness the scale of a fish; as, a
      scale of iron, of bone, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) One of the small scalelike structures covering
      parts of some invertebrates, as those on the wings of
      Lepidoptera and on the body of Thysanura; the elytra of
      certain annelids. See {Lepidoptera}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) A scale insect. (See below.)
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Bot.) A small appendage like a rudimentary leaf,
      resembling the scales of a fish in form, and often in
      arrangement; as, the scale of a bud, of a pine cone, and
      the like. The name is also given to the chaff on the stems
      of ferns.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The thin metallic side plate of the handle of a
      pocketknife. See Illust. of {Pocketknife}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. An incrustation deposit on the inside of a vessel in which
      water is heated, as a steam boiler.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Metal.) The thin oxide which forms on the surface of iron
      forgings. It consists essentially of the magnetic oxide,
      {Fe3O4}. Also, a similar coating upon other metals.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Covering scale} (Zo["o]l.), a hydrophyllium.

   {Ganoid scale}. (Zo["o]l.) See under {Ganoid}.

   {Scale armor} (Mil.), armor made of small metallic scales
      overlapping, and fastened upon leather or cloth.

   {Scale beetle} (Zo["o]l.), the tiger beetle.

   {Scale carp} (Zo["o]l.), a carp having normal scales.

   {Scale insect} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      small hemipterous insects belonging to the family
      {Coccid[ae]}, in which the females, when adult, become
      more or less scalelike in form. They are found upon the
      leaves and twigs of various trees and shrubs, and often do
      great damage to fruit trees. See {Orange scale},under
      {Orange}.

   {Scale moss} (Bot.), any leafy-stemmed moss of the order
      {Hepatic[ae]}; -- so called from the small imbricated
      scalelike leaves of most of the species. See {Hepatica},
      2, and {Jungermannia}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\, v. t. [Cf. It. scalare, fr. L. scalae, scala. See
   {Scale} a ladder.]
   To climb by a ladder, or as if by a ladder; to ascend by
   steps or by climbing; to clamber up; as, to scale the wall of
   a fort.
   [1913 Webster]

         Oft have I scaled the craggy oak.        --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\, v. i.
   To lead up by steps; to ascend. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Satan from hence, now on the lower stair,
         That scaled by steps of gold to heaven-gate,
         Looks down with wonder.                  --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\, v. i.
   1. To separate and come off in thin layers or lamin[ae]; as,
      some sandstone scales by exposure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those that cast their shell are the lobster and
            crab; the old skins are found, but the old shells
            never; so it is likely that they scale off. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To separate; to scatter. [Scot. &amp; Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scale \Scale\, n. [L. scalae, pl., scala staircase, ladder; akin
   to scandere to climb. See {Scan}; cf. {Escalade}.]
   1. A ladder; a series of steps; a means of ascending. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, anything graduated, especially when employed as a
      measure or rule, or marked by lines at regular intervals.
      Specifically:
      (a) A mathematical instrument, consisting of a slip of
          wood, ivory, or metal, with one or more sets of spaces
          graduated and numbered on its surface, for measuring
          or laying off distances, etc., as in drawing,
          plotting, and the like. See {Gunter's scale}.
      (b) A series of spaces marked by lines, and representing
          proportionately larger distances; as, a scale of
          miles, yards, feet, etc., for a map or plan.
      (c) A basis for a numeral system; as, the decimal scale;
          the binary scale, etc.
      (d) (Mus.) The graduated series of all the tones,
          ascending or descending, from the keynote to its
          octave; -- called also the {gamut}. It may be repeated
          through any number of octaves. See {Chromatic scale},
          {Diatonic scale}, {Major scale}, and {Minor scale},
          under {Chromatic}, {Diatonic}, {Major}, and {Minor}.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Gradation; succession of ascending and descending steps
      and degrees; progressive series; scheme of comparative
      rank or order; as, a scale of being.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is a certain scale of duties . . . which for
            want of studying in right order, all the world is in
            confusion.                            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Relative dimensions, without difference in proportion of
      parts; size or degree of the parts or components in any
      complex thing, compared with other like things;
      especially, the relative proportion of the linear
      dimensions of the parts of a drawing, map, model, etc., to
      the dimensions of the corresponding parts of the object
      that is represented; as, a map on a scale of an inch to a
      mile.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Scale of chords}, a graduated scale on which are given the
      lengths of the chords of arcs from 0[deg] to 90[deg] in a
      circle of given radius, -- used in measuring given angles
      and in plotting angles of given numbers of degrees.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>scale
     n 1: an ordered reference standard; "judging on a scale of 1 to
          10" [syn: {scale of measurement}, {graduated table}, {ordered
          series}]
     2: relative magnitude; "they entertained on a grand scale"
     3: the ratio between the size of something and a representation
        of it; "the scale of the map"; "the scale of the model"
     4: an indicator having a graduated sequence of marks
     5: a specialized leaf or bract that protects a bud or catkin
        [syn: {scale leaf}]
     6: a thin flake of dead epidermis shed from the surface of the
        skin [syn: {scurf}, {exfoliation}]
     7: (music) a series of notes differing in pitch according to a
        specific scheme (usually within an octave) [syn: {musical
        scale}]
     8: a measuring instrument for weighing; shows amount of mass
        [syn: {weighing machine}]
     9: a metal sheathing of uniform thickness (such as the shield
        attached to an artillery piece to protect the gunners)
        [syn: {plate}, {shell}]
     10: a flattened rigid plate forming part of the body covering of
         many animals
     v 1: measure by or as if by a scale; "This bike scales only 25
          pounds"
     2: pattern, make, regulate, set, measure, or estimate according
        to some rate or standard
     3: take by attacking with scaling ladders; "The troops scaled
        the walls of the fort"
     4: reach the highest point of; "We scaled the Mont Blanc" [syn:
         {surmount}]
     5: climb up by means of a ladder
     6: remove the scales from; "scale fish" [syn: {descale}]
     7: measure with or as if with scales; "scale the gold"
     8: size or measure according to a scale; "This model must be
        scaled down"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
