<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>scoop</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SCOOP
     
        Structured Concurrent Object-Oriented Prolog.
     
        ["SCOOP, Structured Concurrent Object-Oriented Prolog",
        J. Vaucher et al, in ECOOP '88, S. Gjessing et al eds, LNCS
        322, Springer 1988, pp.191-211].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scoop \Scoop\, n. [OE. scope, of Scand. origin; cf. Sw. skopa,
   akin to D. schop a shovel, G. sch["u]ppe, and also to E.
   shove. See {Shovel}.]
   1. A large ladle; a vessel with a long handle, used for
      dipping liquids; a utensil for bailing boats.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A deep shovel, or any similar implement for digging out
      and dipping or shoveling up anything; as, a flour scoop;
      the scoop of a dredging machine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Surg.) A spoon-shaped instrument, used in extracting
      certain substances or foreign bodies.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A place hollowed out; a basinlike cavity; a hollow.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some had lain in the scoop of the rock. --J. R.
                                                  Drake.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A sweep; a stroke; a swoop.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The act of scooping, or taking with a scoop or ladle; a
      motion with a scoop, as in dipping or shoveling.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. a quantity sufficient to fill a scoop; -- used especially
      for ice cream, dispensed with an ice cream scoop; as, an
      ice cream cone with two scoops.
      [PJC]

   8. an act of reporting (news, research results) before a
      rival; also called a {beat}. [Newspaper or laboratory
      cant]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   9. news or information; as, what's the scoop on John's
      divorce?. [informal]
      [PJC]

   {Scoop net}, a kind of hand net, used in fishing; also, a net
      for sweeping the bottom of a river.

   {Scoop wheel}, a wheel for raising water, having scoops or
      buckets attached to its circumference; a tympanum.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scoop \Scoop\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Scooped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Scooping}.] [OE. scopen. See {Scoop}, n.]
   1. To take out or up with, a scoop; to lade out.
      [1913 Webster]

            He scooped the water from the crystal flood.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To empty by lading; as, to scoop a well dry.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make hollow, as a scoop or dish; to excavate; to dig
      out; to form by digging or excavation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those carbuncles the Indians will scoop, so as to
            hold above a pint.                    --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scoop \Scoop\, v. t.
   to report a story first, before (a rival); to get a scoop, or
   a beat, on (a rival); -- used commonly in the passive; as, we
   were scooped. Also used in certain situations in scientific
   research, when one scientist or team of scientists reports
   their results before another who is working on the same
   problem.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Beat \Beat\, n.
   1. One that beats, or surpasses, another or others; as, the
      beat of him. [Colloq.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. The act of one that beats a person or thing; as:
      (a) (Newspaper Cant) The act of obtaining and publishing a
          piece of news by a newspaper before its competitors;
          also, the news itself; -- also called a {scoop} or
          {exclusive}.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

                It's a beat on the whole country. --Scribner's
                                                  Mag.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
      (b) (Hunting) The act of scouring, or ranging over, a
          tract of land to rouse or drive out game; also, those
          so engaged, collectively. ``Driven out in the course
          of a beat.'' --Encyc. of Sport.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

                Bears coming out of holes in the rocks at the
                last moment, when the beat is close to them.
                                                  --Encyc. of
                                                  Sport.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
      (c) (Fencing) A smart tap on the adversary's blade.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>scoop
     n 1: the quantity a scoop will hold [syn: {scoopful}]
     2: a hollow concave shape made by removing something [syn: {pocket}]
     3: a news report that is reported first by one news
        organization; "he got a scoop on the bribery of city
        officials" [syn: {exclusive}]
     4: street names for gamma hydroxybutyrate [syn: {soap}, {max},
        {liquid ecstasy}, {grievous bodily harm}, {goop}, {Georgia
        home boy}, {easy lay}]
     5: the shovel or bucket of dredge or backhoe [syn: {scoop
        shovel}]
     6: a large ladle; "he used a scoop to serve the ice cream"
     v 1: take out or up with or as if with a scoop; "scoop the sugar
          out of the container" [syn: {scoop out}, {lift out}, {scoop
          up}, {take up}]
     2: get the better of; "the goal was to best the competition"
        [syn: {outdo}, {outflank}, {trump}, {best}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
