<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>score</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>score</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Score \Score\ (sk[=o]r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Scored}
   (sk[=o]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Scoring}.]
   1. To mark with lines, scratches, or notches; to cut notches
      or furrows in; to notch; to scratch; to furrow; as, to
      score timber for hewing; to score the back with a lash.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let us score their backs.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A briar in that tangled wilderness
            Had scored her white right hand.      --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, to mark with significant lines or notches, for
      indicating or keeping account of something; as, to score a
      tally.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To mark or signify by lines or notches; to keep record or
      account of; to set down; to record; to charge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Madam, I know when,
            Instead of five, you scored me ten.   --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor need I tallies thy dear love to score. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To engrave, as upon a shield. [R.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To make a score of, as points, runs, etc., in a game.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mus.) To write down in proper order and arrangement; as,
      to score an overture for an orchestra. See {Score}, n., 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Geol.) To mark with parallel lines or scratches; as, the
      rocks of New England and the Western States were scored in
      the drift epoch.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>score</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Score \Score\ (sk[=o]r), n. [AS. scor twenty, fr. sceran,
   scieran, to shear, cut, divide; or rather the kindred Icel.
   skor incision, twenty, akin to Dan. skure a notch, Sw.
   sk[*a]ra. See {Shear}.]
   1. A notch or incision; especially, one that is made as a
      tally mark; hence, a mark, or line, made for the purpose
      of account.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whereas, before, our forefathers had no other books
            but the score and the tally, thou hast caused
            printing to be used.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An account or reckoning; account of dues; bill; hence,
      indebtedness.
      [1913 Webster]

            He parted well, and paid his score.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Account; reason; motive; sake; behalf.
      [1913 Webster]

            But left the trade, as many more
            Have lately done on the same score.   --Hudibras.
      [1913 Webster]

            You act your kindness in Cydaria's score. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The number twenty, as being marked off by a special score
      or tally; hence, in pl., a large number.
      [1913 Webster]

            Amongst three or four score hogsheads. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            At length the queen took upon herself to grant
            patents of monopoly by scores.        --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A distance of twenty yards; -- a term used in ancient
      archery and gunnery. --Halliwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A weight of twenty pounds. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The number of points gained by the contestants, or either
      of them, in any game, as in cards or cricket.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A line drawn; a groove or furrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mus.) The original and entire draught, or its transcript,
      of a composition, with the parts for all the different
      instruments or voices written on staves one above another,
      so that they can be read at a glance; -- so called from
      the bar, which, in its early use, was drawn through all
      the parts. --Moore (Encyc. of Music).
      [1913 Webster]

   10. the grade received on an examination, such as those given
       in school or as a qualifying examination for a job or
       admission to school; -- it may be expressed as a
       percentage of answers which are correct, or as a number
       or letter; as, a score of 98 in a civil service exam.
       [PJC]

   {In score} (Mus.), having all the parts arranged and placed
      in juxtaposition. --Smart.

   {To quit scores}, to settle or balance accounts; to render an
      equivalent; to make compensation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Does not the earth quit scores with all the elements
            in the noble fruits that issue from it? --South.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>score</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Score \Score\, v. i.
   1. To keep the score in a game; to act as scorer.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. To make or count a point or points, as in a game; to
      tally.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. To run up a score, or account of dues.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. To succeed in finding a partner for sexual intercourse; to
      make a sexual conquest. [slang]
      [PJC]

   5. To purchase drugs illegally. [slang]
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>score</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>score
     n 1: a number or letter indicating quality (especially of a
          student's performance); "she made good marks in
          algebra"; "grade A milk"; "what was your score on your
          homework?" [syn: {mark}, {grade}]
     2: a written form of a musical composition; parts for different
        instruments appear on separate staves on large pages; "he
        studied the score of the sonata" [syn: {musical score}]
     3: a number that expresses the accomplishment of a team or an
        individual in a game or contest; "the score was 7 to 0"
     4: a set of twenty members; "a score were sent out but only one
        returned"
     5: grounds; "don't do it on my account"; "the paper was
        rejected on account of its length"; "he tried to blame the
        victim but his success on that score was doubtful" [syn: {account}]
     6: the facts about an actual situation; "he didn't know the
        score"
     7: an amount due (as at a restaurant or bar); "add it to my
        score and I'll settle later"
     8: a slight surface cut (especially a notch that is made to
        keep a tally) [syn: {scotch}]
     9: a resentment strong enough to justify retaliation; "holding
        a grudge"; "settling a score" [syn: {grudge}, {grievance}]
     10: the act of scoring in a game or sport; "the winning score
         came with less than a minute left to play"
     11: a seduction culminating in sexual intercourse; "calling his
         seduction of the girl a `score' was a typical example of
         male slang" [syn: {sexual conquest}]
     v 1: gain points in a game; "The home team scored many times";
          "He hit a home run"; "He hit .300 in the past season"
          [syn: {hit}, {tally}, {rack up}]
     2: make small marks into the surface of; "score the clay before
        firing it" [syn: {nock}, {mark}]
     3: make underscoring marks [syn: {mark}]
     4: write a musical score for
     5: induce to have sex; "Harry finally seduced Sally"; "Did you
        score last night?"; "Harry made Sally" [syn: {seduce}, {make}]
     6: get a certain number or letter indicating quality or
        performance; "She scored high on the SAT"; "He scored a
        200"
     7: assign a grade or rank to, according to one's evaluation;
        "grade tests"; "score the SAT essays"; "mark homework"
        [syn: {grade}, {mark}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
