<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>scoring</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Score \Score\ (sk[=o]r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Scored}
   (sk[=o]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Scoring}.]
   1. To mark with lines, scratches, or notches; to cut notches
      or furrows in; to notch; to scratch; to furrow; as, to
      score timber for hewing; to score the back with a lash.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let us score their backs.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A briar in that tangled wilderness
            Had scored her white right hand.      --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, to mark with significant lines or notches, for
      indicating or keeping account of something; as, to score a
      tally.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To mark or signify by lines or notches; to keep record or
      account of; to set down; to record; to charge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Madam, I know when,
            Instead of five, you scored me ten.   --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor need I tallies thy dear love to score. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To engrave, as upon a shield. [R.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To make a score of, as points, runs, etc., in a game.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mus.) To write down in proper order and arrangement; as,
      to score an overture for an orchestra. See {Score}, n., 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Geol.) To mark with parallel lines or scratches; as, the
      rocks of New England and the Western States were scored in
      the drift epoch.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scorn \Scorn\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Scorned} (sk[^o]rnd); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Scoring}.] [OE. scornen, scarnen, schornen, OF.
   escarnir, escharnir. See {Scorn}, n.]
   1. To hold in extreme contempt; to reject as unworthy of
      regard; to despise; to contemn; to disdain.
      [1913 Webster]

            I scorn thy meat; 't would choke me.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            This my long sufferance, and my day of grace,
            Those who neglect and scorn shall never taste.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            We scorn what is in itself contemptible or
            disgraceful.                          --C. J. Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To treat with extreme contempt; to make the object of
      insult; to mock; to scoff at; to deride.
      [1913 Webster]

            His fellow, that lay by his bed's side,
            Gan for to laugh, and scorned him full fast.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            To taunt and scorn you thus opprobriously. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To contemn; despise; disdain. See {Contemn}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scoring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>scoring
     n : evaluation of performance by assigning a grade or score;
         "what he disliked about teaching was all the grading he
         had to do" [syn: {marking}, {grading}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
