<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>scrape</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scrape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scrape \Scrape\ (skr[=a]p), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Scraped}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Scraping}.] [Icel. skrapa; akin to Sw. skrapa,
   Dan. skrabe, D. schrapen, schrabben, G. schrappen, and prob.
   to E. sharp.]
   1. To rub over the surface of (something) with a sharp or
      rough instrument; to rub over with something that roughens
      by removing portions of the surface; to grate harshly
      over; to abrade; to make even, or bring to a required
      condition or form, by moving the sharp edge of an
      instrument breadthwise over the surface with pressure,
      cutting away excesses and superfluous parts; to make
      smooth or clean; as, to scrape a bone with a knife; to
      scrape a metal plate to an even surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To remove by rubbing or scraping (in the sense above).
      [1913 Webster]

            I will also scrape her dust from her, and make her
            like the top of a rock.               --Ezek. xxvi.
                                                  4.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To collect by, or as by, a process of scraping; to gather
      in small portions by laborious effort; hence, to acquire
      avariciously and save penuriously; -- often followed by
      together or up; as, to scrape money together.
      [1913 Webster]

            The prelatical party complained that, to swell a
            number the nonconformists did not choose, but
            scrape, subscribers.                  --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To express disapprobation of, as a play, or to silence, as
      a speaker, by drawing the feet back and forth upon the
      floor; -- usually with down. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To scrape acquaintance}, to seek acquaintance otherwise than
      by an introduction. --Farquhar.
      [1913 Webster]

            He tried to scrape acquaintance with her, but failed
            ignominiously.                        --G. W. Cable.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scrape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scrape \Scrape\, n.
   1. The act of scraping; also, the effect of scraping, as a
      scratch, or a harsh sound; as, a noisy scrape on the
      floor; a scrape of a pen.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A drawing back of the right foot when bowing; also, a bow
      made with that accompaniment. --H. Spencer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A disagreeable and embarrassing predicament out of which
      one can not get without undergoing, as it were, a painful
      rubbing or scraping; a perplexity; a difficulty.
      [1913 Webster]

            The too eager pursuit of this his old enemy through
            thick and thin has led him into many of these
            scrapes.                              --Bp.
                                                  Warburton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scrape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scrape \Scrape\, v. i.
   1. To rub over the surface of anything with something which
      roughens or removes it, or which smooths or cleans it; to
      rub harshly and noisily along.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To occupy one's self with getting laboriously; as, he
      scraped and saved until he became rich. ``[Spend] their
      scraping fathers' gold.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To play awkwardly and inharmoniously on a violin or like
      instrument.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To draw back the right foot along the ground or floor when
      making a bow.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scrape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>scrape
     n 1: a harsh noise made by scraping; "the scrape of violin bows
          distracted her" [syn: {scraping}, {scratch}, {scratching}]
     2: an abraded area where the skin is torn or worn off [syn: {abrasion},
         {scratch}, {excoriation}]
     3: a deep bow with the foot drawn backwards (indicating
        excessive humility); "all that bowing and scraping did not
        impress him" [syn: {scraping}]
     4: an indication of damage [syn: {scratch}, {scar}, {mark}]
     v 1: scratch repeatedly; "The cat scraped at the armchair" [syn:
          {grate}]
     2: make by scraping; "They scraped a letter into the stone"
     3: cut the surface of; wear away the surface of [syn: {scratch},
         {scratch up}]
     4: bend the knees and bow in a servile manner [syn: {kowtow}, {genuflect}]
     5: gather (money or other resources) together over time; "She
        had scraped together enough money for college" [syn: {scrape
        up}, {come up}]
     6: bruise, cut, or injure the skin or the surface of; "The boy
        skinned his knee when he fell" [syn: {skin}]
     7: strike against an object; "She stubbed her one's toe in the
        dark and now it's broken" [syn: {stub}, {skin}, {abrade}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
