<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>screw</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>screw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>screw
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; (MIT) A {lose}, usually in software.  Especially used
        for user-visible misbehaviour caused by a bug or {misfeature}.
        This use has become quite widespread outside {MIT}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1994-12-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>screw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Screw \Screw\ (skr[udd]), n. [OE. scrue, OF. escroue, escroe,
   female screw, F. ['e]crou, L. scrobis a ditch, trench, in
   LL., the hole made by swine in rooting; cf. D. schroef a
   screw, G. schraube, Icel. skr[=u]fa.]
   1. A cylinder, or a cylindrical perforation, having a
      continuous rib, called the thread, winding round it
      spirally at a constant inclination, so as to leave a
      continuous spiral groove between one turn and the next, --
      used chiefly for producing, when revolved, motion or
      pressure in the direction of its axis, by the sliding of
      the threads of the cylinder in the grooves between the
      threads of the perforation adapted to it, the former being
      distinguished as the external, or male screw, or, more
      usually the screw; the latter as the internal, or female
      screw, or, more usually, the nut.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The screw, as a mechanical power, is a modification of
         the inclined plane, and may be regarded as a
         right-angled triangle wrapped round a cylinder, the
         hypotenuse of the marking the spiral thread of the
         screw, its base equaling the circumference of the
         cylinder, and its height the pitch of the thread.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically, a kind of nail with a spiral thread and a
      head with a nick to receive the end of the screw-driver.
      Screws are much used to hold together pieces of wood or to
      fasten something; -- called also {wood screws}, and {screw
      nails}. See also {Screw bolt}, below.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything shaped or acting like a screw; esp., a form of
      wheel for propelling steam vessels. It is placed at the
      stern, and furnished with blades having helicoidal
      surfaces to act against the water in the manner of a
      screw. See {Screw propeller}, below.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A steam vesel propelled by a screw instead of wheels; a
      screw steamer; a propeller.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An extortioner; a sharp bargainer; a skinflint; a niggard.
      --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An instructor who examines with great or unnecessary
      severity; also, a searching or strict examination of a
      student by an instructor. [Cant, American Colleges]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A small packet of tobacco. [Slang] --Mayhew.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. An unsound or worn-out horse, useful as a hack, and
      commonly of good appearance. --Ld. Lytton.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Math.) A straight line in space with which a definite
      linear magnitude termed the pitch is associated (cf. 5th
      {Pitch}, 10
      (b) ). It is used to express the displacement of a rigid
          body, which may always be made to consist of a
          rotation about an axis combined with a translation
          parallel to that axis.
          [1913 Webster]

   10. (Zo["o]l.) An amphipod crustacean; as, the skeleton screw
       ({Caprella}). See {Sand screw}, under {Sand}.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Archimedes screw}, {Compound screw}, {Foot screw}, etc. See
      under {Archimedes}, {Compound}, {Foot}, etc.

   {A screw loose}, something out of order, so that work is not
      done smoothly; as, there is a screw loose somewhere. --H.
      Martineau.

   {Endless screw}, or {perpetual screw}, a screw used to give
      motion to a toothed wheel by the action of its threads
      between the teeth of the wheel; -- called also a {worm}.
      

   {Lag screw}. See under {Lag}.

   {Micrometer screw}, a screw with fine threads, used for the
      measurement of very small spaces.

   {Right and left screw}, a screw having threads upon the
      opposite ends which wind in opposite directions.

   {Screw alley}. See {Shaft alley}, under {Shaft}.

   {Screw bean}. (Bot.)
       (a) The curious spirally coiled pod of a leguminous tree
           ({Prosopis pubescens}) growing from Texas to
           California. It is used for fodder, and ground into
           meal by the Indians.
       (b) The tree itself. Its heavy hard wood is used for
           fuel, for fencing, and for railroad ties.

   {Screw bolt}, a bolt having a screw thread on its shank, in
      distinction from a {key bolt}. See 1st {Bolt}, 3.

   {Screw box}, a device, resembling a die, for cutting the
      thread on a wooden screw.

   {Screw dock}. See under {Dock}.

   {Screw engine}, a marine engine for driving a screw
      propeller.

   {Screw gear}. See {Spiral gear}, under {Spiral}.

   {Screw jack}. Same as {Jackscrew}.

   {Screw key}, a wrench for turning a screw or nut; a spanner
      wrench.

   {Screw machine}.
       (a) One of a series of machines employed in the
           manufacture of wood screws.
       (b) A machine tool resembling a lathe, having a number of
           cutting tools that can be caused to act on the work
           successively, for making screws and other turned
           pieces from metal rods.

   {Screw pine} (Bot.), any plant of the endogenous genus
      {Pandanus}, of which there are about fifty species,
      natives of tropical lands from Africa to Polynesia; --
      named from the spiral arrangement of the pineapple-like
      leaves.

   {Screw plate}, a device for cutting threads on small screws,
      consisting of a thin steel plate having a series of
      perforations with internal screws forming dies.

   {Screw press}, a press in which pressure is exerted by means
      of a screw.

   {Screw propeller}, a screw or spiral bladed wheel, used in
      the propulsion of steam vessels; also, a steam vessel
      propelled by a screw.

   {Screw shell} (Zo["o]l.), a long, slender, spiral gastropod
      shell, especially of the genus Turritella and allied
      genera. See {Turritella}.

   {Screw steamer}, a steamship propelled by a screw.

   {Screw thread}, the spiral rib which forms a screw.

   {Screw stone} (Paleon.), the fossil stem of an encrinite.

   {Screw tree} (Bot.), any plant of the genus {Helicteres},
      consisting of about thirty species of tropical shrubs,
      with simple leaves and spirally twisted, five-celled
      capsules; -- also called {twisted-horn}, and {twisty}.

   {Screw valve}, a stop valve which is opened or closed by a
      screw.

   {Screw worm} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of an American fly
      ({Compsomyia macellaria}), allied to the blowflies, which
      sometimes deposits its eggs in the nostrils, or about
      wounds, in man and other animals, with fatal results.

   {Screw wrench}.
       (a) A wrench for turning a screw.
       (b) A wrench with an adjustable jaw that is moved by a
           screw.

   {To put the screws on} or {To put the screw on}, to use
      pressure upon, as for the purpose of extortion; to coerce.
      

   {To put under the screw} or {To put under the screws}, to
      subject to pressure; to force.

   {Wood screw}, a metal screw with a sharp thread of coarse
      pitch, adapted to holding fast in wood. See Illust. of
      {Wood screw}, under {Wood}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>screw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Screw \Screw\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Screwed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Screwing}.]
   1. To turn, as a screw; to apply a screw to; to press,
      fasten, or make firm, by means of a screw or screws; as,
      to screw a lock on a door; to screw a press.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To force; to squeeze; to press, as by screws.
      [1913 Webster]

            But screw your courage to the sticking place,
            And we'll not fail.                   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: To practice extortion upon; to oppress by
      unreasonable or extortionate exactions.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our country landlords, by unmeasurable screwing and
            racking their tenants, have already reduced the
            miserable people to a worse condition than the
            peasants in France.                   --swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To twist; to distort; as, to screw his visage.
      [1913 Webster]

            He screwed his face into a hardened smile. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To examine rigidly, as a student; to subject to a severe
      examination. [Cant, American Colleges]
      [1913 Webster]

   {To screw out}, to press out; to extort.

   {To screw up},
      (a) to force; to bring by violent pressure. --Howell.
      (b) to damage by unskillful effort; to bungle; to botch;
          to mess up.
      (c) [intrans] to fail by unskillful effort, usu. causing
          unpleasant consequences.

   {To screw in}, to force in by turning or twisting.

   {Screw around}
      (a) to act aimlessly or unproductively.
      (b) screw around with, to operate or make changes on (a
          machine or device) without expert knowledge; to fiddle
          with.
      (c) [Colloq.]commit adultery; to be sexually promiscuous.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>screw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Screw \Screw\, v. i.
   1. To use violent mans in making exactions; to be oppressive
      or exacting. --Howitt.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To turn one's self uneasily with a twisting motion; as, he
      screws about in his chair.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>screw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>screw n. [MIT] A {lose}, usually in software. Especially used for
   user-visible misbehavior caused by a bug or misfeature. This use has
   become quite widespread outside MIT.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>screw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>screw
     n 1: someone who guards prisoners [syn: {prison guard}, {jailer},
           {jailor}, {gaoler}, {turnkey}]
     2: a simple machine of the inclined-plane type consisting of a
        spirally threaded cylindrical rod that engages with a
        similarly threaded hole
     3: a propeller with several angled blades that rotates to push
        against water or air [syn: {screw propeller}]
     4: a fastener with a tapered threaded shank and a slotted head
     5: slang terms for sexual intercourse [syn: {fuck}, {fucking},
        {screwing}, {ass}, {nooky}, {nookie}, {piece of ass}, {piece
        of tail}, {roll in the hay}, {shag}, {shtup}]
     v 1: have sexual intercourse with; "This student sleeps with
          everyone in her dorm"; "Adam knew Eve"; "Were you ever
          intimate with this man?" [syn: {roll in the hay}, {love},
           {make out}, {make love}, {sleep with}, {get laid}, {have
          sex}, {know}, {do it}, {be intimate}, {have intercourse},
           {have it away}, {have it off}, {fuck}, {jazz}, {eff}, {hump},
           {lie with}, {bed}, {have a go at it}, {bang}, {get it
          on}, {bonk}]
     2: turn like a screw
     3: cause to penetrate, as with a circular motion; "drive in
        screws or bolts" [syn: {drive in}]
     4: tighten or fasten by means of screwing motions; "Screw the
        bottle cap on" [ant: {unscrew}]
     5: defeat someone in an expectation through trickery or deceit
        [syn: {cheat}, {chouse}, {shaft}, {chicane}, {jockey}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
