<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>scroll</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scroll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>scroll
     
        &lt;interface&gt; (From a scroll of paper) To change the portion of
        a document displayed in a window or on a {VDU} screen.  In a
        {graphical user interface}, scrolling is usually controlled by
        the user via {scroll bars}, whereas on a VDU the text scrolls
        up automatically as lines of data are output at the bottom of
        the screen.
     
        (2001-04-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scroll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SCROLL
     
        String and Character Recording Oriented Logogrammatic
        Language.
     
        ["SCROLL - A Pattern Recording Language", M. Sargent, Proc
        SJCC 36 (1970)].
     
        (1994-12-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scroll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Scroll \Scroll\, n. [A dim. of OE. scroue, scrowe (whence E.
   escrow), OF. escroe, escroue, F. ['e]crou entry in the jail
   book, LL. scroa scroll, probably of Teutonic origin; cf. OD.
   schroode a strip, shred, slip of paper, akin to E. shred. Cf.
   {Shred}, {Escrow}.]
   1. A roll of paper or parchment; a writing formed into a
      roll; a schedule; a list.
      [1913 Webster]

            The heavens shall be rolled together as a scroll.
                                                  --Isa. xxxiv.
                                                  4.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here is the scroll of every man's name. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) An ornament formed of undulations giving off
      spirals or sprays, usually suggestive of plant form. Roman
      architectural ornament is largely of some scroll pattern.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A mark or flourish added to a person's signature, intended
      to represent a seal, and in some States allowed as a
      substitute for a seal. [U.S.] --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Geom.) Same as {Skew surface}. See under {Skew}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Linen scroll} (Arch.) See under {Linen}.

   {Scroll chuck} (Mach.), an adjustable chuck, applicable to a
      lathe spindle, for centering and holding work, in which
      the jaws are adjusted and tightened simultaneously by
      turning a disk having in its face a spiral groove which is
      entered by teeth on the backs of the jaws.

   {Scroll saw}. See under {Saw}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scroll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rule \Rule\, n.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Syn: regulation; law; precept; maxim; guide; canon; order;
        method; direction; control; government; sway; empire.
        [1913 Webster] Rule \Rule\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Ruled};
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Ruling}.] [Cf. OF. riuler, ruiler, L.
   regulare. See {Rule}, n., and cf. {Regulate}.]
   1. To control the will and actions of; to exercise authority
      or dominion over; to govern; to manage. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            A bishop then must be blameless; . . . one that
            ruleth well his own house, having his children in
            subjection.                           --1 Tim. iii.
                                                  2, 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To control or direct by influence, counsel, or persuasion;
      to guide; -- used chiefly in the passive.
      [1913 Webster]

            I think she will be ruled
            In all respects by me.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To establish or settle by, or as by, a rule; to fix by
      universal or general consent, or by common practice.
      [1913 Webster]

            That's are ruled case with the schoolmen.
                                                  --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) To require or command by rule; to give as a
      direction or order of court.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To mark with lines made with a pen, pencil, etc., guided
      by a rule or ruler; to print or mark with lines by means
      of a rule or other contrivance effecting a similar result;
      as, to rule a sheet of paper of a blank book.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ruled surface} (Geom.), any surface that may be described by
      a straight line moving according to a given law; -- called
      also a {scroll}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>scroll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>scroll
     n 1: a round shape formed by a series of concentric circles [syn:
           {coil}, {whorl}, {roll}, {curl}, {curlicue}, {ringlet},
           {gyre}]
     2: a document that can be rolled up (as for storage) [syn: {roll}]
     v : move through text or graphics in order to display parts that
         do not fit on the screen; "Scroll down to see the entire
         text"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
