<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sea</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sea</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SEA
     
        {Self Extracting Archive}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sea</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sea \Sea\ (s[=e]), n. [OE. see, AS. s[=ae]; akin to D. zee, OS.
   &amp; OHG. s[=e]o, G. see, OFries. se, Dan. s["o], Sw. sj["o],
   Icel. s[ae]r, Goth. saiws, and perhaps to L. saevus fierce,
   savage. [root]151a.]
   1. One of the larger bodies of salt water, less than an
      ocean, found on the earth's surface; a body of salt water
      of second rank, generally forming part of, or connecting
      with, an ocean or a larger sea; as, the Mediterranean Sea;
      the Sea of Marmora; the North Sea; the Carribean Sea.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An inland body of water, esp. if large or if salt or
      brackish; as, the Caspian Sea; the Sea of Aral; sometimes,
      a small fresh-water lake; as, the Sea of Galilee.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The ocean; the whole body of the salt water which covers a
      large part of the globe.
      [1913 Webster]

            I marvel how the fishes live in the sea. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ambiguous between sea and land
            The river horse and scaly crocodile.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The swell of the ocean or other body of water in a high
      wind; motion or agitation of the water's surface; also, a
      single wave; a billow; as, there was a high sea after the
      storm; the vessel shipped a sea.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Jewish Antiq.) A great brazen laver in the temple at
      Jerusalem; -- so called from its size.
      [1913 Webster]

            He made a molten sea of ten cubits from brim to
            brim, round in compass, and five cubits the height
            thereof.                              --2 Chron. iv.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Fig.: Anything resembling the sea in vastness; as, a sea
      of glory. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the space . . . was one sea of heads.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sea is often used in the composition of words of
         obvious signification; as, sea-bathed, sea-beaten,
         sea-bound, sea-bred, sea-circled, sealike, sea-nursed,
         sea-tossed, sea-walled, sea-worn, and the like. It is
         also used either adjectively or in combination with
         substantives; as, sea bird, sea-bird, or seabird, sea
         acorn, or sea-acorn.
         [1913 Webster]

   {At sea}, upon the ocean; away from land; figuratively,
      without landmarks for guidance; lost; at the mercy of
      circumstances. ``To say the old man was at sea would be
      too feeble an expression.'' --G. W. Cable

   {At full sea} at the height of flood tide; hence, at the
      height. ``But now God's mercy was at full sea.'' --Jer.
      Taylor.

   {Beyond seas}, or {Beyond the sea} or {Beyond the seas}
      (Law), out of the state, territory, realm, or country.
      --Wharton.

   {Half seas over}, half drunk. [Colloq.] --Spectator.

   {Heavy sea}, a sea in which the waves run high.

   {Long sea}, a sea characterized by the uniform and steady
      motion of long and extensive waves.

   {Short sea}, a sea in which the waves are short, broken, and
      irregular, so as to produce a tumbling or jerking motion.
      

   {To go to sea}, to adopt the calling or occupation of a
      sailor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sea</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ocean \O"cean\ ([=o]"shan), n. [F. oc['e]an, L. oceanus, Gr.
   'wkeano`s ocean, in Homer, the great river supposed to
   encompass the earth.]
   1. The whole body of salt water which covers more than three
      fifths of the surface of the globe; -- called also the
      {sea}, or {great sea}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like the odor of brine from the ocean
            Comes the thought of other years.     --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One of the large bodies of water into which the great
      ocean is regarded as divided, as the Atlantic, Pacific,
      Indian, Arctic and Antarctic oceans.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An immense expanse; any vast space or quantity without
      apparent limits; as, the boundless ocean of eternity; an
      ocean of affairs. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            You're gonna need an ocean
            Of calamine lotion.                   --Lieber &amp;
                                                  Stoller
                                                  (Poison Ivy:
                                                  song lyrics,
                                                  1994)
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sea</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SEA
     Self-Extracting Archive
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sea</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SEA
     Society for Electronic Access (org.)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sea</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sea
     adj : relating to or characteristic of or occurring on the sea or
           ships; "sea stories"; "sea smells"; "sea traffic" [syn:
            {sea(a)}] [ant: {air(a)}, {land(a)}]
     n 1: a division of an ocean or a large body of salt water
          partially enclosed by land
     2: anything apparently limitless in quantity or volume [syn: {ocean}]
     3: turbulent water with swells of considerable size; "heavy
        seas"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
