<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>season</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>season</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Season \Sea"son\, n. [OE. sesoun, F. saison, properly, the
   sowing time, fr. L. satio a sowing, a planting, fr. serere,
   satum, to sow, plant; akin to E. sow, v., to scatter, as
   seed.]
   1. One of the divisions of the year, marked by alterations in
      the length of day and night, or by distinct conditions of
      temperature, moisture, etc., caused mainly by the relative
      position of the earth with respect to the sun. In the
      north temperate zone, four seasons, namely, spring,
      summer, autumn, and winter, are generally recognized. Some
      parts of the world have three seasons, -- the dry, the
      rainy, and the cold; other parts have but two, -- the dry
      and the rainy.
      [1913 Webster]

            The several seasons of the year in their beauty.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, a period of time, especially as regards its fitness
      for anything contemplated or done; a suitable or
      convenient time; proper conjuncture; as, the season for
      planting; the season for rest.
      [1913 Webster]

            The season, prime for sweetest scents and airs.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A period of time not very long; a while; a time.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt be blind, not seeing the sun for a
            season.                               --Acts xiii.
                                                  11.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which gives relish; seasoning. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            You lack the season of all natures, sleep. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In season}, in good time, or sufficiently early for the
      purpose.

   {Out of season}, beyond or out of the proper time or the
      usual or appointed time.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>season</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Season \Sea"son\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Seasoned}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Seasoning}.]
   1. To render suitable or appropriate; to prepare; to fit.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is fit and seasoned for his passage. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fit for any use by time or habit; to habituate; to
      accustom; to inure; to ripen; to mature; as, to season one
      to a climate.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, to prepare by drying or hardening, or removal of
      natural juices; as, to season timber.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To fit for taste; to render palatable; to give zest or
      relish to; to spice; as, to season food.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, to fit for enjoyment; to render agreeable.
      [1913 Webster]

            You season still with sports your serious hours.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The proper use of wit is to season conversation.
                                                  --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To qualify by admixture; to moderate; to temper. ``When
      mercy seasons justice.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To imbue; to tinge or taint. ``Who by his tutor being
      seasoned with the love of the truth.'' --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            Season their younger years with prudent and pious
            principles.                           --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To copulate with; to impregnate. [R.] --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>season</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Season \Sea"son\, v. i.
   1. To become mature; to grow fit for use; to become adapted
      to a climate.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To become dry and hard, by the escape of the natural
      juices, or by being penetrated with other substance; as,
      timber seasons in the sun.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give token; to savor. [Obs.] --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>season</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>season
     n 1: a period of the year marked by special events or activities
          in some field; "he celebrated his 10th season with the
          ballet company"; "she always looked forward to the
          avocado season"
     2: one of the natural periods into which the year is divided by
        the equinoxes and solstices or atmospheric conditions;
        "the regular sequence of the seasons" [syn: {time of year}]
     3: a recurrent time marked by major holidays; "it was the
        Christmas season"
     v 1: lend flavor to; "Season the chicken breast after roasting
          it" [syn: {flavor}, {flavour}]
     2: make fit; "This trip will season even the hardiest
        traveller" [syn: {harden}]
     3: make more temperate, acceptable, or suitable by adding
        something else; moderate; "she tempered her criticism"
        [syn: {temper}, {mollify}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
