<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>second</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>second</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Second \Sec"ond\, a. [F., fr. L. secundus second, properly,
   following, fr. sequi to follow. See {Sue} to follow, and cf.
   {Secund}.]
   1. Immediately following the first; next to the first in
      order of place or time; hence, occurring again; another;
      other.
      [1913 Webster]

            And he slept and dreamed the second time. --Gen.
                                                  xli. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Next to the first in value, power, excellence, dignity, or
      rank; secondary; subordinate; inferior.
      [1913 Webster]

            May the day when we become the second people upon
            earth . . . be the day of our utter extirpation.
                                                  --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Being of the same kind as another that has preceded;
      another, like a prototype; as, a second Cato; a second
      Troy; a second deluge.
      [1913 Webster]

            A Daniel, still say I, a second Daniel! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Second Adventist}. See {Adventist}.

   {Second cousin}, the child of a cousin.

   {Second-cut file}. See under {File}.

   {Second distance} (Art), that part of a picture between the
      foreground and the background; -- called also {middle
      ground}, or {middle distance}. [R.]

   {Second estate} (Eng.), the House of Peers.

   {Second girl}, a female house-servant who does the lighter
      work, as chamber work or waiting on table.

   {Second intention}. See under {Intention}.

   {Second story}, {Second floor}, in America, the second range
      of rooms from the street level. This, in England, is
      called the {first floor}, the one beneath being the
      {ground floor}.

   {Second thought} or {Second thoughts}, consideration of a
      matter following a first impulse or impression;
      reconsideration.
      [1913 Webster]

            On second thoughts, gentlemen, I don't wish you had
            known him.                            --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>second</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Second \Sec"ond\, n.
   1. One who, or that which, follows, or comes after; one next
      and inferior in place, time, rank, importance, excellence,
      or power.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man
            An angel's second, nor his second long. --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who follows or attends another for his support and
      aid; a backer; an assistant; specifically, one who acts as
      another's aid in a duel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Being sure enough of seconds after the first onset.
                                                  --Sir H.
                                                  Wotton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Aid; assistance; help. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Give second, and my love
            Is everlasting thine.                 --J. Fletcher.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. pl. An article of merchandise of a grade inferior to the
      best; esp., a coarse or inferior kind of flour.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [F. seconde. See {Second}, a.] The sixtieth part of a
      minute of time or of a minute of space, that is, the
      second regular subdivision of the degree; as, sound moves
      about 1,140 English feet in a second; five minutes and ten
      seconds north of this place.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. In the duodecimal system of mensuration, the twelfth part
      of an inch or prime; a line. See {Inch}, and {Prime}, n.,
      8.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mus.)
      (a) The interval between any tone and the tone which is
          represented on the degree of the staff next above it.
      (b) The second part in a concerted piece; -- often
          popularly applied to the alto.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Parliamentary Procedure) A motion in support of another
      motion which has been moved in a deliberative body; a
      motion without a second dies without discussion.
      [PJC]

   {Second hand}, the hand which marks the seconds on the dial
      of a watch or a clock.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>second</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Second \Sec"ond\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Seconded}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Seconding}.] [Cf. F. seconder, L. secundare, from
   secundus. See {Second}, a.]
   1. To follow in the next place; to succeed; to alternate.
      [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            In the method of nature, a low valley is immediately
            seconded with an ambitious hill.      --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sin is seconded with sin.             --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To follow or attend for the purpose of assisting; to
      support; to back; to act as the second of; to assist; to
      forward; to encourage.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have supplies to second our attempt. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In human works though labored on with pain,
            A thousand movements scarce one purpose gain;
            In God's, one single can its end produce,
            Yet serves to second too some other use. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically, (Parliamentary Procedure) to support, as a
      motion[6] or proposal, by adding one's voice to that of
      the mover or proposer.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Under common parliamentary rules used by many
         organizations, especially legislative bodies, a motion
         must be seconded in order to come properly before the
         deliberative body for discussion. Any motion[6] for
         which there is no second[8] dies for lack thereof.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>second</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>second
     adj 1: coming next after the first in position in space or time or
            degree or magnitude [syn: {2nd}, {2d}]
     2: coming next after first; "a second chance"; "the second vice
        president"
     3: a part or voice or instrument or orchestra section lower in
        pitch than or subordinate to the first; "second flute";
        "the second violins" [ant: {first}]
     4: having the second highest gear ratio; "second gear"
     n 1: 1/60 of a minute; the basic unit of time adopted under the
          Systeme International d'Unites [syn: {sec}, {s}]
     2: an indefinitely short time; "wait just a moment"; "it only
        takes a minute"; "in just a bit" [syn: {moment}, {minute},
         {bit}]
     3: the fielding position of the player on a baseball team who
        is stationed near 2nd base [syn: {second base}]
     4: a particular point in time; "the moment he arrived the party
        began" [syn: {moment}, {minute}, {instant}]
     5: following the first in an ordering or series; "he came in a
        close second"
     6: a 60th part of a minute of arc; "the treasure is 2 minutes
        and 45 seconds south of here" [syn: {arcsecond}]
     7: the official attendant of a contestant in a duel or boxing
        match
     8: a speech seconding a motion; "do I hear a second?" [syn: {secondment},
         {endorsement}, {indorsement}]
     9: the gear that has the second lowest forward gear ratio in
        the gear box of a motor vehicle; "he had to shift down
        into second to make the hill" [syn: {second gear}]
     10: merchandise that has imperfections; usually sold at a
         reduced price without the brand name [syn: {irregular}]
     adv : in the second place; "second, we must consider the economy"
           [syn: {secondly}]
     v 1: give support or one's approval to; "I'll second that
          motion"; "I can't back this plan"; "endorse a new
          project" [syn: {back}, {endorse}, {indorse}]
     2: transfer an employee to a different, temporary assignment;
        "The officer was seconded for duty overseas"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
