<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>secondhand</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>secondhand</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Second \Sec"ond\, n.
   1. One who, or that which, follows, or comes after; one next
      and inferior in place, time, rank, importance, excellence,
      or power.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man
            An angel's second, nor his second long. --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who follows or attends another for his support and
      aid; a backer; an assistant; specifically, one who acts as
      another's aid in a duel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Being sure enough of seconds after the first onset.
                                                  --Sir H.
                                                  Wotton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Aid; assistance; help. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Give second, and my love
            Is everlasting thine.                 --J. Fletcher.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. pl. An article of merchandise of a grade inferior to the
      best; esp., a coarse or inferior kind of flour.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [F. seconde. See {Second}, a.] The sixtieth part of a
      minute of time or of a minute of space, that is, the
      second regular subdivision of the degree; as, sound moves
      about 1,140 English feet in a second; five minutes and ten
      seconds north of this place.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. In the duodecimal system of mensuration, the twelfth part
      of an inch or prime; a line. See {Inch}, and {Prime}, n.,
      8.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mus.)
      (a) The interval between any tone and the tone which is
          represented on the degree of the staff next above it.
      (b) The second part in a concerted piece; -- often
          popularly applied to the alto.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Parliamentary Procedure) A motion in support of another
      motion which has been moved in a deliberative body; a
      motion without a second dies without discussion.
      [PJC]

   {Second hand}, the hand which marks the seconds on the dial
      of a watch or a clock.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>secondhand</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Secondhand \Sec"ond*hand`\, a.
   1. Not original or primary; received from another; as,
      secondhand information.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            They have but a secondhand or implicit knowledge.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not new; already or previously possessed or used by
      another; as, a secondhand book, garment.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At second hand}. See {Hand}, n., 10.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>secondhand</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>second hand
     n 1: an intermediate person; used in the phrase `at second hand';
          "he could learn at second hand from books"
     2: hand marking seconds on a timepiece
     adv : from a source of previously owned goods; "I prefer to buy
           second hand"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>secondhand</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>secondhand
     adj 1: derived from what is primary or original; not firsthand; "a
            secondhand report"; "a secondhand account of a memory
            of something once read"; "most of our knowledge is
            secondhand"
     2: previously used or owned by another; "bought a secondhand
        (or used) car" [syn: {used}]
     adv : by indirect means; "I heard about it only secondhand or
           thirdhand"; "he prefers to buy secondhand"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
