<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>secretary</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>secretary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Secretary, MD (town, FIPS 70900)
  Location: 38.60739 N, 75.94746 W
  Population (1990): 528 (231 housing units)
  Area: 0.7 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>secretary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Secretary \Sec"re*ta*ry\, n.; pl. {Secretaries}. [F.
   secr['e]taire (cf. Pr. secretari, Sp. &amp; Pg. secretario, It.
   secretario, segretario) LL. secretarius, originally, a
   confidant, one intrusted with secrets, from L. secretum a
   secret. See {Secret}, a. &amp; n.]
   1. One who keeps, or is intrusted with, secrets. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A person employed to write orders, letters, dispatches,
      public or private papers, records, and the like; an
      official scribe, amanuensis, or writer; one who attends to
      correspondence, and transacts other business, for an
      association, a public body, or an individual.
      [1913 Webster]

            That which is most of all profitable is acquaintance
            with the secretaries, and employed men of
            ambassadors.                          --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An officer of state whose business is to superintend and
      manage the affairs of a particular department of
      government, and who is usually a member of the cabinet or
      advisory council of the chief executive; as, the secretary
      of state, who conducts the correspondence and attends to
      the relations of a government with foreign courts; the
      secretary of the treasury, who manages the department of
      finance; the secretary of war, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A piece of furniture, with conveniences for writing and
      for the arrangement of papers; an escritoire.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.) The secretary bird.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Secretary bird}. [So called in allusion to the tufts of
      feathers at the back of its head, which were fancifully
      thought to resemble pens stuck behind the ear.] (Zo["o]l.)
      A large long-legged raptorial bird ({Gypogeranus
      serpentarius}), native of South Africa, but now
      naturalized in the West Indies and some other tropical
      countries. It has a powerful hooked beak, a crest of long
      feathers, and a long tail. It feeds upon reptiles of
      various kinds, and is much prized on account of its habit
      of killing and devouring snakes of all kinds. Called also
      {serpent eater}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See the Note under {Clerk}, n., 4.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>secretary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>secretary
     n 1: a person who is head of an administrative department of
          government
     2: an assistant who handles correspondence and clerical work
        for a boss or an organization [syn: {secretarial assistant}]
     3: a person to whom a secret is entrusted [syn: {repository}]
     4: a desk used for writing [syn: {writing table}, {escritoire},
         {secretaire}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
