<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>seeing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>seeing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>See \See\ (s[=e]), v. t. [imp. {Saw} (s[add]); p. p. {Seen}
   (s[=e]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Seeing}.] [OE. seen, sen, seon,
   AS. se['o]n; akin to OFries. s[=i]a, D. zien, OS. &amp; OHG.
   sehan, G. sehen, Icel. sj[=a], Sw. se, Dan. see, Goth.
   sa['i]hwan, and probably to L. sequi to follow (and so
   originally meaning, to follow with the eyes). Gr. "e`pesqai,
   Skr. sac. Cf. {Sight}, {Sue} to follow.]
   1. To perceive by the eye; to have knowledge of the existence
      and apparent qualities of by the organs of sight; to
      behold; to descry; to view.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will now turn aside, and see this great sight.
                                                  --Ex. iii. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perceive by mental vision; to form an idea or
      conception of; to note with the mind; to observe; to
      discern; to distinguish; to understand; to comprehend; to
      ascertain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go, I pray thee, see whether it be well with thy
            brethren.                             --Gen. xxxvii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jesus saw that he answered discreetly. --Mark xii.
                                                  34.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who's so gross
            That seeth not this palpable device?  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To follow with the eyes, or as with the eyes; to watch; to
      regard attentively; to look after. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had a mind to see him out, and therefore did not
            care for contradicting him.           --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To have an interview with; especially, to make a call
      upon; to visit; as, to go to see a friend.
      [1913 Webster]

            And Samuel came no more to see Saul until the day of
            his death.                            --1 Sam. xv.
                                                  35.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To fall in with; to meet or associate with; to have
      intercourse or communication with; hence, to have
      knowledge or experience of; as, to see military service.
      [1913 Webster]

            Make us glad according to the days wherein thou hast
            afflicted us, and the years wherein we have seen
            evil.                                 --Ps. xc. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

            Verily, verily, I say unto you, if a man keep my
            saying, he shall never see death.     --John viii.
                                                  51.
      [1913 Webster]

            Improvement in wisdom and prudence by seeing men.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To accompany in person; to escort; to wait upon; as, to
      see one home; to see one aboard the cars.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. In poker and similar games at cards, to meet (a bet), or
      to equal the bet of (a player), by staking the same sum.
      ``I'll see you and raise you ten.''
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   {God you see} (or {God him see} or {God me see}, etc.), God
      keep you (him, me, etc.) in his sight; God protect you.
      [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {To see (anything) out}, to see (it) to the end; to be
      present at, work at, or attend, to the end.

   {To see stars}, to see flashes of light, like stars; --
      sometimes the result of concussion of the head. [Colloq.]
      

   {To see (one) through}, to help, watch, or guard (one) to the
      end of a course or an undertaking.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>seeing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Seeing \See"ing\, conj. (but originally a present participle).
   In view of the fact (that); considering; taking into account
   (that); insmuch as; since; because; -- followed by a
   dependent clause; as, he did well, seeing that he was so
   young.
   [1913 Webster]

         Wherefore come ye to me, seeing ye hate me? --Gen.
                                                  xxvi. 27.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>seeing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>seeing
     adj : having vision, not blind
     n 1: perception by means of the eyes [syn: {visual perception}, {beholding}]
     2: normal use of the faculty of vision [syn: {eyesight}, {sightedness}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
