<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>seem</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>seem</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Seem \Seem\ (s[=e]m), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Seemed} (s[=e]md); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Seeming}.] [OE. semen to seem, to become,
   befit, AS. s[=e]man to satisfy, pacify; akin to Icel. s[ae]ma
   to honor, to bear with, conform to, s[ae]mr becoming, fit,
   s[=o]ma to beseem, to befit, sama to beseem, semja to
   arrange, settle, put right, Goth. samjan to please, and to E.
   same. The sense is probably due to the adj. seemly.
   [root]191. See {Same}, a., and cf. {Seemly}.]
   To appear, or to appear to be; to have a show or semblance;
   to present an appearance; to look; to strike one's
   apprehension or fancy as being; to be taken as. ``It now
   seemed probable.'' --Macaulay.
   [1913 Webster]

         Thou picture of what thou seem'st.       --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         All seemed well pleased; all seemed, but were not all.
                                                  --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]

         There is a way which seemeth right unto a man; but the
         end thereof are the ways of death.       --Prov. xiv.
                                                  12.
   [1913 Webster]

   {It seems}, it appears; it is understood as true; it is said.
      [1913 Webster]

            A prince of Italy, it seems, entertained his
            mistress on a great lake.             --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To appear; look.

   Usage: {Seem}, {Appear}. To appear has reference to a thing's
          being presented to our view; as, the sun appears; to
          seem is connected with the idea of semblance, and
          usually implies an inference of our mind as to the
          probability of a thing's being so; as, a storm seems
          to be coming. ``The story appears to be true,'' means
          that the facts, as presented, go to show its truth;
          ``the story seems to be true,'' means that it has the
          semblance of being so, and we infer that it is true.
          ``His first and principal care being to appear unto
          his people such as he would have them be, and to be
          such as he appeared.'' --Sir P. Sidney.
          [1913 Webster]

                Ham. Ay, madam, it is common.
                Queen. If it be,
                Why seems it so particular with thee?
                Ham. Seems, madam! Nay, it is; I know not
                ``seems.''                        --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>seem</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Seem \Seem\, v. t.
   To befit; to beseem. [Obs.] --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>seem</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>seem
     v 1: give a certain impression or have a certain outward aspect;
          "She seems to be sleeping"; "This appears to be a very
          difficult problem"; "This project looks fishy"; "They
          appeared like people who had not eaten or slept for a
          long time" [syn: {look}, {appear}]
     2: seem to be true, probable, or apparent; "It seems that he is
        very gifted"; "It appears that the weather in California
        is very bad" [syn: {appear}]
     3: appear to exist; "There seems no reason to go ahead with the
        project now"
     4: appear to one's own mind or opinion; "I seem to be
        misunderstood by everyone"; "I can't seem to learn these
        Chinese characters"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
