<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>selling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>selling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sell \Sell\ (s[e^]l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sold} (s[=o]ld); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Selling}.] [OE. sellen, sillen, AS. sellan,
   syllan, to give, to deliver; akin to OS. sellian, OFries.
   sella, OHG. sellen, Icel. selja to hand over, to sell, Sw.
   s["a]lja to sell, Dan. s[ae]lge, Goth. saljan to offer a
   sacrifice; all from a noun akin to E. sale. Cf. {Sale}.]
   1. To transfer to another for an equivalent; to give up for a
      valuable consideration; to dispose of in return for
      something, especially for money. It is the correlative of
      buy.
      [1913 Webster]

            If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that thou hast,
            and give to the poor.                 --Matt. xix.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am changed; I'll go sell all my land. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sell is corellative to buy, as one party buys what the
         other sells. It is distinguished usually from exchange
         or barter, in which one commodity is given for another;
         whereas in selling the consideration is usually money,
         or its representative in current notes.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To make a matter of bargain and sale of; to accept a price
      or reward for, as for a breach of duty, trust, or the
      like; to betray.
      [1913 Webster]

            You would have sold your king to slaughter. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To impose upon; to trick; to deceive; to make a fool of;
      to cheat. [Slang] --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To sell one's life dearly}, to cause much loss to those who
      take one's life, as by killing a number of one's
      assailants.

   {To sell} (anything) {out}, to dispose of it wholly or
      entirely; as, he had sold out his corn, or his interest in
      a business.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>selling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>selling
     n : the exchange of goods for an agreed sum of money [syn: {merchandising},
          {marketing}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
