<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sending</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sending</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Send \Send\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sent}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sending}.] [AS. sendan; akin to OS. sendian, D. zenden, G.
   senden, OHG. senten, Icel. senda, Sw. s["a]nda, Dan. sende,
   Goth. sandjan, and to Goth. sinp a time (properly, a going),
   gasinpa companion, OHG. sind journey, AS. s[=i]?, Icel. sinni
   a walk, journey, a time. W. hynt a way, journey, OIr. s?t.
   Cf. {Sense}.]
   1. To cause to go in any manner; to dispatch; to commission
      or direct to go; as, to send a messenger.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have not sent these prophets, yet they ran. --Jer.
                                                  xxiii. 21.
      [1913 Webster]

            I proceeded forth and came from God; neither came I
            of myself, but he sent me.            --John viii.
                                                  42.
      [1913 Webster]

            Servants, sent on messages, stay out somewhat longer
            than the message requires.            --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give motion to; to cause to be borne or carried; to
      procure the going, transmission, or delivery of; as, to
      send a message.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . sent letters by posts on horseback.
                                                  --Esther viii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

            O send out thy light an thy truth; let them lead me.
                                                  --Ps. xliii.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To emit; to impel; to cast; to throw; to hurl; as, to send
      a ball, an arrow, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cause to be or to happen; to bestow; to inflict; to
      grant; -- sometimes followed by a dependent proposition.
      ``God send him well!'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord shall send upon thee cursing, vexation, and
            rebuke.                               --Deut.
                                                  xxviii. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

            And sendeth rain on the just and on the unjust.
                                                  --Matt. v. 45.
      [1913 Webster]

            God send your mission may bring back peace. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sending</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sending
     n : the act of causing something to go (especially messages)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
