<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sense</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sense</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sense \Sense\, n. [L. sensus, from sentire, sensum, to perceive,
   to feel, from the same root as E. send; cf. OHG. sin sense,
   mind, sinnan to go, to journey, G. sinnen to meditate, to
   think: cf. F. sens. For the change of meaning cf. {See}, v.
   t. See {Send}, and cf. {Assent}, {Consent}, {Scent}, v. t.,
   {Sentence}, {Sentient}.]
   1. (Physiol.) A faculty, possessed by animals, of perceiving
      external objects by means of impressions made upon certain
      organs (sensory or sense organs) of the body, or of
      perceiving changes in the condition of the body; as, the
      senses of sight, smell, hearing, taste, and touch. See
      {Muscular sense}, under {Muscular}, and {Temperature
      sense}, under {Temperature}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let fancy still my sense in Lethe steep. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            What surmounts the reach
            Of human sense I shall delineate.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The traitor Sense recalls
            The soaring soul from rest.           --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Perception by the sensory organs of the body; sensation;
      sensibility; feeling.
      [1913 Webster]

            In a living creature, though never so great, the
            sense and the affects of any one part of the body
            instantly make a transcursion through the whole.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Perception through the intellect; apprehension;
      recognition; understanding; discernment; appreciation.
      [1913 Webster]

            This Basilius, having the quick sense of a lover.
                                                  --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

            High disdain from sense of injured merit. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Sound perception and reasoning; correct judgment; good
      mental capacity; understanding; also, that which is sound,
      true, or reasonable; rational meaning. ``He speaks
      sense.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He raves; his words are loose
            As heaps of sand, and scattering wide from sense.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is felt or is held as a sentiment, view, or
      opinion; judgment; notion; opinion.
      [1913 Webster]

            I speak my private but impartial sense
            With freedom.                         --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The municipal council of the city had ceased to
            speak the sense of the citizens.      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Meaning; import; signification; as, the true sense of
      words or phrases; the sense of a remark.
      [1913 Webster]

            So they read in the book in the law of God
            distinctly, and gave the sense.       --Neh. viii.
                                                  8.
      [1913 Webster]

            I think 't was in another sense.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Moral perception or appreciation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some are so hardened in wickedness as to have no
            sense of the most friendly offices.   --L' Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Geom.) One of two opposite directions in which a line,
      surface, or volume, may be supposed to be described by the
      motion of a point, line, or surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Common sense}, according to Sir W. Hamilton:
      (a) ``The complement of those cognitions or convictions
          which we receive from nature, which all men possess in
          common, and by which they test the truth of knowledge
          and the morality of actions.''
      (b) ``The faculty of first principles.'' These two are the
          philosophical significations.
      (c) ``Such ordinary complement of intelligence, that,if a
          person be deficient therein, he is accounted mad or
          foolish.''
      (d) When the substantive is emphasized: ``Native practical
          intelligence, natural prudence, mother wit, tact in
          behavior, acuteness in the observation of character,
          in contrast to habits of acquired learning or of
          speculation.''

   {Moral sense}. See under {Moral},
      (a) .

   {The inner sense}, or {The internal sense}, capacity of the
      mind to be aware of its own states; consciousness;
      reflection. ``This source of ideas every man has wholly in
      himself, and though it be not sense, as having nothing to
      do with external objects, yet it is very like it, and
      might properly enough be called internal sense.'' --Locke.

   {Sense capsule} (Anat.), one of the cartilaginous or bony
      cavities which inclose, more or less completely, the
      organs of smell, sight, and hearing.

   {Sense organ} (Physiol.), a specially irritable mechanism by
      which some one natural force or form of energy is enabled
      to excite sensory nerves; as the eye, ear, an end bulb or
      tactile corpuscle, etc.

   {Sense organule} (Anat.), one of the modified epithelial
      cells in or near which the fibers of the sensory nerves
      terminate.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Understanding; reason.

   Usage: {Sense}, {Understanding}, {Reason}. Some philosophers
          have given a technical signification to these terms,
          which may here be stated. Sense is the mind's acting
          in the direct cognition either of material objects or
          of its own mental states. In the first case it is
          called the outer, in the second the inner, sense.
          Understanding is the logical faculty, i. e., the power
          of apprehending under general conceptions, or the
          power of classifying, arranging, and making
          deductions. Reason is the power of apprehending those
          first or fundamental truths or principles which are
          the conditions of all real and scientific knowledge,
          and which control the mind in all its processes of
          investigation and deduction. These distinctions are
          given, not as established, but simply because they
          often occur in writers of the present day.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sense</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sense \Sense\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sensed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sensing}.]
   To perceive by the senses; to recognize. [Obs. or Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Is he sure that objects are not otherwise sensed by
         others than they are by him?             --Glanvill.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sense</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sense
     n 1: a general conscious awareness; "a sense of security"; "a
          sense of happiness"; "a sense of danger"; "a sense of
          self"
     2: the meaning of a word or expression; the way in which a word
        or expression or situation can be interpreted; "the
        dictionary gave several senses for the word"; "in the best
        sense charity is really a duty"; "the signifier is linked
        to the signified" [syn: {signified}]
     3: the faculty through which the external world is apprehended;
        "in the dark he had to depend on touch and on his senses
        of smell and hearing" [syn: {sensation}, {sentience}, {sentiency},
         {sensory faculty}]
     4: sound practical judgment; "I can't see the sense in doing it
        now"; "he hasn't got the sense God gave little green
        apples"; "fortunately she had the good sense to run away"
        [syn: {common sense}, {good sense}, {gumption}, {horse
        sense}, {mother wit}]
     5: a natural appreciation or ability; "a keen musical sense";
        "a good sense of timing"
     v 1: perceive by a physical sensation, e.g., coming from the skin
          or muscles; "He felt the wind"; "She felt an object
          brushing her arm"; "He felt his flesh crawl"; "She felt
          the heat when she got out of the car" [syn: {feel}]
     2: detect some circumstance or entity automatically; "This
        robot can sense the presence of people in the room";
        "particle detectors sense ionization"
     3: become aware of not through the senses but instinctively; "I
        sense his hostility"
     4: comprehend; "I sensed the real meaning of his letter"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
