<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sensible</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sensible</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sensible \Sen"si*ble\, a. [F., fr. L. sensibilis, fr. sensus
   sense.]
   1. Capable of being perceived by the senses; apprehensible
      through the bodily organs; hence, also, perceptible to the
      mind; making an impression upon the sense, reason, or
      understanding; ?????? heat; sensible resistance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Air is sensible to the touch by its motion.
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

            The disgrace was more sensible than the pain. --Sir
                                                  W. Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

            Any very sensible effect upon the prices of things.
                                                  --A. Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Having the capacity of receiving impressions from external
      objects; capable of perceiving by the instrumentality of
      the proper organs; liable to be affected physsically or
      mentally; impressible.
      [1913 Webster]

            Would your cambric were sensible as your finger.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: Liable to impression from without; easily affected;
      having nice perception or acute feeling; sensitive; also,
      readily moved or affected by natural agents; delicate; as,
      a sensible thermometer. ``With affection wondrous
      sensible.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Perceiving or having perception, either by the senses or
      the mind; cognizant; perceiving so clearly as to be
      convinced; satisfied; persuaded.
      [1913 Webster]

            He [man] can not think at any time, waking or
            sleeping, without being sensible of it. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            They are now sensible it would have been better to
            comply than to refuse.                --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Having moral perception; capable of being affected by
      moral good or evil.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Possessing or containing sense or reason; giftedwith, or
      characterized by, good or common sense; intelligent; wise.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now a sensible man, by and by a fool. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Sensible note} or {Sensible tone} (Mus.), the major seventh
      note of any scale; -- so called because, being but a half
      step below the octave, or key tone, and naturally leading
      up to that, it makes the ear sensible of its approaching
      sound. Called also the {leading tone}.

   {Sensible horizon}. See {Horizon}, n., 2.
      (a) .
          [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Intelligent; wise.

   Usage: {Sensible}, {Intelligent}. We call a man sensible
          whose judgments and conduct are marked and governed by
          sound judgment or good common semse. We call one
          intelligent who is quick and clear in his
          understanding, i. e., who discriminates readily and
          nicely in respect to difficult and important
          distinction. The sphere of the sensible man lies in
          matters of practical concern; of the intelligent man,
          in subjects of intellectual interest. ``I have been
          tired with accounts from sensible men, furnished with
          matters of fact which have happened within their own
          knowledge.'' --Addison. ``Trace out numerous footsteps
          . . . of a most wise and intelligent architect
          throughout all this stupendous fabric.'' --Woodward.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sensible</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sensible \Sen"si*ble\, n.
   1. Sensation; sensibility. [R.] ''Our temper changed . . .
      which must needs remove the sensible of pain.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which impresses itself on the sense; anything
      perceptible.
      [1913 Webster]

            Aristotle distinguished sensibles into common and
            proper.                               --Krauth-Fleming.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which has sensibility; a sensitive being. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This melancholy extends itself not to men only, but
            even to vegetals and sensibles.       --Burton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sensible</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sensible
     adj 1: showing reason or sound judgment; "a sensible choice"; "a
            sensible person" [syn: {reasonable}] [ant: {unreasonable}]
     2: able to feel or perceive; "even amoeba are sensible
        creatures"; "the more sensible p{ enveloping(a),
        shrouding(a), concealing,&amp; (concealing by enclosing or
        wrapping as if in something that is not solid; "the
        enveloping darkness"; "hills concealed by shrouding
        mists") }arts of the skin" [syn: {sensitive}] [ant: {insensible}]
     3: acting with or showing thought and good sense; "a sensible
        young man" [syn: {thoughtful}]
     4: marked by the exercise of good judgment or common sense in
        practical matters; "judicious use of one's money"; "a
        sensible manager"; "a wise decision" [syn: {judicious}, {wise}]
     5: readily perceived by the senses; "the sensible universe"; "a
        sensible odor"
     6: aware intuitively or intellectually of something sensed;
        "made sensible of his mistakes"; "I am sensible that the
        mention of such a circumstance may appear trifling"- Henry
        Hallam; "sensible that a good deal more is still to be
        done"- Edmund Burke
     7: proceeding from good sense or judgment; "a sensible choice"
        [syn: {judicious}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
