<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sequence</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sequence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sequence \Se"quence\ (s[=e]"kwens), n. [F. s['e]quence, L.
   sequentia, fr. sequens. See {Sequent}.]
   1. The state of being sequent; succession; order of
      following; arrangement.
      [1913 Webster]

            How art thou a king
            But by fair sequence and succession?  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sequence and series of the seasons of the year.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which follows or succeeds as an effect; sequel;
      consequence; result.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inevitable sequences of sin and punishment.
                                                  --Bp. Hall.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Philos.) Simple succession, or the coming after in time,
      without asserting or implying causative energy; as, the
      reactions of chemical agents may be conceived as merely
      invariable sequences.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mus.)
      (a) Any succession of chords (or harmonic phrase) rising
          or falling by the regular diatonic degrees in the same
          scale; a succession of similar harmonic steps.
      (b) A melodic phrase or passage successively repeated one
          tone higher; a rosalia.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (R.C.Ch.) A hymn introduced in the Mass on certain
      festival days, and recited or sung immediately before the
      gospel, and after the gradual or introit, whence the name.
      --Bp. Fitzpatrick.
      [1913 Webster]

            Originally the sequence was called a Prose, because
            its early form was rhythmical prose.  --Shipley.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Card Playing)
      (a) (Whist) Three or more cards of the same suit in
          immediately consecutive order of value; as, ace, king,
          and queen; or knave, ten, nine, and eight.
      (b) (Poker) All five cards, of a hand, in consecutive
          order as to value, but not necessarily of the same
          suit; when of one suit, it is called a {sequence
          flush}.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. the specific order of any linear arrangement of items; as,
      the sequence of amino acid residues in a protein; the
      sequence of instructions in a computer program; the
      sequence of acts in a variety show.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sequence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sequence \Se"quence\, v. t. (Biochem.)
   to determine the sequence of; as, to sequence a protein or a
   DNA fragment.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sequence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sequence
     n 1: serial arrangement in which things follow in logical order
          or a recurrent pattern; "the sequence of names was
          alphabetical"; "he invented a technique to determine the
          sequence of base pairs in DNA"
     2: a following of one thing after another in time; "the doctor
        saw a sequence of patients" [syn: {chronological sequence},
         {succession}, {successiveness}, {chronological succession}]
     3: film consisting of a succession of related shots that
        develop a given subject in a movie [syn: {episode}]
     4: the action of following in order; "he played the trumps in
        sequence" [syn: {succession}]
     5: several repetitions of a melodic phrase in different keys
     v 1: arrange in a sequence
     2: determine the order of constituents in; "They sequenced the
        human genome"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
