<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>serve</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>serve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>serve
     
        &lt;networking&gt; To be a {server}, to provide a {service}.
     
        E.g., "The {shttpd} serves requested documents to clients over
        a secure link."
     
        (1997-09-11)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>serve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Serve \Serve\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Served}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Serving}.] [OE. serven, servien, OF. &amp; F. servir, fr. L.
   servire; akin to servus a servant or slave, servare to
   protect, preserve, observe; cf. Zend har to protect, haurva
   protecting. Cf. {Conserve}, {Desert} merit, {Dessert},
   {Observe}, {Serf}, {Sergeant}.]
   1. To work for; to labor in behalf of; to exert one's self
      continuously or statedly for the benefit of; to do service
      for; to be in the employment of, as an inferior, domestic,
      serf, slave, hired assistant, official helper, etc.;
      specifically, in a religious sense, to obey and worship.
      [1913 Webster]

            God is my witness, whom I serve with my spirit.
                                                  --Rom. i. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jacob loved Rachel; and said, I will serve thee
            seven years for Rachel thy younger daughter. --Gen.
                                                  xxix. 18.
      [1913 Webster]

            No man can serve two masters.         --Matt. vi.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

            Had I but served my God with half the zeal
            I served my king, he would not in mine age
            Have left me naked to mine enemies.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be subordinate to; to act a secondary part under; to
      appear as the inferior of; to minister to.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bodies bright and greater should not serve
            The less not bright.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be suitor to; to profess love to. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To serve a lady in his beste wise.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To wait upon; to supply the wants of; to attend;
      specifically, to wait upon at table; to attend at meals;
      to supply with food; as, to serve customers in a shop.
      [1913 Webster]

            Others, pampered in their shameless pride,
            Are served in plate and in their chariots ride.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, to bring forward, arrange, deal, or distribute, as
      a portion of anything, especially of food prepared for
      eating; -- often with up; formerly with in.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bid them cover the table, serve in the meat, and we
            will come in to dinner.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some part he roasts, then serves it up so dressed.
                                                  --Dryde.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To perform the duties belonging to, or required in or for;
      hence, to be of use to; as, a curate may serve two
      churches; to serve one's country.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To contribute or conduce to; to promote; to be sufficient
      for; to satisfy; as, to serve one's turn.
      [1913 Webster]

            Turn it into some advantage, by observing where it
            can serve another end.                --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To answer or be (in the place of something) to; as, a sofa
      serves one for a seat and a couch.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To treat; to behave one's self to; to requite; to act
      toward; as, he served me very ill.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To work; to operate; as, to serve the guns.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Law)
       (a) To bring to notice, deliver, or execute, either
           actually or constructively, in such manner as the law
           requires; as, to serve a summons.
       (b) To make legal service opon (a person named in a writ,
           summons, etc.); as, to serve a witness with a
           subp[oe]na.
           [1913 Webster]

   12. To pass or spend, as time, esp. time of punishment; as,
       to serve a term in prison.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To copulate with; to cover; as, a horse serves a mare; --
       said of the male.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Tennis) To lead off in delivering (the ball).
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Naut.) To wind spun yarn, or the like, tightly around (a
       rope or cable, etc.) so as to protect it from chafing or
       from the weather. See under {Serving}.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To serve an attachment} or {To serve a writ of attachment}
      (Law), to levy it on the person or goods by seizure, or to
      seize.

   {To serve an execution} (Law), to levy it on a lands, goods,
      or person, by seizure or taking possession.

   {To serve an office}, to discharge a public duty.

   {To serve a process} (Law), in general, to read it, so as to
      give due notice to the party concerned, or to leave an
      attested copy with him or his attorney, or his usual place
      of abode.

   {To serve a warrant}, to read it, and seize the person
      against whom it is issued.

   {To serve a writ} (Law), to read it to the defendant, or to
      leave an attested copy at his usual place of abode.

   {To serve one out}, to retaliate upon; to requite. ``I'll
      serve you out for this.'' --C. Kingsley.

   {To serve one right}, to treat, or cause to befall one,
      according to his deserts; -- used commonly of ill deserts;
      as, it serves the scoundrel right.

   {To serve one's self of}, to avail one's self of; to make use
      of. [A Gallicism]
      [1913 Webster]

            I will serve myself of this concession.
                                                  --Chillingworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To serve out}, to distribute; as, to serve out rations.

   {To serve the time} or {To serve the hour}, to regulate one's
      actions by the requirements of the time instead of by
      one's duty; to be a timeserver. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They think herein we serve the time, because thereby
            we either hold or seek preferment.    --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To obey; minister to; subserve; promote; aid; help;
        assist; benefit; succor.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>serve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Serve \Serve\, v. i.
   1. To be a servant or a slave; to be employed in labor or
      other business for another; to be in subjection or
      bondage; to render menial service.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord shall give thee rest . . . from the hard
            bondage wherein thou wast made to serve. --Isa. xiv.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perform domestic offices; to be occupied with household
      affairs; to prepare and dish up food, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            But Martha . . . said, Lord, dost thou not care that
            my sister hath left me to serve alone? --Luke x. 40.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be in service; to do duty; to discharge the
      requirements of an office or employment. Specifically, to
      act in the public service, as a soldier, seaman. etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many . . . who had before been great commanders, but
            now served as private gentlemen without pay.
                                                  --Knolles.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be of use; to answer a purpose; to suffice; to suit; to
      be convenient or favorable.
      [1913 Webster]

            This little brand will serve to light your fire.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            As occasion serves, this noble queen
            And prince shall follow with a fresh supply. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Tennis) To lead off in delivering the ball.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>serve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>serve
     n : (sports) a stroke that puts the ball in play; "his powerful
         serves won the game" [syn: {service}]
     v 1: serve a purpose, role, or function; "The tree stump serves
          as a table"; "The female students served as a control
          group"; "This table would serve very well"; "His freedom
          served him well"; "The table functions as a desk" [syn:
          {function}]
     2: do duty or hold offices; serve in a specific function; "He
        served as head of the department for three years"; "She
        served in Congress for two terms"
     3: contribute or conduce to; "The scandal served to increase
        his popularity"
     4: be used by; as of a utility; "The sewage plant served the
        neighboring communities"; "The garage served to shelter
        his horses" [syn: {service}]
     5: help to some food; help with food or drink; "I served him
        three times, and after that he helped himself" [syn: {help}]
     6: provide (usually but not necessarily food); "We serve meals
        for the homeless"; "She dished out the soup at 8 P.M.";
        "The entertainers served up a lively show" [syn: {serve up},
         {dish out}, {dish up}, {dish}]
     7: devote (part of) one's life or efforts to, as of countries,
        institutions, or ideas; "She served the art of music"; "He
        served the church"; "serve the country"
     8: promote, benefit, or be useful or beneficial to; "Art serves
        commerce"; "Their interests are served"; "The lake serves
        recreation"; "The President's wisdom has served the
        counrty well" [syn: {serve well}]
     9: spend time in prison or in a labor camp; "He did six years
        for embezzlement" [syn: {do}]
     10: work for or be a servant to; "May I serve you?"; "She
         attends the old lady in the wheelchair"; "Can you wait on
         our table, please?"; "Is a salesperson assisting you?";
         "The minister served the King for many years" [syn: {attend
         to}, {wait on}, {attend}, {assist}]
     11: deliver a warrant or summons to someone; "He was processed
         by the sheriff" [syn: {process}, {swear out}]
     12: be sufficient; be adequate, either in quality or quantity;
         "A few words would answer"; "This car suits my purpose
         well"; "Will $100 do?"; "A 'B' grade doesn't suffice to
         get me into medical school"; "Nothing else will serve"
         [syn: {suffice}, {do}, {answer}]
     13: do military service; "She served in Vietnam"; "My sons never
         served, because they are short-sighted"
     14: mate with; "male animals serve the females for breeding
         purposes" [syn: {service}]
     15: put the ball into play; "It was Agassi's turn to serve"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
