<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>session</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>session</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>session
     
        &lt;networking&gt; 1. A lasting connection between a user (or user
        agent) and a {peer}, typically a {server}, usually involving
        the exchange of many packets between the user's computer and
        the server.  A session is typically implemented as a layer in
        a network {protocol} (e.g. {telnet}, {FTP}).
     
        In the case of protocols where there is no concept of a
        session layer (e.g. {UDP}) or where sessions at the {session
        layer} are generally very short-lived (e.g. {HTTP}), {virtual}
        sessions are implemented by having each exchange between the
        user and the remote host include some form of {cookie} which
        stores state (e.g. a unique session ID, information about the
        user's preferences or authorisation level, etc.).
     
        See also {login}.
     
        2. A lasting connection using the {session layer} of a
        networking protocol.
     
        (1997-08-03)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>session</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Session \Ses"sion\, n. [L. sessio, fr. sedere, sessum, to sit:
   cf. F. session. See {Sit}.]
   1. The act of sitting, or the state of being seated.
      [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            So much his ascension into heaven and his session at
            the right hand of God do import.      --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            But Viven, gathering somewhat of his mood, . . .
            Leaped from her session on his lap, and stood.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The actual sitting of a court, council, legislature, etc.,
      or the actual assembly of the members of such a body, for
      the transaction of business.
      [1913 Webster]

            It's fit this royal session do proceed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, also, the time, period, or term during which a
      court, council, legislature, etc., meets daily for
      business; or, the space of time between the first meeting
      and the prorogation or adjournment; thus, a session of
      Parliaments is opened with a speech from the throne, and
      closed by prorogation. The session of a judicial court is
      called a term.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was resolved that the convocation should meet at
            the beginning of the next session of Parliament.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sessions, in some of the States, is particularly used
         as a title for a court of justices, held for granting
         licenses to innkeepers, etc., and for laying out
         highways, and the like; it is also the title of several
         courts of criminal jurisdiction in England and the
         United States.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Church session}, the lowest court in the Presbyterian
      Church, composed of the pastor and a body of elders
      elected by the members of a particular church, and having
      the care of matters pertaining to the religious interests
      of that church, as the admission and dismission of
      members, discipline, etc.

   {Court of Session}, the supreme civil court of Scotland.

   {Quarter sessions}. (Eng.Law) See under {Quarter}.

   {Sessions of the peace}, sittings held by justices of the
      peace. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>session</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>session
     n 1: a meeting for execution of a group's functions; "it was the
          opening session of the legislature"
     2: the time during which a school holds classes; "they had to
        shorten the school term" [syn: {school term}, {academic
        term}, {academic session}]
     3: a meeting devoted to a particular activity; "a filming
        session"; "a gossip session"
     4: a meeting of spiritualists; "the seance was held in the
        medium's parlor" [syn: {seance}, {sitting}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
