<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>settling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>settling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Settle \Set"tle\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Settled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Settling}.] [OE. setlen, AS. setlan. [root]154. See
   {Settle}, n. In senses 7, 8, and 9 perhaps confused with OE.
   sahtlen to reconcile, AS. sahtlian, fr. saht reconciliation,
   sacon to contend, dispute. Cf. {Sake}.]
   1. To place in a fixed or permanent condition; to make firm,
      steady, or stable; to establish; to fix; esp., to
      establish in life; to fix in business, in a home, or the
      like.
      [1913 Webster]

            And he settled his countenance steadfastly upon him,
            until he was ashamed.                 --2 Kings
                                                  viii. 11.
                                                  (Rev. Ver.)
      [1913 Webster]

            The father thought the time drew on
            Of setting in the world his only son. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To establish in the pastoral office; to ordain or install
      as pastor or rector of a church, society, or parish; as,
      to settle a minister. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to be no longer in a disturbed condition; to
      render quiet; to still; to calm; to compose.
      [1913 Webster]

            God settled then the huge whale-bearing lake.
                                                  --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hoping that sleep might settle his brains. --Bunyan.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To clear of dregs and impurities by causing them to sink;
      to render pure or clear; -- said of a liquid; as, to
      settle coffee, or the grounds of coffee.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To restore or bring to a smooth, dry, or passable
      condition; -- said of the ground, of roads, and the like;
      as, clear weather settles the roads.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cause to sink; to lower; to depress; hence, also, to
      render close or compact; as, to settle the contents of a
      barrel or bag by shaking it.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To determine, as something which is exposed to doubt or
      question; to free from unscertainty or wavering; to make
      sure, firm, or constant; to establish; to compose; to
      quiet; as, to settle the mind when agitated; to settle
      questions of law; to settle the succession to a throne; to
      settle an allowance.
      [1913 Webster]

            It will settle the wavering, and confirm the
            doubtful.                             --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To adjust, as something in discussion; to make up; to
      compose; to pacify; as, to settle a quarrel.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To adjust, as accounts; to liquidate; to balance; as, to
      settle an account.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Hence, to pay; as, to settle a bill. [Colloq.] --Abbott.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To plant with inhabitants; to colonize; to people; as,
       the French first settled Canada; the Puritans settled New
       England; Plymouth was settled in 1620.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To settle on} or {To settle upon},
       (a) to confer upon by permanent grant; to assure to. ``I
           . . . have settled upon him a good annuity.''
           --Addison.
       (b) to choose; to decide on; -- sometimes with the
           implication that the choice is not ideal, but the
           best available.

   {To settle the land} (Naut.), to cause it to sink, or appear
      lower, by receding from it.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To fix; establish; regulate; arrange; compose; adjust;
        determine; decide.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>settling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Settling \Set"tling\, n.
   1. The act of one who, or that which, settles; the act of
      establishing one's self, of colonizing, subsiding,
      adjusting, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. That which settles at the bottom of a liquid; lees;
      dregs; sediment. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Settling day}, a day for settling accounts, as in the stock
      market.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>settling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>settling
     n : a gradual sinking to a lower level [syn: {subsiding}, {subsidence}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
