<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shade</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shade, OH
  Zip code(s): 45776
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shade \Shade\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Shaded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Shading}.]
   1. To shelter or screen by intercepting the rays of light; to
      keep off illumination from. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            I went to crop the sylvan scenes,
            And shade our altars with their leafy greens.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To shelter; to cover from injury; to protect; to screen;
      to hide; as, to shade one's eyes.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ere in our own house I do shade my head. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To obscure; to dim the brightness of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shad'st
            The full blaze of thy beams.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To pain in obscure colors; to darken.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To mark with gradations of light or color.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To present a shadow or image of; to shadow forth; to
      represent. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            [The goddess] in her person cunningly did shade
            That part of Justice which is Equity. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shade \Shade\ (sh[=a]d), n. [OE. shade, shadewe, schadewe, AS.
   sceadu, scead; akin to OS. skado, D. schaduw, OHG. scato,
   (gen. scatewes), G. schatten, Goth. skadus, Ir. &amp; Gael.
   sgath, and probably to Gr. sko`tos darkness. [root]162. Cf.
   {Shadow}, {Shed} a hat.]
   1. Comparative obscurity owing to interception or
      interruption of the rays of light; partial darkness caused
      by the intervention of something between the space
      contemplated and the source of light.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Shade differs from shadow as it implies no particular
         form or definite limit; whereas a shadow represents in
         form the object which intercepts the light. When we
         speak of the shade of a tree, we have no reference to
         its form; but when we speak of measuring a pyramid or
         other object by its shadow, we have reference to its
         form and extent.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Darkness; obscurity; -- often in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            The shades of night were falling fast. --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An obscure place; a spot not exposed to light; hence, a
      secluded retreat.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let us seek out some desolate shade, and there
            Weep our sad bosoms empty.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which intercepts, or shelters from, light or the
      direct rays of the sun; hence, also, that which protects
      from heat or currents of air; a screen; protection;
      shelter; cover; as, a lamp shade.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord is thy shade upon thy right hand. --Ps.
                                                  cxxi. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sleep under a fresh tree's shade.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let the arched knife well sharpened now assail the
            spreading shades of vegetables.       --J. Philips.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Shadow. [Poetic.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Envy will merit, as its shade, pursue. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The soul after its separation from the body; -- so called
      because the ancients it to be perceptible to the sight,
      though not to the touch; a spirit; a ghost; as, the shades
      of departed heroes.
      [1913 Webster]

            Swift as thought the flitting shade
            Thro' air his momentary journey made. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Painting, Drawing, etc.) The darker portion of a picture;
      a less illuminated part. See Def. 1, above.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Degree or variation of color, as darker or lighter,
      stronger or paler; as, a delicate shade of pink.
      [1913 Webster]

            White, red, yellow, blue, with their several
            degrees, or shades and mixtures, as green only in by
            the eyes.                             --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A minute difference or variation, as of thought, belief,
      expression, etc.; also, the quality or degree of anything
      which is distinguished from others similar by slight
      differences; as, the shades of meaning in synonyms.
      [1913 Webster]

            New shades and combinations of thought. --De
                                                  Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every shade of religious and political opinion has
            its own headquarters.                 --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   {The Shades}, the Nether World; the supposed abode of souls
      after leaving the body.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shade \Shade\ (sh[=a]d), v. i. [See {Shade}, n.]
   To undergo or exhibit minute difference or variation, as of
   color, meaning, expression, etc.; to pass by slight changes;
   -- used chiefly with a preposition, as into, away, off.

         This small group will be most conveniently treated with
         the emotional division, into which it shades. --Edmund
                                                  Gurney.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shade
     n 1: relative darkness caused by light rays being intercepted by
          an opaque body; "it is much cooler in the shade";
          "there's too much shadiness to take good photographs"
          [syn: {shadiness}, {shadowiness}]
     2: a quality of a given color that differs slightly from a
        primary color; "after several trials he mixed the shade of
        pink that she wanted" [syn: {tint}, {tincture}, {tone}]
     3: protective covering that protects something from direct
        sunlight; "they used umbrellas as shades"; "as the sun
        moved he readjusted the shade"
     4: a subtle difference in meaning or opinion or attitude;
        "without understanding the finer nuances you can't enjoy
        the humor"; "don't argue about shades of meaning" [syn: {nuance},
         {nicety}, {subtlety}, {refinement}]
     5: a position of relative inferiority; "an achievement that
        puts everything else in the shade"; "his brother's success
        left him in the shade"
     6: a slight amount or degree of difference; "a tad too
        expensive"; "not a tad of difference"; "the new model is a
        shade better than the old one" [syn: {tad}]
     7: a mental representation of some haunting experience; "he
        looked like he had seen a ghost"; "it aroused specters
        from his past" [syn: {ghost}, {spook}, {wraith}, {specter},
         {spectre}]
     8: a representation of the effect of shade in a picture or
        drawing (as by shading or darker pigment)
     v 1: cast a shadow over [syn: {shadow}, {shade off}]
     2: represent the effect of shade or shadow on [syn: {fill in}]
     3: protect from light, heat, or view; "Shade your eyes when you
        step out into the bright sunlight"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
