<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shape</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shape \Shape\ (sh[=a]p), v. t. [imp. {Shaped} (sh[=a]pt); p. p.
   {Shaped} or {Shapen} (sh[=a]p"'n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Shaping}.] [OE. shapen, schapen, AS. sceapian. The p. p.
   shapen is from the strong verb, AS. scieppan, scyppan,
   sceppan, p. p. sceapen. See {Shape}, n.]
   1. To form or create; especially, to mold or make into a
      particular form; to give proper form or figure to.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was shapen in iniquity.             --Ps. li. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

            Grace shaped her limbs, and beauty decked her face.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To adapt to a purpose; to regulate; to adjust; to direct;
      as, to shape the course of a vessel.
      [1913 Webster]

            To the stream, when neither friends, nor force,
            Nor speed nor art avail, he shapes his course.
                                                  --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

            Charmed by their eyes, their manners I acquire,
            And shape my foolishness to their desire. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To imagine; to conceive; to call forth (ideas). [archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Oft my jealousy
            Shapes faults that are not.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To design; to prepare; to plan; to arrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            When shapen was all this conspiracy,
            From point to point.                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Shaping machine}. (Mach.) Same as {Shaper}.

   {To shape one's self}, to prepare; to make ready. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I will early shape me therefor.       --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shape \Shape\, v. i.
   To suit; to be adjusted or conformable. [R.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shape \Shape\, n. [OE. shap, schap, AS. sceap in gesceap
   creation, creature, fr. the root of scieppan, scyppan,
   sceppan, to shape, to do, to effect; akin to OS. giskeppian,
   OFries. skeppa, D. scheppen, G. schaffen, OHG. scaffan,
   scepfen, skeffen, Icer. skapa, skepja, Dan. skabe, skaffe,
   Sw. skapa, skaffa, Goth. gaskapjan, and perhaps to E. shave,
   v. Cf. {-ship}.]
   1. Character or construction of a thing as determining its
      external appearance; outward aspect; make; figure; form;
      guise; as, the shape of a tree; the shape of the head; an
      elegant shape.
      [1913 Webster]

            He beat me grievously, in the shape of a woman.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which has form or figure; a figure; an appearance; a
      being.
      [1913 Webster]

            Before the gates three sat,
            On either side, a formidable shape.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A model; a pattern; a mold.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Form of embodiment, as in words; form, as of thought or
      conception; concrete embodiment or example, as of some
      quality. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Dress for disguise; guise. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Look better on this virgin, and consider
            This Persian shape laid by, and she appearing
            In a Greekish dress.                  --Messinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Iron Manuf.)
      (a) A rolled or hammered piece, as a bar, beam, angle
          iron, etc., having a cross section different from
          merchant bar.
      (b) A piece which has been roughly forged nearly to the
          form it will receive when completely forged or fitted.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To take shape}, to assume a definite form.

   {in shape,, having a good muscle tone; healthy.

   {Get into shape}, to exercise so as to acquire a good muscle
      tone.1
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shape</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shape
     n 1: any spatial attributes (especially as defined by outline);
          "he could barely make out their shapes through the
          smoke" [syn: {form}, {configuration}, {contour}, {conformation}]
     2: the spatial arrangement of something as distinct from its
        substance; "geometry is the mathematical science of shape"
        [syn: {form}]
     3: alternative names for the body of a human being; "Leonardo
        studied the human body"; "he has a strong physique"; "the
        spirit is willing but the flesh is weak" [syn: {human body},
         {physical body}, {material body}, {soma}, {build}, {figure},
         {physique}, {anatomy}, {bod}, {chassis}, {frame}, {form},
         {flesh}]
     4: a concrete representation of an otherwise nebulous concept;
        "a circle was the embodiment of his concept of life" [syn:
         {embodiment}]
     5: the visual appearance of something or someone; "the delicate
        cast of his features" [syn: {form}, {cast}]
     6: the state of (good) health (especially in the phrases `in
        condition' or `in shape' or `out of condition' or `out of
        shape') [syn: {condition}]
     7: the supremem headquarters that advises NATO on military
        matters and oversees all aspects of the Allied Command
        Europe [syn: {Supreme Headquarters Allied Powers Europe}]
     8: a perceptual structure; "the composition presents problems
        for students of musical form"; "a visual pattern must
        include not only objects but the spaces between them"
        [syn: {form}, {pattern}]
     v 1: shape or influence; give direction to; "experience often
          determines ability"; "mold public opinion" [syn: {determine},
           {mold}, {influence}, {regulate}]
     2: make something, usually for a specific function; "She molded
        the riceballs carefully"; "Form cylinders from the dough";
        "shape a figure"; "Work the metal into a sword" [syn: {form},
         {work}, {mold}, {mould}, {forge}]
     3: give a shape or form to; "shape the dough" [syn: {form}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
