<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>share</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>share</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Share \Share\, n. [OE. schar, AS. scear; akin to OHG. scaro, G.
   schar, pflugshar, and E. shear, v. See {Shear}.]
   1. The part (usually an iron or steel plate) of a plow which
      cuts the ground at the bottom of a furrow; a plowshare.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The part which opens the ground for the reception of the
      seed, in a machine for sowing seed. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>share</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Share \Share\, v. i.
   To have part; to receive a portion; to partake, enjoy, or
   suffer with others.
   [1913 Webster]

         A right of inheritance gave every one a title to share
         in the goods of his father.              --Locke.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>share</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Share \Share\, n. [OE. share, AS. scearu, scaru, fr. sceran to
   shear, cut. See {Shear}, v.]
   1. A certain quantity; a portion; a part; a division; as, a
      small share of prudence.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, the part allotted or belonging to one, of any
      property or interest owned by a number; a portion among
      others; an apportioned lot; an allotment; a dividend. ``My
      share of fame.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, one of a certain number of equal portions into
      which any property or invested capital is divided; as, a
      ship owned in ten shares.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The pubes; the sharebone. [Obs.] --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To go shares}, to partake; to be equally concerned.

   {Share and share alike}, in equal shares.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>share</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Share \Share\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Shared}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sharing}.]
   1. To part among two or more; to distribute in portions; to
      divide.
      [1913 Webster]

            Suppose I share my fortune equally between my
            children and a stranger.              --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To partake of, use, or experience, with others; to have a
      portion of; to take and possess in common; as, to share a
      shelter with another.
      [1913 Webster]

            While avarice and rapine share the land. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cut; to shear; to cleave; to divide. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The shared visage hangs on equal sides. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>share</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>share
     n 1: any of the equal portions into which the capital stock of a
          corporation is divided and ownership of which is
          evidenced by a stock certificate; "he bought 100 shares
          of IBM at the market price"
     2: assets belonging to or due to or contributed by an
        individual person or group; "he wanted his share in cash"
        [syn: {portion}, {part}, {percentage}]
     3: the result of parcelling out or sharing; "death gets more
        than its share of attention from theologicans" [syn: {parcel},
         {portion}]
     4: any one of a number of individual efforts in a common
        endeavor; "I am proud of my contribution to the team's
        success"; "they all did their share of the work" [syn: {contribution},
         {part}]
     5: a sharp steel wedge that cuts loose the top layer of soil
        [syn: {plowshare}, {ploughshare}]
     v 1: have in common; "Our children share a love of music"; "The
          two countries share a long border"
     2: use jointly or in common
     3: have, give, or receive a share of; "We shared the cake"
        [syn: {partake}, {partake in}]
     4: give out as one's portion or share [syn: {divvy up}, {portion
        out}, {apportion}, {deal}]
     5: communicate; "I'd like to share this idea with you"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
