<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sheet</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sheet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sheet \Sheet\, n. [OE. shete, schete, AS. sc[=e]te, sc[=y]te,
   fr. sce['a]t a projecting corner, a fold in a garment (akin
   to D. schoot sheet, bosom, lap, G. schoss bosom, lap, flap of
   a coat, Icel. skaut, Goth. skauts the hem of a garment);
   originally, that which shoots out, from the root of AS.
   sce['o]tan to shoot. [root]159. See {Shoot}, v. t.]
   In general, a large, broad piece of anything thin, as paper,
   cloth, etc.; a broad, thin portion of any substance; an
   expanded superficies. Specifically:
   (a) A broad piece of cloth, usually linen or cotton, used for
       wrapping the body or for a covering; especially, one used
       as an article of bedding next to the body.
       [1913 Webster]

             He fell into a trance, and saw heaven opened, and a
             certain vessel descending unto him, as it had been
             a great sheet knit at the four corners. --Acts x.
                                                  10, 11.
       [1913 Webster]

             If I do die before thee, prithee, shroud me
             In one of those same sheets.         --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]
   (b) A broad piece of paper, whether folded or unfolded,
       whether blank or written or printed upon; hence, a
       letter; a newspaper, etc.
   (c) A single signature of a book or a pamphlet; in pl., the
       book itself.
       [1913 Webster]

             To this the following sheets are intended for a
             full and distinct answer.            --Waterland.
       [1913 Webster]
   (d) A broad, thinly expanded portion of metal or other
       substance; as, a sheet of copper, of glass, or the like;
       a plate; a leaf.
   (e) A broad expanse of water, or the like. ``The two
       beautiful sheets of water.'' --Macaulay.
   (f) A sail. --Dryden.
   (g) (Geol.) An extensive bed of an eruptive rock intruded
       between, or overlying, other strata.
       [1913 Webster]

   2. [AS. sce['a]ta. See the Etymology above.] (Naut.)
      (a) A rope or chain which regulates the angle of
          adjustment of a sail in relation in relation to the
          wind; -- usually attached to the lower corner of a
          sail, or to a yard or a boom.
      (b) pl. The space in the forward or the after part of a
          boat where there are no rowers; as, fore sheets; stern
          sheets.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sheet is often used adjectively, or in combination, to
         denote that the substance to the name of which it is
         prefixed is in the form of sheets, or thin plates or
         leaves; as, sheet brass, or sheet-brass; sheet glass,
         or sheet-glass; sheet gold, or sheet-gold; sheet iron,
         or sheet-iron, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {A sheet in the wind}, half drunk. [Sailors' Slang]

   {Both sheets in the wind}, very drunk. [Sailors' Slang]

   {In sheets}, lying flat or expanded; not folded, or folded
      but not bound; -- said especially of printed sheets.

   {Sheet bend} (Naut.), a bend or hitch used for temporarily
      fastening a rope to the bight of another rope or to an
      eye.

   {Sheet lightning}, {Sheet piling}, etc. See under
      {Lightning}, {Piling}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sheet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sheet \Sheet\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sheeted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sheeting}.]
   1. To furnish with a sheet or sheets; to wrap in, or cover
      with, a sheet, or as with a sheet. ``The sheeted dead.''
      ``When snow the pasture sheets.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To expand, as a sheet.
      [1913 Webster]

            The star shot flew from the welkin blue,
            As it fell from the sheeted sky.      --J. R. Drake.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To sheet home} (Naut.), to haul upon a sheet until the sail
      is as flat, and the clew as near the wind, as possible.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sheet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sheet
     n 1: any broad thin expanse or surface; "a sheet of ice"
     2: used for writing or printing [syn: {piece of paper}, {sheet
        of paper}]
     3: bed linen consisting of a large rectangular piece of cotton
        or linen cloth; used in pairs [syn: {bed sheet}]
     4: (mathematics) an unbounded two-dimensional shape; "we will
        refer to the plane of the graph as the X-Y plane"; "any
        line joining two points on a plane lies wholly on that
        plane" [syn: {plane}]
     5: newspaper with half-size pages [syn: {tabloid}, {rag}]
     6: a flat artifact that is thin relative to its length and
        width [syn: {flat solid}]
     7: (nautical) a line (rope or chain) that regulates the angle
        at which a sail is set in relation to the wind [syn: {tack},
         {mainsheet}, {weather sheet}, {shroud}]
     8: a large piece of fabric (as canvas) by means of which wind
        is used to propel a sailing vessel [syn: {sail}, {canvas},
         {canvass}]
     v 1: come down as if in sheets; "The rain was sheeting down
          during the monsoon"
     2: cover with a sheet, as if by wrapping; "sheet the body"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
