<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sheep</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sheep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sheep
   are of different varieties. Probably the flocks of Abraham and
   Isaac were of the wild species found still in the mountain
   regions of Persia and Kurdistan. After the Exodus, and as a
   result of intercourse with surrounding nations, other species
   were no doubt introduced into the herds of the people of Israel.
   They are frequently mentioned in Scripture. The care of a
   shepherd over his flock is referred to as illustrating God's
   care over his people (Ps. 23:1, 2; 74:1; 77:20; Isa. 40:11;
   53:6; John 10:1-5, 7-16).
   
     "The sheep of Palestine are longer in the head than ours, and
   have tails from 5 inches broad at the narrowest part to 15
   inches at the widest, the weight being in proportion, and
   ranging generally from 10 to 14 lbs., but sometimes extending to
   30 lbs. The tails are indeed huge masses of fat" (Geikie's Holy
   Land, etc.). The tail was no doubt the "rump" so frequently
   referred to in the Levitical sacrifices (Ex. 29:22; Lev. 3:9;
   7:3; 9:19). Sheep-shearing was generally an occasion of great
   festivity (Gen. 31:19; 38:12, 13; 1 Sam. 25:4-8, 36; 2 Sam.
   13:23-28).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sheep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SHEEP
     
        &lt;mathematics, tool&gt; A package for {symbolic mathematics},
        especially {tensor analysis} and General Relativity, developed
        by Inge Frick in Stockholm in the late 1970s to early 1980s.
        SHEEP was implemented in {DEC-10} {assembly language}, then in
        several {LISPs}.  The current version runs on {Sun}-3 and is
        based on {Portable Standard LISP}.
     
        ["Sheep, a Computer Algebra System for General Relativity",
        J.E.F. Skea et al in Proc First Brazilian School on Comp Alg,
        W. Roque et al eds, Oxford U Press 1993, v2].
     
       
     {(http://www.riaca.win.tue.nl/archive/can/SystemsOverview/Special/Tensoranalysis/SHEEP/index.html)}.
     
        (2002-12-28)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sheep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sheep \Sheep\, n. sing. &amp; pl. [OE. shep, scheep, AS. sc?p,
   sce['a]p; akin to OFries. sk?p, LG. &amp; D. schaap, G. schaf,
   OHG. sc[=a]f, Skr. ch[=a]ga. [root]295. Cf. {Sheepherd}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) Any one of several species of ruminants of the
      genus {Ovis}, native of the higher mountains of both
      hemispheres, but most numerous in Asia.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The domestic sheep ({Ovis aries}) varies much in size,
         in the length and texture of its wool, the form and
         size of its horns, the length of its tail, etc. It was
         domesticated in prehistoric ages, and many distinct
         breeds have been produced; as the merinos, celebrated
         for their fine wool; the Cretan sheep, noted for their
         long horns; the fat-tailed, or Turkish, sheep,
         remarkable for the size and fatness of the tail, which
         often has to be supported on trucks; the Southdowns, in
         which the horns are lacking; and an Asiatic breed which
         always has four horns.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A weak, bashful, silly fellow. --Ainsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. Fig.: The people of God, as being under the government
      and protection of Christ, the great Shepherd.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Rocky mountain sheep}.(Zo["o]l.) See {Bighorn}.

   {Maned sheep}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Aoudad}.

   {Sheep bot} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of the sheep botfly. See
      {Estrus}.

   {Sheep dog} (Zo["o]l.), a shepherd dog, or collie.

   {Sheep laurel} (Bot.), a small North American shrub ({Kalmia
      angustifolia}) with deep rose-colored flowers in corymbs.
      

   {Sheep pest} (Bot.), an Australian plant ({Ac[ae]na ovina})
      related to the burnet. The fruit is covered with barbed
      spines, by which it adheres to the wool of sheep.

   {Sheep run}, an extensive tract of country where sheep range
      and graze.

   {Sheep's beard} (Bot.), a cichoraceous herb ({Urospermum
      Dalechampii}) of Southern Europe; -- so called from the
      conspicuous pappus of the achenes.

   {Sheep's bit} (Bot.), a European herb ({Jasione montana})
      having much the appearance of scabious.

   {Sheep pox} (Med.), a contagious disease of sheep,
      characterixed by the development of vesicles or pocks upon
      the skin.

   {Sheep scabious}. (Bot.) Same as {Sheep's bit}.

   {Sheep shears}, shears in which the blades form the two ends
      of a steel bow, by the elasticity of which they open as
      often as pressed together by the hand in cutting; -- so
      called because used to cut off the wool of sheep.

   {Sheep sorrel}. (Bot.), a prerennial herb ({Rumex
      Acetosella}) growing naturally on poor, dry, gravelly
      soil. Its leaves have a pleasant acid taste like sorrel.
      

   {Sheep's-wool} (Zo["o]l.), the highest grade of Florida
      commercial sponges ({Spongia equina}, variety
      {gossypina}).

   {Sheep tick} (Zo["o]l.), a wingless parasitic insect
      ({Melophagus ovinus}) belonging to the Diptera. It fixes
      its proboscis in the skin of the sheep and sucks the
      blood, leaving a swelling. Called also {sheep pest}, and
      {sheep louse}.

   {Sheep walk}, a pasture for sheep; a sheep run.

   {Wild sheep}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Argali}, {Mouflon}, and
      {O["o]rial}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sheep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sheep
     n 1: woolly usually horned ruminant mammal related to the goat
     2: a timid defenseless simpleton who is readily preyed upon
     3: a docile and vulnerable person who would rather follow than
        make an independent decision; "his students followed him
        like sheep"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
