<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shell</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SHELL
     
        &lt;language&gt; An early system on the {Datatron 200} series.
     
        [Listed in CACM 2(5):16 (May 1959)].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-05-11)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shell
     
        1. &lt;operating system&gt; (Originally from {Multics}, widely
        propagated via {Unix}) The {command interpreter} used to pass
        commands to an {operating system}; so called because it is the
        part of the operating system that interfaces with the outside
        world.
     
        The commonest Unix shells are the c shell ({csh}) and the
        Bourne shell ({sh}).
     
        2. (Or "wrapper") Any interface program that mediates access
        to a special resource or {server} for convenience, efficiency,
        or security reasons; for this meaning, the usage is usually "a
        shell around" whatever.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-05-11)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shell, WY
  Zip code(s): 82441
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shell \Shell\, n. [OE. shelle, schelle, AS. scell, scyll; akin
   to D. shel, Icel. skel, Goth. skalja a tile, and E. skill.
   Cf. {Scale} of fishes, {Shale}, {Skill}.]
   1. A hard outside covering, as of a fruit or an animal.
      Specifically:
      (a) The covering, or outside part, of a nut; as, a
          hazelnut shell.
      (b) A pod.
      (c) The hard covering of an egg.
          [1913 Webster]

                Think him as a serpent's egg, . . .
                And kill him in the shell.        --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) (Zo["o]l.) The hard calcareous or chitinous external
          covering of mollusks, crustaceans, and some other
          invertebrates. In some mollusks, as the cuttlefishes,
          it is internal, or concealed by the mantle. Also, the
          hard covering of some vertebrates, as the armadillo,
          the tortoise, and the like.
      (e) (Zo["o]l.) Hence, by extension, any mollusks having
          such a covering.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) A hollow projectile, of various shapes, adapted for
      a mortar or a cannon, and containing an explosive
      substance, ignited with a fuse or by percussion, by means
      of which the projectile is burst and its fragments
      scattered. See {Bomb}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The case which holds the powder, or charge of powder and
      shot, used with breechloading small arms.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any slight hollow structure; a framework, or exterior
      structure, regarded as not complete or filled in; as, the
      shell of a house.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A coarse kind of coffin; also, a thin interior coffin
      inclosed in a more substantial one. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An instrument of music, as a lyre, -- the first lyre
      having been made, it is said, by drawing strings over a
      tortoise shell.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Jubal struck the chorded shell.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. An engraved copper roller used in print works.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. pl. The husks of cacao seeds, a decoction of which is
      often used as a substitute for chocolate, cocoa, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) The outer frame or case of a block within which
      the sheaves revolve.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A light boat the frame of which is covered with thin wood
       or with paper; as, a racing shell.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Something similar in form or action to an ordnance shell;
       specif.:
       (a) (Fireworks) A case or cartridge containing a charge
           of explosive material, which bursts after having been
           thrown high into the air. It is often elevated
           through the agency of a larger firework in which it
           is contained.
       (b) (Oil Wells) A torpedo.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. A concave rough cast-iron tool in which a convex lens is
       ground to shape.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   13. A gouge bit or shell bit.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Message shell}, a bombshell inside of which papers may be
      put, in order to convey messages.

   {Shell bit}, a tool shaped like a gouge, used with a brace in
      boring wood. See {Bit}, n., 3.

   {Shell button}.
       (a) A button made of shell.
       (b) A hollow button made of two pieces, as of metal, one
           for the front and the other for the back, -- often
           covered with cloth, silk, etc.

   {Shell cameo}, a cameo cut in shell instead of stone.

   {Shell flower}. (Bot.) Same as {Turtlehead}.

   {Shell gland}. (Zo["o]l.)
       (a) A glandular organ in which the rudimentary shell is
           formed in embryonic mollusks.
       (b) A glandular organ which secretes the eggshells of
           various worms, crustacea, mollusks, etc.

   {Shell gun}, a cannon suitable for throwing shells.

   {Shell ibis} (Zo["o]l.), the openbill of India.

   {Shell jacket}, an undress military jacket.

   {Shell lime}, lime made by burning the shells of shellfish.
      

   {Shell marl} (Min.), a kind of marl characterized by an
      abundance of shells, or fragments of shells.

   {Shell meat}, food consisting of shellfish, or testaceous
      mollusks. --Fuller.

   {Shell mound}. See under {Mound}.

   {Shell of a boiler}, the exterior of a steam boiler, forming
      a case to contain the water and steam, often inclosing
      also flues and the furnace; the barrel of a cylindrical,
      or locomotive, boiler.

   {Shell road}, a road of which the surface or bed is made of
      shells, as oyster shells.

   {Shell sand}, minute fragments of shells constituting a
      considerable part of the seabeach in some places.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shell \Shell\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Shelled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Shelling}.]
   1. To strip or break off the shell of; to take out of the
      shell, pod, etc.; as, to shell nuts or pease; to shell
      oysters.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To separate the kernels of (an ear of Indian corn, wheat,
      oats, etc.) from the cob, ear, or husk.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To throw shells or bombs upon or into; to bombard; as, to
      shell a town.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To shell out}, to distribute freely; to bring out or pay, as
      money. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shell \Shell\, v. i.
   1. To fall off, as a shell, crust, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cast the shell, or exterior covering; to fall out of
      the pod or husk; as, nuts shell in falling.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be disengaged from the ear or husk; as, wheat or rye
      shells in reaping.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shell n. [orig. {{Multics}} techspeak, widely propagated via Unix] 1.
   [techspeak] The command interpreter used to pass commands to an
   operating system; so called because it is the part of the operating
   system that interfaces with the outside world. 2. More generally, any
   interface program that mediates access to a special resource or {server}
   for convenience, efficiency, or security reasons; for this meaning, the
   usage is usually `a shell around' whatever. This sort of program is also
   called a `wrapper'. 3. A skeleton program, created by hand or by another
   program (like, say, a parser generator), which provides the necessary
   {incantation}s to set up some task and the control flow to drive it (the
   term {driver} is sometimes used synonymously). The user is meant to fill
   in whatever code is needed to get real work done. This usage is common
   in the AI and Microsoft Windows worlds, and confuses Unix hackers.

   Historical note: Apparently, the original Multics shell (sense 1) was
   so called because it was a shell (sense 3); it ran user programs not by
   starting up separate processes, but by dynamically linking the programs
   into its own code, calling them as subroutines, and then dynamically
   de-linking them on return. The VMS command interpreter still does
   something very like this.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shell
     n 1: ammunition consisting of a cylindrical metal casing
          containing an explosive charge and a projectile; fired
          from a large gun
     2: the material that forms the hard outer covering of many
        animals
     3: hard outer covering or case of certain organisms such as
        arthropods and turtles [syn: {carapace}, {cuticle}]
     4: the hard usually fibrous outer layer of some fruits
        especially nuts
     5: the exterior covering of a bird's egg [syn: {eggshell}]
     6: a rigid covering that envelops an object; "the satellite is
        covered with a smooth shell of ice"
     7: a very light narrow racing boat [syn: {racing shell}]
     8: the housing or outer covering of something; "the clock has a
        walnut case" [syn: {case}, {casing}]
     9: a metal sheathing of uniform thickness (such as the shield
        attached to an artillery piece to protect the gunners)
        [syn: {plate}, {scale}]
     10: the hard largely calcareous covering of a mollusc
     v 1: use explosives on; "The enemy has been shelling us all day"
          [syn: {blast}]
     2: fall out of the pod or husk; "The corn shelled"
     3: hit the pitches of hard and regularly; "He shelled the
        pitcher for eight runs in the first inning"
     4: look for and collect shells by the seashore
     5: come out better in a competition, race, or conflict; "Agassi
        beat Becker in the tennis championship"; "We beat the
        competition"; "Harvard defeated Yale in the last football
        game" [syn: {beat}, {beat out}, {crush}, {trounce}, {vanquish}]
     6: remove from its shell or outer covering; "shell the
        legumes"; "shell mussels"
     7: remove the husks from; "husk corn" [syn: {husk}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
