<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shield</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shield</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shield
   used in defensive warfare, varying at different times and under
   different circumstances in size, form, and material (1 Sam.
   17:7; 2 Sam. 1:21; 1 Kings 10:17; 1 Chr. 12:8, 24, 34; Isa.
   22:6; Ezek. 39:9; Nahum 2:3).
   
     Used figuratively of God and of earthly princes as the
   defenders of their people (Gen. 15:1; Deut. 33:29; Ps. 33:20;
   84:11). Faith is compared to a shield (Eph. 6:16).
   
     Shields were usually "anointed" (Isa. 21:5), in order to
   preserve them, and at the same time make the missiles of the
   enemy glide off them more easily.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shield</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shield \Shield\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Shielded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Shielding}.] [AS. scidan, scyldan. See {Shield}, n.]
   1. To cover with, or as with, a shield; to cover from danger;
      to defend; to protect from assault or injury.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shouts of applause ran ringing through the field,
            To see the son the vanquished father shield.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            A woman's shape doth shield thee.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To ward off; to keep off or out.
      [1913 Webster]

            They brought with them their usual weeds, fit to
            shield the cold to which they had been inured.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To avert, as a misfortune; hence, as a supplicatory
      exclamation, forbid! [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            God shield that it should so befall.  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            God shield I should disturb devotion! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shield</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shield \Shield\, n. [OE. sheld, scheld, AS. scield, scild,
   sceld, scyld; akin to OS. scild, OFries. skeld, D. &amp; G.
   schild, OHG. scilt, Icel. skj["o]ldr, Sw. sk["o]ld, Dan.
   skiold, Goth. skildus; of uncertain origin. Cf. {Sheldrake}.]
   1. A broad piece of defensive armor, carried on the arm, --
      formerly in general use in war, for the protection of the
      body. See {Buckler}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now put your shields before your hearts and fight,
            With hearts more proof than shields.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything which protects or defends; defense; shelter;
      protection. ``My council is my shield.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Figuratively, one who protects or defends.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fear not, Abram; I am thy shield, and thy exceeding
            great reward.                         --Gen. xv. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bot.) In lichens, a Hardened cup or disk surrounded by a
      rim and containing the fructification, or asci.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Her.) The escutcheon or field on which are placed the
      bearings in coats of arms. Cf. {Lozenge}. See Illust. of
      {Escutcheon}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mining &amp; Tunneling) A framework used to protect workmen
      in making an adit under ground, and capable of being
      pushed along as excavation progresses.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A spot resembling, or having the form of, a shield.
      ``Bespotted as with shields of red and black.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A coin, the old French crown, or ['e]cu, having on one
      side the figure of a shield. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Shield fern} (Bot.), any fern of the genus {Aspidium}, in
      which the fructifications are covered with shield-shaped
      indusia; -- called also {wood fern}. See Illust. of
      {Indusium}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shield</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shield
     n 1: a protective covering or structure
     2: armor carried on the arm to intercept blows [syn: {buckler}]
     v 1: protect, hide, or conceal from danger or harm [syn: {screen}]
     2: hold back a thought or feeling about; "She is harboring a
        grudge against him" [syn: {harbor}, {harbour}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
