<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shifted</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shifted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shift \Shift\ (sh[i^]ft), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Shifted}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Shifting}.] [OE. shiften, schiften, to divide,
   change, remove. AS. sciftan to divide; akin to LG. &amp; D.
   schiften to divide, distinguish, part Icel. skipta to divide,
   to part, to shift, to change, Dan skifte, Sw. skifta, and
   probably to Icel. sk[=i]fa to cut into slices, as n., a
   slice, and to E. shive, sheave, n., shiver, n.]
   1. To divide; to distribute; to apportion. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To which God of his bounty would shift
            Crowns two of flowers well smelling.  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To change the place of; to move or remove from one place
      to another; as, to shift a burden from one shoulder to
      another; to shift the blame.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hastily he schifte him[self].         --Piers
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pare saffron between the two St. Mary's days,
            Or set or go shift it that knowest the ways.
                                                  --Tusser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To change the position of; to alter the bearings of; to
      turn; as, to shift the helm or sails.
      [1913 Webster]

            Carrying the oar loose, [they] shift it hither and
            thither at pleasure.                  --Sir W.
                                                  Raleigh.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To exchange for another of the same class; to remove and
      to put some similar thing in its place; to change; as, to
      shift the clothes; to shift the scenes.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would advise you to shift a shirt.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To change the clothing of; -- used reflexively. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            As it were to ride day and night; and . . . not to
            have patience to shift me.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To put off or out of the way by some expedient. ``I
      shifted him away.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To shift off}, to delay; to defer; to put off; to lay aside.
      

   {To shift the scene}, to change the locality or the
      surroundings, as in a play or a story.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shift the scene for half an hour;
            Time and place are in thy power.      --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
