<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shire</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shire \Shire\, n. [AS. sc[=i]re, sc[=i]r, a division, province,
   county. Cf. {Sheriff}.]
   1. A portion of Great Britain originally under the
      supervision of an earl; a territorial division, usually
      identical with a county, but sometimes limited to a
      smaller district; as, Wiltshire, Yorkshire, Richmondshire,
      Hallamshire.
      [1913 Webster]

            An indefinite number of these hundreds make up a
            county or shire.                      --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A division of a State, embracing several contiguous
      townships; a county. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Shire is commonly added to the specific designation of
         a county as a part of its name; as, Yorkshire instead
         of York shire, or the shire of York; Berkshire instead
         of Berks shire. Such expressions as the county of
         Yorkshire, which in a strict sense are tautological,
         are used in England. In the United States the composite
         word is sometimes the only name of a county; as,
         Berkshire county, as it is called in Massachusetts,
         instead of Berks county, as in Pensylvania.
         [1913 Webster]

               The Tyne, Tees, Humber, Wash, Yare, Stour, and
               Thames separate the counties of Northumberland,
               Durham, Yorkshire, Lincolnshire, etc. --Encyc.
                                                  Brit.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Knight of the shire}. See under {Knight}.

   {Shire clerk}, an officer of a county court; also, an under
      sheriff. [Eng.]

   {Shire mote} (Old. Eng. Law), the county court; sheriff's
      turn, or court. [Obs.] --Cowell. --Blackstone.

   {Shire reeve} (Old Eng. Law), the reeve, or bailiff, of a
      shire; a sheriff. --Burrill.

   {Shire town}, the capital town of a county; a county town.

   {Shire wick}, a county; a shire. [Obs.] --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>County \Coun"ty\ (koun"t[y^]), n.; pl. {Counties} (-t[i^]z). [F.
   comt['e], fr. LL. comitatus. See {Count}.]
   1. An earldom; the domain of a count or earl. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A circuit or particular portion of a state or kingdom,
      separated from the rest of the territory, for certain
      purposes in the administration of justice and public
      affairs; -- called also a {shire}. See {Shire}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every county, every town, every family, was in
            agitation.                            --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A count; an earl or lord. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {County commissioners}. See {Commissioner}.

   {County corporate}, a city or town having the privilege to be
      a county by itself, and to be governed by its own sheriffs
      and other magistrates, irrespective of the officers of the
      county in which it is situated; as London, York, Bristol,
      etc. [Eng.] --Mozley &amp; W.

   {County court}, a court whose jurisdiction is limited to
      county.

   {County palatine}, a county distinguished by particular
      privileges; -- so called a palatio (from the palace),
      because the owner had originally royal powers, or the same
      powers, in the administration of justice, as the king had
      in his palace; but these powers are now abridged. The
      counties palatine, in England, are Lancaster, Chester, and
      Durham.

   {County rates}, rates levied upon the county, and collected
      by the boards of guardians, for the purpose of defraying
      the expenses to which counties are liable, such as
      repairing bridges, jails, etc. [Eng.]

   {County seat}, a county town. [U.S.]

   {County sessions}, the general quarter sessions of the peace
      for each county, held four times a year. [Eng.]

   {County town}, the town of a county, where the county
      business is transacted; a shire town.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shire
     n 1: a former administrative district of England; equivalent to a
          county
     2: British breed of large heavy draft horse [syn: {shire horse}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
