<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shoes</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shoe \Shoe\ (sh[=oo]), n.; pl. {Shoes} (sh[=oo]z), formerly
   {Shoon} (sh[=oo]n), now provincial. [OE. sho, scho, AS.
   sc[=o]h, sce['o]h; akin to OFries. sk[=o], OS. sk[=o]h, D.
   schoe, schoen, G. schuh, OHG. scuoh, Icel. sk[=o]r, Dan. &amp;
   Sw. sko, Goth. sk[=o]hs; of unknown origin.]
   1. A covering for the human foot, usually made of leather,
      having a thick and somewhat stiff sole and a lighter top.
      It differs from a boot on not extending so far up the leg.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your hose should be ungartered, . . . yourshoe
            untied.                               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Spare none but such as go in clouted shoon. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything resembling a shoe in form, position, or use.
      Specifically:
      (a) A plate or rim of iron nailed to the hoof of an animal
          to defend it from injury.
      (b) A band of iron or steel, or a ship of wood, fastened
          to the bottom of the runner of a sleigh, or any
          vehicle which slides on the snow.
      (c) A drag, or sliding piece of wood or iron, placed under
          the wheel of a loaded vehicle, to retard its motion in
          going down a hill.
      (d) The part of an automobile or railroad car brake which
          presses upon the wheel to retard its motion.
      (e) (Arch.) A trough-shaped or spout-shaped member, put at
          the bottom of the water leader coming from the eaves
          gutter, so as to throw the water off from the
          building.
      (f) (Milling.) The trough or spout for conveying the grain
          from the hopper to the eye of the millstone.
      (g) An inclined trough in an ore-crushing mill.
      (h) An iron socket or plate to take the thrust of a strut
          or rafter.
      (i) An iron socket to protect the point of a wooden pile.
      (j) (Mach.) A plate, or notched piece, interposed between
          a moving part and the stationary part on which it
          bears, to take the wear and afford means of
          adjustment; -- called also {slipper}, and {gib}.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Shoe is often used adjectively, or in composition; as,
         shoe buckle, or shoe-buckle; shoe latchet, or
         shoe-latchet; shoe leathet, or shoe-leather; shoe
         string, shoe-string, or shoestring.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The outer cover or tread of a pneumatic tire, esp. for an
      automobile.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Shoe of an anchor}. (Naut.)
      (a) A small block of wood, convex on the back, with a hole
          to receive the point of the anchor fluke, -- used to
          prevent the anchor from tearing the planks of the
          vessel when raised or lowered.
      (b) A broad, triangular piece of plank placed upon the
          fluke to give it a better hold in soft ground.

   {Shoe block} (Naut.), a block with two sheaves, one above the
      other, and at right angles to each other.

   {Shoe bolt}, a bolt with a flaring head, for fastening shoes
      on sleigh runners.

   {Shoe pac}, a kind of moccasin. See {Pac}.

   {Shoe stone}, a sharpening stone used by shoemakers and other
      workers in leather.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ammunition \Am`mu*ni"tion\, n. [F. amunition, for munition,
   prob. caused by taking la munition as l'amunition. See
   {Munition}.]
   1. Military stores, or provisions of all kinds for attack or
      defense. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Articles used in charging firearms and ordnance of all
      kinds; as powder, balls, shot, shells, percussion caps,
      rockets, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any stock of missiles, literal or figurative.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ammunition bread}, {shoes}, etc., such as are contracted for
      by government, and supplied to the soldiers. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shoes
     n : a particular situation; "If you were in my place what would
         you do?" [syn: {place}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
