<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shooting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shooting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shoot \Shoot\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Shot}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Shooting}. The old participle {Shotten} is obsolete. See
   {Shotten}.] [OE. shotien, schotien, AS. scotian, v. i.,
   sce['o]tan; akin to D. schieten, G. schie?en, OHG. sciozan,
   Icel. skj?ta, Sw. skjuta, Dan. skyde; cf. Skr. skund to jump.
   [root]159. Cf. {Scot} a contribution, {Scout} to reject,
   {Scud}, {Scuttle}, v. i., {Shot}, {Sheet}, {Shut}, {Shuttle},
   {Skittish}, {Skittles}.]
   1. To let fly, or cause to be driven, with force, as an arrow
      or a bullet; -- followed by a word denoting the missile,
      as an object.
      [1913 Webster]

            If you please
            To shoot an arrow that self way.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To discharge, causing a missile to be driven forth; --
      followed by a word denoting the weapon or instrument, as
      an object; -- often with off; as, to shoot a gun.
      [1913 Webster]

            The two ends od a bow, shot off, fly from one
            another.                              --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To strike with anything shot; to hit with a missile;
      often, to kill or wound with a firearm; -- followed by a
      word denoting the person or thing hit, as an object.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Roger shot the hawk hovering over his master's
            dove house.                           --A. Tucker.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To send out or forth, especially with a rapid or sudden
      motion; to cast with the hand; to hurl; to discharge; to
      emit.
      [1913 Webster]

            An honest weaver as ever shot shuttle. --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

            A pit into which the dead carts had nightly shot
            corpses by scores.                    --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To push or thrust forward; to project; to protrude; --
      often with out; as, a plant shoots out a bud.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shoot out the lip, they shake the head. --Ps.
                                                  xxii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

            Beware the secret snake that shoots a sting.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Carp.) To plane straight; to fit by planing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Two pieces of wood that are shot, that is, planed or
            else pared with a paring chisel.      --Moxon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To pass rapidly through, over, or under; as, to shoot a
      rapid or a bridge; to shoot a sand bar.
      [1913 Webster]

            She . . . shoots the Stygian sound.   --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To variegate as if by sprinkling or intermingling; to
      color in spots or patches.
      [1913 Webster]

            The tangled water courses slept,
            Shot over with purple, and green, and yellow.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To be shot of}, to be discharged, cleared, or rid of.
      [Colloq.] ``Are you not glad to be shot of him?'' --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shooting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shooting \Shoot"ing\, n.
   1. The act of one who, or that which, shoots; as, the
      shooting of an archery club; the shooting of rays of
      light.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A wounding or killing with a firearm; specifically
      (Sporting), the killing of game; as, a week of shooting.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sensation of darting pain; as, a shooting in one's head.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shooting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shooting \Shoot"ing\, a.
   Of or pertaining to shooting; for shooting; darting.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Shooting board} (Joinery), a fixture used in planing or
      shooting the edge of a board, by means of which the plane
      is guided and the board held true.

   {Shooting box}, a small house in the country for use in the
      shooting season. --Prof. Wilson.

   {Shooting gallery}, a range, usually covered, with targets
      for practice with firearms.

   {Shooting iron}, a firearm. [Slang, U.S.]

   {Shooting star}.
   (a) (Astron.) A starlike, luminous meteor, that, appearing
       suddenly, darts quickly across some portion of the sky,
       and then as suddenly disappears, leaving sometimes, for a
       few seconds, a luminous train, -- called also {falling
       star}.

   Note: Shooting stars are small cosmical bodies which
         encounter the earth in its annual revolution, and which
         become visible by coming with planetary velocity into
         the upper regions of the atmosphere. At certain
         periods, as on the 13th of November and 10th of August,
         they appear for a few hours in great numbers,
         apparently diverging from some point in the heavens,
         such displays being known as meteoric showers, or star
         showers. These bodies, before encountering the earth,
         were moving in orbits closely allied to the orbits of
         comets. See {Leonids}, {Perseids}.
   (b) (Bot.) The American cowslip ({Dodecatheon Meadia}). See
       under {Cowslip}.

   {Shooting stick} (Print.), a tapering piece of wood or iron,
      used by printers to drive up the quoins in the chase.
      --Hansard.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shooting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shooting
     n 1: the act of firing a projectile; "his shooting was slow but
          accurate" [syn: {shot}]
     2: killing someone by gunfire; "when the shooting stopped there
        were three dead bodies"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
