<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shoulder</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoulder</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Girdle \Gir"dle\, n. [OE. gurdel, girdel, AS. gyrdel, fr.
   gyrdan; akin to D. gordel, G. g["u]rtel, Icel. gyr?ill. See
   {Gird}, v. t., to encircle, and cf. {Girth}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. That which girds, encircles, or incloses; a circumference;
      a belt; esp., a belt, sash, or article of dress encircling
      the body usually at the waist; a cestus.
      [1913 Webster]

            Within the girdle of these walls.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their breasts girded with golden girdles. --Rev. xv.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The zodiac; also, the equator. [Poetic] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            From the world's girdle to the frozen pole.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

            That gems the starry girdle of the year. --Campbell.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Jewelry) The line ofgreatest circumference of a
      brilliant-cut diamond, at which it is grasped by the
      setting. See Illust. of {Brilliant}. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mining) A thin bed or stratum of stone. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.) The clitellus of an earthworm.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Girdle bone} (Anat.), the sphenethmoid. See under
      {Sphenethmoid}.

   {Girdle wheel}, a spinning wheel.

   {Sea girdle} (Zo["o]l.), a ctenophore. See {Venus's girdle},
      under {Venus}.

   {Shoulder}, {Pectoral}, &amp; {Pelvic}, {girdle}. (Anat.) See
      under {Pectoral}, and {Pelvic}.

   {To have under the girdle}, to have bound to one, that is, in
      subjection.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoulder</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shoulder \Shoul"der\, n. [OE. shulder, shuldre, schutder, AS.
   sculdor; akin to D. schoulder, G. schulter, OHG. scultarra,
   Dan. skulder, Sw. skuldra.]
   1. (Anat.) The joint, or the region of the joint, by which
      the fore limb is connected with the body or with the
      shoulder girdle; the projection formed by the bones and
      muscles about that joint.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The flesh and muscles connected with the shoulder joint;
      the upper part of the back; that part of the human frame
      on which it is most easy to carry a heavy burden; -- often
      used in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then by main force pulled up, and on his shoulders
            bore
            The gates of Azza.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Adown her shoulders fell her length of hair.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fig.: That which supports or sustains; support.
      [1913 Webster]

            In thy shoulder do I build my seat.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which resembles a human shoulder, as any protuberance
      or projection from the body of a thing.
      [1913 Webster]

            The north western shoulder of the mountain. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The upper joint of the fore leg and adjacent parts of an
      animal, dressed for market; as, a shoulder of mutton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Fort.) The angle of a bastion included between the face
      and flank. See Illust. of {Bastion}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. An abrupt projection which forms an abutment on an object,
      or limits motion, etc., as the projection around a tenon
      at the end of a piece of timber, the part of the top of a
      type which projects beyond the base of the raised
      character, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Shoulder belt}, a belt that passes across the shoulder.

   {Shoulder blade} (Anat.), the flat bone of the shoulder, to
      which the humerus is articulated; the scapula.

   {Shoulder block} (Naut.), a block with a projection, or
      shoulder, near the upper end, so that it can rest against
      a spar without jamming the rope.

   {Shoulder clapper}, one who claps another on the shoulder, or
      who uses great familiarity. [Obs.] --Shak.

   {Shoulder girdle}. (Anat.) See {Pectoral girdle}, under
      {Pectoral}.

   {Shoulder knot}, an ornamental knot of ribbon or lace worn on
      the shoulder; a kind of epaulet or braided ornament worn
      as part of a military uniform.

   {Shoulder-of-mutton sail} (Naut.), a triangular sail carried
      on a boat's mast; -- so called from its shape.

   {Shoulder slip}, dislocation of the shoulder, or of the
      humerous. --Swift.

   {Shoulder strap}, a strap worn on or over the shoulder.
      Specifically (Mil. &amp; Naval), a narrow strap worn on the
      shoulder of a commissioned officer, indicating, by a
      suitable device, the rank he holds in the service. See
      Illust. in App.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoulder</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shoulder \Shoul"der\, v. i.
   To push with the shoulder; to make one's way, as through a
   crowd, by using the shoulders; to move swaying the shoulders
   from side to side.

         A yoke of the great sulky white bullocks . . . came
         shouldering along together.              --Kipling.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoulder</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shoulder \Shoul"der\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Shouldered}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Shouldering}.]
   1. To push or thrust with the shoulder; to push with
      violence; to jostle.
      [1913 Webster]

            As they the earth would shoulder from her seat.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Around her numberless the rabble flowed,
            Shouldering each other, crowding for a view. --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take upon the shoulder or shoulders; as, to shoulder a
      basket; hence, to assume the burden or responsibility of;
      as, to shoulder blame; to shoulder a debt.
      [1913 Webster]

            As if Hercules
            Or burly Atlas shouldered up their state. --Marston.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Right shoulder arms} (Mil.), a position in the Manual of
      Arms which the piece is placed on the right shoulder, with
      the lock plate up, and the muzzle elevated and inclined to
      the left, and held as in the illustration.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shoulder</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shoulder
     n 1: the part of the body between the neck and the upper arm
     2: a cut of beef from the shoulder of the animal
     3: a ball-and-socket joint between the head of the humerus and
        a cavity of the scapula [syn: {shoulder joint}, {articulatio
        humeri}]
     4: narrow edge of land (usually unpaved) along the side of a
        road [syn: {berm}]
     v 1: lift onto one's shoulders
     2: push with the shoulders; "He shouldered his way into the
        crowd"
     3: carry a burden, either real or metaphoric; "shoulder the
        burden"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
