<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>showcase</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>showcase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Show \Show\, n. [Formerly written also shew.]
   1. The act of showing, or bringing to view; exposure to
      sight; exhibition.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which os shown, or brought to view; that which is
      arranged to be seen; a spectacle; an exhibition; as, a
      traveling show; a cattle show.
      [1913 Webster]

            As for triumphs, masks, feasts, and such shows.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Proud or ostentatious display; parade; pomp.
      [1913 Webster]

            I envy none their pageantry and show. --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Semblance; likeness; appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            He through the midst unmarked,
            In show plebeian angel militant
            Of lowest order, passed.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. False semblance; deceitful appearance; pretense.
      [1913 Webster]

            Beware of the scribes, . . . which devour widows'
            houses, and for a shew make long prayers. --Luke xx.
                                                  46. 47.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Med.) A discharge, from the vagina, of mucus streaked
      with blood, occuring a short time before labor.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining) A pale blue flame, at the top of a candle flame,
      indicating the presence of fire damp. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Show bill}, a broad sheet containing an advertisement in
      large letters.

   {Show box}, a box xontaining some object of curiosity carried
      round as a show.

   {Show card}, an advertising placard; also, a card for
      displaying samples.

   {Show case}, a gla?ed case, box, or cabinet for displaying
      and protecting shopkeepers' wares, articles on exhibition
      in museums, etc.

   {Show glass}, a glass which displays objects; a mirror.

   {Show of hands}, a raising of hands to indicate judgment; as,
      the vote was taken by a show of hands.

   {Show stone}, a piece of glass or crystal supposed to have
      the property of exhibiting images of persons or things not
      present, indicating in that way future events.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>showcase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>showcase
     n 1: a setting in which something can be displayed to best
          effect; "it was a showcase for democracy in Africa"
          [syn: {show window}]
     2: a glass container used to store and display items in a shop
        or museum or home [syn: {case}, {display case}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
