<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>show</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>show</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Show \Show\, v. t. [imp. {Showed}; p. p. {Shown}or {Showed}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Showing}. It is sometimes written {shew},
   {shewed}, {shewn}, {shewing}.] [OE. schowen, shewen, schewen,
   shawen, AS. sce['a]wian, to look, see, view; akin to OS.
   scaw?n, OFries. skawia, D. schouwen, OHG. scouw?n, G.
   schauen, Dan. skue, Sw. sk?da, Icel. sko?a, Goth. usskawjan
   to waken, skuggwa a mirror, Icel. skuggy shade, shadow, L.
   cavere to be on one's guard, Gr. ??? to mark, perceive, hear,
   Skr. kavi wise. Cf. {Caution}, {Scavenger}, {Sheen}.]
   1. To exhibit or present to view; to place in sight; to
      display; -- the thing exhibited being the object, and
      often with an indirect object denoting the person or thing
      seeing or beholding; as, to show a house; show your
      colors; shopkeepers show customers goods (show goods to
      customers).
      [1913 Webster]

            Go thy way, shew thyself to the priest. --Matt.
                                                  viii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor want we skill or art from whence to raise
            Magnificence; and what can heaven show more?
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To exhibit to the mental view; to tell; to disclose; to
      reveal; to make known; as, to show one's designs.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shew them the way wherein they must walk. --Ex.
                                                  xviii. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

            If it please my father to do thee evil, then I will
            shew it thee, and send thee away.     --1 Sam. xx.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically, to make known the way to (a person); hence,
      to direct; to guide; to asher; to conduct; as, to show a
      person into a parlor; to show one to the door.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make apparent or clear, as by evidence, testimony, or
      reasoning; to prove; to explain; also, to manifest; to
      evince; as, to show the truth of a statement; to show the
      causes of an event.
      [1913 Webster]

            I 'll show my duty by my timely care. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To bestow; to confer; to afford; as, to show favor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shewing mercy unto thousands of them that love me.
                                                  --Ex. xx. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To show forth}, to manifest; to publish; to proclaim.

   {To show his paces}, to exhibit the gait, speed, or the like;
      -- said especially of a horse.

   {To show off}, to exhibit ostentatiously.

   {To show up}, to expose. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>show</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Show \Show\, v. i. [Written also shew.]
   1. To exhibit or manifest one's self or itself; to appear; to
      look; to be in appearance; to seem.
      [1913 Webster]

            Just such she shows before a rising storm. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            All round a hedge upshoots, and shows
            At distance like a little wood.       --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To have a certain appearance, as well or ill, fit or
      unfit; to become or suit; to appear.
      [1913 Webster]

            My lord of York, it better showed with you. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To show off}, to make a show; to display one's self.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>show</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Show \Show\, n. [Formerly written also shew.]
   1. The act of showing, or bringing to view; exposure to
      sight; exhibition.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which os shown, or brought to view; that which is
      arranged to be seen; a spectacle; an exhibition; as, a
      traveling show; a cattle show.
      [1913 Webster]

            As for triumphs, masks, feasts, and such shows.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Proud or ostentatious display; parade; pomp.
      [1913 Webster]

            I envy none their pageantry and show. --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Semblance; likeness; appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            He through the midst unmarked,
            In show plebeian angel militant
            Of lowest order, passed.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. False semblance; deceitful appearance; pretense.
      [1913 Webster]

            Beware of the scribes, . . . which devour widows'
            houses, and for a shew make long prayers. --Luke xx.
                                                  46. 47.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Med.) A discharge, from the vagina, of mucus streaked
      with blood, occuring a short time before labor.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining) A pale blue flame, at the top of a candle flame,
      indicating the presence of fire damp. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Show bill}, a broad sheet containing an advertisement in
      large letters.

   {Show box}, a box xontaining some object of curiosity carried
      round as a show.

   {Show card}, an advertising placard; also, a card for
      displaying samples.

   {Show case}, a gla?ed case, box, or cabinet for displaying
      and protecting shopkeepers' wares, articles on exhibition
      in museums, etc.

   {Show glass}, a glass which displays objects; a mirror.

   {Show of hands}, a raising of hands to indicate judgment; as,
      the vote was taken by a show of hands.

   {Show stone}, a piece of glass or crystal supposed to have
      the property of exhibiting images of persons or things not
      present, indicating in that way future events.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>show</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>show
     n 1: a public exhibition of entertainment; "a remarkable show of
          skill"
     2: something intended to communicate a particular impression;
        "made a display of strength"; "a show of impatience"; "a
        good show of looking interested" [syn: {display}]
     3: a public exhibition or entertainment; "they wanted to see
        some of the shows on Broadway"
     4: pretending that something is the case in order to make a
        good impression; "they try to keep up appearances"; "that
        ceremony is just for show" [syn: {appearance}]
     v 1: show or demonstrate something to an interested audience;
          "She shows her dogs frequently"; "We will demo the new
          software in Washington" [syn: {demo}, {exhibit}, {present},
           {demonstrate}]
     2: establish the validity of something, as by an example,
        explanation or experiment; "The experiment demonstrated
        the instability of the compound"; "The mathematician
        showed the validity of the conjecture" [syn: {prove}, {demonstrate},
         {establish}, {shew}] [ant: {disprove}]
     3: provide evidence for; "The blood test showed that he was the
        father"; "Her behavior testified to her incompetence"
        [syn: {testify}, {bear witness}, {prove}, {evidence}]
     4: make visible or noticeable; "She showed her talent for
        cooking"; "Show me your etchings, please" [ant: {hide}]
     5: show in, or as in, a picture; "This scene depicts country
        life"; "the face of the child is rendered with much
        tenderness in this painting" [syn: {picture}, {depict}, {render}]
     6: give expression to; "She showed her disappointment" [syn: {express},
         {evince}]
     7: indicate a place, direction, person, or thing; either
        spatially or figuratively; "I showed the customer the
        glove section"; "He pointed to the empty parking space";
        "he indicated his opponents" [syn: {indicate}, {point}]
     8: make clear and visible; "The article revealed the policies
        of the government" [syn: {reveal}, {display}]
     9: be or become visible or noticeable; "His good upbringing
        really shows"; "The dirty side will show" [syn: {show up}]
     10: indicate a certain reading; of gauges and instruments; "The
         thermometer showed thirteen degrees below zero"; "The
         gauge read `empty'" [syn: {read}, {register}, {record}]
     11: give evidence of, as of records; "The diary shows his
         distress that evening"
     12: show (someone) to their seats, as in theaters or
         auditoriums; "The usher showed us to our seats" [syn: {usher}]
     13: finish third or better in a horse or dog race; "he bet $2 on
         number six to show"
     [also: {shown}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
