<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shrewd</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shrewd</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shrewd \Shrewd\, a. [Compar. {Shrewder}; superl. {Shrewdest}.]
   [Originally the p. p. of shrew, v.t.]
   1. Inclining to shrew; disposing to curse or scold; hence,
      vicious; malicious; evil; wicked; mischievous; vexatious;
      rough; unfair; shrewish. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            [Egypt] hath many shrewd havens, because of the
            great rocks that ben strong and dangerous to pass
            by.                                   --Sir J.
                                                  Mandeville.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every of this happy number
            That have endured shrewd days and nights with us.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Artful; wily; cunning; arch.
      [1913 Webster]

            These women are shrewd tempters with their tongues.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Able or clever in practical affairs; sharp in business;
      astute; sharp-witted; sagacious; keen; as, a shrewd
      observer; a shrewd design; a shrewd reply.
      [1913 Webster]

            Professing to despise the ill opinion of mankind
            creates a shrewd suspicion that we have deserved it.
                                                  --Secker.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Keen; critical; subtle; artful; astute; sagacious;
        discerning; acute; penetrating.

   Usage: {Shrewd}, {Sagacious}. One who is shrewd is keen to
          detect errors, to penetrate disguises, to foresee and
          guard against the selfishness of others. Shrewd is a
          word of less dignity than sagacious, which implies a
          comprehensive as well as penetrating mind, whereas
          shrewd does not.
          [1913 Webster] -- {Shrewd"ly}, adv. -- {Shrewd"ness},
          n.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shrewd</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shrewd
     adj 1: marked by practical hardheaded intelligence; "a smart
            businessman"; "an astute tenant always reads the small
            print in a lease"; "he was too shrewd to go along with
            them on a road that could lead only to their
            overthrow" [syn: {astute}, {sharp}]
     2: used of persons; "the most calculating and selfish men in
        the community" [syn: {calculating}, {calculative}, {conniving},
         {scheming}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
