<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>shuttle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shuttle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shuttle \Shut"tle\, n. [Also shittle, OE. schitel, scytyl,
   schetyl; cf. OE. schitel a bolt of a door, AS. scyttes; all
   from AS. sce['o]tan to shoot; akin to Dan. skyttel, skytte,
   shuttle, dial. Sw. skyttel, sk["o]ttel. [root]159. See
   {Shoot}, and cf. {Shittle}, {Skittles}.]
   1. An instrument used in weaving for passing or shooting the
      thread of the woof from one side of the cloth to the other
      between the threads of the warp.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like shuttles through the loom, so swiftly glide
            My feathered hours.                   --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The sliding thread holder in a sewing machine, which
      carries the lower thread through a loop of the upper
      thread, to make a lock stitch.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A shutter, as for a channel for molten metal. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Shuttle box} (Weaving), a case at the end of a shuttle race,
      to receive the shuttle after it has passed the thread of
      the warp; also, one of a set of compartments containing
      shuttles with different colored threads, which are passed
      back and forth in a certain order, according to the
      pattern of the cloth woven.

   {Shutten race}, a sort of shelf in a loom, beneath the warp,
      along which the shuttle passes; a channel or guide along
      which the shuttle passes in a sewing machine.

   {Shuttle shell} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      marine gastropods of the genus {Volva}, or {Radius},
      having a smooth, spindle-shaped shell prolonged into a
      channel at each end.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shuttle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shuttle \Shut"tle\, v. i.
   To move backwards and forwards, like a shuttle.
   [1913 Webster]

         I had to fly far and wide, shutting athwart the big
         Babel, wherever his calls and pauses had to be.
                                                  --Carlyle.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>shuttle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>shuttle
     n 1: badminton equipment consisting of a ball of cork or rubber
          with a crown of feathers [syn: {shuttlecock}, {bird}, {birdie}]
     2: public transport that consists of a bus or train or airplane
        that plies back and forth between two points
     3: bobbin that passes the weft thread between the warp threads
     v : travel back and forth between two points
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
