<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>side</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>side</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Side \Side\ (s[imac]d), n. [AS. s[=i]de; akin to D. zijde, G.
   seite, OHG. s[=i]ta, Icel. s[=i]?a, Dan. side, Sw. sida; cf.
   AS. s[=i]d large, spacious, Icel. s[=i]?r long, hanging.]
   1. The margin, edge, verge, or border of a surface;
      especially (when the thing spoken of is somewhat oblong in
      shape), one of the longer edges as distinguished from the
      shorter edges, called ends; a bounding line of a
      geometrical figure; as, the side of a field, of a square
      or triangle, of a river, of a road, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any outer portion of a thing considered apart from, and
      yet in relation to, the rest; as, the upper side of a
      sphere; also, any part or position viewed as opposite to
      or contrasted with another; as, this or that side.
      [1913 Webster]

            Looking round on every side beheld
            A pathless desert.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4.
      (a) One of the halves of the body, of an animals or man,
          on either side of the mesial plane; or that which
          pertains to such a half; as, a side of beef; a side of
          sole leather.
      (b) The right or left part of the wall or trunk of the
          body; as, a pain in the side.
          [1913 Webster]

                One of the soldiers with a spear pierced his
                side.                             --John xix.
                                                  34.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. A slope or declivity, as of a hill, considered as opposed
      to another slope over the ridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Along the side of yon small hill.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The position of a person or party regarded as opposed to
      another person or party, whether as a rival or a foe; a
      body of advocates or partisans; a party; hence, the
      interest or cause which one maintains against another; a
      doctrine or view opposed to another.
      [1913 Webster]

            God on our side, doubt not of victory. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have not always been of the . . . same side in
            politics.                             --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sets the passions on the side of truth. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A line of descent traced through one parent as
      distinguished from that traced through another.
      [1913 Webster]

            To sit upon thy father David's throne,
            By mother's side thy father.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Fig.: Aspect or part regarded as contrasted with some
      other; as, the bright side of poverty.
      [1913 Webster]

   {By the side of}, close at hand; near to.

   {Exterior side}. (Fort.) See {Exterior}, and Illust. of
      {Ravelin}.

   {Interior side} (Fort.), the line drawn from the center of
      one bastion to that of the next, or the line curtain
      produced to the two oblique radii in front. --H. L. Scott.

   {Side by side}, close together and abreast; in company or
      along with.

   {To choose sides}, to select those who shall compete, as in a
      game, on either side.

   {To take sides}, to attach one's self to, or give assistance
      to, one of two opposing sides or parties.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>side</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Side \Side\, a.
   1. Of or pertaining to a side, or the sides; being on the
      side, or toward the side; lateral.
      [1913 Webster]

            One mighty squadron with a side wind sped. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, indirect; oblique; collateral; incidental; as, a
      side issue; a side view or remark.
      [1913 Webster]

            The law hath no side respect to their persons.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. [AS. s[=i]d. Cf {Side}, n.] Long; large; extensive. [Obs.
      or Scot.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            His gown had side sleeves down to mid leg.
                                                  --Laneham.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Side action}, in breech-loading firearms, a mechanism for
      operating the breech block, which is moved by a lever that
      turns sidewise.

   {Side arms}, weapons worn at the side, as sword, bayonet,
      pistols, etc.

   {Side ax}, an ax of which the handle is bent to one side.

   {Side-bar rule} (Eng. Law.), a rule authorized by the courts
      to be granted by their officers as a matter of course,
      without formal application being made to them in open
      court; -- so called because anciently moved for by the
      attorneys at side bar, that is, informally. --Burril.

   {Side box}, a box or inclosed seat on the side of a theater.
      [1913 Webster]

            To insure a side-box station at half price.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Side chain},
      (a) one of two safety chains connecting a tender with a
          locomotive, at the sides.
      (b) (Chem.) a chain of atoms attached to the main
          structure of a large molecule, especially of a
          polymer.

   {Side cut}, a canal or road branching out from the main one.
      [U.S.]

   {Side dish}, one of the dishes subordinate to the main
      course.

   {Side glance}, a glance or brief look to one side.

   {Side hook} (Carp.), a notched piece of wood for clamping a
      board to something, as a bench.

   {Side lever}, a working beam of a side-lever engine.

   {Side-lever engine}, a marine steam engine having a working
      beam of each side of the cylinder, near the bottom of the
      engine, communicating motion to a crank that is above
      them.

   {Side pipe} (Steam Engine), a steam or exhaust pipe
      connecting the upper and lower steam chests of the
      cylinder of a beam engine.

   {Side plane}, a plane in which the cutting edge of the iron
      is at the side of the stock.

   {Side posts} (Carp.), posts in a truss, usually placed in
      pairs, each post set at the same distance from the middle
      of the truss, for supporting the principal rafters,
      hanging the tiebeam, etc.

   {Side rod}.
      (a) One of the rods which connect the piston-rod crosshead
          with the side levers, in a side-lever engine.
      (b) See {Parallel rod}, under {Parallel}.

   {Side screw} (Firearms), one of the screws by which the lock
      is secured to the side of a firearm stock.

   {Side table}, a table placed either against the wall or aside
      from the principal table.

   {Side tool} (Mach.), a cutting tool, used in a lathe or
      planer, having the cutting edge at the side instead of at
      the point.

   {Side wind}, a wind from one side; hence, an indirect attack,
      or indirect means. --Wright.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>side</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Side \Side\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sided}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Siding}.]
   1. To lean on one side. [Obs.] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To embrace the opinions of one party, or engage in its
      interest, in opposition to another party; to take sides;
      as, to side with the ministerial party.
      [1913 Webster]

            All side in parties, and begin the attack. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>side</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Side \Side\, v. t.
   1. To be or stand at the side of; to be on the side toward.
      [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            His blind eye that sided Paridell.    --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To suit; to pair; to match. [Obs.] --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Shipbuilding) To work (a timber or rib) to a certain
      thickness by trimming the sides.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To furnish with a siding; as, to side a house.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>side</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>side
     adj 1: located on a side; "side fences"; "the side porch" [syn: {side(a)}]
            [ant: {top(a)}, {bottom(a)}]
     2: added as a consequence or supplement; "a side benefit" [syn:
         {side(a)}]
     n 1: a place within a region identified relative to a center or
          reference location; "they always sat on the right side
          of the church"; "he never left my side"
     2: one of two or more contesting groups; "the Confederate side
        was prepared to attack"
     3: either the left or right half of a body; "he had a pain in
        his side"
     4: an extended outer surface of an object; "he turned the box
        over to examine the bottom side"; "they painted all four
        sides of the house"
     5: a surface forming part of the outside of an object; "he
        examined all sides of the crystal"; "dew dripped from the
        face of the leaf" [syn: {face}]
     6: a line segment forming part of the perimeter of a plane
        figure; "the hypotenuse of a right triangle is always the
        longest side"
     7: an aspect of something (as contrasted with some other
        implied aspect); "he was on the heavy side"; "he is on the
        purchasing side of the business"; "it brought out his
        better side"
     8: a family line of descent; "he gets his brains from his
        father's side"
     9: a lengthwise dressed half of an animal's carcass used for
        food [syn: {side of meat}]
     10: an opinion that is held in opposition to another in an
         argument or dispute; "there are two sides to every
         question" [syn: {position}]
     11: an elevated geological formation; "he climbed the steep
         slope"; "the house was built on the side of the mountain"
         [syn: {slope}, {incline}]
     12: (sports) the spin given to a ball by striking it on one side
         or releasing it with a sharp twist [syn: {English}]
     v 1: take sides with; align oneself with; show strong sympathy
          for; "We all rooted for the home team"; "I'm pulling for
          the underdog"; "Are you siding with the defender of the
          title?" [syn: {pull}, {root}]
     2: take the side of; be on the side of; "Whose side are you
        on?"; "Why are you taking sides with the accused?" [syn: {go
        with}] [ant: {straddle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
