<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sidebyside</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sidebyside</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Side \Side\ (s[imac]d), n. [AS. s[=i]de; akin to D. zijde, G.
   seite, OHG. s[=i]ta, Icel. s[=i]?a, Dan. side, Sw. sida; cf.
   AS. s[=i]d large, spacious, Icel. s[=i]?r long, hanging.]
   1. The margin, edge, verge, or border of a surface;
      especially (when the thing spoken of is somewhat oblong in
      shape), one of the longer edges as distinguished from the
      shorter edges, called ends; a bounding line of a
      geometrical figure; as, the side of a field, of a square
      or triangle, of a river, of a road, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any outer portion of a thing considered apart from, and
      yet in relation to, the rest; as, the upper side of a
      sphere; also, any part or position viewed as opposite to
      or contrasted with another; as, this or that side.
      [1913 Webster]

            Looking round on every side beheld
            A pathless desert.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4.
      (a) One of the halves of the body, of an animals or man,
          on either side of the mesial plane; or that which
          pertains to such a half; as, a side of beef; a side of
          sole leather.
      (b) The right or left part of the wall or trunk of the
          body; as, a pain in the side.
          [1913 Webster]

                One of the soldiers with a spear pierced his
                side.                             --John xix.
                                                  34.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. A slope or declivity, as of a hill, considered as opposed
      to another slope over the ridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Along the side of yon small hill.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The position of a person or party regarded as opposed to
      another person or party, whether as a rival or a foe; a
      body of advocates or partisans; a party; hence, the
      interest or cause which one maintains against another; a
      doctrine or view opposed to another.
      [1913 Webster]

            God on our side, doubt not of victory. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have not always been of the . . . same side in
            politics.                             --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sets the passions on the side of truth. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A line of descent traced through one parent as
      distinguished from that traced through another.
      [1913 Webster]

            To sit upon thy father David's throne,
            By mother's side thy father.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Fig.: Aspect or part regarded as contrasted with some
      other; as, the bright side of poverty.
      [1913 Webster]

   {By the side of}, close at hand; near to.

   {Exterior side}. (Fort.) See {Exterior}, and Illust. of
      {Ravelin}.

   {Interior side} (Fort.), the line drawn from the center of
      one bastion to that of the next, or the line curtain
      produced to the two oblique radii in front. --H. L. Scott.

   {Side by side}, close together and abreast; in company or
      along with.

   {To choose sides}, to select those who shall compete, as in a
      game, on either side.

   {To take sides}, to attach one's self to, or give assistance
      to, one of two opposing sides or parties.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sidebyside</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>side by side
     adj 1: nearest in space or position; immediately adjoining without
            intervening space; "had adjacent rooms"; "in the next
            room"; "the person sitting next to me"; "our rooms
            were side by side" [syn: {adjacent}, {next}, {side by
            side(p)}]
     2: closely related or associated; "a city in which communism
        and democracy had to live side by side"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
