<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sight</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sight \Sight\ (s[imac]t), n. [OE. sight, si[thorn]t, siht, AS.
   siht, gesiht, gesih[eth], gesieh[eth], gesyh[eth]; akin to D.
   gezicht, G. sicht, gesicht, Dan. sigte, Sw. sigt, from the
   root of E. see. See {See}, v. t.]
   1. The act of seeing; perception of objects by the eye; view;
      as, to gain sight of land.
      [1913 Webster]

            A cloud received him out of their sight. --Acts. i.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The power of seeing; the faculty of vision, or of
      perceiving objects by the instrumentality of the eyes.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy sight is young,
            And thou shalt read when mine begin to dazzle.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            O loss of sight, of thee I most complain! --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The state of admitting unobstructed vision; visibility;
      open view; region which the eye at one time surveys; space
      through which the power of vision extends; as, an object
      within sight.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A spectacle; a view; a show; something worth seeing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Moses said, I will now turn aside and see this great
            sight, why the bush is not burnt.     --Ex. iii. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            They never saw a sight so fair.       --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The instrument of seeing; the eye.
      [1913 Webster]

            Why cloud they not their sights?      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Inspection; examination; as, a letter intended for the
      sight of only one person.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Mental view; opinion; judgment; as, in their sight it was
      harmless. --Wake.
      [1913 Webster]

            That which is highly esteemed among men is
            abomination in the sight of God.      --Luke xvi.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A small aperture or optical device through which objects
      are to be seen, and by which their direction is settled or
      ascertained; -- used on surveying instruments; as, the
      sight of a quadrant.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thier eyes of fire sparking through sights of steel.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. An optical device or small piece of metal, fixed or
      movable, on the breech, muzzle, center, or trunnion of a
      gun, or on the breech and the muzzle of a rifle, pistol,
      etc., by means of which the eye is guided in aiming. A
      telescope mounted on a weapon, such as a rifle, and used
      for accurate aiming at distant targets is called a
      {telescopic sight}. --Farrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. In a drawing, picture, etc., that part of the surface, as
       of paper or canvas, which is within the frame or the
       border or margin. In a frame or the like, the open space,
       the opening.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A great number, quantity, or sum; as, a sight of money.
       [Now colloquial]
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sight in this last sense was formerly employed in the
         best usage. ``A sight of lawyers.'' --Latimer.
         [1913 Webster]

               A wonder sight of flowers.         --Gower.
         [1913 Webster]

   {At sight}, as soon as seen, or presented to sight; as, a
      draft payable at sight: to read Greek at sight; to shoot a
      person at sight.

   {Front sight} (Firearms), the sight nearest the muzzle.

   {Open sight}. (Firearms)
       (a) A front sight through which the objects aimed at may
           be seen, in distinction from one that hides the
           object.
       (b) A rear sight having an open notch instead of an
           aperture.

   {Peep sight}, {Rear sight}. See under {Peep}, and {Rear}.

   {Sight draft}, an order, or bill of exchange, directing the
      payment of money at sight.

   {To take sight}, to take aim; to look for the purpose of
      directing a piece of artillery, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Vision; view; show; spectacle; representation;
        exhibition.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sight \Sight\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sighted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sighting}.]
   1. To get sight of; to see; as, to sight land; to sight a
      wreck. --Kane.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To look at through a sight; to see accurately; as, to
      sight an object, as a star.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To apply sights to; to adjust the sights of; also, to give
      the proper elevation and direction to by means of a sight;
      as, to sight a rifle or a cannon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sight \Sight\, v. i. (Mil.)
   To take aim by a sight.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sight
     n 1: an instance of visual perception; "the sight of his wife
          brought him back to reality"; "the train was an
          unexpected sight"
     2: anything that is seen; "he was a familiar sight on the
        television"; "they went to Paris to see the sights"
     3: the ability to see; the faculty of vision [syn: {vision}, {visual
        sense}, {visual modality}]
     4: a optical instrument for aiding the eye in aiming, as on a
        firearm or surveying instrument
     5: a range of mental vision; "in his sight she could do no
        wrong"
     6: the range of vision; "out of sight of land" [syn: {ken}]
     7: the act of looking or seeing or observing; "he tried to get
        a better view of it"; "his survey of the battlefield was
        limited" [syn: {view}, {survey}]
     8: (often followed by `of') a large number or amount or extent;
        "a batch of letters"; "a deal of trouble"; "a lot of
        money"; "he made a mint on the stock market"; "it must
        have cost plenty" [syn: {batch}, {deal}, {flock}, {good
        deal}, {great deal}, {hatful}, {heap}, {lot}, {mass}, {mess},
         {mickle}, {mint}, {muckle}, {peck}, {pile}, {plenty}, {pot},
         {quite a little}, {raft}, {slew}, {spate}, {stack}, {tidy
        sum}, {wad}, {whole lot}, {whole slew}]
     v : catch sight of; to perceive with the eyes; "he caught sight
         of the king's men coming over the ridge"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
