<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>simulation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>simulation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>simulation
     
        Attempting to predict aspects of the behaviour of some system
        by creating an approximate (mathematical) model of it.  This
        can be done by physical modelling, by writing a
        special-purpose computer program or using a more general
        simulation package, probably still aimed at a particular kind
        of simulation (e.g. structural engineering, fluid flow).
        Typical examples are aircraft flight simlators or electronic
        circuit simulators.  A great many simulation languages exist,
        e.g. {Simula}.
     
        See also {emulation}, {Markov chain}.
     
        {Usenet} newsgroup: {news:comp.simulation}.
     
        (1995-02-23)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>simulation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Simulation \Sim`u*la"tion\, n. [F. simulation, L. simulatio.]
   The act of simulating, or assuming an appearance which is
   feigned, or not true; -- distinguished from dissimulation,
   which disguises or conceals what is true.
   [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Counterfeiting; feint; pretense.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>simulation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>simulation
     n 1: (computer science) the technique of representing the real
          world by a computer program; "a simulation should
          imitate the internal processes and not merely the
          results of the thing being simulated" [syn: {computer
          simulation}]
     2: the act of imitating the behavior of some situation or some
        process by means of something suitably analogous
        (especially for the purpose of study or personnel
        training)
     3: representation of something (sometimes on a smaller scale)
        [syn: {model}]
     4: the act of giving a false appearance; "his conformity was
        only pretending" [syn: {pretense}, {pretence}, {pretending},
         {feigning}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
