<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sin
   is "any want of conformity unto or transgression of the law of
   God" (1 John 3:4; Rom. 4:15), in the inward state and habit of
   the soul, as well as in the outward conduct of the life, whether
   by omission or commission (Rom. 6:12-17; 7:5-24). It is "not a
   mere violation of the law of our constitution, nor of the system
   of things, but an offence against a personal lawgiver and moral
   governor who vindicates his law with penalties. The soul that
   sins is always conscious that his sin is (1) intrinsically vile
   and polluting, and (2) that it justly deserves punishment, and
   calls down the righteous wrath of God. Hence sin carries with it
   two inalienable characters, (1) ill-desert, guilt (reatus); and
   (2) pollution (macula).", Hodge's Outlines.
   
     The moral character of a man's actions is determined by the
   moral state of his heart. The disposition to sin, or the habit
   of the soul that leads to the sinful act, is itself also sin
   (Rom. 6:12-17; Gal. 5:17; James 1:14, 15).
   
     The origin of sin is a mystery, and must for ever remain such
   to us. It is plain that for some reason God has permitted sin to
   enter this world, and that is all we know. His permitting it,
   however, in no way makes God the author of sin.
   
     Adam's sin (Gen. 3:1-6) consisted in his yielding to the
   assaults of temptation and eating the forbidden fruit. It
   involved in it, (1) the sin of unbelief, virtually making God a
   liar; and (2) the guilt of disobedience to a positive command.
   By this sin he became an apostate from God, a rebel in arms
   against his Creator. He lost the favour of God and communion
   with him; his whole nature became depraved, and he incurred the
   penalty involved in the covenant of works.
   
     Original sin. "Our first parents being the root of all
   mankind, the guilt of their sin was imputed, and the same death
   in sin and corrupted nature were conveyed to all their
   posterity, descending from them by ordinary generation." Adam
   was constituted by God the federal head and representative of
   all his posterity, as he was also their natural head, and
   therefore when he fell they fell with him (Rom. 5:12-21; 1 Cor.
   15:22-45). His probation was their probation, and his fall their
   fall. Because of Adam's first sin all his posterity came into
   the world in a state of sin and condemnation, i.e., (1) a state
   of moral corruption, and (2) of guilt, as having judicially
   imputed to them the guilt of Adam's first sin.
   
     "Original sin" is frequently and properly used to denote only
   the moral corruption of their whole nature inherited by all men
   from Adam. This inherited moral corruption consists in, (1) the
   loss of original righteousness; and (2) the presence of a
   constant proneness to evil, which is the root and origin of all
   actual sin. It is called "sin" (Rom. 6:12, 14, 17; 7:5-17), the
   "flesh" (Gal. 5:17, 24), "lust" (James 1:14, 15), the "body of
   sin" (Rom. 6:6), "ignorance," "blindness of heart," "alienation
   from the life of God" (Eph. 4:18, 19). It influences and
   depraves the whole man, and its tendency is still downward to
   deeper and deeper corruption, there remaining no recuperative
   element in the soul. It is a total depravity, and it is also
   universally inherited by all the natural descendants of Adam
   (Rom. 3:10-23; 5:12-21; 8:7). Pelagians deny original sin, and
   regard man as by nature morally and spiritually well;
   semi-Pelagians regard him as morally sick; Augustinians, or, as
   they are also called, Calvinists, regard man as described above,
   spiritually dead (Eph. 2:1; 1 John 3:14).
   
     The doctrine of original sin is proved, (1.) From the fact of
   the universal sinfulness of men. "There is no man that sinneth
   not" (1 Kings 8:46; Isa. 53:6; Ps. 130:3; Rom. 3:19, 22, 23;
   Gal. 3:22). (2.) From the total depravity of man. All men are
   declared to be destitute of any principle of spiritual life;
   man's apostasy from God is total and complete (Job 15:14-16;
   Gen. 6:5,6). (3.) From its early manifestation (Ps. 58:3; Prov.
   22:15). (4.) It is proved also from the necessity, absolutely
   and universally, of regeneration (John 3:3; 2 Cor. 5:17). (5.)
   From the universality of death (Rom. 5:12-20).
   
     Various kinds of sin are mentioned, (1.) "Presumptuous sins,"
   or as literally rendered, "sins with an uplifted hand", i.e.,
   defiant acts of sin, in contrast with "errors" or
   "inadvertencies" (Ps. 19:13). (2.) "Secret", i.e., hidden sins
   (19:12); sins which escape the notice of the soul. (3.) "Sin
   against the Holy Ghost" (q.v.), or a "sin unto death" (Matt.
   12:31, 32; 1 John 5:16), which amounts to a wilful rejection of
   grace.
   
     Sin, a city in Egypt, called by the Greeks Pelusium, which
   means, as does also the Hebrew name, "clayey" or "muddy," so
   called from the abundance of clay found there. It is called by
   Ezekel (Ezek. 30:15) "the strength of Egypt, "thus denoting its
   importance as a fortified city. It has been identified with the
   modern Tineh, "a miry place," where its ruins are to be found.
   Of its boasted magnificence only four red granite columns
   remain, and some few fragments of others.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sin \Sin\, adv., prep., &amp; conj.
   Old form of {Since}. [Obs. or Prov. Eng. &amp; Scot.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Sin that his lord was twenty year of age. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sin \Sin\, n. [OE. sinne, AS. synn, syn; akin to D. zonde, OS.
   sundia, OHG. sunta, G. s["u]nde, Icel., Dan. &amp; Sw. synd, L.
   sons, sontis, guilty, perhaps originally from the p. pr. of
   the verb signifying, to be, and meaning, the one who it is.
   Cf. {Authentic}, {Sooth}.]
   1. Transgression of the law of God; disobedience of the
      divine command; any violation of God's will, either in
      purpose or conduct; moral deficiency in the character;
      iniquity; as, sins of omission and sins of commission.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whosoever committeth sin is the servant of sin.
                                                  --John viii.
                                                  34.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sin is the transgression of the law.  --1 John iii.
                                                  4.
      [1913 Webster]

            I think 't no sin.
            To cozen him that would unjustly win. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Enthralled
            By sin to foul, exorbitant desires.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An offense, in general; a violation of propriety; a
      misdemeanor; as, a sin against good manners.
      [1913 Webster]

            I grant that poetry's a crying sin.   --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sin offering; a sacrifice for sin.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hath made him to be sin for us, who knew no sin.
                                                  --2 Cor. v.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An embodiment of sin; a very wicked person. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy ambition,
            Thou scarlet sin, robbed this bewailing land
            Of noble Buckingham.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sin is used in the formation of some compound words of
         obvious signification; as, sin-born; sin-bred,
         sin-oppressed, sin-polluted, and the like.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Actual sin}, {Canonical sins}, {Original sin}, {Venial sin}.
      See under {Actual}, {Canonical}, etc.

   {Deadly sins}, or {Mortal sins} (R. C. Ch.), willful and
      deliberate transgressions, which take away divine grace;
      -- in distinction from vental sins. The seven deadly sins
      are pride, covetousness, lust, wrath, gluttony, envy, and
      sloth.

   {Sin eater}, a man who (according to a former practice in
      England) for a small gratuity ate a piece of bread laid on
      the chest of a dead person, whereby he was supposed to
      have taken the sins of the dead person upon himself.

   {Sin offering}, a sacrifice for sin; something offered as an
      expiation for sin.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Iniquity; wickedness; wrong. See {Crime}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sin \Sin\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sinned}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sinning}.] [OE. sinnen, singen, sinegen, AS. syngian. See
   {Sin}, n.]
   1. To depart voluntarily from the path of duty prescribed by
      God to man; to violate the divine law in any particular,
      by actual transgression or by the neglect or nonobservance
      of its injunctions; to violate any known rule of duty; --
      often followed by against.
      [1913 Webster]

            Against thee, thee only, have I sinned. --Ps. li. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

            All have sinned, and come short of the glory of God.
                                                  --Rom. iii.
                                                  23.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To violate human rights, law, or propriety; to commit an
      offense; to trespass; to transgress.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am a man
            More sinned against than sinning.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who but wishes to invert the laws
            Of order, sins against the eternal cause. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sin, bush

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sin
     n 1: estrangement from god [syn: {sinfulness}, {wickedness}]
     2: an act that is regarded by theologians as a transgression of
        God's will [syn: {sinning}]
     3: ratio of the opposite side to the hypotenuse of a
        right-angled triangle [syn: {sine}]
     4: (Akkadian) god of the moon; counterpart of Sumerian Nanna
     5: the 21st letter of the Hebrew alphabet
     6: violent and excited activity; "they began to fight like sin"
        [syn: {hell}]
     v 1: commit a sin; violate a law of God or a moral law [syn: {transgress},
           {trespass}]
     2: commit a faux pas or a fault or make a serious mistake; "I
        blundered during the job interview" [syn: {blunder}, {boob},
         {goof}]
     [also: {sinning}, {sinned}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
