<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sink</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sink \Sink\ (s[i^][ng]k), v. t.
   1. To cause to sink; to put under water; to immerse or
      submerge in a fluid; as, to sink a ship.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The Athenians] fell upon the wings and sank a
            single ship.                          --Jowett
                                                  (Thucyd.).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Figuratively: To cause to decline; to depress; to degrade;
      hence, to ruin irretrievably; to destroy, as by drowping;
      as, to sink one's reputation.
      [1913 Webster]

            I raise of sink, imprison or set free. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

            If I have a conscience, let it sink me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy cruel and unnatural lust of power
            Has sunk thy father more than all his years. --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make (a depression) by digging, delving, or cutting,
      etc.; as, to sink a pit or a well; to sink a die.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To bring low; to reduce in quantity; to waste.
      [1913 Webster]

            You sunk the river repeated draughts. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To conseal and appropriate. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

            If sent with ready money to buy anything, and you
            happen to be out of pocket, sink the money, and take
            up the goods on account.              --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To keep out of sight; to suppress; to ignore.
      [1913 Webster]

            A courtly willingness to sink obnoxious truths.
                                                  --Robertson.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To reduce or extinguish by payment; as, to sink the
      national debt.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sink \Sink\ (s[i^][ng]k), v. i. [imp. {Sunk} (s[u^][ng]k), or
   ({Sank} (s[a^][ng]k)); p. p. {Sunk} (obs. {Sunken}, -- now
   used as adj.); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Sinking}.] [OE. sinken, AS.
   sincan; akin to D. zinken, OS. sincan, G. sinken, Icel.
   s["o]kkva, Dan. synke, Sw. sjunka, Goth. siggan, and probably
   to E. silt. Cf. {Silt}.]
   1. To fall by, or as by, the force of gravity; to descend
      lower and lower; to decline gradually; to subside; as, a
      stone sinks in water; waves rise and sink; the sun sinks
      in the west.
      [1913 Webster]

            I sink in deep mire.                  --Ps. lxix. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To enter deeply; to fall or retire beneath or below the
      surface; to penetrate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The stone sunk into his forehead.     --1 San. xvii.
                                                  49.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, to enter so as to make an abiding impression; to
      enter completely.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let these sayings sink down into your ears. --Luke
                                                  ix. 44.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be overwhelmed or depressed; to fall slowly, as so the
      ground, from weakness or from an overburden; to fail in
      strength; to decline; to decay; to decrease.
      [1913 Webster]

            I think our country sinks beneath the yoke. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He sunk down in his chariot.          --2 Kings ix.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let not the fire sink or slacken.     --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To decrease in volume, as a river; to subside; to become
      diminished in volume or in apparent height.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Alps and Pyreneans sink before him. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To fall; subside; drop; droop; lower; decline; decay;
        decrease; lessen.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sink \Sink\ (s[i^][ng]k), n.
   1. A drain to carry off filthy water; a jakes.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A shallow box or vessel of wood, stone, iron, or other
      material, connected with a drain, and used for receiving
      filthy water, etc., as in a kitchen.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A hole or low place in land or rock, where waters sink and
      are lost; -- called also {sink hole}. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The lowest part of a natural hollow or closed basin whence
      the water of one or more streams escapes by evaporation;
      as, the sink of the Humboldt River. [Western U. S.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Sink hole}.
      (a) The opening to a sink drain.
      (b) A cesspool.
      (c) Same as {Sink}, n., 3.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sink
     n 1: plumbing fixture consisting of a water basin fixed to a wall
          or floor and having a drainpipe
     2: (technology) a process that acts to absorb or remove energy
        or a substance from a system; "the ocean is a sink for
        carbon dioxide" [ant: {source}]
     3: a depression in the ground communicating with a subterranean
        passage (especially in limestone) and formed by solution
        or by collapse of a cavern roof [syn: {sinkhole}, {swallow
        hole}]
     4: a covered cistern; waste water and sewage flow into it [syn:
         {cesspool}, {cesspit}, {sump}]
     v 1: fall or drop to a lower place or level; "He sank to his
          knees" [syn: {drop}, {drop down}]
     2: cause to sink; "The Japanese sank American ships in Pearl
        Harbor"
     3: pass into a specified state or condition; "He sank into
        Nirvana" [syn: {pass}, {lapse}]
     4: go under, "The raft sank and its occupants drowned" [syn: {settle},
         {go down}, {go under}] [ant: {float}]
     5: descend into or as if into some soft substance or place; "He
        sank into bed"; "She subsided into the chair" [syn: {subside}]
     6: appear to move downward; "The sun dipped below the horizon";
        "The setting sun sank below the tree line" [syn: {dip}]
     7: fall heavily or suddenly; decline markedly; "The real estate
        market fell off" [syn: {slump}, {fall off}]
     8: fall or sink heavily; "He slumped onto the couch"; "My
        spirits sank" [syn: {slump}, {slide down}]
     9: embed deeply; "She sank her fingers into the soft sand"; "He
        buried his head in her lap" [syn: {bury}]
     [also: {sunken}, {sunk}, {sank}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
