<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sit
     
        {Stuffit}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sit \Sit\,
   obs. 3d pers. sing. pres. of {Sit}, for sitteth.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sit \Sit\, v. i. [imp. {Sat}({Sate}, archaic); p. p. {Sat}
   ({Sitten}, obs.); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Sitting}.] [OE. sitten,
   AS. sittan; akin to OS. sittian, OFries. sitta, D. zitten, G.
   sitzen, OHG. sizzen, Icel. sitja, SW. sitta, Dan. sidde,
   Goth. sitan, Russ. sidiete, L. sedere, Gr. ???, Skr. sad.
   [root]154. Cf. {Assess},{Assize}, {Cathedral}, {Chair},
   {Dissident}, {Excise}, {Insidious}, {Possess}, {Reside},
   {Sanhedrim}, {Seance}, {Seat}, n., {Sedate}, {4th Sell},
   {Siege}, {Session}, {Set}, v. t., {Sizar}, {Size},
   {Subsidy}.]
   1. To rest upon the haunches, or the lower extremity of the
      trunk of the body; -- said of human beings, and sometimes
      of other animals; as, to sit on a sofa, on a chair, or on
      the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

            And he came and took the book put of the right hand
            of him that sate upon the seat.       --Bible (1551)
                                                  (Rev. v. 7.)
      [1913 Webster]

            I pray you, jest, sir, as you sit at dinner. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perch; to rest with the feet drawn up, as birds do on a
      branch, pole, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To remain in a state of repose; to rest; to abide; to rest
      in any position or condition.
      [1913 Webster]

            And Moses said to . . . the children of Reuben,
            Shall your brothren go to war, and shall ye sit
            here?                                 --Num. xxxii.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like a demigod here sit I in the sky. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To lie, rest, or bear; to press or weigh; -- with on; as,
      a weight or burden sits lightly upon him.
      [1913 Webster]

            The calamity sits heavy on us.        --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be adjusted; to fit; as, a coat sts well or ill.
      [1913 Webster]

            This new and gorgeous garment, majesty,
            Sits not so easy on me as you think.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To suit one well or ill, as an act; to become; to befit;
      -- used impersonally. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cover and warm eggs for hatching, as a fowl; to brood;
      to incubate.
      [1913 Webster]

            As the partridge sitteth on eggs, and hatcheth them
            not.                                  --Jer. xvii.
                                                  11.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To have position, as at the point blown from; to hold a
      relative position; to have direction.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like a good miller that knows how to grind, which
            way soever the wind sits.             --Selden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sits the wind in that quarter?        --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To occupy a place or seat as a member of an official body;
      as, to sit in Congress.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To hold a session; to be in session for official
       business; -- said of legislative assemblies, courts,
       etc.; as, the court sits in January; the aldermen sit
       to-night.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To take a position for the purpose of having some
       artistic representation of one's self made, as a picture
       or a bust; as, to sit to a painter.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To sit at}, to rest under; to be subject to. [Obs.] ``A
      farmer can not husband his ground so well if he sit at a
      great rent''. --Bacon.

   {To sit at meat} or {To sit at table}, to be at table for
      eating.

   {To sit down}.
       (a) To place one's self on a chair or other seat; as, to
           sit down when tired.
       (b) To begin a siege; as, the enemy sat down before the
           town.
       (c) To settle; to fix a permanent abode. --Spenser.
       (d) To rest; to cease as satisfied. ``Here we can not sit
           down, but still proceed in our search.'' --Rogers.

   {To sit for a fellowship}, to offer one's self for
      examination with a view to obtaining a fellowship. [Eng.
      Univ.]

   {To sit out}.
       (a) To be without engagement or employment. [Obs.] --Bp.
           Sanderson.
       (b) To outstay.

   {To sit under}, to be under the instruction or ministrations
      of; as, to sit under a preacher; to sit under good
      preaching.

   {To sit up}, to rise from, or refrain from, a recumbent
      posture or from sleep; to sit with the body upright; as,
      to sit up late at night; also, to watch; as, to sit up
      with a sick person. ``He that was dead sat up, and began
      to speak.'' --Luke vii. 15.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sit \Sit\, v. t.
   1. To sit upon; to keep one's seat upon; as, he sits a horse
      well.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hardly the muse can sit the headstrong horse.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to be seated or in a sitting posture; to furnish
      a seat to; -- used reflexively.
      [1913 Webster]

            They sat them down to weep.           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sit you down, father; rest you.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To suit (well or ill); to become. [Obs. or R.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SIT
     institut fuer SIchere Telekommunikation (GMD, org.)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sit
     v 1: be seated [syn: {sit down}] [ant: {stand}, {lie}]
     2: sit around, often unused; "The object sat in the corner"
     3: take a seat [syn: {sit down}] [ant: {arise}]
     4: be in session; "When does the court of law sit?"
     5: assume a posture as for artistic purposes; "We don't know
        the woman who posed for Leonardo so often" [syn: {model},
        {pose}, {posture}]
     6: sit and travel on the back of animal, usually while
        controlling its motions; "She never sat a horse!"; "Did
        you ever ride a camel?"; "The girl liked to drive the
        young mare" [syn: {ride}]
     7: work or act as a baby-sitter; "I cannot baby-sit tonight; I
        have too much homework to do" [syn: {baby-sit}]
     8: show to a seat; assign a seat for; "The host seated me next
        to Mrs. Smith" [syn: {seat}, {sit down}]
     [also: {sitting}, {sat}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
