<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>size</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Size \Size\, v. t.
   1. To fix the standard of. ``To size weights and measures.''
      [R.] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To adjust or arrange according to size or bulk.
      Specifically:
      (a) (Mil.) To take the height of men, in order to place
          them in the ranks according to their stature.
      (b) (Mining) To sift, as pieces of ore or metal, in order
          to separate the finer from the coarser parts.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. To swell; to increase the bulk of. --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mech.) To bring or adjust anything exactly to a required
      dimension, as by cutting.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To size up}, to estimate or ascertain the character and
      ability of. See 4th {Size}, 4. [Slang, U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We had to size up our fellow legislators. --The
                                                  Century.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Size \Size\, n. [See {Sice}, and {Sise}.]
   Six.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Size \Size\, n. [OIt. sisa glue used by painters, shortened fr.
   assisa, fr. assidere, p. p. assiso, to make to sit, to seat,
   to place, L. assidere to sit down; ad + sidere to sit down,
   akin to sedere to sit. See {Sit}, v. i., and cf. {Assize},
   {Size} bulk.]
   1. A thin, weak glue used in various trades, as in painting,
      bookbinding, paper making, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any viscous substance, as gilder's varnish.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Size \Size\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sized}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sizing}.]
   To cover with size; to prepare with size.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Size \Size\, n. [Abbrev. from assize. See {Assize}, and cf.
   {Size} glue.]
   1. A settled quantity or allowance. See {Assize}. [Obs.] ``To
      scant my sizes.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Univ. of Cambridge, Eng.) An allowance of food and drink
      from the buttery, aside from the regular dinner at
      commons; -- corresponding to battel at Oxford.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Extent of superficies or volume; bulk; bigness; magnitude;
      as, the size of a tree or of a mast; the size of a ship or
      of a rock.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Figurative bulk; condition as to rank, ability, character,
      etc.; as, the office demands a man of larger size.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men of a less size and quality.       --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            The middling or lower size of people. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A conventional relative measure of dimension, as for
      shoes, gloves, and other articles made up for sale.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An instrument consisting of a number of perforated gauges
      fastened together at one end by a rivet, -- used for
      ascertaining the size of pearls. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Size roll}, a small piese of parchment added to a roll.

   {Size stick}, a measuring stick used by shoemakers for
      ascertaining the size of the foot.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Dimension; bigness; largeness; greatness; magnitude.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Size \Size\, v. i.
   1. To take greater size; to increase in size.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our desires give them fashion, and so,
            As they wax lesser, fall, as they size, grow.
                                                  --Donne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Univ. of Cambridge, Eng.) To order food or drink from the
      buttery; hence, to enter a score, as upon the buttery
      book.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Assize \As*size"\, n. [OE. assise, asise, OF. assise, F.
   assises, assembly of judges, the decree pronounced by them,
   tax, impost, fr. assis, assise, p. p. of asseoir, fr. L.
   assid?re to sit by; ad + sed[=e]re to sit. See {Sit}, {Size},
   and cf. {Excise}, {Assess}.]
   1. An assembly of knights and other substantial men, with a
      bailiff or justice, in a certain place and at a certain
      time, for public business. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law)
      (a) A special kind of jury or inquest.
      (b) A kind of writ or real action.
      (c) A verdict or finding of a jury upon such writ.
      (d) A statute or ordinance in general. Specifically: (1) A
          statute regulating the weight, measure, and
          proportions of ingredients and the price of articles
          sold in the market; as, the assize of bread and other
          provisions; (2) A statute fixing the standard of
          weights and measures.
      (e) Anything fixed or reduced to a certainty in point of
          time, number, quantity, quality, weight, measure,
          etc.; as, rent of assize. --Glanvill. --Spelman.
          --Cowell. --Blackstone. --Tomlins. --Burrill.

   Note: [This term is not now used in England in the sense of a
         writ or real action, and seldom of a jury of any kind,
         but in Scotch practice it is still technically applied
         to the jury in criminal cases. --Stephen. --Burrill.
         --Erskine.]
      (f) A court, the sitting or session of a court, for the
          trial of processes, whether civil or criminal, by a
          judge and jury. --Blackstone. --Wharton. --Encyc.
          Brit.
      (g) The periodical sessions of the judges of the superior
          courts in every county of England for the purpose of
          administering justice in the trial and determination
          of civil and criminal cases; -- usually in the plural.
          --Brande. --Wharton. --Craig. --Burrill.
      (h) The time or place of holding the court of assize; --
          generally in the plural, assizes.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Measure; dimension; size. [In this sense now corrupted
      into {size}.]
      [1913 Webster]

            An hundred cubits high by just assize. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster] [Formerly written, as in French, {assise}.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>size</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>size
     adj : (used in combination) sized; "the economy-size package";
           "average-size house"
     n 1: the physical magnitude of something (how big it is); "a wolf
          is about the size of a large dog"
     2: the property resulting from being one of a series of
        graduated measurements (as of clothing); "he wears a size
        13 shoe"
     3: any glutinous material used to fill pores in surfaces or to
        stiffen fabrics; "size gives body to a fabric" [syn: {sizing}]
     4: the actual state of affairs; "that's the size of the
        situation"; "she hates me, that's about the size of it"
        [syn: {size of it}]
     5: a large magnitude; "he blanched when he saw the size of the
        bill"; "the only city of any size in that area"
     v 1: cover or stiffen or glaze a porous material with size or
          sizing (a glutinous substance)
     2: sort according to size
     3: make to a size; bring to a suitable size
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
