<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>skid</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skid \Skid\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Skidded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Skidding}.]
   1. To protect or support with a skid or skids; also, to cause
      to move on skids.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To check with a skid, as wagon wheels. --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Forestry) To haul (logs) to a skid and load on a skidway.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skid \Skid\ (sk[i^]d), n. [Icel. sk[=i][eth] a billet of wood.
   See {Shide}.] [Written also {skeed}.]
   1. A shoe or clog, as of iron, attached to a chain, and
      placed under the wheel of a wagon to prevent its turning
      when descending a steep hill; a drag; a skidpan; also, by
      extension, a hook attached to a chain, and used for the
      same purpose.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A piece of timber used as a support, or to receive
      pressure. Specifically:
      (a) pl. (Naut.) Large fenders hung over a vessel's side to
          protect it in handling a cargo. --Totten.
      (b) One of a pair of timbers or bars, usually arranged so
          as to form an inclined plane, as form a wagon to a
          door, along which anything is moved by sliding or
          rolling.
      (c) One of a pair of horizontal rails or timbers for
          supporting anything, as a boat, a barrel, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (A["e]ronautics) A runner (one or two) under some flying
      machines, used for landing.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. A low movable platform for supporting heavy items to be
      transported, typically of two layers, and having a space
      between the layers into which the fork of a fork lift can
      be inserted; it is used to conveniently transport heavy
      objects by means of a fork lift; -- a skid without wheels
      is the same as a {pallet}.
      [PJC]

   5. pl. Declining fortunes; a movement toward defeat or
      downfall; -- used mostly in the phrase

   {on the skids} and

   {hit the skids}.
      [PJC]

   6. [From the v.] Act of skidding; -- called also {side slip}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skid \Skid\, v. i.
   1. To slide without rotating; -- said of a wheel held from
      turning while the vehicle moves onward.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. To fail to grip the roadway; specif., to slip sideways on
      the road; to side-slip; -- said esp. of a cycle or
      automobile.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ski
     n : narrow wood or metal or plastic runners used for gliding
         over snow [syn: {skis}]
     v : move along on skis; "We love to ski the Rockies"
     [also: {ski'd}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>skid
     n 1: one of a pair of planks used to make a track for rolling or
          sliding objects
     2: a restraint provided when the brake linings are moved
        hydraulically against the brake drum to retard the wheel's
        rotation [syn: {brake shoe}, {shoe}]
     3: an unexpected slide [syn: {slip}, {sideslip}]
     v 1: slide without control; "the car skidded in the curve on the
          wet road"
     2: elevate onto skids
     3: apply a brake or skid to
     4: move obliquely or sideways, usually in an uncontrolled
        manner; "the wheels skidded against the sidewalk" [syn: {slip},
         {slue}, {slew}, {slide}]
     [also: {skidding}, {skidded}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ski'd
     See {ski}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
