<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>skill</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skill
     
        A somewhat peculiar blend between {Franz-Lisp} and {C}, with a
        large set of various {CAD} primitives.  It is owned by
        {Cadence Design Systems} and has been used in their CAD
        frameworks since 1985.  It's an {extension language} to the
        CAD framework (in the same way that {Emacs-Lisp} extends {GNU
        Emacs}), enabling you to automate virtually everything that
        you can do manually in for example the graphic editor.  Skill
        accepts {C}-syntax, fun(a b), as well as {Lisp} syntax, (fun a
        b), but most users (including Cadence themselves) use the
        C-style.
     
        [Jonas Jarnestrom &lt;etxjojm@eua.ericsson.se&gt;].
     
        (1995-02-14)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skill \Skill\, n. [Icel. skil a distinction, discernment; akin
   to skilja to separate, divide, distinguish, Sw. skilja,.
   skille to separate, skiel reason, right, justice, Sw. sk["a]l
   reason, Lith. skelli to cleave. Cf. {Shell}, {Shoal}, a
   multitude.]
   1. Discrimination; judgment; propriety; reason; cause. [Obs.]
      --Shak. ``As it was skill and right.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            For great skill is, he prove that he wrought. [For
      with good reason he should test what he created.]
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Knowledge; understanding. [Obsoles.]
      [1913 Webster]

            That by his fellowship he color might
            Both his estate and love from skill of any wight.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor want we skill or art.             --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The familiar knowledge of any art or science, united with
      readiness and dexterity in execution or performance, or in
      the application of the art or science to practical
      purposes; power to discern and execute; ability to
      perceive and perform; expertness; aptitude; as, the skill
      of a mathematician, physician, surgeon, mechanic, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Phocion, . . . by his great wisdom and skill at
            negotiations, diverted Alexander from the conquest
            of Athens.                            --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where patience her sweet skill imparts. --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Display of art; exercise of ability; contrivance; address.
      [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Richard . . . by a thousand princely skills,
            gathering so much corn as if he meant not to return.
                                                  --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Any particular art. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Learned in one skill, and in another kind of
            learning unskillful.                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Dexterity; adroitness; expertness; art; aptitude;
        ability.

   Usage: {Skill}, {Dexterity}, {Adroitness}. Skill is more
          intelligent, denoting familiar knowledge united to
          readiness of performance. Dexterity, when applied to
          the body, is more mechanical, and refers to habitual
          ease of execution. Adroitness involves the same image
          with dexterity, and differs from it as implaying a
          general facility of movement (especially in avoidance
          of danger or in escaping from a difficalty). The same
          distinctions apply to the figurative sense of the
          words. A man is skillful in any employment when he
          understands both its theory and its practice. He is
          dexterous when he maneuvers with great lightness. He
          is adroit in the use od quick, sudden, and
          well-directed movements of the body or the mind, so as
          to effect the object he has in view.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skill \Skill\, v. t.
   To know; to understand. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         To skill the arts of expressing our mind. --Barrow.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skill \Skill\, v. i.
   1. To be knowing; to have understanding; to be dexterous in
      performance. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I can not skill of these thy ways.    --Herbert.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make a difference; to signify; to matter; -- used
      impersonally. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            What skills it, if a bag of stones or gold
            About thy neck do drown thee?         --Herbert.
      [1913 Webster]

            It skills not talking of it.          --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>skill
     n 1: an ability that has been acquired by training [syn: {accomplishment},
           {acquirement}, {acquisition}, {attainment}]
     2: ability to produce solutions in some problem domain; "the
        skill of a well-trained boxer"; "the sweet science of
        pugilism" [syn: {science}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
