<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>skin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skin \Skin\, n. [Icel. skinn; akin to Sw. skinn, Dan. skind, AS.
   scinn, G. schined to skin.]
   1. (Anat.) The external membranous integument of an animal.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In man, and the vertebrates generally, the skin consist
         of two layers, an outer nonsensitive and nonvascular
         epidermis, cuticle, or skarfskin, composed of cells
         which are constantly growing and multiplying in the
         deeper, and being thrown off in the superficial,
         layers; and an inner sensitive, and vascular dermis,
         cutis, corium, or true skin, composed mostly of
         connective tissue.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The hide of an animal, separated from the body, whether
      green, dry, or tanned; especially, that of a small animal,
      as a calf, sheep, or goat.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A vessel made of skin, used for holding liquids. See
      {Bottle}, 1. ``Skins of wine.'' --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The bark or husk of a plant or fruit; the exterior coat of
      fruits and plants.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.)
      (a) That part of a sail, when furled, which remains on the
          outside and covers the whole. --Totten.
      (b) The covering, as of planking or iron plates, outside
          the framing, forming the sides and bottom of a vessel;
          the shell; also, a lining inside the framing.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Skin friction}, {Skin resistance} (Naut.), the friction, or
      resistance, caused by the tendency of water to adhere to
      the immersed surface (skin) of a vessel.

   {Skin graft} (Surg.), a small portion of skin used in the
      process of grafting. See {Graft}, v. t., 2.

   {Skin moth} (Zo["o]l.), any insect which destroys the
      prepared skins of animals, especially the larva of
      Dermestes and Anthrenus.

   {Skin of the teeth}, nothing, or next to nothing; the least
      possible hold or advantage. --Job xix. 20.

   {Skin wool}, wool taken from dead sheep.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skin \Skin\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Skinned}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Skinning}.]
   1. To strip off the skin or hide of; to flay; to peel; as, to
      skin an animal.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover with skin, or as with skin; hence, to cover
      superficially.
      [1913 Webster]

            It will but skin and film the ulcerous place.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To strip of money or property; to cheat. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Skin \Skin\, v. i.
   1. To become covered with skin; as, a wound skins over.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To produce, in recitation, examination, etc., the work of
      another for one's own, or to use in such exercise cribs,
      memeoranda, etc., which are prohibited. [College Cant,
      U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>skin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>skin
     n 1: a natural protective covering of the body; site of the sense
          of touch; "your skin is the largest organ of your body"
          [syn: {tegument}, {cutis}]
     2: the tissue forming the hard outer layer (of e.g. a fruit)
        [syn: {rind}, {peel}]
     3: an outer surface (usually thin); "the skin of an airplane"
     4: body covering of a living animal [syn: {hide}, {pelt}]
     5: a person's skin regarded as their life; "he tried to save
        his skin"
     6: the rind of a fruit or vegetable [syn: {peel}]
     7: a bag serving as a container for liquids; it is made from
        the skin of an animal
     v 1: climb awkwardly, as if by scrambling [syn: {clamber}, {scramble},
           {shin}, {shinny}, {struggle}, {sputter}]
     2: bruise, cut, or injure the skin or the surface of; "The boy
        skinned his knee when he fell" [syn: {scrape}]
     3: remove the bark of a tree [syn: {bark}]
     4: strip the skin off; "pare apples" [syn: {peel}, {pare}]
     5: strike against an object; "She stubbed her one's toe in the
        dark and now it's broken" [syn: {stub}, {scrape}, {abrade}]
     [also: {skinning}, {skinned}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
