<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sleep</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sleep
     
        1. &lt;operating system, multitasking&gt; (Or "{block}") When a
        {process} on a {multitasking} system asks the {scheduler} to
        deactivate it until some given external event (e.g. an
        {interrupt} or a specified time delay) occurs.
     
        The alternative is to {poll} or "{busy wait}" for the event
        but this uses processing power.
     
        Also used in the phrase "sleep on" (or "block on") some
        external event, meaning to wait for it.
     
        E.g. the {Unix} command of the same name which pauses the
        current process for a given number of seconds.
     
        2. &lt;hardware&gt; To go into partial deactivation to save power.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2000-09-25)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sleep \Sleep\, v. t.
   1. To be slumbering in; -- followed by a cognate object; as,
      to sleep a dreamless sleep. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give sleep to; to furnish with accomodations for
      sleeping; to lodge. [R.] --Blackw. Mag.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To sleep away}, to spend in sleep; as, to sleep away
      precious time.

   {To sleep off}, to become free from by sleep; as, to sleep
      off drunkeness or fatigue.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sleep \Sleep\, obs.
   imp. of Sleep. Slept. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sleep \Sleep\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Slept}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sleeping}.] [OE. slepen, AS. sl?pan; akin to OFries. sl?pa,
   OS. sl[=a]pan, D. slapen, OHG. sl[=a]fan, G. schlafen, Goth.
   sl?pan, and G. schlaff slack, loose, and L. labi to glide,
   slide, labare to totter. Cf. {Lapse}.]
   1. To take rest by a suspension of the voluntary exercise of
      the powers of the body and mind, and an apathy of the
      organs of sense; to slumber. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Watching at the head of these that sleep. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Figuratively:
      (a) To be careless, inattentive, or uncouncerned; not to
          be vigilant; to live thoughtlessly.
          [1913 Webster]

                We sleep over our happiness.      --Atterbury.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To be dead; to lie in the grave.
          [1913 Webster]

                Them also which sleep in Jesus will God bring
                with him.                         --1 Thess. iv.
                                                  14.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To be, or appear to be, in repose; to be quiet; to be
          unemployed, unused, or unagitated; to rest; to lie
          dormant; as, a question sleeps for the present; the
          law sleeps.
          [1913 Webster]

                How sweet the moonlight sleep upon this bank!
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sleep \Sleep\, n. [AS. sl[=ae]p; akin to OFries. sl[=e]p, OS.
   sl[=a]p, D. slaap, OHG. sl[=a]f, G. schlaf, Goth. sl[=e]ps.
   See {Sleep}, v. i.]
   A natural and healthy, but temporary and periodical,
   suspension of the functions of the organs of sense, as well
   as of those of the voluntary and rational soul; that state of
   the animal in which there is a lessened acuteness of sensory
   perception, a confusion of ideas, and a loss of mental
   control, followed by a more or less unconscious state. ``A
   man that waketh of his sleep.'' --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

         O sleep, thou ape of death.              --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sleep is attended by a relaxation of the muscles, and
         the absence of voluntary activity for any rational
         objects or purpose. The pulse is slower, the
         respiratory movements fewer in number but more
         profound, and there is less blood in the cerebral
         vessels. It is susceptible of greater or less intensity
         or completeness in its control of the powers.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Sleep of plants} (Bot.), a state of plants, usually at
      night, when their leaflets approach each other, and the
      flowers close and droop, or are covered by the folded
      leaves.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Slumber; repose; rest; nap; doze; drowse.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sleep vi. 1. [techspeak] To relinquish a claim (of a process on a
   multitasking system) for service; to indicate to the scheduler that a
   process may be deactivated until some given event occurs or a specified
   time delay elapses. 2. In jargon, used very similarly to v. {block};
   also in `sleep on', syn. with `block on'. Often used to indicate that
   the speaker has relinquished a demand for resources until some (possibly
   unspecified) external event: "They can't get the fix I've been asking
   for into the next release, so I'm going to sleep on it until the
   release, then start hassling them again."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleep</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sleep
     n 1: a natural and periodic state of rest during which
          consciousness of the world is suspended; "he didn't get
          enough sleep last night"; "calm as a child in dreamless
          slumber" [syn: {slumber}]
     2: a torpid state resembling sleep
     3: a period of time spent sleeping; "he felt better after a
        little sleep"; "there wasn't time for a nap" [syn: {nap}]
     4: euphemisms for death (based on an analogy between lying in a
        bed and in a tomb); "she was laid to rest beside her
        husband"; "they had to put their family pet to sleep"
        [syn: {rest}, {eternal rest}, {eternal sleep}, {quietus}]
     v 1: be asleep [syn: {kip}, {slumber}, {log Z's}, {catch some Z's}]
          [ant: {wake}]
     2: be able to accommodate for sleeping; "This tent sleeps six
        people"
     [also: {slept}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
