<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sleeve</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleeve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sleeve \Sleeve\ (sl[=e]v), n.
   See {Sleave}, untwisted thread.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleeve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sleeve \Sleeve\, n. [OE. sleeve, sleve, AS. sl?fe, sl?fe; akin
   to sl?fan to put on, to clothe; cf. OD. sloove the turning up
   of anything, sloven to turn up one's sleeves, sleve a sleeve,
   G. schlaube a husk, pod.]
   1. The part of a garment which covers the arm; as, the sleeve
      of a coat or a gown. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A narrow channel of water. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The Celtic Sea, called oftentimes the Sleeve.
                                                  --Drayton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.)
      (a) A tubular part made to cover, sustain, or steady
          another part, or to form a connection between two
          parts.
      (b) A long bushing or thimble, as in the nave of a wheel.
      (c) A short piece of pipe used for covering a joint, or
          forming a joint between the ends of two other pipes.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Elec.) A double tube of copper, in section like the
      figure 8, into which the ends of bare wires are pushed so
      that when the tube is twisted an electrical connection is
      made. The joint thus made is called

   {a McIntire joint}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Sleeve button}, a detachable button to fasten the wristband
      or cuff.

   {Sleeve links}, two bars or buttons linked together, and used
      to fasten a cuff or wristband.

   {To laugh in the sleeve} or {To laugh up one's sleeve} to
      laugh privately or unperceived, especially while
      apparently preserving a grave or serious demeanor toward
      the person or persons laughed at; that is, perhaps,
      originally, by hiding the face in the wide sleeves of
      former times.

   {To pinon the sleeve of}, or {To hang on the sleeve of}, to
      be, or make, dependent upon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleeve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sleeve \Sleeve\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sleeved} (sl[=e]vd); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Sleeving}.]
   To furnish with sleeves; to put sleeves into; as, to sleeve a
   coat.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sleeve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sleeve
     n 1: the part of a garment that is attached at armhole and
          provides a cloth covering for the arm [syn: {arm}]
     2: small case into which an object fits
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
