<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>slice</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>slice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Slice \Slice\, n. [OE. slice, sclice, OF. esclice, from
   esclicier, esclichier, to break to pieces, of German origin;
   cf. OHG. sl[=i]zan to split, slit, tear, G. schleissen to
   slit. See {Slit}, v. t.]
   1. A thin, broad piece cut off; as, a slice of bacon; a slice
      of cheese; a slice of bread.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is thin and broad, like a slice. Specifically:
      (a) A broad, thin piece of plaster.
      (b) A salver, platter, or tray. [Obs.]
      (c) A knife with a thin, broad blade for taking up or
          serving fish; also, a spatula for spreading anything,
          as paint or ink.
      (d) A plate of iron with a handle, forming a kind of
          chisel, or a spadelike implement, variously
          proportioned, and used for various purposes, as for
          stripping the planking from a vessel's side, for
          cutting blubber from a whale, or for stirring a fire
          of coals; a slice bar; a peel; a fire shovel. [Cant]
      (e) (Shipbuilding) One of the wedges by which the cradle
          and the ship are lifted clear of the building blocks
          to prepare for launching.
      (f) (Printing) A removable sliding bottom to galley.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Slice bar}, a kind of fire iron resembling a poker, with a
      broad, flat end, for stirring a fire of coals, and
      clearing it and the grate bars from clinkers, ashes, etc.;
      a slice.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>slice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Slice \Slice\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sliced}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Slicing}.]
   1. To cut into thin pieces, or to cut off a thin, broad piece
      from.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cut into parts; to divide.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To clear by means of a slice bar, as a fire or the grate
      bars of a furnace.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Golf) To hit (the ball) so that the face of the club
      draws across the face of the ball and deflects it.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>slice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>slice
     n 1: a share of something; "a slice of the company's revenue"
          [syn: {piece}]
     2: a serving that has been cut from a larger portion; "a piece
        of pie"; "a slice of bread" [syn: {piece}]
     3: a wound made by cutting; "he put a bandage over the cut"
        [syn: {cut}, {gash}, {slash}]
     4: a golf shot that curves to the right for a right-handed
        golfer; "he took lessons to cure his slicing" [syn: {fade},
         {slicing}]
     5: a thin flat piece cut off of some object
     6: a spatula for spreading paint or ink
     v 1: make a clean cut through; "slit her throat" [syn: {slit}]
     2: hit a ball and put a spin on it so that it travels in a
        different direction
     3: cut into slices; "Slice the salami, please" [syn: {slice up}]
     4: hit a ball so that it causes a backspin
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
