<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>slide</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>slide</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Slide \Slide\, v. t. [imp. {Slid}; p. p. {Slidden}, {Slid}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Slidding}.] [OE. sliden, AS. sl[=i]dan; akin to
   MHG. sl[=i]ten, also to AS. slidor slippery, E. sled, Lith.
   slidus slippery. Cf. {Sled}.]
   1. To move along the surface of any body by slipping, or
      without walking or rolling; to slip; to glide; as, snow
      slides down the mountain's side.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, to move over snow or ice with a smooth,
      uninterrupted motion, as on a sled moving by the force of
      gravity, or on the feet.
      [1913 Webster]

            They bathe in summer, and in winter slide. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass inadvertently.
      [1913 Webster]

            Beware thou slide not by it.          --Ecclus.
                                                  xxviii. 26.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To pass along smoothly or unobservedly; to move gently
      onward without friction or hindrance; as, a ship or boat
      slides through the water.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ages shall slide away without perceiving. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Parts answering parts shall slide into a whole.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To slip when walking or standing; to fall.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their foot shall slide in due time.   --Deut. xxxii.
                                                  35.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mus.) To pass from one note to another with no
      perceptible cassation of sound.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To pass out of one's thought as not being of any
      consequence. [Obs. or Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            With good hope let he sorrow slide.   --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            With a calm carelessness letting everything slide.
                                                  --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>slide</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Slide \Slide\, v. t.
   1. To cause to slide; to thrust along; as, to slide one piece
      of timber along another.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pass or put imperceptibly; to slip; as, to slide in a
      word to vary the sense of a question.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>slide</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Slide \Slide\, n. [AS. sl[=i]de.]
   1. The act of sliding; as, a slide on the ice.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Smooth, even passage or progress.
      [1913 Webster]

            A better slide into their business.   --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That on which anything moves by sliding. Specifically:
      (a) An inclined plane on which heavy bodies slide by the
          force of gravity, esp. one constructed on a mountain
          side for conveying logs by sliding them down.
      (b) A surface of ice or snow on which children slide for
          amusement.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. That which operates by sliding. Specifically:
      (a) A cover which opens or closes an aperture by sliding
          over it.
      (b) (Mach.) A moving piece which is guided by a part or
          parts along which it slides.
      (c) A clasp or brooch for a belt, or the like.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. A plate or slip of glass on which is a picture or
      delineation to be exhibited by means of a magic lantern,
      stereopticon, or the like; a plate on which is an object
      to be examined with a microscope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The descent of a mass of earth, rock, or snow down a hill
      or mountain side; as, a land slide, or a snow slide; also,
      the track of bare rock left by a land slide.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Geol.) A small dislocation in beds of rock along a line
      of fissure. --Dana.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mus.)
      (a) A grace consisting of two or more small notes moving
          by conjoint degrees, and leading to a principal note
          either above or below.
      (b) An apparatus in the trumpet and trombone by which the
          sounding tube is lengthened and shortened so as to
          produce the tones between the fundamental and its
          harmonics.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Phonetics) A sound which, by a gradual change in the
      position of the vocal organs, passes imperceptibly into
      another sound.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Steam Engine)
       (a) Same as {Guide bar}, under {Guide}.
       (b) A slide valve.
           [1913 Webster]

   {Slide box} (Steam Engine), a steam chest. See under {Steam}.
      

   {Slide lathe}, an engine lathe. See under {Lathe}.

   {Slide rail}, a transfer table. See under {Transfer}.

   {Slide rest} (Turning lathes), a contrivance for holding,
      moving, and guiding, the cutting tool, made to slide on
      ways or guides by screws or otherwise, and having compound
      motion.

   {Slide rule}, a mathematical instrument consisting of two
      parts, one of which slides upon the other, for the
      mechanical performance of addition and subtraction, and,
      by means of logarithmic scales, of multiplication and
      division.

   {Slide valve}.
       (a) Any valve which opens and closes a passageway by
           sliding over a port.
       (b) A particular kind of sliding valve, often used in
           steam engines for admitting steam to the piston and
           releasing it, alternately, having a cuplike cavity in
           its face, through which the exhaust steam passes. It
           is situated in the steam chest, and moved by the
           valve gear. It is sometimes called a {D valve}, -- a
           name which is also applied to a semicylindrical pipe
           used as a sliding valve.
           [1913 Webster] In the illustration, a is the cylinder
           of a steam engine, in which plays the piston p; b the
           steam chest, receiving its supply from the pipe i,
           and containing the slide valve s, which is shown as
           admitting steam to one end of the cylinder through
           the port e, and opening communication between the
           exhaust passage f and the port c, for the release of
           steam from the opposite end of the cylinder.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>slide</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>slide
     n 1: a small flat rectangular piece of glass on which specimens
          can be mounted for microscopic study [syn: {microscope
          slide}]
     2: (geology) the descent of a large mass of earth or rocks or
        snow etc.
     3: (music) rapid sliding up or down the musical scale; "the
        violinist was indulgent with his swoops and slides" [syn:
        {swoop}]
     4: plaything consisting of a sloping chute down which children
        can slide
     5: the act of moving smoothly along a surface while remaining
        in contact with it; "his slide didn't stop until the
        bottom of the hill"; "the children lined up for a coast
        down the snowy slope" [syn: {glide}, {coast}]
     6: a transparency mounted in a frame; viewed with a slide
        projector [syn: {lantern slide}]
     7: sloping channel through which things can descend [syn: {chute},
         {slideway}, {sloping trough}]
     v 1: move obliquely or sideways, usually in an uncontrolled
          manner; "the wheels skidded against the sidewalk" [syn:
          {skid}, {slip}, {slue}, {slew}]
     2: to pass or move unobtrusively or smoothly; "They slid
        through the wicket in the big gate" [syn: {slither}]
     3: move smoothly along a surface; "He slid the money over to
        the other gambler"
     [also: {slidden}, {slid}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
