<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>smartest</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>smartest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Smart \Smart\, a. [Compar. {Smarter}; superl. {Smartest}.] [OE.
   smerte. See {Smart}, v. i.]
   1. Causing a smart; pungent; pricking; as, a smart stroke or
      taste.
      [1913 Webster]

            How smart lash that speech doth give my conscience.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Keen; severe; poignant; as, smart pain.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Vigorous; sharp; severe. ``Smart skirmishes, in which many
      fell.'' --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Accomplishing, or able to accomplish, results quickly;
      active; sharp; clever. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Efficient; vigorous; brilliant. ``The stars shine
      smarter.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Marked by acuteness or shrewdness; quick in suggestion or
      reply; vivacious; witty; as, a smart reply; a smart
      saying.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who, for the poor renown of being smart
            Would leave a sting within a brother's heart?
                                                  --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

            A sentence or two, . . . which I thought very smart.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Pretentious; showy; spruce; as, a smart gown.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Brisk; fresh; as, a smart breeze.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Smart money}.
      (a) Money paid by a person to buy himself off from some
          unpleasant engagement or some painful situation.
      (b) (Mil.) Money allowed to soldiers or sailors, in the
          English service, for wounds and injures received;
          also, a sum paid by a recruit, previous to being sworn
          in, to procure his release from service.
      (c) (Law) Vindictive or exemplary damages; damages beyond
          a full compensation for the actual injury done.
          --Burrill. --Greenleaf.

   {Smart ticket}, a certificate given to wounded seamen,
      entitling them to smart money. [Eng.] --Brande &amp; C.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Pungent; poignant; sharp; tart; acute; quick; lively;
        brisk; witty; clever; keen; dashy; showy.

   Usage: {Smart}, {Clever}. Smart has been much used in New
          England to describe a person who is intelligent,
          vigorous, and active; as, a smart young fellow; a
          smart workman, etc., conciding very nearly with the
          English sense of clever. The nearest approach to this
          in England is in such expressions as, he was smart
          (pungent or witty) in his reply, etc.; but smart and
          smartness, when applied to persons, more commonly
          refer to dress; as, a smart appearance; a smart gown,
          etc.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
