<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>snag</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snag</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>snag
     
        {bug}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snag</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snag \Snag\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Snagged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Snagging}.]
   1. To cut the snags or branches from, as the stem of a tree;
      to hew roughly. [Prov. Eng.] --Halliwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To injure or destroy, as a steamboat or other vessel, by a
      snag, or projecting part of a sunken tree. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To catch on a snag [5]

   4. (Fig.) To obtain by a quick action, as though by snagging
      [3] something passing by; -- often used of an
      opportunistic or fortunate action.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snag</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snag \Snag\, n. [Prov. E., n., a lump on a tree where a branch
   has been cut off; v., to cut off the twigs and small branches
   from a tree, of Celtic origin; cf. Gael. snaigh, snaidh, to
   cut down, to prune, to sharpen, p. p. snaighte, snaidhte, cut
   off, lopped, Ir. snaigh a hewing, cutting.]
   1. A stump or base of a branch that has been lopped off; a
      short branch, or a sharp or rough branch; a knot; a
      protuberance.
      [1913 Webster]

            The coat of arms
            Now on a naked snag in triumph borne. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A tooth projecting beyond the rest; contemptuously, a
      broken or decayed tooth. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A tree, or a branch of a tree, fixed in the bottom of a
      river or other navigable water, and rising nearly or quite
      to the surface, by which boats are sometimes pierced and
      sunk.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) One of the secondary branches of an antler.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Any sharp protuberant part of an object, which may catch,
      scratch, or tear other objects brought into contact with
      it.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Snag boat}, a steamboat fitted with apparatus for removing
      snags and other obstructions in navigable streams. [U.S.]

   {Snag tooth}. Same as {Snag}, 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            How thy snag teeth stand orderly,
            Like stakes which strut by the water side. --J.
                                                  Cotgrave.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snag</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>snag
     n 1: a sharp protuberance
     2: a dead tree that is still standing, usually in an
        undisturbed forest; "a snag can provide food and a habitat
        for insects and birds"
     3: an opening made forcibly as by pulling apart; "there was a
        rip in his pants"; "she had snags in her stockings" [syn:
        {rip}, {rent}, {split}, {tear}]
     4: an unforeseen obstacle [syn: {hang-up}, {hitch}, {rub}]
     v 1: catch on a snag; "I snagged my stocking"
     2: get by acting quickly and smartly; "snag a bargain"
     3: hew jaggedly
     [also: {snagging}, {snagged}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
