<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>snail</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snail
   (1.) Heb. homit, among the unclean creeping things (Lev. 11:30).
   This was probably the sand-lizard, of which there are many
   species in the wilderness of Judea and the Sinai peninsula.
   
     (2.) Heb. shablul (Ps. 58:8), the snail or slug proper.
   Tristram explains the allusions of this passage by a reference
   to the heat and drought by which the moisture of the snail is
   evaporated. "We find," he says, "in all parts of the Holy Land
   myriads of snail-shells in fissures still adhering by the
   calcareous exudation round their orifice to the surface of the
   rock, but the animal of which is utterly shrivelled and wasted,
   'melted away.'"
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snail \Snail\ (sn[=a]l), n. [OE. snaile, AS. sn[ae]gel, snegel,
   sn[ae]gl; akin to G. schnecke, OHG. snecko, Dan. snegl, Icel.
   snigill.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any one of numerous species of terrestrial
          air-breathing gastropods belonging to the genus Helix
          and many allied genera of the family {Helicid[ae]}.
          They are abundant in nearly all parts of the world
          except the arctic regions, and feed almost entirely on
          vegetation; a land snail.
      (b) Any gastropod having a general resemblance to the true
          snails, including fresh-water and marine species. See
          {Pond snail}, under {Pond}, and {Sea snail}.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, a drone; a slow-moving person or thing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mech.) A spiral cam, or a flat piece of metal of spirally
      curved outline, used for giving motion to, or changing the
      position of, another part, as the hammer tail of a
      striking clock.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A tortoise; in ancient warfare, a movable roof or shed to
      protect besiegers; a testudo. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They had also all manner of gynes [engines] . . .
            that needful is [in] taking or sieging of castle or
            of city, as snails, that was naught else but hollow
            pavises and targets, under the which men, when they
            fought, were heled [protected], . . . as the snail
            is in his house; therefore they cleped them snails.
                                                  --Vegetius
                                                  (Trans.).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Bot.) The pod of the sanil clover.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ear snail}, {Edible snail}, {Pond snail}, etc. See under
      {Ear}, {Edible}, etc.

   {Snail borer} (Zo["o]l.), a boring univalve mollusk; a drill.
      

   {Snail clover} (Bot.), a cloverlike plant ({Medicago
      scuttellata}, also, {M. Helix}); -- so named from its
      pods, which resemble the shells of snails; -- called also
      {snail trefoil}, {snail medic}, and {beehive}.

   {Snail flower} (Bot.), a leguminous plant ({Phaseolus
      Caracalla}) having the keel of the carolla spirally coiled
      like a snail shell.

   {Snail shell} (Zo["o]l.), the shell of snail.

   {Snail trefoil}. (Bot.) See {Snail clover}, above.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>snail vt. To {snail-mail} something. "Snail me a copy of those
   graphics, will you?"


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>snail
     n 1: freshwater or marine or terrestrial gastropod mollusk
          usually having an external enclosing spiral shell
     2: edible terrestrial snail usually served in the shell with a
        sauce of melted butter and garlic [syn: {escargot}]
     v : gather snails; "We went snailing in the summer"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
