<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>snap</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SNAP
     
        1. Early (IBM 360?) interpreted text-processing language for
        beginners, close to basic English.  ["Computer Programming in
        English", M.P. Barnett, Harcourt Brace 1969].
     
        2. ["Some Proposals for SNAP, A Language with Formal Macro
        Facilities", R.B. Napper, Computer J 10(3):231-243 (1967)].
        [same as 1?]
     
        3. To replace a pointer to a pointer with a direct pointer; to
        replace an old address with the forwarding address found
        there.  If you telephone the main number for an institution
        and ask for a particular person by name, the operator may tell
        you that person's extension before connecting you, in the
        hopes that you will "snap your pointer" and dial direct next
        time.  The underlying metaphor may be that of a rubber band
        stretched through a number of intermediate points; if you
        remove all the thumbtacks in the middle, it snaps into a
        straight line from first to last.  See {chase pointers}.
     
        Often, the behaviour of a {trampoline} is to perform an error
        check once and then snap the pointer that invoked it so as
        henceforth to bypass the trampoline (and its one-shot error
        check).  In this context one also speaks of "snapping links".
        For example, in a {Lisp} implementation, a function interface
        trampoline might check to make sure that the caller is passing
        the correct number of arguments; if it is, and if the caller
        and the callee are both compiled, then snapping the link
        allows that particular path to use a direct procedure-call
        instruction with no further overhead.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snap \Snap\, v. i.
   1. To break short, or at once; to part asunder suddenly; as,
      a mast snaps; a needle snaps.
      [1913 Webster]

            But this weapon will snap short, unfaithful to the
            hand that employs it.                 --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give forth, or produce, a sharp, cracking noise; to
      crack; as, blazing firewood snaps.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make an effort to bite; to aim to seize with the teeth;
      to catch eagerly (at anything); -- often with at; as, a
      dog snapsat a passenger; a fish snaps at the bait.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To utter sharp, harsh, angry words; -- often with at; as,
      to snap at a child.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To miss fire; as, the gun snapped.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Of the eyes, to emit sudden, brief sparkles like those of
      a snapping fire, as sometimes in anger.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snap \Snap\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Snapped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Snapping}.] [LG. or D. snappen to snap up, to snatch; akin
   to G. schnappen, MHG. snaben, Dan. snappe, and to D. snavel
   beak, bill. Cf. {Neb}, {Snaffle}, n.]
   1. To break at once; to break short, as substances that are
      brittle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Breaks the doors open, snaps the locks. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To strike, to hit, or to shut, with a sharp sound.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bite or seize suddenly, especially with the teeth.
      [1913 Webster]

            He, by playing too often at the mouth of death, has
            been snapped by it at last.           --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To break upon suddenly with sharp, angry words; to treat
      snappishly; -- usually with up. --Granville.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To crack; to cause to make a sharp, cracking noise; as, to
      snap a whip.
      [1913 Webster]

            MacMorian snapped his fingers repeatedly. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To project with a snap.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Cricket) To catch out sharply (a batsman who has just
      snicked a bowled ball).
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To snap back} (Football), to roll the ball back with the
      foot; -- done only by the center rush, who thus delivers
      the ball to the quarter back on his own side when both
      sides are ranged in line.

   {To snap off}.
      (a) To break suddenly.
      (b) To bite off suddenly.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snap \Snap\, n. [Cf. D. snap a snatching. See {Snap}, v. t.]
   1. A sudden breaking or rupture of any substance.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A sudden, eager bite; a sudden seizing, or effort to
      seize, as with the teeth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sudden, sharp motion or blow, as with the finger sprung
      from the thumb, or the thumb from the finger.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A sharp, abrupt sound, as that made by the crack of a
      whip; as, the snap of the trigger of a gun.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A greedy fellow. --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That which is, or may be, snapped up; something bitten
      off, seized, or obtained by a single quick movement;
      hence, a bite, morsel, or fragment; a scrap.
      [1913 Webster]

            He's a nimble fellow,
            And alike skilled in every liberal science,
            As having certain snaps of all.       --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A sudden severe interval or spell; -- applied to the
      weather; as, a cold snap. --Lowell.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A small catch or fastening held or closed by means of a
      spring, or one which closes with a snapping sound, as the
      catch of a bracelet, necklace, clasp of a book, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Zo["o]l.) A snap beetle.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A thin, crisp cake, usually small, and flavored with
       ginger; -- used chiefly in the plural.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Briskness; vigor; energy; decision. [Colloq.]
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Any circumstance out of which money may be made or an
       advantage gained. [Slang]
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Any task, labor, set of circumstances, or the like, that
       yields satisfactory results or gives pleasure with little
       trouble or effort, as an easy course of study, a job
       where work is light, a bargain, etc. [Slang, Chiefly U.
       S.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   14. A snap shot with a firearm.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   15. (Photog.) A snapshot.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   16. Something of no value; as, not worth a snap. [Colloq.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   17. (Football) The action of snapping the ball back, from the
       center usu. to the quarterback, which commences the play
       (down), and, if the clock had stopped, restarts the timer
       clock; a {snap back}.
       [PJC]

   {Snap back} (Football), the act of snapping back the ball.

   {Snap beetle}, or {Snap bug} (Zo["o]l.), any beetle of the
      family {Elaterid[ae]}, which, when laid on its back, is
      able to leap to a considerable height by means of a
      thoracic spring; -- called also {snapping beetle}.

   {Snap flask} (Molding), a flask for small work, having its
      sides separable and held together by latches, so that the
      flask may be removed from around the sand mold.

   {Snap judgment}, a judgment formed on the instant without
      deliberation.

   {Snap lock}, a lock shutting with a catch or snap.

   {Snap riveting}, riveting in which the rivets have snapheads
      formed by a die or swaging tool.

   {Snap shot}, a quick offhand shot, without deliberately
      taking aim.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snap \Snap\, a.
   Done, performed, made, executed, carried through, or the
   like, quickly and without deliberation; as, a snap judgment
   or decision; a snap political convention. [Colloq.]
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>snap v. To replace a pointer to a pointer with a direct pointer; to
   replace an old address with the forwarding address found there. If you
   telephone the main number for an institution and ask for a particular
   person by name, the operator may tell you that person's extension before
   connecting you, in the hopes that you will `snap your pointer' and dial
   direct next time. The underlying metaphor may be that of a rubber band
   stretched through a number of intermediate points; if you remove all the
   thumbtacks in the middle, it snaps into a straight line from first to
   last. See {chase pointers}.

   Often, the behavior of a {trampoline} is to perform an error check
   once and then snap the pointer that invoked it so as henceforth to
   bypass the trampoline (and its one-shot error check). In this context
   one also speaks of `snapping links'. For example, in a LISP
   implementation, a function interface trampoline might check to make sure
   that the caller is passing the correct number of arguments; if it is,
   and if the caller and the callee are both compiled, then snapping the
   link allows that particular path to use a direct procedure-call
   instruction with no further overhead.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SNAP
     SubNetwork Access Protocol (LAN, ethernet)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SNAP
     SubNetwork Attachment Point (IEEE 802.1a)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SNAP
     System and Network Administration Program
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>snap
     n 1: the act of catching an object with the hands; "Mays made the
          catch with his back to the plate"; "he made a grab for
          the ball before it landed"; "Martin's snatch at the
          bridle failed and the horse raced away"; "the
          infielder's snap and throw was a single motion" [syn: {catch},
           {grab}, {snatch}]
     2: a spell of cold weather; "a cold snap in the middle of May"
     3: tender green beans without strings that easily snap into
        sections [syn: {snap bean}]
     4: a crisp round cookie flavored with ginger [syn: {gingersnap},
         {ginger snap}, {ginger nut}]
     5: the noise produced by the rapid movement of a finger from
        the tip to the base of the thumb on the same hand;
        "servants appeared at the snap of his fingers"
     6: a sudden sharp noise; "the crack of a whip"; "he heard the
        cracking of the ice"; "he can hear the snap of a twig"
        [syn: {crack}, {cracking}]
     7: a sudden breaking
     8: the tendency of a body to return to its original shape after
        it has been stretched or compressed; "the waistband had
        lost its snap" [syn: {elasticity}] [ant: {inelasticity}]
     9: an informal photograph; usually made with a small hand-held
        camera; "my snapshots haven't been developed yet"; "he
        tried to get unposed shots of his friends" [syn: {snapshot},
         {shot}]
     10: a fastener used on clothing; fastens with a snapping sound;
         "children can manage snaps better than buttons" [syn: {snap
         fastener}, {press stud}]
     11: any undertaking that is easy to do; "marketing this product
         will be no picnic" [syn: {cinch}, {breeze}, {picnic}, {duck
         soup}, {child's play}, {pushover}, {walkover}, {piece of
         cake}]
     12: the act of snapping the fingers; movement of a finger from
         the tip to the base of the thumb on the same hand; "he
         gave his fingers a snap"
     13: (American football) putting the ball in play by passing it
         (between the legs) to a back; "the quarterback fumbled
         the snap" [syn: {centering}]
     v 1: utter in an angry, sharp, or abrupt tone; "The sales clerky
          snapped a reply at the angry customer"; "The guard
          snarled at us" [syn: {snarl}]
     2: separate or cause to separate abruptly; "The rope snapped";
        "tear the paper" [syn: {tear}, {rupture}, {bust}]
     3: break suddenly and abruptly, as under tension; "The rope
        snapped" [syn: {crack}]
     4: move or strike with a noise; "he clicked on the light"; "his
        arm was snapped forward" [syn: {click}]
     5: snap close with a sound; "The lock snapped shut"
     6: make a sharp sound; "his fingers snapped" [syn: {crack}]
     7: move with a snapping sound; "bullets snapped past us"
     8: to grasp hastily or eagerly; "Before I could stop him the
        dog snatched the ham bone" [syn: {snatch}, {snatch up}]
     9: put in play with a snap; "snap a football"
     10: cause to make a snapping sound; "snap your fingers" [syn: {click},
          {flick}]
     11: lose control of one's emotions; "When she heard that she had
         not passed the exam, she lost it completely"; "When her
         baby died, she snapped" [syn: {break down}, {lose it}]
     12: record on photographic film; "I photographed the scene of
         the accident"; "She snapped a picture of the President"
         [syn: {photograph}, {shoot}]
     [also: {snapping}, {snapped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
