<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>snare</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snare
   The expression (Amos 3:5), "Shall one take up a snare from the
   earth?" etc. (Authorized Version), ought to be, as in the
   Revised Version, "Shall a snare spring up from the ground?" etc.
   (See {GIN}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snare \Snare\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Snared}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Snaring}.]
   To catch with a snare; to insnare; to entangle; hence, to
   bring into unexpected evil, perplexity, or danger.
   [1913 Webster]

         Lest that too heavenly form . . . snare them. --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]

         The mournful crocodile
         With sorrow snares relenting passengers. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Snare \Snare\, n. [AS. sneara cord, a string; akin to D. snoer,
   G. schnur, OHG. snour a cord, snarahha a noose, Dan. snare,
   Sw. &amp; Icel. snara, Goth. sn?rj? a basket; and probably also
   to E. needle. See {Needle}, and cf. {Snarl} to entangle.]
   1. A contrivance, often consisting of a noose of cord, or the
      like, by which a bird or other animal may be entangled and
      caught; a trap; a gin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, anything by which one is entangled and brought into
      trouble.
      [1913 Webster]

            If thou retire, the Dauphin, well appointed,
            Stands with the snares of war to tangle thee.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The gut or string stretched across the lower head of a
      drum.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Med.) An instrument, consisting usually of a wireloop or
      noose, for removing tumors, etc., by avulsion.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Snare drum}, the smaller common military drum, as
      distinguished from the bass drum; -- so called because (in
      order to render it more resonant) it has stretched across
      its lower head a catgut string or strings.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>snare</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>snare
     n 1: something (often something deceptively attractive) that
          catches you unawares; "the exam was full of trap
          questions"; "it was all a snare and delusion" [syn: {trap}]
     2: a small drum with two heads and a snare stretched across the
        lower head [syn: {snare drum}, {side drum}]
     3: a surgical instrument consisting of wire hoop that can be
        drawn tight around the base of polyps or small tumors to
        sever them; used especially in body cavities
     4: strings stretched across the lower head of a snare drum;
        they make a rattling sound when the drum is hit
     5: a trap for birds or small mammals; often has a noose [syn: {gin},
         {noose}]
     v 1: catch in or as if in a trap; "The men trap foxes" [syn: {trap},
           {entrap}, {ensnare}, {trammel}]
     2: entice and trap; "The car salesman had snared three
        potential customers" [syn: {hook}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
