<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>socket</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>socket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>socket
     
        &lt;networking&gt; The {Berkeley Unix} mechansim for creating a
        virtual connection between processes.  Sockets interface
        {Unix}'s {standard I/O} with its {network} communication
        facilities.  They can be of two types, stream (bi-directional)
        or {datagram} (fixed length destination-addressed messages).
        The socket library function socket() creates a communications
        end-point or socket and returns a {file descriptor} with which
        to access that socket.  The socket has associated with it a
        socket address, consisting of a {port} number and the local
        host's network address.
     
        {Unix manual page}: socket(2).
     
        (1995-01-31)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>socket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Socket \Sock"et\, n. [OE. soket, a dim. through OF. fr. L.
   soccus. See {Sock} a covering for the foot.]
   1. An opening into which anything is fitted; any hollow thing
      or place which receives and holds something else; as, the
      sockets of the teeth.
      [1913 Webster]

            His eyeballs in their hollow sockets sink. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, the hollow tube or place in which a candle is
      fixed in the candlestick.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Electricity) the receptacle of an electric lamp into
      which a light bulb is inserted, containing contacts to
      conduct electricity to the bulb.
      [PJC]

   4. (Electricity) the receptacle fixed in a wall and connected
      by conductive wiring to an electrical supply, containing
      contacts to conduct electricity, and into which the plug
      of an electrical device is inserted; -- called also a
      {wall socket} or {outlet}. The socket will typically have
      two or three contacts; if three, the third is connected to
      a ground for safety.
      [PJC]

            And in the sockets oily bubbles dance. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Socket bolt} (Mach.), a bolt that passes through a thimble
      that is placed between the parts connected by the bolt.

   {Socket chisel}. Same as {Framing chisel}. See under
      {Framing}.

   {Socket pipe}, a pipe with an expansion at one end to receive
      the end of a connecting pipe.

   {Socket pole}, a pole armed with iron fixed on by means of a
      socket, and used to propel boats, etc. [U.S.]

   {Socket wrench}, a wrench consisting of a socket at the end
      of a shank or rod, for turning a nut, bolthead, etc., in a
      narrow or deep recess.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>socket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>socket
     n 1: a bony hollow into which a structure fits
     2: receptacle where something (a pipe or probe or end of a
        bone) is inserted
     3: a receptacle into which an electric device can be inserted
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
