<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>soda</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soda</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SODA
     
        Symbolic Optimum DEUCE Assembly Program.
     
        The symbolic {assembler} for a {one-level storage} {virtual
        machine} for the {English ELectric} {DEUCE}.
     
        ["SODA Manual of Operation", R. C. Brigham and C. G. Bell,
        School of Elec Eng, U New S Wales, Sydney, NSW (1958)].
     
        (1994-11-04)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soda</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Soda \So"da\, n. [It., soda, in OIt., ashes used in making
   glass, fr. L. solida, fem. of solidus solid; solida having
   probably been a name of glasswort. See {Solid}.]
   1. (Chem.)
      (a) Sodium oxide or hydroxide.
      (b) Popularly, sodium carbonate or bicarbonate. Sodium
          bicarbonate is also called {baking soda}
          [1913 Webster]

   2. same as {sodium}, used in terms such as {bicarbonate of
      soda}.
      [PJC]

   3. same as {soda water}.
      [PJC]

   4. a non-alcoholic beverage, sweetened by various means,
      containing flavoring and supersaturated with carbon
      dioxide, so as to be effervescent when the container is
      opened; -- in different localities it is variously called
      also {soda pop}, {pop}, {mineral water}, and {minerals}.
      It has many variants. The sweetening agent may be natural,
      such as cane sugar or corn syrup, or artificial, such as
      saccharin or aspartame. The flavoring varies widely,
      popular variants being fruit or cola flavoring.
      [PJC]

   {Caustic soda}, sodium hydroxide.

   {Cooking soda}, sodium bicarbonate. [Colloq.]

   {Sal soda}. See {Sodium carbonate}, under {Sodium}.

   {Soda alum} (Min.), a mineral consisting of the hydrous
      sulphate of alumina and soda.

   {Soda ash}, crude sodium carbonate; -- so called because
      formerly obtained from the ashes of sea plants and certain
      other plants, as saltwort ({Salsola}). See under {Sodium}.
      

   {Soda fountain}, an apparatus for drawing soda water, fitted
      with delivery tube, faucets, etc.

   {Soda lye}, a lye consisting essentially of a solution of
      sodium hydroxide, used in soap making.

   {Soda niter}. See {Nitratine}.

   {Soda salts}, salts having sodium for the base; specifically,
      sodium sulphate or Glauber's salts.

   {Soda waste}, the waste material, consisting chiefly of
      calcium hydroxide and sulphide, which accumulates as a
      useless residue or side product in the ordinary Leblanc
      process of soda manufacture; -- called also {alkali
      waste}.

   {Washing soda}, sodium carbonate. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soda</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Soda pop \So"da pop\, n.
   a popular non-alcoholic beverage, sweetened by various means,
   containing flavoring and supersaturated with carbon dioxide,
   so as to be effervescent when the container is opened; -- in
   different localities it is variously called also {soda},
   {pop}, {mineral water}, and {minerals}. It has many variants.
   The sweetening agent may be natural, such as cane sugar or
   corn syrup, or artificial, such as saccharin or aspartame.
   The flavoring varies widely, popular variants being fruit
   juices, fruit sirups, cream, or cola flavoring; the soda pop
   is usually served chilled.

   Note: Several large corporations started primarily as
         bottlers of soda pop, such as {Coca-Cola},
         {Pepsi-Cola}, and {Dr. Pepper}.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soda</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sodium \So"di*um\, n. [NL., fr.E. soda.] (Chem.)
   A common metallic element of the alkali group, in nature
   always occuring combined, as in common salt, in albite, etc.
   It is isolated as a soft, waxy, white, unstable metal, so
   highly reactive that it combines violently with water, and to
   be preserved must be kept under petroleum or some similar
   liquid. Sodium is used combined in many salts, in the free
   state as a reducer, and as a means of obtaining other metals
   (as magnesium and aluminium) is an important commercial
   product. Symbol Na ({Natrium}). Atomic weight 22.990.
   Specific gravity 0.97.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Sodium amalgam}, an alloy of sodium and mercury, usually
      produced as a gray metallic crystalline substance, which
      is used as a reducing agent, and otherwise.

   {Sodium carbonate}, a white crystalline substance,
      {Na2CO3.10H2O}, having a cooling alkaline taste, found in
      the ashes of many plants, and produced artifically in
      large quantities from common salt. It is used in making
      soap, glass, paper, etc., and as alkaline agent in many
      chemical industries. Called also {sal soda}, {washing
      soda}, or {soda}. Cf. {Sodium bicarbonate}, and {Trona}.
      

   {Sodium chloride}, common, or table, salt, {NaCl}.

   {Sodium hydroxide}, a white opaque brittle solid, {NaOH},
      having a fibrous structure, produced by the action of
      quicklime, or of calcium hydrate (milk of lime), on sodium
      carbonate. It is a strong alkali, and is used in the
      manufacture of soap, in making wood pulp for paper, etc.
      Called also {sodium hydrate}, and {caustic soda}. By
      extension, a solution of sodium hydroxide.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soda</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SODA
     Simplified OS for Distributed Applications (OS)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soda</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SODA
     System Optimization and Design Algorithm
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soda</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>soda
     n 1: a sodium salt of carbonic acid; used in making soap powders
          and glass and paper [syn: {sodium carbonate}, {washing
          soda}, {sal soda}, {soda ash}]
     2: a sweet drink containing carbonated water and flavoring; "in
        New England they call sodas tonics" [syn: {pop}, {soda pop},
         {soda water}, {tonic}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
