<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>some</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>some</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-some \-some\ (-s[=o]m).
   A combining form or suffix from Gr. sw^ma (gen. sw`matos) the
   body; as in merosome, a body segment; cephalosome, etc.
   [1913 Webster]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>some</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-some \-some\ (-s[u^]m). [AS. -sum; akin to G. &amp; OHG. -sam,
   Icel. samr, Goth. lustusams longed for. See {Same}, a., and
   cf. {Some}, a.]
   An adjective suffix having primarily the sense of like or
   same, and indicating a considerable degree of the thing or
   quality denoted in the first part of the compound; as in
   mettlesome, full of mettle or spirit; gladsome, full of
   gladness; winsome, blithesome, etc.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>some</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Some \Some\ (s[u^]m), a. [OE. som, sum, AS. sum; akin to OS.,
   OFries., &amp; OHG. sum, OD. som, D. sommig, Icel. sumr, Dan.
   somme (pl.), Sw. somlige (pl.), Goth. sums, and E. same.
   [root]191. See {Same}, a., and cf. {-some}.]
   1. Consisting of a greater or less portion or sum; composed
      of a quantity or number which is not stated; -- used to
      express an indefinite quantity or number; as, some wine;
      some water; some persons. Used also pronominally; as, I
      have some.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some theoretical writers allege that there was a
            time when there was no such thing as society.
                                                  --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A certain; one; -- indicating a person, thing, event,
      etc., as not known individually, or designated more
      specifically; as, some man, that is, some one man. ``Some
      brighter clime.'' --Mrs. Barbauld.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some man praiseth his neighbor by a wicked intent.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Most gentlemen of property, at some period or other
            of their lives, are ambitious of representing their
            county in Parliament.                 --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not much; a little; moderate; as, the censure was to some
      extent just.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. About; near; more or less; -- used commonly with numerals,
      but formerly also with a singular substantive of time or
      distance; as, a village of some eighty houses; some two or
      three persons; some hour hence. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The number slain on the rebel's part were some two
            thousand.                             --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Considerable in number or quantity. ``Bore us some leagues
      to sea.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            On its outer point, some miles away.
            The lighthouse lifts its massive masonry.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Certain; those of one part or portion; -- in distinction
      from {other} or {others}; as, some men believe one thing,
      and others another.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some [seeds] fell among thorns; . . . but other fell
            into good ground.                     --Matt. xiii.
                                                  7, 8.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A part; a portion; -- used pronominally, and followed
      sometimes by of; as, some of our provisions.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your edicts some reclaim from sins,
            But most your life and blest example wins. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {All and some}, one and all. See under {All}, adv. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The illiterate in the United States and Scotland often
         use some as an adverb, instead of somewhat, or an
         equivalent expression; as, I am some tired; he is some
         better; it rains some, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Some . . . some}, one part . . . another part; these . . .
      those; -- used distributively.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some to the shores do fly,
            Some to the woods, or whither fear advised.
                                                  --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Formerly used also of single persons or things: this
         one . . . that one; one . . . another.
         [1913 Webster]

               Some in his bed, some in the deep sea. --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>some</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>some
     adj 1: quantifier; used with either mass nouns or plural count
            nouns to indicate an unspecified number or quantity;
            "have some milk"; "some roses were still blooming";
            "having some friends over"; "some apples"; "some
            paper" [syn: {some(a)}] [ant: {no(a)}, {all(a)}]
     2: unknown or unspecified; "some lunatic drove into my car";
        "some man telephoned while you were out"; "some day my
        prince will come"; "some enchanted evening" [syn: {some(a)}]
     3: relatively many but unspecified in number; "they were here
        for some weeks"; "we did not meet again for some years"
        [syn: {some(a)}]
     4: remarkable; "that was some party"; "she is some skier"
     5: relatively much but unspecified in amount or extent; "we
        talked for some time"; "he was still some distance away"
        [syn: {some(a)}]
     adv : (of quantities) imprecise but fairly close to correct;
           "lasted approximately an hour"; "in just about a
           minute"; "he's about 30 years old"; "I've had about all
           I can stand"; "we meet about once a month"; "some forty
           people came"; "weighs around a hundred pounds";
           "roughly $3,000"; "holds 3 gallons, more or less"; "20
           or so people were at the party" [syn: {approximately},
           {about}, {close to}, {just about}, {roughly}, {more or
           less}, {around}, {or so}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
