<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sort</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sort
     
        1. &lt;application, algorithm&gt; To arrange a collection of items
        in some specified order.  The items - {records} in a file or
        data structures in memory - consist of one or more {fields} or
        members.  One of these fields is designated as the "sort key"
        which means the records will be ordered according to the value
        of that field.  Sometimes a sequence of key fields is
        specified such that if all earlier keys are equal then the
        later keys will be compared.  Within each field some ordering
        is imposed, e.g. ascending or descending numerical, {lexical
        ordering}, or date.
     
        Sorting is the subject of a great deal of study since it is a
        common operation which can consume a lot of computer time.
        There are many well-known sorting {algorithms} with different
        time and space behaviour and programming {complexity}.
     
        Examples are {quicksort}, {insertion sort}, {bubble sort},
        {heap sort}, and {tree sort}.  These employ many different
        data structures to store sorted data, such as {arrays},
        {linked lists}, and {binary trees}.
     
        2. &lt;tool&gt; The {Unix} utility program for sorting lines of
        files.
     
        {Unix manual page}: sort(1).
     
        (1997-02-12)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sort \Sort\, n. [F. sorl, L. sors, sortis. See {Sort} kind.]
   Chance; lot; destiny. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         By aventure, or sort, or cas [chance].   --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

         Let blockish Ajax draw
         The sort to fight with Hector.           --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sort \Sort\, n. [F. sorie (cf. It. sorta, sorte), from L. sors,
   sorti, a lot, part, probably akin to serere to connect. See
   {Series}, and cf. {Assort}, {Consort}, {Resort}, {Sorcery},
   {Sort} lot.]
   1. A kind or species; any number or collection of individual
      persons or things characterized by the same or like
      qualities; a class or order; as, a sort of men; a sort of
      horses; a sort of trees; a sort of poems.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Manner; form of being or acting.
      [1913 Webster]

            Which for my part I covet to perform,
            In sort as through the world I did proclaim.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Flowers, in such sort worn, can neither be smelt nor
            seen well by those that wear them.    --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll deceive you in another sort.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To Adam in what sort
            Shall I appear?                       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            I shall not be wholly without praise, if in some
            sort I have copied his style.         --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Condition above the vulgar; rank. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A chance group; a company of persons who happen to be
      together; a troop; also, an assemblage of animals. [Obs.]
      ``A sort of shepherds.'' --Spenser. ``A sort of steers.''
      --Spenser. ``A sort of doves.'' --Dryden. ``A sort of
      rogues.'' --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

            A boy, a child, and we a sort of us,
            Vowed against his voyage.             --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A pair; a set; a suit. --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. pl. (Print.) Letters, figures, points, marks, spaces, or
      quadrats, belonging to a case, separately considered.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Out of sorts} (Print.), with some letters or sorts of type
      deficient or exhausted in the case or font; hence,
      colloquially, out of order; ill; vexed; disturbed.

   {To run upon sorts} (Print.), to use or require a greater
      number of some particular letters, figures, or marks than
      the regular proportion, as, for example, in making an
      index.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Kind; species; rank; condition.

   Usage: {Sort}, {Kind}. Kind originally denoted things of the
          same family, or bound together by some natural
          affinity; and hence, a class. Sort signifies that
          which constitutes a particular lot of parcel, not
          implying necessarily the idea of affinity, but of mere
          assemblage. the two words are now used to a great
          extent interchangeably, though sort (perhaps from its
          original meaning of lot) sometimes carries with it a
          slight tone of disparagement or contempt, as when we
          say, that sort of people, that sort of language.
          [1913 Webster]

                As when the total kind
                Of birds, in orderly array on wing,
                Came summoned over Eden to receive
                Their names of there.             --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                None of noble sort
                Would so offend a virgin.         --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sort \Sort\, v. i.
   1. To join or associate with others, esp. with others of the
      same kind or species; to agree.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor do metals only sort and herd with metals in the
            earth, and minerals with minerals.    --Woodward.
      [1913 Webster]

            The illiberality of parents towards children makes
            them base, and sort with any company. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To suit; to fit; to be in accord; to harmonize.
      [1913 Webster]

            They are happy whose natures sort with their
            vocations.                            --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Things sort not to my will.           --herbert.
      [1913 Webster]

            I can not tell you precisely how they sorted. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sort \Sort\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sorted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Sorting}.]
   1. To separate, and place in distinct classes or divisions,
      as things having different qualities; as, to sort cloths
      according to their colors; to sort wool or thread
      according to its fineness.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rays which differ in refrangibility may be parted
            and sorted from one another.          --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To reduce to order from a confused state. --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To conjoin; to put together in distribution; to class.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shellfish have been, by some of the ancients,
            compared and sorted with insects.     --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            She sorts things present with things past. --Sir J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To choose from a number; to select; to cull.
      [1913 Webster]

            That he may sort out a worthy spouse. --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll sort some other time to visit you. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To conform; to adapt; to accommodate. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I pray thee, sort thy heart to patience. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sort
     n 1: a category of things distinguished by some common
          characteristic or quality; "sculpture is a form of art";
          "what kinds of desserts are there?" [syn: {kind}, {form},
           {variety}]
     2: an approximate definition or example; "she wore a sort of
        magenta dress"; "she served a creamy sort of dessert
        thing"
     3: a person of a particular character or nature; "what sort of
        person is he?"; "he's a good sort"
     4: an operation that segregates items into groups according to
        a specified criterion; "the bottleneck in mail delivery it
        the process of sorting" [syn: {sorting}]
     v 1: examine in order to test suitability; "screen these
          samples"; "screen the job applicants" [syn: {screen}, {screen
          out}, {sieve}]
     2: arrange or order by classes or categories; "How would you
        classify these pottery shards--are they prehistoric?"
        [syn: {classify}, {class}, {assort}, {sort out}, {separate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
