<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>soso</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soso</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Soso, MS (town, FIPS 69160)
  Location: 31.75457 N, 89.27636 W
  Population (1990): 366 (163 housing units)
  Area: 5.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 39480
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soso</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>So \So\, adv. [OE. so, sa, swa, AS. sw[=a]; akin to OFries,
   s[=a], s?, D. zoo, OS. &amp; OHG. s?, G. so, Icel. sv[=a], sv?,
   svo, so, Sw. s?, Dan. saa, Goth. swa so, sw? as; cf. L. suus
   one's own, Skr. sva one's own, one's self. [root]192. Cf. As,
   {Custom}, {Ethic}, {Idiom}, {Such}.]
   1. In that manner or degree; as, indicated (in any way), or
      as implied, or as supposed to be known.
      [1913 Webster]

            Why is his chariot so long in coming? --Judges v.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. In like manner or degree; in the same way; thus; for like
      reason; whith equal reason; -- used correlatively,
      following as, to denote comparison or resemblance;
      sometimes, also, following inasmuch as.
      [1913 Webster]

            As a war should be undertaken upon a just motive, so
            a prince ought to consider the condition he is in.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. In such manner; to such degree; -- used correlatively with
      as or that following; as, he was so fortunate as to
      escape.
      [1913 Webster]

            I viewed in may mind, so far as I was able, the
            beginning and progress of a rising world. --T.
                                                  Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is very much in Sir Roger's esteem, so that he
            lives in the family rather as a relation than
            dependent.                            --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Very; in a high degree; that is, in such a degree as can
      not well be expressed; as, he is so good; he planned so
      wisely.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. In the same manner; as has been stated or suggested; in
      this or that condition or state; under these
      circumstances; in this way; -- with reflex reference to
      something just asserted or implied; used also with the
      verb to be, as a predicate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Use him [your tutor] with great respect yourself,
            and cause all your family to do so too. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            It concerns every man, with the greatest
            seriousness, to inquire into those matters, whether
            they be so or not.                    --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is Sir Robert's son, and so art thou. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The case being such; therefore; on this account; for this
      reason; on these terms; -- used both as an adverb and a
      conjuction.
      [1913 Webster]

            God makes him in his own image an intellectual
            creature, and so capable of dominion. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here, then, exchange we mutually forgiveness;
            So may the guilt of all my broken vows,
            My perjuries to thee, be all forgotten. --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. It is well; let it be as it is, or let it come to pass; --
      used to express assent.
      [1913 Webster]

            And when 't is writ, for my sake read it over,
            And if it please you, so; if not, why, so. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is Percy; if your father will do me any honor,
            so; if not, let him kill the next Percy himself.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Well; the fact being as stated; -- used as an expletive;
      as, so the work is done, is it?
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Is it thus? do you mean what you say? -- with an upward
      tone; as, do you say he refuses? So? [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   10. About the number, time, or quantity specified;
       thereabouts; more or less; as, I will spend a week or so
       in the country; I have read only a page or so.
       [1913 Webster]

             A week or so will probably reconcile us. --Gay.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: See the Note under {Ill}, adv.
         [1913 Webster]

   {So} . . . {as}. So is now commonly used as a demonstrative
      correlative of as when it is the puprpose to emphasize the
      equality or comparison suggested, esp. in negative
      assertions, and questions implying a negative answer. By
      Shakespeare and others so . . . as was much used where as
      . . . as is now common. See the Note under {As}, 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            So do, as thou hast said.             --Gen. xviii.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

            As a flower of the field, so he flourisheth. --Ps.
                                                  ciii. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

            Had woman been so strong as men.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            No country suffered so much as England. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   {So far}, to that point or extent; in that particular. ``The
      song was moral, and so far was right.'' --Cowper.

   {So far forth}, as far; to such a degree. --Shak. --Bacon.

   {So forth}, further in the same or similar manner; more of
      the same or a similar kind. See {And so forth}, under
      {And}.

   {So, so}, well, well. ``So, so, it works; now, mistress, sit
      you fast.'' --Dryden. Also, moderately or tolerably well;
      passably; as, he succeeded but so so. ``His leg is but so
      so.'' --Shak.

   {So that}, to the end that; in order that; with the effect or
      result that.

   {So then}, thus then it is; therefore; the consequence is.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soso</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>So-so \So"-so`\, adv.
   Tolerably; passably. --H. James.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soso</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>So-so \So"-so`\, a. [So + so.]
   Neither very good nor very bad; middling; passable;
   tolerable; indifferent.
   [1913 Webster]

         In some Irish houses, where things are so-so,
         One gammon of bacon hangs up for a show. --Goldsmith.
   [1913 Webster]

         He [Burns] certainly wrote some so-so verses to the
         Tree of Liberty.                         --Prof.
                                                  Wilson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>soso</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>so-so
     adj : neither good nor bad; "an indifferent performance"; "a
           gifted painter but an indifferent actor"; "her work at
           the office is passable"; "a so-so golfer"; "feeling
           only so-so"; "prepared a tolerable dinner"; "a
           tolerable working knowledge of French" [syn: {indifferent},
            {passable}, {so-so(p)}, {tolerable}]
     adv : in an acceptable (but not outstanding) manner; "she plays
           tennis tolerably" [syn: {acceptably}, {tolerably}]
           [ant: {unacceptably}, {unacceptably}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
