<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>source</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>source</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>source
     
        {source code}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>source</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Source \Source\, n. [OE. sours, OF. sourse, surse, sorse, F.
   source, fr. OF. sors, p. p. of OF. sordre, surdre, sourdre,
   to spring forth or up, F. sourdre, fr. L. surgere to lift or
   raise up, to spring up. See {Surge}, and cf. {Souse} to
   plunge or swoop as a bird upon its prey.]
   1. The act of rising; a rise; an ascent. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore right as an hawk upon a sours
            Up springeth into the air, right so prayers . . .
            Maken their sours to Goddes ears two. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The rising from the ground, or beginning, of a stream of
      water or the like; a spring; a fountain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where as the Poo out of a welle small
            Taketh his firste springing and his sours.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Kings that rule
            Behind the hidden sources of the Nile. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That from which anything comes forth, regarded as its
      cause or origin; the person from whom anything originates;
      first cause.
      [1913 Webster]

            This source of ideas every man has wholly in
            himself.                              --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            The source of Newton's light, of Bacon's sense.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See {Origin}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>source</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>source n. [very common] In reference to software, `source' is
   invariably shorthand for `source code', the preferred human-readable and
   human-modifiable form of the program. This is as opposed to object code,
   the derived binary executable form of a program. This shorthand readily
   takes derivative forms; one may speak of "the sources of a system" or of
   "having source".


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>source</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>source
     n 1: the place where something begins, where it springs into
          being; "the Italian beginning of the Renaissance";
          "Jupiter was the origin of the radiation"; "Pittsburgh
          is the source of the Ohio River"; "communism's Russian
          root" [syn: {beginning}, {origin}, {root}, {rootage}]
     2: a person who supplies information [syn: {informant}]
     3: a publication (or a passage from a publication) that is
        referred to; "he carried an armful of references back to
        his desk"; "he spent hours looking for the source of that
        quotation" [syn: {reference}]
     4: a document (or organization) from which information is
        obtained; "the reporter had two sources for the story"
     5: a facility where something is available
     6: anything that provides inspiration for later work [syn: {seed},
         {germ}]
     7: someone who originates or causes or initiates something; "he
        was the generator of several complaints" [syn: {generator},
         {author}]
     8: (technology) a process by which energy or a substance enters
        a system; "a heat source"; "a source of carbon dioxide"
        [ant: {sink}]
     9: anything (a person or animal or plant or substance) in which
        an infectious agent normally lives and multiplies; "an
        infectious agent depends on a reservoir for its survival"
        [syn: {reservoir}]
     v 1: get (a product) from another country or business; "She
          sourced a supply of carpet"; "They are sourcing from
          smaller companies"
     2: specify the origin of; "The writer carefully sourced her
        report"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
