<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>space</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>space</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>space
     
        &lt;character&gt; The space character, {ASCII} 32.
     
        See {octal forty}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>space</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Space \Space\ (sp[=a]s), n. [OE. space, F. espace, from L.
   spatium space; cf. Gr. spa^n to draw, to tear; perh. akin to
   E. span. Cf. {Expatiate}.]
   1. Extension, considered independently of anything which it
      may contain; that which makes extended objects conceivable
      and possible.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pure space is capable neither of resistance nor
            motion.                               --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Place, having more or less extension; room.
      [1913 Webster]

            They gave him chase, and hunted him as hare;
            Long had he no space to dwell [in].   --R. of
                                                  Brunne.
      [1913 Webster]

            While I have time and space.          --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A quantity or portion of extension; distance from one
      thing to another; an interval between any two or more
      objects; as, the space between two stars or two hills; the
      sound was heard for the space of a mile.
      [1913 Webster]

            Put a space betwixt drove and drove.  --Gen. xxxii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Quantity of time; an interval between two points of time;
      duration; time. ``Grace God gave him here, this land to
      keep long space.'' --R. of brunne.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nine times the space that measures day and night.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            God may defer his judgments for a time, and give a
            people a longer space of repentance.  --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A short time; a while. [R.] ``To stay your deadly strife a
      space.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Walk; track; path; course. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This ilke [same] monk let old things pace,
            And held after the new world the space. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Print.)
      (a) A small piece of metal cast lower than a face type, so
          as not to receive the ink in printing, -- used to
          separate words or letters.
      (b) The distance or interval between words or letters in
          the lines, or between lines, as in books, on a
          computer screen, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Spaces are of different thicknesses to enable the
         compositor to arrange the words at equal distances from
         each other in the same line.
         [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mus.) One of the intervals, or open places, between the
      lines of the staff.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. that portion of the universe outside the earth or its
      atmosphere; -- called also {outer space}.
      [PJC]

   {Absolute space}, {Euclidian space}, etc. See under
      {Absolute}, {Euclidian}, etc.

   {deep space}, the part of outer space which is beyond the
      limits of the solar system.

   {Space line} (Print.), a thin piece of metal used by printers
      to open the lines of type to a regular distance from each
      other, and for other purposes; a lead. --Hansard.

   {Space rule} (Print.), a fine, thin, short metal rule of the
      same height as the type, used in printing short lines in
      tabular matter.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>space</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Space \Space\, v. i. [Cf. OF. espacier, L. spatiari. See
   {Space}, n.]
   To walk; to rove; to roam. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         And loved in forests wild to space.      --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>space</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Space \Space\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Spaced}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Spacong}.] [Cf. F. espacer. See {Space}, n.] (Print.)
   To arrange or adjust the spaces in or between; as, to space
   words, lines, or letters.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>space</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>space
     n 1: the unlimited expanse in which everything is located; "they
          tested his ability to locate objects in space"
     2: an empty area (usually bounded in some way between things);
        "the architect left space in front of the building"; "they
        stopped at an open space in the jungle"; "the space
        between his teeth"
     3: an area reserved for some particular purpose; "the
        laboratory's floor space"
     4: a blank character used to separate successive words in
        writing or printing; "he said the space is the most
        important character in the alphabet" [syn: {blank}]
     5: the interval between two times; "the distance from birth to
        death"; "it all happened in the space of 10 minutes" [syn:
         {distance}]
     6: a blank area; "write your name in the space provided" [syn:
        {blank space}, {place}]
     7: one of the areas between or below or above the lines of a
        musical staff; "the spaces are the notes F-A-C-E"
     8: (printing) a block of type without a raised letter; used for
        spacing between words [syn: {quad}]
     v : place at intervals; "Space the interviews so that you have
         some time between the different candidates"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
