<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>specific</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>specific</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Specific \Spe*cif"ic\, n.
   1. (Med.) A specific remedy. See {Specific}, a., 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            His parents were weak enough to believe that the
            royal touch was a specific for this malady.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything having peculiar adaption to the purpose to which
      it is applied. --Dr. H. More.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>specific</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>specific \spe*cif"ic\ (sp[-e]*s[i^]f"[i^]k), a. [F.
   sp['e]cifique, or NL. spesificus; L. species a particular
   sort or kind + facere to make. Cf. {specify}.]
   1. Of or pertaining to a species; characterizing or
      constituting a species; possessing the peculiar property
      or properties of a thing which constitute its species, and
      distinguish it from other things; as, the specific form of
      an animal or a plant; the specific qualities of a drug;
      the specific distinction between virtue and vice.
      [1913 Webster]

            Specific difference is that primary attribute which
            distinguishes each species from one another. --I.
                                                  Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifying; definite, or making definite; limited;
      precise; discriminating; as, a specific statement.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Med.) Exerting a peculiar influence over any part of the
      body; preventing or curing disease by a peculiar
      adaptation, and not on general principles; as, quinine is
      a specific medicine in cases of malaria.
      [1913 Webster]

            In fact, all medicines will be found specific in the
            perfection of the science.            --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Specific character} (Nat. Hist.), a characteristic or
      characteristics distinguishing one species from every
      other species of the same genus.

   {Specific disease} (Med.)
      (a) A disease which produces a determinate definite effect
          upon the blood and tissues or upon some special
          tissue.
      (b) A disease which is itself uniformly produced by a
          definite and peculiar poison or organism.

   {Specific duty}. (Com.) See under {Duty}.

   {Specific gravity}. (Physics) See under {Gravity}.

   {Specific heat} (Physics), the quantity of heat required to
      raise the temperature of a body one degree, taking as the
      unit of measure the quantity required to raise the same
      weight of water from zero to one degree; thus, the
      specific heat of mercury is 0.033, that of water being
      1.000.

   {Specific inductive capacity} (Physics), the effect of a
      dielectric body in producing static electric induction as
      compared with that of some other body or bodies referred
      to as a standard.

   {Specific legacy} (Law), a bequest of a particular thing, as
      of a particular animal or piece of furniture, specified
      and distinguished from all others. --Wharton. --Burrill.

   {Specific name} (Nat. Hist.), the name which, appended to the
      name of the genus, constitutes the distinctive name of the
      species; -- originally applied by Linn[ae]us to the
      essential character of the species, or the essential
      difference. The present specific name he at first called
      the {trivial name}.

   {Specific performance} (Law), the peformance of a contract or
      agreement as decreed by a court of equity.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>specific</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>specific
     adj 1: (sometimes followed by `to') applying to or characterized by
            or distinguishing something particular or special or
            unique; "rules with specific application"; "demands
            specific to the job"; "a specific and detailed account
            of the accident" [ant: {general}, {nonspecific}]
     2: stated explicitly or in detail; "needed a specific amount"
     3: relating to or distinguishing or constituting a taxonomic
        species; "specific characters"
     4: being or affecting a disease produced by a particular
        microorganism or condition; used also of stains or dyes
        used in making microscope slides; "quinine is highly
        specific for malaria"; "a specific remedy"; "a specific
        stain is one having a specific affinity for particular
        structural elements" [ant: {nonspecific}]
     n 1: a fact about some part (as opposed to general); "he always
          reasons from the particular to the general" [syn: {particular}]
          [ant: {general}, {general}]
     2: a medicine that has a mitigating effect on a specific
        disease; "quinine is a specific for malaria"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
