<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>special</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>special</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>SPECIAL
     
        A SRI specification language.  [HDM?]
     
        ["SPECIAL - A Specification and Assertion Language",
        L. Robinson et al, TR CSL-46, SRI, Jan 1987].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>special</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Special \Spe"cial\, a. [L. specialis, fr. species a particular
   sort, kind, or quality: cf. F. sp['e]cial. See {Species}, and
   cf. {Especial}.]
   1. Of or pertaining to a species; constituting a species or
      sort.
      [1913 Webster]

            A special is called by the schools a ``species''.
                                                  --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Particular; peculiar; different from others;
      extraordinary; uncommon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our Savior is represented everywhere in Scripture as
            the special patron of the poor and the afficted.
                                                  --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

            To this special evil an improvement of style would
            apply a special redress.              --De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Appropriate; designed for a particular purpose, occasion,
      or person; as, a special act of Parliament or of Congress;
      a special sermon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Limited in range; confined to a definite field of action,
      investigation, or discussion; as, a special dictionary of
      commercial terms; a special branch of study.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Chief in excellence. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The king hath drawn
            The special head of all the land together. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Special administration} (Law), an administration limited to
      certain specified effects or acts, or one granted during a
      particular time or the existence of a special cause, as
      during a controversy respecting the probate of a will, or
      the right of administration, etc.

   {Special agency}, an agency confined to some particular
      matter.

   {Special bail}, {Bail above}, or {Bail to the action} (Law),
      sureties who undertake that, if the defendant is
      convicted, he shall satisfy the plaintiff, or surrender
      himself into custody. --Tomlins. --Wharton (Law Dict.).

   {Special constable}. See under {Constable}. --Bouvier.

   {Special damage} (Law), a damage resulting from the act
      complained of, as a natural, but not the necessary,
      consequence of it.

   {Special demurrer} (Law), a demurrer for some defect of form
      in the opposite party pleading, in which the cause of
      demurrer is particularly stated.

   {Special deposit}, a deposit made of a specific thing to be
      kept distinct from others.

   {Special homology}. (Biol.) See under {Homology}.

   {Special injuction} (Law), an injuction granted on special
      grounds, arising of the circumstances of the case.
      --Daniell.

   {Special issue} (Law), an issue produced upon a special plea.
      --Stephen.

   {Special jury} (Law), a jury consisting of persons of some
      particular calling, station, or qualification, which is
      called upon motion of either party when the cause is
      supposed to require it; a struck jury.

   {Special orders} (Mil.), orders which do not concern, and are
      not published to, the whole command, such as those
      relating to the movement of a particular corps, a detail,
      a temporary camp, etc.

   {Special partner}, a limited partner; a partner with a
      limited or restricted responsibility; -- unknown at common
      law.

   {Special partnership}, a limited or particular partnership;
      -- a term sometimes applied to a partnership in a
      particular business, operation, or adventure.

   {Special plea in bar} (Law), a plea setting forth particular
      and new matter, distinguished from the general issue.
      --Bouvier.

   {Special pleader} (Law), originally, a counsel who devoted
      himself to drawing special counts and pleas; in a wider
      sense, a lawyer who draws pleadings.

   {Special pleading} (Law), the allegation of special or new
      matter, as distingiushed from a direct denial of matter
      previously alleged on the side. --Bouvier. The popular
      denomination of the whole science of pleading. --Stephen.
      The phrase is sometimes popularly applied to the specious,
      but unsound, argumentation of one whose aim is victory,
      and not truth. --Burrill.

   {Special property} (Law), a qualified or limited ownership
      possession, as in wild animals, things found or bailed.

   {Special session}, an extraordinary session; a session at an
      unusual time or for an unusual purpose; as, a special
      session of Congress or of a legislature.

   {Special statute}, or {Special law}, an act of the
      legislature which has reference to a particular person,
      place, or interest; a {private law}; -- in distinction
      from a {general law} or {public law}.

   {Special verdict} (Law), a special finding of the facts of
      the case, leaving to the court the application of the law
      to them. --Wharton (Law Dict.).
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Peculiar; appropriate; specific; dictinctive;
        particular; exceptional; singular. See {Peculiar}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>special</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Special \Spe"cial\, n.
   1. A particular. [Obs.] --Hammond.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One appointed for a special service or occasion.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In special}, specially; in particular. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>special</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>special
     adj 1: unique or specific to a person or thing or category; "the
            particular demands of the job"; "has a paraticular
            preference for Chinese art"; "a peculiar bond of
            sympathy between them"; "an expression peculiar to
            Canadians"; "rights peculiar to the rich"; "the
            special features of a computer"; "my own special
            chair" [syn: {particular(a)}, {peculiar(a)}, {special(a)}]
     2: for a special service or occasion; "a special
        correspondent"; "a special adviser to the committee"; "had
        to get special permission for the event"
     3: surpassing what is common or usual or expected; "he paid
        especial attention to her"; "exceptional kindness"; "a
        matter of particular and unusual importance"; "a special
        occasion"; "a special reason to confide in her"; "what's
        so special about the year 2000?" [syn: {especial(a)}, {exceptional},
         {particular(a)}]
     4: adapted to or reserved for a particular purpose; "a special
        kind of paint"; "a special medication for arthritis"
     5: having a specific function or scope; "a special (or
        specific) role in the mission" [syn: {limited}]
     6: first and most important; "his special interest is music";
        "she gets special (or particular) satisfaction from her
        volunteer work" [syn: {particular}]
     7: added to a regular schedule; "a special holiday flight";
        "put on special buses for the big game" [syn: {extra}]
     n 1: a special offering (usually temporary and at a reduced
          price) that is featured in advertising; "they are having
          a special on pork chops"
     2: a dish or meal given prominence in e.g. a restaurant
     3: a television production that features a particular person or
        work or topic; "the last of a series of BBC specials on
        Iran is being shown tonight"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
