<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>spell</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spell
     
        {incantation}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Spelled}or {Spelt}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Spelling}.] [OE. spellen, spellien, tell, relate, AS.
   spellian, fr. spell a saying, tale; akin to MHG. spellen to
   relate, Goth. spill?n.e {Spell} a tale. In sense 4 and those
   following, OE. spellen, perhaps originally a different word,
   and from or influenced by spell a splinter, from the use of a
   piece of wood to point to the letters in schools: cf. D.
   spellen to spell. Cf. {Spell} splinter.]
   1. To tell; to relate; to teach. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Might I that legend find,
            By fairies spelt in mystic rhymes.    --T. Warton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put under the influence of a spell; to affect by a
      spell; to bewitch; to fascinate; to charm. ``Spelled with
      words of power.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was much spelled with Eleanor Talbot. --Sir G.
                                                  Buck.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To constitute; to measure. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The Saxon heptarchy, when seven kings put together
            did spell but one in effect.          --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To tell or name in their proper order letters of, as a
      word; to write or print in order the letters of, esp. the
      proper letters; to form, as words, by correct orthography.
      [1913 Webster]

            The word ``satire'' ought to be spelled with i, and
            not with y.                           --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To discover by characters or marks; to read with
      difficulty; -- usually with out; as, to spell out the
      sense of an author; to spell out a verse in the Bible.
      [1913 Webster]

            To spell out a God in the works of creation.
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            To sit spelling and observing divine justice upon
            every accident.                       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, n.
   1. The relief of one person by another in any piece of work
      or watching; also, a turn at work which is carried on by
      one person or gang relieving another; as, a spell at the
      pumps; a spell at the masthead.
      [1913 Webster]

            A spell at the wheel is called a trick. --Ham. Nav.
                                                  Encyc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The time during which one person or gang works until
      relieved; hence, any relatively short period of time,
      whether a few hours, days, or weeks.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing new has happened in this quarter, except the
            setting in of a severe spell of cold weather.
                                                  --Washington.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One of two or more persons or gangs who work by spells.
      [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Their toil is so extreme that they can not endure it
            above four hours in a day, but are succeeded by
            spells.                               --Garew.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A gratuitous helping forward of another's work; as, a
      logging spell. [Local, U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, n. [OE. speld, AS. speld a spill to light a
   candle with; akin to D. speld a pin, OD. spelle, G. spalten
   to split, OHG. spaltan, MHG. spelte a splinter, Icel. spjald
   a square tablet, Goth. spilda a writing tablet. Cf.
   {Spill}splinter, roll of paper, {Spell} to tell the letters
   of.]
   A spelk, or splinter. [Obs.] --Holland.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, n.[AS. spell a saying, tale, speech; akin to OS.
   &amp; OHG. spel, Icel. spjall,Goth. spill. Cf. {Gospel}, {Spell}
   to tell the letters of.]
   1. A story; a tale. [Obs.] ``Hearken to my spell.''
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A stanza, verse, or phrase supposed to be endowed with
      magical power; an incantation; hence, any charm.
      [1913 Webster]

            Start not; her actions shall be holy as
            You hear my spell is lawful.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Spelled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Spelling}.] [AS. spelian to supply another's place.]
   To supply the place of for a time; to take the turn of, at
   work; to relieve; as, to spell the helmsman.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, v. i.
   1. To form words with letters, esp. with the proper letters,
      either orally or in writing.
      [1913 Webster]

            When what small knowledge was, in them did dwell,
            And he a god, who could but read or spell. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To study by noting characters; to gain knowledge or learn
      the meaning of anything, by study. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Where I may sit and rightly spell
            Of every star that heaven doth shew,
            And every herb that sips the dew.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spell n. Syn. {incantation}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spell
     n 1: a psychological state induced by (or as if induced by) a
          magical incantation [syn: {enchantment}, {trance}]
     2: a time for working (after which you will be relieved by
        someone else); "it's my go"; "a spell of work" [syn: {go},
         {tour}, {turn}]
     3: a period of indeterminate length (usually short) marked by
        some action or condition; "he was here for a little
        while"; "I need to rest for a piece"; "a spell of good
        weather"; "a patch of bad weather" [syn: {while}, {piece},
         {patch}]
     4: a verbal formula believed to have magical force; "he
        whispered a spell as he moved his hands"; "inscribed
        around its base is a charm in Balinese" [syn: {magic spell},
         {charm}]
     v 1: recite the letters of or give the spelling of; "How do you
          spell this word?"
     2: indicate or signify; "I'm afraid this spells trouble!" [syn:
         {import}]
     3: write or name the letters that comprise the conventionally
        accepted form of (a word or part of a word); "He spelled
        the word wrong in this letter" [syn: {write}]
     4: place under a spell [ant: {unspell}]
     [also: {spelt}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
