<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>spelled</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spelled</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Spelled}or {Spelt}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Spelling}.] [OE. spellen, spellien, tell, relate, AS.
   spellian, fr. spell a saying, tale; akin to MHG. spellen to
   relate, Goth. spill?n.e {Spell} a tale. In sense 4 and those
   following, OE. spellen, perhaps originally a different word,
   and from or influenced by spell a splinter, from the use of a
   piece of wood to point to the letters in schools: cf. D.
   spellen to spell. Cf. {Spell} splinter.]
   1. To tell; to relate; to teach. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Might I that legend find,
            By fairies spelt in mystic rhymes.    --T. Warton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put under the influence of a spell; to affect by a
      spell; to bewitch; to fascinate; to charm. ``Spelled with
      words of power.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was much spelled with Eleanor Talbot. --Sir G.
                                                  Buck.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To constitute; to measure. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The Saxon heptarchy, when seven kings put together
            did spell but one in effect.          --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To tell or name in their proper order letters of, as a
      word; to write or print in order the letters of, esp. the
      proper letters; to form, as words, by correct orthography.
      [1913 Webster]

            The word ``satire'' ought to be spelled with i, and
            not with y.                           --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To discover by characters or marks; to read with
      difficulty; -- usually with out; as, to spell out the
      sense of an author; to spell out a verse in the Bible.
      [1913 Webster]

            To spell out a God in the works of creation.
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            To sit spelling and observing divine justice upon
            every accident.                       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spelled</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spell \Spell\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Spelled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Spelling}.] [AS. spelian to supply another's place.]
   To supply the place of for a time; to take the turn of, at
   work; to relieve; as, to spell the helmsman.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
