<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>spider</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spider
   The trust of the hypocrite is compared to the spider's web or
   house (Job 8:14). It is said of the wicked by Isaiah that they
   "weave the spider's web" (59:5), i.e., their works and designs
   are, like the spider's web, vain and useless. The Hebrew word
   here used is _'akkabish_, "a swift weaver."
   
     In Prov. 30:28 a different Hebrew word (semamith) is used. It
   is rendered in the Vulgate by stellio, and in the Revised
   Version by "lizard." It may, however, represent the spider, of
   which there are, it is said, about seven hundred species in
   Palestine.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spider
     
        &lt;World-Wide Web&gt; (Or "robot", "crawler") A program that
        automatically explores the {World-Wide Web} by retrieving a
        document and recursively retrieving some or all the documents
        that are referenced in it.  This is in contrast with a normal
        {web browser} operated by a human that doesn't automatically
        follow links other than {inline images} and {URL redirection}.
     
        The {algorithm} used to pick which references to follow
        strongly depends on the program's purpose.  {Index}-building
        spiders usually retrieve a significant proportion of the
        references.  The other extreme is spiders that try to validate
        the references in a set of documents; these usually do not
        retrieve any of the links apart from redirections.
     
        The {standard for robot exclusion} is designed to avoid some
        problems with spiders.
     
        Early examples were {Lycos} and {WebCrawler}.
     
        {Home
        (http://info.webcrawler.com/mak/projects/robots/robots.html)}.
     
        (2001-04-30)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spider \Spi"der\, n.[OE. spi[thorn]re, fr. AS. spinnan to spin;
   -- so named from spinning its web; cf. D. spin a spider, G.
   spinne, Sw. spindel. See {Spin}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) Any one of numerous species of arachnids
      comprising the order Araneina. Spiders have the mandibles
      converted into poison fangs, or falcers. The abdomen is
      large and not segmented, with two or three pairs of
      spinnerets near the end, by means of which they spin
      threads of silk to form cocoons, or nests, to protect
      their eggs and young. Many species spin also complex webs
      to entrap the insects upon which they prey. The eyes are
      usually eight in number (rarely six), and are situated on
      the back of the cephalothorax. See Illust. under
      {Araneina}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Spiders are divided into two principal groups: the
         Dipneumona, having two lungs: and the Tetrapneumona,
         having four lungs. See {Mygale}. The former group
         includes several tribes; as, the jumping spiders (see
         {Saltigrad[ae]}), the wolf spiders, or {Citigrad[ae]}
         (see under {Wolf}), the crab spiders, or
         {Laterigrad[ae]} (see under {Crab}), the garden, or
         geometric, spiders, or {Orbitell[ae]} (see under
         {Geometrical}, and {Garden}), and others. See {Bird
         spider}, under {Bird}, {Grass spider}, under {Grass},
         {House spider}, under {House}, {Silk spider}, under
         {Silk}.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Zo["o]l.) Any one of various other arachnids resembling
      the true spiders, especially certain mites, as the red
      spider (see under {Red}).
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An iron pan with a long handle, used as a kitchen utensil
      in frying food. Originally, it had long legs, and was used
      over coals on the hearth.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A trevet to support pans or pots over a fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mach.) A skeleton, or frame, having radiating arms or
      members, often connected by crosspieces; as, a casting
      forming the hub and spokes to which the rim of a fly wheel
      or large gear is bolted; the body of a piston head; a
      frame for strengthening a core or mold for a casting, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Spider ant}. (Zo["o]l.) Same as {Solitary ant}, under
      {Solitary}.

   {Spider crab} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      maioid crabs having a more or less triangular body and ten
      long legs. Some of the species grow to great size, as the
      great Japanese spider crab ({Macrocheira Kempferi}),
      measuring sometimes more than fifteen feet across the legs
      when they are extended.

   {Spider fly} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      parasitic dipterous insects of the family
      {Hippoboscid[ae]}. They are mostly destitute of wings, and
      live among the feathers of birds and the hair of bats.
      Called also {bird tick}, and {bat tick}.

   {Spider hunter} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      East Indian sunbirds of the genus {Arachnothera}.

   {Spider lines}, filaments of a spider's web crossing the
      field of vision in optical instruments; -- used for
      determining the exact position of objects and making
      delicate measurements. Fine wires, silk fibers, or lines
      on glass similarly placed, are called spider lines.

   {Spider mite}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any one of several species of parasitic mites of the
          genus {Argas} and allied genera. See {Argas}.
      (b) Any one of numerous small mites injurious to plants.
          

   {Spider monkey} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      South American monkeys of the genus {Ateles}, having very
      long legs and a long prehensile tail.

   {Spider orchis} (Bot.), a European orchidaceous plant
      ({Ophrys aranifera}), having flowers which resemble
      spiders.

   {Spider shell} (Zo["o]l.), any shell of the genus
      {Pteroceras}. See {Pteroceras}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spider The Web-walking part of a search engine that collects pages for
   indexing in the search engine's database. Also called a {bot}. The
   best-known spider is Scooter, the web-walker for the Alta Vista search
   engine.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spider
     n 1: predatory arachnid that usually has silk-spinning organs at
          the back end of the body; they spin silk to make cocoons
          for eggs or traps for prey
     2: a computer program that prowls the internet looking for
        publicly accessible resources that can be added to a
        database; the database can then be searched with a search
        engine [syn: {wanderer}]
     3: a skillet made of cast iron
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
