<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>spoiler</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spoiler</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spoiler
     
        1. A remark which reveals important plot elements
        from books or movies, thus denying the reader (of the article)
        the proper suspense when reading the book or watching the
        movie.
     
        2. Any remark which telegraphs the solution of a problem or
        puzzle, thus denying the reader the pleasure of working out
        the correct answer (see also {interesting}).  Either sense
        readily forms compounds like "total spoiler", "quasi-spoiler"
        and even "pseudo-spoiler".
     
        By convention, {Usenet} news articles which are spoilers in
        either sense should contain the word "spoiler" in the Subject:
        line, or guarantee via various tricks that the answer appears
        only after several screens-full of warning, or conceal the
        sensitive information via {rot13}, or some combination of
        these techniques.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-01-18)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spoiler</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spoiler \Spoil"er\ (spoil"[~e]r), n.
   1. One who spoils; a plunderer; a pillager; a robber; a
      despoiler.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who corrupts, mars, or renders useless.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Aeronautics) A device attached to the wing of an airplane
      or other airfoil, which breaks the smooth flow of air
      during flight and decreases the lift of the airfoil; --
      used to control the attitude of the airplane during
      banking or descent.
      [PJC]

   4. A device attached to a car to decrease lift and increase
      traction, usually shaped as a flat surface and attached
      above the rear of the car, and working on the same
      principal as the aircraft spoiler[3].
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spoiler</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spoiler n. [Usenet] 1. A remark which reveals important plot elements
   from books or movies, thus denying the reader (of the article) the
   proper suspense when reading the book or watching the movie. 2. Any
   remark which telegraphs the solution of a problem or puzzle, thus
   denying the reader the pleasure of working out the correct answer (see
   also {interesting}). Either sense readily forms compounds like `total
   spoiler', `quasi-spoiler' and even `pseudo-spoiler'.

   By convention, articles which are spoilers in either sense should
   contain the word `spoiler' in the Subject: line, or guarantee via
   various tricks that the answer appears only after several screens-full
   of warning, or conceal the sensitive information via {rot13}, {spoiler
   space} or some combination of these techniques.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spoiler</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spoiler
     n 1: a candidate with no chance of winning but who may draw
          enough votes to prevent one of the leading candidates
          from winning
     2: someone who takes spoils or plunder (as in war) [syn: {plunderer},
         {pillager}, {looter}, {despoiler}, {raider}, {freebooter}]
     3: someone who pampers or spoils by excessive indulgence [syn:
        {pamperer}, {coddler}, {mollycoddler}]
     4: an airfoil mounted on the rear of a car to reduce lift at
        high speeds
     5: a hinged airfoil on the upper surface of an aircraft wing
        that is raised to reduce lift and increase drag
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
