<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>spray</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spray, OR (town, FIPS 69450)
  Location: 44.83202 N, 119.79332 W
  Population (1990): 149 (84 housing units)
  Area: 0.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 97874
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spray \Spray\, n. [Probably from a Dutch or Low German form akin
   to E. spread. See {Spread}, v. t.]
   1. Water flying in small drops or particles, as by the force
      of wind, or the dashing of waves, or from a waterfall, and
      the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Med.)
      (a) A jet of fine medicated vapor, used either as an
          application to a diseased part or to charge the air of
          a room with a disinfectant or a deodorizer.
      (b) An instrument for applying such a spray; an atomizer.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Spray condenser} (Steam Engine), an injection condenser in
      which the steam is condensed by a spray of water which
      mingles with it.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spray \Spray\ (spr[=a]), n. [Cf. Dan. sprag. See {Sprig}.]
   1. A small shoot or branch; a twig. --Chaucer.

   Syn: sprig.
        [1913 Webster]

              The painted birds, companions of the spring,
              Hopping from spray to spray, were heard to sing.
                                                  --Dryden.
        [1913 Webster]

   2. A collective body of small branches, or cut flowers with
      long stems; as, the tree has a beautiful spray; many
      sprays were sent in condolence to teh funeral home.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            And from the trees did lop the needless spray.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Founding)
      (a) A side channel or branch of the runner of a flask,
          made to distribute the metal in all parts of the mold.
      (b) A group of castings made in the same mold and
          connected by sprues formed in the runner and its
          branches. --Knight.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Spray drain} (Agric.), a drain made by laying under earth
      the sprays or small branches of trees, which keep passages
      open.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spray \Spray\, v. t.
   1. To let fall in the form of spray. [Poetic] --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To throw spray upon; to treat with a liquid in the form of
      spray; as, to spray a wound, or a surgical instrument,
      with carbolic acid.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spray
     n 1: a pesticide in suspension or solution; intended for spraying
     2: a dispenser that turns a liquid (such as perfume) into a
        fine spray [syn: {atomizer}, {atomiser}, {sprayer}]
     3: a quantity of small objects flying through the air; "a spray
        of bullets" [syn: {spraying}]
     4: flower arrangement consisting of a single branch or shoot
        bearing flowers and foliage
     5: water in small drops in the atmosphere; blown from waves or
        thrown up by a waterfall
     6: a jet of vapor
     v 1: be discharged in sprays of liquid; "Water sprayed all over
          the floor"
     2: scatter in a mass or jet of droplets; "spray water on
        someone"; "spray paint on the wall"
     3: cover by spraying with a liquid; "spray the wall with paint"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
