<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>spreading</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spreading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spread \Spread\ (spr[e^]d), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Spread}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Spreading}.] [OE. spreden, AS. spr[ae]dan; akin to
   D. spreiden, spreijen, LG. spreden, spreen, spreien, G.
   spreiten, Dan. sprede, Sw. sprida. Cf. {Spray} water flying
   in drops.]
   1. To extend in length and breadth, or in breadth only; to
      stretch or expand to a broad or broader surface or extent;
      to open; to unfurl; as, to spread a carpet; to spread a
      tent or a sail.
      [1913 Webster]

            He bought a parcel of a field where he had spread
            his tent.                             --Gen. xxxiii.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here the Rhone
            Hath spread himself a couch.          --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To extend so as to cover something; to extend to a great
      or greater extent in every direction; to cause to fill or
      cover a wide or wider space.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rose, as in a dance, the stately trees, and spread
            Their branches hung with copious fruit. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To divulge; to publish, as news or fame; to cause to be
      more extensively known; to disseminate; to make known
      fully; as, to spread a report; -- often accompanied by
      abroad.
      [1913 Webster]

            They, when they were departed, spread abroad his
            fame in all that country.             --Matt. ix.
                                                  31.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To propagate; to cause to affect great numbers; as, to
      spread a disease.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To diffuse, as emanations or effluvia; to emit; as,
      odoriferous plants spread their fragrance.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To strew; to scatter over a surface; as, to spread manure;
      to spread lime on the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To prepare; to set and furnish with provisions; as, to
      spread a table.
      [1913 Webster]

            Boiled the flesh, and spread the board. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To spread cloth}, to unfurl sail. [Obs.] --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To diffuse; propagate; disperse; publish; distribute;
        scatter; circulate; disseminate; dispense.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>spreading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>spreading
     adj 1: spreading over a wide area; "under the spreading chestnut
            tree"; "the spreading circle of lamplight";
            "wide-spreading branches" [syn: {wide-spreading}]
     2: spreading by diffusion [syn: {diffusing(a)}, {diffusive}, {dispersive},
         {disseminative}, {disseminating}, {scattering}]
     n 1: process or result of distributing or extending over a wide
          expanse of space [syn: {spread}]
     2: the opening of a subject to widespread discussion and debate
        [syn: {dissemination}, {airing}, {public exposure}]
     3: act of extending over a wider scope or expanse of space or
        time [syn: {spread}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
