<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>square</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>square</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Square
     
        &lt;language&gt; A {query language}, a precursor to {SQL}.
     
        ["Specifying Queries as Relational Expressions: The SQUARE
        Data Sublanguage", R.E. Boyce et al, CACM 18(11):621-628 (Nov
        1975)].
     
        (1995-05-02)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>square</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Square \Square\ (skw[^a]r), n. [OF. esquarre, esquierre, F.
   ['e]querre a carpenter's square (cf. It. squadra), fr.
   (assumed) LL. exquadrare to make square; L. ex + quadrus a
   square, fr. quattuor four. See {Four}, and cf. {Quadrant},
   {Squad}, {Squire} a square.]
   1. (Geom.)
      (a) The corner, or angle, of a figure. [Obs.]
      (b) A parallelogram having four equal sides and four right
          angles.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, anything which is square, or nearly so; as:
      (a) A square piece or fragment.
          [1913 Webster]

                He bolted his food down his capacious throat in
                squares of three inches.          --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A pane of glass.
      (c) (Print.) A certain number of lines, forming a portion
          of a column, nearly square; -- used chiefly in
          reckoning the prices of advertisements in newspapers.
      (d) (Carp.) One hundred superficial feet.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. An area of four sides, generally with houses on each side;
      sometimes, a solid block of houses; also, an open place or
      area for public use, as at the meeting or intersection of
      two or more streets.
      [1913 Webster]

            The statue of Alexander VII. stands in the large
            square of the town.                   --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mech. &amp; Joinery) An instrument having at least one right
      angle and two or more straight edges, used to lay out or
      test square work. It is of several forms, as the T square,
      the carpenter's square, the try-square., etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, a pattern or rule. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Arith. &amp; Alg.) The product of a number or quantity
      multiplied by itself; thus, 64 is the square of 8, for 8
      [times] 8 = 64; the square of a + b is a^{2} + 2ab +
      b^{2}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Exact proportion; justness of workmanship and conduct;
      regularity; rule. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They of Galatia [were] much more out of square.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have not kept my square.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mil.) A body of troops formed in a square, esp. one
      formed to resist a charge of cavalry; a squadron. ``The
      brave squares of war.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Fig.: The relation of harmony, or exact agreement;
      equality; level.
      [1913 Webster]

            We live not on the square with such as these.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Astrol.) The position of planets distant ninety degrees
       from each other; a quadrate. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

   11. The act of squaring, or quarreling; a quarrel. [R.]
       [1913 Webster]

   12. The front of a woman's dress over the bosom, usually
       worked or embroidered. [Obs.] --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   {fair and square} in a fair, straightforward, and honest
      manner; justly; as, he beat me fair and square.

   {Geometrical square}. See {Quadrat}, n., 2.

   {Hollow square} (Mil.), a formation of troops in the shape of
      a square, each side consisting of four or five ranks, and
      the colors, officers, horses, etc., occupying the middle.
      

   {Least square}, {Magic square}, etc. See under {Least},
      {Magic}, etc.

   {On the square}, or {Upon the square},
       (a) in an open, fair manner; honestly, or upon honor;
           justly. [Obs or Colloq.]
       (b) at right angles.

   {On the square with}, or {Upon the square with}, upon
      equality with; even with. --Nares.

   {To be all squares}, to be all settled. [Colloq.] --Dickens.

   {To be at square}, to be in a state of quarreling. [Obs.]
      --Nares.

   {To break no squares}, to give no offense; to make no
      difference. [Obs.]

   {To break squares}, to depart from an accustomed order.
      [Obs.]

   {To see how the squares go}, to see how the game proceeds; --
      a phrase taken from the game of chess, the chessboard
      being formed with squares. [Obs.] --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>square</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Square \Square\ (skw[^a]r), a.
   1. (Geom.) Having four equal sides and four right angles; as,
      a square figure.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Forming a right angle; as, a square corner.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Having a shape broad for the height, with rectilineal and
      angular rather than curving outlines; as, a man of a
      square frame.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Exactly suitable or correspondent; true; just.
      [1913 Webster]

            She's a most triumphant lady, if report be square to
            her.                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Rendering equal justice; exact; fair; honest; as, square
      dealing.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Even; leaving no balance; as, to make or leave the
      accounts square.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Leaving nothing; hearty; vigorous.
      [1913 Webster]

            By Heaven, square eaters.
            More meat, I say.                     --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Naut.) At right angles with the mast or the keel, and
      parallel to the horizon; -- said of the yards of a
      square-rigged vessel when they are so braced.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Square is often used in self-explaining compounds or
         combinations, as in square-built, square-cornered,
         square-cut, square-nosed, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Square foot}, an area equal to that of a square the sides of
      which are twelve inches; 144 square inches.

   {Square knot}, a knot in which the terminal and standing
      parts are parallel to each other; a reef knot. See Illust.
      under {Knot}.

   {Square measure}, the measure of a superficies or surface
      which depends on the length and breadth taken conjointly.
      The units of square measure are squares whose sides are
      the linear measures; as, square inches, square feet,
      square meters, etc.

   {Square number}. See {Square}, n., 6.

   {Square root of a number} or {Square root of a quantity}
      (Math.), that number or quantity which, multiplied by
      itself, produces the given number or quantity.

   {Square sail} (Naut.), a four-sided sail extended upon a yard
      suspended by the middle; sometimes, the foresail of a
      schooner set upon a yard; also, a cutter's or sloop's sail
      boomed out. See Illust. of {Sail}.

   {Square stern} (Naut.), a stern having a transom and joining
      the counter timbers at an angle, as distinguished from a
      round stern, which has no transom.

   {Three-square}, {Five-square}, etc., having three, five,
      etc., equal sides; as, a three-square file.

   {To get square with}, to get even with; to pay off. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>square</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Square \Square\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Squared} (skw[^a]rd); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Squaring}.] [Cf. OF. escarrer, esquarrer. See
   {Square}, n.]
   1. To form with four equal sides and four right angles.
      --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form with right angles and straight lines, or flat
      surfaces; as, to square masons' work.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To compare with, or reduce to, any given measure or
      standard. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To adjust; to regulate; to mold; to shape; to fit; as, to
      square our actions by the opinions of others.
      [1913 Webster]

            Square my trial
            To my proportioned strength.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To make even, so as to leave no remainder or difference;
      to balance; as, to square accounts.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Math.) To multiply by itself; as, to square a number or a
      quantity.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Astrol.) To hold a quartile position respecting.
      [1913 Webster]

            The icy Goat and Crab that square the Scales.
                                                  --Creech.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Naut.) To place at right angles with the keel; as, to
      square the yards.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To square one's shoulders}, to raise the shoulders so as to
      give them a square appearance, -- a movement expressing
      contempt or dislike. --Sir W. Scott.

   {To square the circle} (Math.), to determine the exact
      contents of a circle in square measure. The solution of
      this famous problem is now generally admitted to be
      impossible.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>square</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Square \Square\, v. i.
   1. To accord or agree exactly; to be consistent with; to
      conform or agree; to suit; to fit.
      [1913 Webster]

            No works shall find acceptance . . .
            That square not truly with the Scripture plan.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To go to opposite sides; to take an attitude of offense or
      defense, or of defiance; to quarrel. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Are you such fools
            To square for this?                   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To take a boxing attitude; -- often with up, sometimes
      with off. [Colloq.] --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>square</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rhomb \Rhomb\ (r[o^]mb or r[o^]m; 277), n. [L. rhombus, Gr.
   "ro`mbos rhomb, a spinning top, magic wheel, fr. "re`mbein to
   turn or whirl round, perhaps akin to E. wrench: cf. F.
   rhombe. Cf. {Rhombus}, {Rhumb}.]
   1. (Geom.) An equilateral parallelogram, or quadrilateral
      figure whose sides are equal and the opposite sides
      parallel. The angles may be unequal, two being obtuse and
      two acute, as in the cut, or the angles may be equal, in
      which case it is usually called a {square}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geom.) A rhombohedron.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fresnel's rhomb} (Opt.), a rhomb or oblique parallelopiped
      of crown or St. Gobain glass so cut that a ray of light
      entering one of its faces at right angles shall emerge at
      right angles at the opposite face, after undergoing within
      the rhomb, at other faces, two reflections. It is used to
      produce a ray circularly polarized from a plane-polarized
      ray, or the reverse. --Nichol.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>square</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>square
     adj 1: having four equal sides and four right angles or forming a
            right angle; "a square peg in a round hole"; "a square
            corner" [ant: {round}]
     2: leaving no balance; "my account with you is now all square"
        [syn: {square(p)}]
     3: characterized by honesty and fairness; "a square deal";
        "wanted to do the square thing" [syn: {straight}]
     4: without evasion or compromise; "a square contradiction"; "he
        is not being as straightforward as it appears" [syn: {square(a)},
         {straightforward}]
     5: rigidly conventional or old-fashioned [syn: {straight}]
     n 1: (geometry) a plane rectangle with four equal sides and four
          right angles; a four-sided regular polygon; "you can
          compute the area of a square if you know the length of
          its sides" [syn: {foursquare}]
     2: the product of two equal terms; "nine is the second power of
        three"; "gravity is inversely proportional to the square
        of the distance" [syn: {second power}]
     3: an open area at the meeting of two or more streets [syn: {public
        square}]
     4: something approximating the shape of a square
     5: someone who doesn't understand what is going on [syn: {lame}]
     6: a formal and conservative person with old-fashioned views
        [syn: {square toes}]
     7: any artifact having a shape similar to a plane geometric
        figure with four equal sides and four right angles; "a
        checkerboard has 64 squares"
     8: a hand tool consisting of two straight arms at right angles;
        used to construct or test right angles; "the carpenter who
        built this room must have lost his square"
     adv 1: in a straight direct way; "looked him squarely in the eye";
            "ran square into me" [syn: {squarely}]
     2: with honesty and fairness; "dealt squarely with his
        customers"; "always treated me square" [syn: {squarely}]
     3: in a square shape; "a squarely cut piece of paper"; "folded
        the sheet of paper square" [syn: {squarely}]
     4: firmly and solidly; "hit the ball squarely"; "the bat met
        the ball squarely"; "planted his great bulk square before
        his enemy" [syn: {squarely}]
     v 1: raise to the second power
     2: make square; "Square the circle"; "square the wood with a
        file" [syn: {square up}]
     3: cause to match, as of ideas or acts
     4: position so as to be square; "He squared his shoulders"
     5: be compatible with; "one idea squares with another"
     6: pay someone and settle a debt; "I squared with him"
     7: turn the paddle; in canoeing [syn: {feather}]
     8: turn the oar, while rowing [syn: {feather}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
