<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stack</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stack
     
        &lt;programming&gt; (See below for synonyms) A data structure for
        storing items which are to be accessed in last-in first-out
        order.
     
        The operations on a stack are to create a new stack, to "push"
        a new item onto the top of a stack and to "pop" the top item
        off.  Error conditions are raised by attempts to pop an empty
        stack or to push an item onto a stack which has no room for
        further items (because of its implementation).
     
        Most processors include support for stacks in their
        {instruction set architecture}s.  Perhaps the most common use
        of stacks is to store subroutine arguments and return
        addresses.  This is usually supported at the {machine code}
        level either directly by "jump to subroutine" and "return from
        subroutine" instructions or by {auto-increment} and
        auto-decrement {addressing mode}s, or both.  These allow a
        contiguous area of memory to be set aside for use as a stack
        and use either a special-purpose {register} or a general
        purpose register, chosen by the user, as a {stack pointer}.
     
        The use of a stack allows subroutines to be {recursive} since
        each call can have its own calling context, represented by a
        stack frame or {activation record}.  There are many other
        uses.  The programming language {Forth} uses a data stack in
        place of variables when possible.
     
        Although a stack may be considered an {object} by users,
        implementations of the object and its access details differ.
        For example, a stack may be either ascending (top of stack is
        at highest address) or descending.  It may also be "full" (the
        stack pointer points at the top of stack) or "empty" (the
        stack pointer points just past the top of stack, where the
        next element would be pushed).  The full/empty terminology is
        used in the {Acorn Risc Machine} and possibly elsewhere.
     
        In a list-based or {functional language}, a stack might be
        implemented as a {linked list} where a new stack is an empty
        list, push adds a new element to the head of the list and pop
        splits the list into its head (the popped element) and tail
        (the stack in its modified form).
     
        At {MIT}, {pdl} used to be a more common synonym for stack,
        and this may still be true.  {Knuth} ("The Art of Computer
        Programming", second edition, vol. 1, p. 236) says:
     
          Many people who realised the importance of stacks and queues
          independently have given other names to these structures:
          stacks have been called push-down lists, reversion storages,
          cellars, dumps, nesting stores, piles, last-in first-out
          ("LIFO") lists, and even yo-yo lists!
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-04-10)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stack \Stack\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stacked} (st[a^]kt); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Stacking}.] [Cf. Sw. stacka, Dan. stakke. See
   {Stack}, n.]
   1. To lay in a conical or other pile; to make into a large
      pile; as, to stack hay, cornstalks, or grain; to stack or
      place wood.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically: To place in a vertical arrangement so that
      each item in a pile is resting on top of another item in
      the pile, except for the bottom item; as, to stack the
      papers neatly on the desk; to stack the bricks.
      [PJC]

   3. To select or arrange dishonestly so as to achieve an
      unfair advantage; as, to stack a deck of cards; to stack a
      jury with persons prejudiced against the defendant.
      [PJC]

   {To stack arms} (Mil.), to set up a number of muskets or
      rifles together, with the bayonets crossing one another,
      and forming a sort of conical pile.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stack \Stack\ (st[a^]k), n. [Icel. stakkr; akin to Sw. stack,
   Dan. stak. Cf. {Stake}.]
   1. A large and to some degree orderly pile of hay, grain,
      straw, or the like, usually of a nearly conical form, but
      sometimes rectangular or oblong, contracted at the top to
      a point or ridge, and sometimes covered with thatch.
      [1913 Webster]

            But corn was housed, and beans were in the stack.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: An orderly pile of any type of object, indefinite
      in quantity; -- used especially of piles of wood. A stack
      is usually more orderly than a {pile}
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Against every pillar was a stack of billets above a
            man's height.                         --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically: A pile of wood containing 108 cubic feet.
      [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence: A large quantity; as, a stack of cash. [Informal]
      [PJC]

   5. (Arch.)
      (a) A number of flues embodied in one structure, rising
          above the roof. Hence:
      (b) Any single insulated and prominent structure, or
          upright pipe, which affords a conduit for smoke; as,
          the brick smokestack of a factory; the smokestack of a
          steam vessel.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Computer programming)
      (a) A section of memory in a computer used for temporary
          storage of data, in which the last datum stored is the
          first retrieved.
      (b) A data structure within random-access memory used to
          simulate a hardware stack; as, a push-down stack.
          [PJC]

   7. pl. The section of a library containing shelves which hold
      books less frequently requested.
      [PJC]

   {Stack of arms} (Mil.), a number of muskets or rifles set up
      together, with the bayonets crossing one another, forming
      a sort of conical self-supporting pile.

   {to blow one's stacks} to become very angry and lose one's
      self-control, and especially to display one's fury by
      shouting.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stack n. The set of things a person has to do in the future. One speaks
   of the next project to be attacked as having risen to the top of the
   stack. "I'm afraid I've got real work to do, so this'll have to be
   pushed way down on my stack." "I haven't done it yet because every time
   I pop my stack something new gets pushed." If you are interrupted
   several times in the middle of a conversation, "My stack overflowed"
   means "I forget what we were talking about." The implication is that
   more items were pushed onto the stack than could be remembered, so the
   least recent items were lost. The usual physical example of a stack is
   to be found in a cafeteria: a pile of plates or trays sitting on a
   spring in a well, so that when you put one on the top they all sink
   down, and when you take one off the top the rest spring up a bit. See
   also {push} and {pop}.

   At MIT, {PDL} used to be a more common synonym for {stack} in all
   these contexts, and this may still be true. Everywhere else {stack}
   seems to be the preferred term. {Knuth} ("The Art of Computer
   Programming", second edition, vol. 1, p. 236) says:

     Many people who realized the importance of stacks and queues
  independently have given other names to these structures:
  stacks have been called push-down lists, reversion storages,
  cellars, nesting stores, piles, last-in-first-out ("LIFO")
  lists, and even yo-yo lists!
  

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stack
     n 1: an orderly pile
     2: (often followed by `of') a large number or amount or extent;
        "a batch of letters"; "a deal of trouble"; "a lot of
        money"; "he made a mint on the stock market"; "it must
        have cost plenty" [syn: {batch}, {deal}, {flock}, {good
        deal}, {great deal}, {hatful}, {heap}, {lot}, {mass}, {mess},
         {mickle}, {mint}, {muckle}, {peck}, {pile}, {plenty}, {pot},
         {quite a little}, {raft}, {sight}, {slew}, {spate}, {tidy
        sum}, {wad}, {whole lot}, {whole slew}]
     3: a list in which the next item to be removed is the item most
        recently stored (LIFO) [syn: {push-down list}, {push-down
        stack}]
     4: a large tall chimney through which combustion gases and
        smoke can be evacuated [syn: {smokestack}]
     5: a storage device that handles data so that the next item to
        be retrieved is the item most recently stored (LIFO) [syn:
         {push-down storage}, {push-down store}]
     v 1: load or cover with stacks; "stack a truck with boxes"
     2: arrange in stacks; "heap firewood around the fireplace";
        "stack your books up on the shelves" [syn: {pile}, {heap}]
     3: arrange the order of so as to increase one's winning
        chances; "stack the deck of cards"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
