<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stage</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stage \Stage\ (st[=a]j), v. t.
   To exhibit upon a stage, or as upon a stage; to display
   publicly. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stage \Stage\ (st[=a]j), n. [OF. estage, F. ['e]tage, (assumed)
   LL. staticum, from L. stare to stand. See {Stand}, and cf.
   {Static}.]
   1. A floor or story of a house. [Obs.] --Wyclif.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An elevated platform on which an orator may speak, a play
      be performed, an exhibition be presented, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A floor elevated for the convenience of mechanical work,
      or the like; a scaffold; a staging.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A platform, often floating, serving as a kind of wharf.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The floor for scenic performances; hence, the theater; the
      playhouse; hence, also, the profession of representing
      dramatic compositions; the drama, as acted or exhibited.
      [1913 Webster]

            Knights, squires, and steeds, must enter on the
            stage.                                --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lo! where the stage, the poor, degraded stage,
            Holds its warped mirror to a gaping age. --C.
                                                  Sprague.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A place where anything is publicly exhibited; the scene of
      any noted action or career; the spot where any remarkable
      affair occurs; as, politicians must live their lives on
      the public stage.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            When we are born, we cry that we are come
            To this great stage of fools.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Music and ethereal mirth
            Wherewith the stage of air and earth did ring.
                                                  --Miton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The platform of a microscope, upon which an object is
      placed to be viewed. See Illust. of {Microscope}.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A place of rest on a regularly traveled road; a stage
      house; a station; a place appointed for a relay of horses.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A degree of advancement in a journey; one of several
      portions into which a road or course is marked off; the
      distance between two places of rest on a road; as, a stage
      of ten miles.
      [1913 Webster]

            A stage . . . signifies a certain distance on a
            road.                                 --Jeffrey.
      [1913 Webster]

            He traveled by gig, with his wife, his favorite
            horse performing the journey by easy stages.
                                                  --Smiles.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A degree of advancement in any pursuit, or of progress
       toward an end or result.
       [1913 Webster]

             Such a polity is suited only to a particular stage
             in the progress of society.          --Macaulay.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A large vehicle running from station to station for the
       accommodation of the public; a stagecoach; an omnibus.
       ``A parcel sent you by the stage.'' --Cowper.
       [Obsolescent]
       [1913 Webster]

             I went in the sixpenny stage.        --Swift.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Biol.) One of several marked phases or periods in the
       development and growth of many animals and plants; as,
       the larval stage; pupa stage; z[oe]a stage.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Stage box}, a box close to the stage in a theater.

   {Stage carriage}, a stagecoach.

   {Stage door}, the actors' and workmen's entrance to a
      theater.

   {Stage lights}, the lights by which the stage in a theater is
      illuminated.

   {Stage micrometer}, a graduated device applied to the stage
      of a microscope for measuring the size of an object.

   {Stage wagon}, a wagon which runs between two places for
      conveying passengers or goods.

   {Stage whisper}, a loud whisper, as by an actor in a theater,
      supposed, for dramatic effect, to be unheard by one or
      more of his fellow actors, yet audible to the audience; an
      aside.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stage
     n 1: any distinct time period in a sequence of events; "we are in
          a transitional stage in which many former ideas must be
          revised or rejected" [syn: {phase}]
     2: a specific identifiable position in a continuum or series or
        especially in a process; "a remarkable degree of
        frankness"; "at what stage are the social sciences?" [syn:
         {degree}, {level}, {point}]
     3: a large platform on which people can stand and can be seen
        by an audience; "he clambered up onto the stage and got
        the actors to help him into the box"
     4: the theater as a profession (usually `the stage'); "an early
        movie simply showed a long kiss by two actors of the
        contemporary stage"
     5: any scene regarded as a setting for exhibiting or doing
        something; "All the world's a stage"--Shakespeare; "it set
        the stage for peaceful negotiations"
     6: a large coach-and-four formerly used to carry passengers and
        mail on regular routes between towns; "we went out of town
        together by stage about ten or twelve miles" [syn: {stagecoach}]
     7: a section or portion of a journey or course; "then we
        embarked on the second stage of our Caribbean cruise"
        [syn: {leg}]
     8: a small platform on a microscope where the specimen is
        mounted for examination [syn: {microscope stage}]
     v 1: perform (a play), especially on a stage; "we are going to
          stage `Othello'" [syn: {present}, {represent}]
     2: plan, organize, and carry out (an event) [syn: {bring about},
         {arrange}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
