<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stained</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stained</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stain \Stain\ (st[=a]n), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stained}
   (st[=a]nd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Staining}.] [Abbrev. fr.
   distain.]
   1. To discolor by the application of foreign matter; to make
      foul; to spot; as, to stain the hand with dye; armor
      stained with blood.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To color, as wood, glass, paper, cloth, or the like, by
      processes affecting, chemically or otherwise, the material
      itself; to tinge with a color or colors combining with, or
      penetrating, the substance; to dye; as, to stain wood with
      acids, colored washes, paint rubbed in, etc.; to stain
      glass.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To spot with guilt or infamy; to bring reproach on; to
      blot; to soil; to tarnish.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of honor void,
            Of innocence, of faith, of purity,
            Our wonted ornaments now soiled and stained.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cause to seem inferior or soiled by comparison.
      [1913 Webster]

            She stains the ripest virgins of her age. --Beau. &amp;
                                                  Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

            That did all other beasts in beauty stain.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Stained glass}, glass colored or stained by certain metallic
      pigments fused into its substance, -- often used for
      making ornamental windows.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To paint; dye; blot; soil; sully; discolor; disgrace;
        taint.

   Usage: {Paint}, {Stain}, {Dye}. These denote three different
          processes; the first mechanical, the other two,
          chiefly chemical. To paint a thing is to spread a coat
          of coloring matter over it; to stain or dye a thing is
          to impart color to its substance. To stain is said
          chiefly of solids, as wood, glass, paper; to dye, of
          fibrous substances, textile fabrics, etc.; the one,
          commonly, a simple process, as applying a wash; the
          other more complex, as fixing colors by mordants.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stained</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stained
     adj 1: marked or dyed or discolored with foreign matter; "a badly
            stained tablecloth"; "tear-stained cheeks" [ant: {unstained}]
     2: having a coating of stain or varnish [syn: {varnished}]
     3: especially of reputation; "the senator's seriously damaged
        reputation"; "a flyblown reputation"; "a tarnished
        reputation"; "inherited a spotted name" [syn: {besmirched},
         {damaged}, {flyblown}, {spotted}, {sullied}, {tainted}, {tarnished}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
