<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stake</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>@stake
     
        &lt;security, software&gt; A computer security development group and
        consultancy dedicated to researching and documenting security
        flaws that exist in {operating systems}, {network}
        {protocols}, or software.
     
        @stake publishes information about security flaws through
        advisories, research reports, and tools.  They release the
        information and tools to help system administrators, users,
        and software and hardware vendors better secure their
        systems.
     
        L0pht merged with @stake in January 2000.
     
        {@stake home (http://www.atstake.com/research/redirect.html)}.
     
        (2003-06-12)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stake \Stake\ (st[=a]k), n. [AS. staca, from the root of E.
   stick; akin to OFries. &amp; LG. stake, D. staak, Sw. stake, Dan.
   stage. See {Stick}, v. t., and cf. {Estacade}, {Stockade}.]
   1. A piece of wood, usually long and slender, pointed at one
      end so as to be easily driven into the ground as a support
      or stay; as, a stake to support vines, fences, hedges,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            A sharpened stake strong Dryas found. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A stick inserted upright in a loop, eye, or mortise, at
      the side or end of a cart, a flat car, or the like, to
      prevent goods from falling off.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The piece of timber to which a martyr was affixed to be
      burned; hence, martyrdom by fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A small anvil usually furnished with a tang to enter a
      hole in a bench top, -- used by tinsmiths, blacksmiths,
      etc., for light work, punching upon, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is laid down as a wager; that which is staked
      or hazarded; a pledge.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mormon Ch.) A territorial division; -- called also {stake
      of Zion}.

            Every city, or ``stake,'' including a chief town and
            surrounding towns, has its president, with two
            counselors; and this president has a high council of
            chosen men.                           --Schaff-Herzog
                                                  Encyc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {At stake}, in danger; hazarded; pledged. ``I see my
      reputation is at stake.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stake \Stake\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Staked} (st[=a]kd); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Staking}.]
   1. To fasten, support, or defend with stakes; as, to stake
      vines or plants.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mark the limits of by stakes; -- with out; as, to stake
      out land; to stake out a new road.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To put at hazard upon the issue of competition, or upon a
      future contingency; to wager; to pledge.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll stake yon lamb, that near the fountain plays.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To pierce or wound with a stake. --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stake
     n 1: (law) a right or legal share of something; a financial
          involvement with something; "they have interests all
          over the world"; "a stake in the company's future" [syn:
           {interest}]
     2: a pole or stake set up to mark something (as the start or
        end of a race track); "a pair of posts marked the goal";
        "the corner of the lot was indicated by a stake" [syn: {post}]
     3: instrument of execution consisting of a vertical post that a
        victim is tied to for burning
     4: the money risked on a gamble [syn: {stakes}, {bet}, {wager}]
     v 1: put at risk; "I will stake my good reputation for this"
          [syn: {venture}, {hazard}, {adventure}, {jeopardize}]
     2: place a bet on; "Which horse are you backing?"; "I'm betting
        on the new horse" [syn: {bet on}, {back}, {gage}, {game},
        {punt}]
     3: mark with a stake; "stake out the path" [syn: {post}]
     4: tie or fasten to a stake; "stake your goat"
     5: kill by piercing with a spear or sharp pole; "the enemies
        were impaled and left to die" [syn: {impale}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
