<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stall</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stall \Stall\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stalled} (st[add]ld); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Stalling}.] [Cf. Sw. stalla, Dan. stalde.]
   1. To put into a stall or stable; to keep in a stall or
      stalls; as, to stall an ox.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where King Latinus then his oxen stalled. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fatten; as, to stall cattle. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To place in an office with the customary formalities; to
      install. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To plunge into mire or snow so as not to be able to get
      on; to set; to fix; as, to stall a cart. --Burton.
      [1913 Webster]

            His horses had been stalled in the snow. --E. E.
                                                  Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To forestall; to anticipate. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This is not to be stall'd by my report. --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To keep close; to keep secret. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Stall this in your bosom.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stall \Stall\ (st[add]l), n. [OE. stal, AS. steall, stall, a
   place, seat, or station, a stable; akin to D. &amp; OHG. stal, G.
   &amp; Sw. stall, Icel. stallr, Dan. stald, originally, a standing
   place; akin also to G. stelle a place, stellen to place, Gr.
   ste`llein to set, place, send, and E. stand. [root]163. See
   {Stand}, and cf. {Apostle}, {Epistle}, {Forestall},
   {Install}, {Stale}, a. &amp; v. i., 1st {Stalk}, {Stallion},
   {Still}.]
   1. A stand; a station; a fixed spot; hence, the stand or
      place where a horse or an ox is kept and fed; the division
      of a stable, or the compartment, for one horse, ox, or
      other animal. ``In an oxes stall.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A stable; a place for cattle.
      [1913 Webster]

            At last he found a stall where oxen stood. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A small apartment or shed in which merchandise is exposed
      for sale; as, a butcher's stall; a bookstall.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A bench or table on which small articles of merchandise
      are exposed for sale.
      [1913 Webster]

            How peddlers' stalls with glittering toys are laid.
                                                  --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A seat in the choir of a church, for one of the
      officiating clergy. It is inclosed, either wholly or
      partially, at the back and sides. The stalls are
      frequently very rich, with canopies and elaborate carving.
      [1913 Webster]

            The dignified clergy, out of humility, have called
            their thrones by the names of stalls. --Bp.
                                                  Warburton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Loud the monks sang in their stalls.  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. In the theater, a seat with arms or otherwise partly
      inclosed, as distinguished from the benches, sofas, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining) The space left by excavation between pillars. See
      {Post and stall}, under {Post}.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A covering or sheath, as of leather, horn, of iron, for a
      finger or thumb; a cot; as, a thumb stall; a finger stall.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Stall reader}, one who reads books at a stall where they are
      exposed for sale.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cries the stall reader, ``Bless us! what a word on
            A titlepage is this!''                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stall \Stall\, v. i. [AS. steallian to have room. See {Stall},
   n.]
   1. To live in, or as in, a stall; to dwell. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We could not stall together
            In the whole world.                   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To kennel, as dogs. --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be set, as in mire or snow; to stick fast.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be tired of eating, as cattle. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stall
     n 1: a compartment in a stable where a single animal is confined
          and fed
     2: small area set off by walls for special use [syn: {booth}, {cubicle},
         {kiosk}]
     3: a booth where articles are displayed for sale [syn: {stand},
         {sales booth}]
     4: a malfunction in the flight of an aircraft in which there is
        a sudden loss of lift that results in a downward plunge;
        "the plane went into a stall and I couldn't control it"
     5: small individual study area in a library [syn: {carrel}, {carrell},
         {cubicle}]
     6: a tactic used to mislead or delay [syn: {stalling}]
     v 1: postpone doing what one should be doing; "He did not want to
          write the letter and procrastinated for days" [syn: {procrastinate},
           {drag one's feet}, {drag one's heels}, {shillyshally},
          {dilly-dally}, {dillydally}]
     2: come to a stop; "The car stalled in the driveway" [syn: {conk}]
     3: deliberately delay an event or action; "she doesn't want to
        write the report, so she is stalling"
     4: put into, or keep in, a stall; "Stall the horse"
     5: experience a stall in flight, of airplanes
     6: cause an airplane to go into a stall
     7: cause an engine to stop; "The inexperienced driver kept
        stalling the car"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
