<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stamp</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stamp \Stamp\, n.
   1. The act of stamping, as with the foot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The which stamps; any instrument for making impressions on
      other bodies, as a die.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is gold so pure
            It can not bear the stamp without alloy. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The mark made by stamping; a mark imprinted; an
      impression.
      [1913 Webster]

            That sacred name gives ornament and grace,
            And, like his stamp, makes basest metals pass.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is marked; a thing stamped.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hanging a golden stamp about their necks. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [F. estampe, of German origin. See {Stamp}, v. t.] A
      picture cut in wood or metal, or made by impression; a
      cut; a plate. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            At Venice they put out very curious stamps of the
            several edifices which are most famous for their
            beauty and magnificence.              --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An official mark set upon things chargeable with a duty or
      tax to government, as evidence that the duty or tax is
      paid; as, the stamp on a bill of exchange.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence: A stamped or printed device, usually paper, issued
      by the government at a fixed price, and required by law to
      be affixed to, or stamped on, certain papers, as evidence
      that the government dues are paid; as, a postage stamp; a
      tax stamp; a receipt stamp, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. An instrument for cutting out, or shaping, materials, as
      paper, leather, etc., by a downward pressure.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A character or reputation, good or bad, fixed on anything
      as if by an imprinted mark; current value; authority; as,
      these persons have the stamp of dishonesty; the Scriptures
      bear the stamp of a divine origin.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of the same stamp is that which is obtruded on us,
            that an adamant suspends the attraction of the
            loadstone.                            --Sir T.
                                                  Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Make; cast; form; character; as, a man of the same stamp,
       or of a different stamp.
       [1913 Webster]

             A soldier of this season's stamp.    --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A kind of heavy hammer, or pestle, raised by water or
       steam power, for beating ores to powder; anything like a
       pestle, used for pounding or beating.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A half-penny. [Obs.] --Beau. &amp; Fl.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. pl. Money, esp. paper money. [Slang, U.S.]
       [1913 Webster]

   {Stamp act}, an act of the British Parliament [1765] imposing
      a duty on all paper, vellum, and parchment used in the
      American colonies, and declaring all writings on unstamped
      materials to be null and void.

   {Stamp collector},
       (a) an officer who receives or collects stamp duties.
       (b) one who collects postage or other stamps, as an
           avocation or for investment; a philatelist.

   {Stamp duty}, a duty, or tax, imposed on paper and parchment
      used for certain writings, as deeds, conveyances, etc.,
      the evidence of the payment of the duty or tax being a
      stamp. [Eng.]

   {Stamp hammer}, a hammer, worked by power, which rises and
      falls vertically, like a stamp in a stamp mill.

   {Stamp head}, a heavy mass of metal, forming the head or
      lower end of a bar, which is lifted and let fall, in a
      stamp mill.

   {Stamp mill} (Mining), a mill in which ore is crushed with
      stamps; also, a machine for stamping ore.

   {Stamp note}, a stamped certificate from a customhouse
      officer, which allows goods to be received by the captain
      of a ship as freight. [Eng.]

   {Stamp office}, an office for the issue of stamps and the
      reception of stamp duties.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stamp \Stamp\ (st[a^]mp) v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stamped}
   (st[a^]mt; 215); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Stamping}.] [OE. stampen;
   akin to LG. &amp; D. stampen, G. stampfen, OHG. stampf[=o]n, Dan.
   stampe, Sw. stampa, Icel. stappa, G. stampf a pestle and E.
   step. See {Step}, v. i., and cf. {Stampede}.]
   1. To strike beat, or press forcibly with the bottom of the
      foot, or by thrusting the foot downward. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He frets, he fumes, he stares, he stamps the ground.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring down (the foot) forcibly on the ground or floor;
      as, he stamped his foot with rage.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To crush; to pulverize; specifically (Metal.), to crush by
      the blow of a heavy stamp, as ore in a mill.
      [1913 Webster]

            I took your sin, the calf which ye had made, and
            burnt it with fire, and stamped it, and ground it
            very small.                           --Deut. ix.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To impress with some mark or figure; as, to stamp a plate
      with arms or initials.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Fig.: To impress; to imprint; to fix deeply; as, to stamp
      virtuous principles on the heart.
      [1913 Webster]

            God . . . has stamped no original characters on our
            minds wherein we may read his being.  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cut out, bend, or indent, as paper, sheet metal, etc.,
      into various forms, by a blow or suddenly applied pressure
      with a stamp or die, etc.; to mint; to coin.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To put a stamp on, as for postage; as, to stamp a letter;
      to stamp a legal document.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To stamp out}, to put an end to by sudden and energetic
      action; to extinguish; as, to stamp out a rebellion.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stamp \Stamp\, v. i.
   1. To strike; to beat; to crush.
      [1913 Webster]

            These cooks how they stamp and strain and grind.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To strike the foot forcibly downward.
      [1913 Webster]

            But starts, exclaims, and stamps, and raves, and
            dies.                                 --Dennis.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stamp
     n 1: a token that postal fees have been paid [syn: {postage}, {postage
          stamp}]
     2: the distinctive form in which a thing is made; "pottery of
        this cast was found throughout the region" [syn: {cast}, {mold}]
     3: a type or class; "more men of his stamp are needed"
     4: a symbol that is the result of printing; "he put his stamp
        on the envelope" [syn: {impression}]
     5: machine consisting of a heavy bar that moves vertically for
        pounding or crushing ores [syn: {pestle}]
     6: a block or die used to imprint a mark or design
     7: a device incised to make an impression; used to secure a
        closing or to authenticate documents [syn: {seal}]
     v 1: walk heavily; "The men stomped through the snow in their
          heavy boots" [syn: {stomp}, {stump}]
     2: to mark, or produce an imprint in or on something; "a man
        whose name is permanently stamped on our maps"
     3: reveal clearly as having a certain character; "His playing
        stamps him as a Romantic"
     4: affix a stamp to; "Are the letters properly stamped?"
     5: treat or classify according to a mental stereotype; "I was
        stereotyped as a lazy Southern European" [syn: {pigeonhole},
         {stereotype}]
     6: destroy or extinguish as if by stamping with the foot;
        "Stamp fascism into submission"; "stamp out tyranny"
     7: form or cut out with a mold, form, or die; "stamp needles"
     8: crush or grind with a heavy instrument; "stamp fruit extract
        the juice"
     9: raise in a relief; "embossed stationary" [syn: {emboss}, {boss}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
