<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>standing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stand \Stand\ (st[a^]nd), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stood}
   (st[oo^]d); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Standing}.] [OE. standen; AS.
   standan; akin to OFries. stonda, st[=a]n, D. staan, OS.
   standan, st[=a]n, OHG. stantan, st[=a]n, G. stehen, Icel.
   standa, Dan. staae, Sw. st[*a], Goth. standan, Russ. stoiate,
   L. stare, Gr. 'ista`nai to cause to stand, sth^nai to stand,
   Skr. sth[=a]. [root]163. Cf. {Assist}, {Constant},
   {Contrast}, {Desist}, {Destine}, {Ecstasy}, {Exist},
   {Interstice}, {Obstacle}, {Obstinate}, {Prest}, n., {Rest}
   remainder, {Solstice}, {Stable}, a. &amp; n., {Staff}, {Stage},
   {Stall}, n., {Stamen}, {Stanchion}, {Stanza}, {State}, n.,
   {Statute}, {Stead}, {Steed}, {Stool}, {Stud} of horses,
   {Substance}, {System}.]
   1. To be at rest in an erect position; to be fixed in an
      upright or firm position; as:
      (a) To be supported on the feet, in an erect or nearly
          erect position; -- opposed to {lie}, {sit}, {kneel},
          etc. ``I pray you all, stand up!'' --Shak.
      (b) To continue upright in a certain locality, as a tree
          fixed by the roots, or a building resting on its
          foundation.
          [1913 Webster]

                It stands as it were to the ground yglued.
                                                  --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]

                The ruined wall
                Stands when its wind-worn battlements are gone.
                                                  --Byron.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. To occupy or hold a place; to have a situation; to be
      situated or located; as, Paris stands on the Seine.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wite ye not where there stands a little town?
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cease from progress; not to proceed; to stop; to pause;
      to halt; to remain stationary.
      [1913 Webster]

            I charge thee, stand,
            And tell thy name.                    --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The star, which they saw in the east, went before
            them, till it came and stood over where the young
            child was.                            --Matt. ii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To remain without ruin or injury; to hold good against
      tendencies to impair or injure; to be permanent; to
      endure; to last; hence, to find endurance, strength, or
      resources.
      [1913 Webster]

            My mind on its own center stands unmoved. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To maintain one's ground; to be acquitted; not to fail or
      yield; to be safe.
      [1913 Webster]

            Readers by whose judgment I would stand or fall.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To maintain an invincible or permanent attitude; to be
      fixed, steady, or firm; to take a position in resistance
      or opposition. ``The standing pattern of their
      imitation.'' --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king granted the Jews . . . to gather themselves
            together, and to stand for their life. --Esther
                                                  viii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To adhere to fixed principles; to maintain moral
      rectitude; to keep from falling into error or vice.
      [1913 Webster]

            We must labor so as to stand with godliness,
            according to his appointment.         --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To have or maintain a position, order, or rank; to be in a
      particular relation; as, Christian charity, or love,
      stands first in the rank of gifts.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To be in some particular state; to have essence or being;
      to be; to consist. ``Sacrifices . . . which stood only in
      meats and drinks.'' --Heb. ix. 10.
      [1913 Webster]

            Accomplish what your signs foreshow;
            I stand resigned, and am prepared to go. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou seest how it stands with me, and that I may not
            tarry.                                --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To be consistent; to agree; to accord.
       [1913 Webster]

             Doubt me not; by heaven, I will do nothing
             But what may stand with honor.       --Massinger.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Naut.) To hold a course at sea; as, to stand from the
       shore; to stand for the harbor.
       [1913 Webster]

             From the same parts of heaven his navy stands.
                                                  --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To offer one's self, or to be offered, as a candidate.
       [1913 Webster]

             He stood to be elected one of the proctors of the
             university.                          --Walton.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To stagnate; not to flow; to be motionless.
       [1913 Webster]

             Or the black water of Pomptina stands. --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. To measure when erect on the feet.
       [1913 Webster]

             Six feet two, as I think, he stands. --Tennyson.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Law)
       (a) To be or remain as it is; to continue in force; to
           have efficacy or validity; to abide. --Bouvier.
       (b) To appear in court. --Burrill.
           [1913 Webster]

   16. (Card Playing) To be, or signify that one is, willing to
       play with one's hand as dealt.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Stand by} (Naut.), a preparatory order, equivalent to {Be
      ready}.

   {To stand against}, to oppose; to resist.

   {To stand by}.
       (a) To be near; to be a spectator; to be present.
       (b) To be aside; to be set aside with disregard. ``In the
           interim [we] let the commands stand by neglected.''
           --Dr. H. More.
       (c) To maintain; to defend; to support; not to desert;
           as, to stand by one's principles or party.
       (d) To rest on for support; to be supported by.
           --Whitgift.
       (e) To remain as a spectator, and take no part in an
           action; as, we can't just stand idly by while people
           are being killed.

   {To stand corrected}, to be set right, as after an error in a
      statement of fact; to admit having been in error.
      --Wycherley.

   {To stand fast}, to be fixed; to be unshaken or immovable.

   {To stand firmly on}, to be satisfied or convinced of.
      ``Though Page be a secure fool, and stands so firmly on
      his wife's frailty.'' --Shak.

   {To stand for}.
       (a) To side with; to espouse the cause of; to support; to
           maintain, or to profess or attempt to maintain; to
           defend. ``I stand wholly for you.'' --Shak.
       (b) To be in the place of; to be the substitute or
           representative of; to represent; as, a cipher at the
           left hand of a figure stands for nothing. ``I will
           not trouble myself, whether these names stand for the
           same thing, or really include one another.'' --Locke.
       (c) To tolerate; as, I won't stand for any delay.

   {To stand in}, to cost. ``The same standeth them in much less
      cost.'' --Robynson (More's Utopia).

            The Punic wars could not have stood the human race
            in less than three millions of the species. --Burke.

   {To stand in hand}, to conduce to one's interest; to be
      serviceable or advantageous.

   {To stand off}.
       (a) To keep at a distance.
       (b) Not to comply.
       (c) To keep at a distance in friendship, social
           intercourse, or acquaintance.
       (d) To appear prominent; to have relief. ``Picture is
           best when it standeth off, as if it were carved.''
           --Sir H. Wotton.

   {To stand off and on} (Naut.), to remain near a coast by
      sailing toward land and then from it.

   {To stand on} (Naut.), to continue on the same tack or
      course.

   {To stand out}.
       (a) To project; to be prominent. ``Their eyes stand out
           with fatness.'' --Psalm lxxiii. 7.
       (b) To persist in opposition or resistance; not to yield
           or comply; not to give way or recede.

                 His spirit is come in,
                 That so stood out against the holy church.
                                                  --Shak.

   {To stand to}.
       (a) To ply; to urge; to persevere in using. ``Stand to
           your tackles, mates, and stretch your oars.''
           --Dryden.
       (b) To remain fixed in a purpose or opinion. ``I will
           stand to it, that this is his sense.'' --Bp.
           Stillingfleet.
       (c) To abide by; to adhere to; as to a contract,
           assertion, promise, etc.; as, to stand to an award;
           to stand to one's word.
       (d) Not to yield; not to fly; to maintain, as one's
           ground. ``Their lives and fortunes were put in
           safety, whether they stood to it or ran away.''
           --Bacon.
       (e) To be consistent with; to agree with; as, it stands
           to reason that he could not have done so; same as
           {stand with}, below .
       (f) To support; to uphold. ``Stand to me in this cause.''
           --Shak.

   {To stand together}, to be consistent; to agree.

   {To stand to reason} to be reasonable; to be expected.

   {To stand to sea} (Naut.), to direct the course from land.

   {To stand under}, to undergo; to withstand. --Shak.

   {To stand up}.
       (a) To rise from sitting; to be on the feet.
       (b) To arise in order to speak or act. ``Against whom,
           when the accusers stood up, they brought none
           accusation of such things as I supposed.'' --Acts
           xxv. 18.
       (c) To rise and stand on end, as the hair.
       (d) To put one's self in opposition; to contend. ``Once
           we stood up about the corn.'' --Shak.

   {To stand up for}, to defend; to justify; to support, or
      attempt to support; as, to stand up for the
      administration.

   {To stand upon}.
       (a) To concern; to interest.
       (b) To value; to esteem. ``We highly esteem and stand
           much upon our birth.'' --Ray.
       (c) To insist on; to attach much importance to; as, to
           stand upon security; to stand upon ceremony.
       (d) To attack; to assault. [A Hebraism] ``So I stood upon
           him, and slew him.'' --2 Sam. i. 10.

   {To stand with}, to be consistent with. ``It stands with
      reason that they should be rewarded liberally.'' --Sir J.
      Davies.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Standing \Stand"ing\, a.
   1. Remaining erect; not cut down; as, standing corn.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not flowing; stagnant; as, standing water.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not transitory; not liable to fade or vanish; lasting; as,
      a standing color.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Established by law, custom, or the like; settled;
      continually existing; permanent; not temporary; as, a
      standing army; legislative bodies have standing rules of
      proceeding and standing committees.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Not movable; fixed; as, a standing bed (distinguished from
      a trundle-bed).
      [1913 Webster]

   {Standing army}. See {Standing army}, under {Army}.

   {Standing bolt}. See {Stud bolt}, under {Stud}, a stem.

   {Standing committee}, in legislative bodies, etc., a
      committee appointed for the consideration of all subjects
      of a particular class which shall arise during the session
      or a stated period.

   {Standing cup}, a tall goblet, with a foot and a cover.

   {Standing finish} (Arch.), that part of the interior
      fittings, esp. of a dwelling house, which is permanent and
      fixed in its place, as distinguished from doors, sashes,
      etc.

   {Standing order}
      (a) (Eccl.), the denomination (Congregational) established
          by law; -- a term formerly used in Connecticut. See
          also under {Order}.
      (a) (Com.) an order for goods which are to be delivered
          periodically, without the need for renewal of the
          order before each delivery.

   {Standing part}. (Naut.)
      (a) That part of a tackle which is made fast to a block,
          point, or other object.
      (b) That part of a rope around which turns are taken with
          the running part in making a knot or the like.

   {Standing rigging} (Naut.), the cordage or ropes which
      sustain the masts and remain fixed in their position, as
      the shrouds and stays, -- distinguished from {running
      rigging}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Standing \Stand"ing\, n.
   1. The act of stopping, or coming to a stand; the state of
      being erect upon the feet; stand.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Maintenance of position; duration; duration or existence
      in the same place or condition; continuance; as, a custom
      of long standing; an officer of long standing.
      [1913 Webster]

            An ancient thing of long standing.    --Bunyan.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Place to stand in; station; stand.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will provide you a good standing to see his entry.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            I sink in deep mire, where there is no standing.
                                                  --Ps. lxix. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Condition in society; relative position; reputation; rank;
      as, a man of good standing, or of high standing.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Standing off} (Naut.), sailing from the land.

   {Standing on} (Naut.), sailing toward land.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>standing
     adj 1: having a supporting base; "a standing lamp" [syn: {standing(a)}]
     2: (of fluids) not moving or flowing; "mosquitoes breed in
        standing water" [syn: {standing(a)}] [ant: {running(a)}]
     3: not created for a particular occasion; "a standing
        committee" [syn: {standing(a)}]
     4: maintaining an erect position; "standing timber"; "many
        buildings were still standing" [syn: {upright}] [ant: {falling}]
     5: executed in or initiated from a standing position; "a
        standing ovation"; "race from a standing start"; "a
        standing jump"; "a standing ovation" [syn: {standing(a)}]
        [ant: {running(a)}]
     6: (of persons) on the feet; having the torso in an erect
        position supported by straight legs; "standing room only";
        "a standing ovation" [ant: {seated}]
     7: permanent; "a standing army"
     8: not cut down; "standing timber"; "uncut trees" [syn: {uncut}]
     n 1: social or financial or professional status or reputation;
          "of equal standing"; "a member in good standing"
     2: the act of assuming or maintaining an erect upright position
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
