<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>standard</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>standard
     
        &lt;standard&gt; Standards are necessary for {interworking},
        {portability}, and {reusability}.  They may be {de facto
        standards} for various communities, or officially recognised
        national or international standards.
     
        {Andrew Tanenbaum}, in his Computer Networks book, once said,
        "The nice thing about standards is that there are so many of
        them to choose from", a reference to the fact that competing
        standards become a source of confusion, division,
        obsolescence, and duplication of effort instead of an
        enhancement to the usefulness of products.
     
        Some bodies concerned in one way or another with computing
        standards are {IAB} ({RFC} and {STD}), {ISO}, {ANSI}, {DoD},
        {ECMA}, {IEEE}, {IETF}, {OSF}, {W3C}.
     
        (1999-07-06)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Standard, IL (village, FIPS 72221)
  Location: 41.25640 N, 89.18032 W
  Population (1990): 260 (117 housing units)
  Area: 1.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sheth \Sheth\, n.
   The part of a plow which projects downward beneath the beam,
   for holding the share and other working parts; -- also called
   {standard}, or {post}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Standard \Stand"ard\ (-[~e]rd), n. [OF. estendart, F.
   ['e]tendard, probably fr. L. extendere to spread out, extend,
   but influenced by E. stand. See {Extend}.]
   1. A flag; colors; a banner; especially, a national or other
      ensign.
      [1913 Webster]

            His armies, in the following day,
            On those fair plains their standards proud display.
                                                  --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is established by authority as a rule for the
      measure of quantity, extent, value, or quality; esp., the
      original specimen weight or measure sanctioned by
      government, as the standard pound, gallon, or yard.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is established as a rule or model by authority,
      custom, or general consent; criterion; test.
      [1913 Webster]

            The court, which used to be the standard of
            propriety and correctness of speech.  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            A disposition to preserve, and an ability to
            improve, taken together, would be my standard of a
            statesman.                            --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Coinage) The proportion of weights of fine metal and
      alloy established by authority.
      [1913 Webster]

            By the present standard of the coinage, sixty-two
            shillings is coined out of one pound weight of
            silver.                               --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Hort.) A tree of natural size supported by its own stem,
      and not dwarfed by grafting on the stock of a smaller
      species nor trained upon a wall or trellis.
      [1913 Webster]

            In France part of their gardens is laid out for
            flowers, others for fruits; some standards, some
            against walls.                        --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Bot.) The upper petal or banner of a papilionaceous
      corolla.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mech. &amp; Carp.) An upright support, as one of the poles of
      a scaffold; any upright in framing.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Shipbuilding) An inverted knee timber placed upon the
      deck instead of beneath it, with its vertical branch
      turned upward from that which lies horizontally.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The sheth of a plow.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A large drinking cup. --Greene.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Standard bearer}, an officer of an army, company, or troop,
      who bears a standard; -- commonly called color sergeantor
      color bearer; hence, the leader of any organization; as,
      the standard bearer of a political party.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Standard \Stand"ard\, a.
   1. Being, affording, or according with, a standard for
      comparison and judgment; as, standard time; standard
      weights and measures; a standard authority as to nautical
      terms; standard gold or silver.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: Having a recognized and permanent value; as,
      standard works in history; standard authors.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Hort.)
      (a) Not supported by, or fastened to, a wall; as, standard
          fruit trees.
      (b) Not of the dwarf kind; as, a standard pear tree.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Standard candle}, {Standard gauge}. See under {Candle}, and
      {Gauge}.

   {Standard solution}. (Chem.) See {Standardized solution},
      under {Solution}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>standard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>standard
     adj 1: conforming to or constituting a standard of measurement or
            value; or of the usual or regularized or accepted
            kind; "windows of standard width"; "standard sizes";
            "the standard fixtures"; "standard brands"; "standard
            operating procedure" [ant: {nonstandard}]
     2: commonly used or supplied; "standard procedure"; "standard
        car equipment"
     3: established or widely recognized as a model of authority or
        excellence; "a standard reference work" [ant: {nonstandard}]
     4: conforming to the established language usage of educated
        native speakers; "standard English" (American); "received
        standard English is sometimes called the King's English"
        (British) [syn: {received}] [ant: {nonstandard}]
     5: regularly and widely used or sold; "a standard size"; "a
        stock item" [syn: {stock}]
     n 1: a basis for comparison; a reference point against which
          other things can be evaluated; "they set the measure for
          all subsequent work" [syn: {criterion}, {measure}, {touchstone}]
     2: the ideal in terms of which something can be judged; "they
        live by the standards of their community" [syn: {criterion}]
     3: a board measure = 1980 board feet
     4: the value behind the money in a monetary system [syn: {monetary
        standard}]
     5: an upright pole or beam (especially one used as a support);
        "distance was marked by standards every mile"; "lamps
        supported on standards provided illumination"
     6: any distinctive flag
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
