<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>starting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>starting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>start \start\ (st[aum]rt), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {started}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {starting}.] [OE. sterten; akin to D. storten to
   hurl, rush, fall, G. st["u]rzen, OHG. sturzen to turn over,
   to fall, Sw. st["o]rta to cast down, to fall, Dan. styrte,
   and probably also to E. start a tail; the original sense
   being, perhaps, to show the tail, to tumble over suddenly.
   [root]166. Cf. {Start} a tail.]
   1. To leap; to jump. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move suddenly, as with a spring or leap, from surprise,
      pain, or other sudden feeling or emotion, or by a
      voluntary act.
      [1913 Webster]

            And maketh him out of his sleep to start. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I start as from some dreadful dream.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Keep your soul to the work when ready to start
            aside.                                --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

            But if he start,
            It is the flesh of a corrupted heart. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To set out; to commence a course, as a race or journey; to
      begin; as, to start in business.
      [1913 Webster]

            At once they start, advancing in a line. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            At intervals some bird from out the brakes
            Starts into voice a moment, then is still. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To become somewhat displaced or loosened; as, a rivet or a
      seam may start under strain or pressure.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To start after}, to set out after; to follow; to pursue.

   {To start against}, to act as a rival candidate against.

   {To start for}, to be a candidate for, as an office.

   {To start up}, to rise suddenly, as from a seat or couch; to
      come suddenly into notice or importance.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>starting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Starting \Start"ing\ (st[aum]rt"[i^]ng),
   a. &amp; n. from {Start}, v.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Starting bar} (Steam Eng.), a hand lever for working the
      valves in starting an engine.

   {Starting hole}, a loophole; evasion. [Obs.]

   {Starting point}, the point from which motion begins, or from
      which anything starts.

   {Starting post}, a post, stake, barrier, or place from which
      competitors in a race start, or begin the race.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>starting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>starting
     adj 1: (especially of eyes) bulging or protruding as with fear;
            "with eyes starting from their sockets"
     2: appropriate to the beginning or start of an event; "the
        starting point"; "hands in the starting position"
     n : a turn to be a starter (in a game at the beginning); "he got
         his start because one of the regular pitchers was in the
         hospital"; "his starting meant that the coach thought he
         was one of their best linemen" [syn: {start}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
