<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>start</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>start</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>start \start\ (st[aum]rt), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {started}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {starting}.] [OE. sterten; akin to D. storten to
   hurl, rush, fall, G. st["u]rzen, OHG. sturzen to turn over,
   to fall, Sw. st["o]rta to cast down, to fall, Dan. styrte,
   and probably also to E. start a tail; the original sense
   being, perhaps, to show the tail, to tumble over suddenly.
   [root]166. Cf. {Start} a tail.]
   1. To leap; to jump. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move suddenly, as with a spring or leap, from surprise,
      pain, or other sudden feeling or emotion, or by a
      voluntary act.
      [1913 Webster]

            And maketh him out of his sleep to start. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I start as from some dreadful dream.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Keep your soul to the work when ready to start
            aside.                                --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

            But if he start,
            It is the flesh of a corrupted heart. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To set out; to commence a course, as a race or journey; to
      begin; as, to start in business.
      [1913 Webster]

            At once they start, advancing in a line. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            At intervals some bird from out the brakes
            Starts into voice a moment, then is still. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To become somewhat displaced or loosened; as, a rivet or a
      seam may start under strain or pressure.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To start after}, to set out after; to follow; to pursue.

   {To start against}, to act as a rival candidate against.

   {To start for}, to be a candidate for, as an office.

   {To start up}, to rise suddenly, as from a seat or couch; to
      come suddenly into notice or importance.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>start</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Start \Start\ (st[aum]rt), v. t.
   1. To cause to move suddenly; to disturb suddenly; to
      startle; to alarm; to rouse; to cause to flee or fly; as,
      the hounds started a fox.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon malicious bravery dost thou come
            To start my quiet?                    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Brutus will start a spirit as soon as C[ae]sar.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring into being or into view; to originate; to invent.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sensual men agree in the pursuit of every pleasure
            they can start.                       --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to move or act; to set going, running, or
      flowing; as, to start a railway train; to start a mill; to
      start a stream of water; to start a rumor; to start a
      business.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was engaged in conversation upon a subject which
            the people love to start in discourse. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To move suddenly from its place or position; to displace
      or loosen; to dislocate; as, to start a bone; the storm
      started the bolts in the vessel.
      [1913 Webster]

            One, by a fall in wrestling, started the end of the
            clavicle from the sternum.            --Wiseman.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [Perh. from D. storten, which has this meaning also.]
      (Naut.) To pour out; to empty; to tap and begin drawing
      from; as, to start a water cask.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>start</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Start \Start\, n.
   1. The act of starting; a sudden spring, leap, or motion,
      caused by surprise, fear, pain, or the like; any sudden
      motion, or beginning of motion.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fright awakened Arcite with a start. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A convulsive motion, twitch, or spasm; a spasmodic effort.
      [1913 Webster]

            For she did speak in starts distractedly. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nature does nothing by starts and leaps, or in a
            hurry.                                --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sudden, unexpected movement; a sudden and capricious
      impulse; a sally; as, starts of fancy.
      [1913 Webster]

            To check the starts and sallies of the soul.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The beginning, as of a journey or a course of action;
      first motion from a place; act of setting out; the outset;
      -- opposed to {finish}.
      [1913 Webster]

            The start of first performance is all. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            I see you stand like greyhounds in the slips,
            Straining upon the start.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At a start}, at once; in an instant. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            At a start he was betwixt them two.   --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To get the start}, or {To have the start}, to begin before
      another; to gain or have the advantage in a similar
      undertaking; -- usually with of. ``Get the start of the
      majestic world.'' --Shak. ``She might have forsaken him if
      he had not got the start of her.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>start</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Start \Start\, n. [OE. stert a tail, AS. steort; akin to LG.
   stert, steert, D. staart, G. sterz, Icel. stertr, Dan.
   stiert, Sw. stjert. [root]166. Cf. Stark naked, under
   {Stark}, {Start}, v. i.]
   1. A tail, or anything projecting like a tail.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The handle, or tail, of a plow; also, any long handle.
      [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The curved or inclined front and bottom of a water-wheel
      bucket.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mining) The arm, or lever, of a gin, drawn around by a
      horse.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>start</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>START \START\ (st[aum]rt), n. [From Strategic Arms Reduction
   Treaty.]
   A Treaty between the United States and the Soviet Union which
   provided for stepwise reductions in the number of nuclear
   weapons possessed by each country.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>start</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>start
     n 1: the beginning of anything; "it was off to a good start"
     2: the time at which something is supposed to begin; "they got
        an early start"; "she knew from the get-go that he was the
        man for her" [syn: {beginning}, {commencement}, {first}, {outset},
         {get-go}, {kickoff}, {starting time}, {showtime}, {offset}]
        [ant: {middle}, {end}]
     3: a turn to be a starter (in a game at the beginning); "he got
        his start because one of the regular pitchers was in the
        hospital"; "his starting meant that the coach thought he
        was one of their best linemen" [syn: {starting}]
     4: a sudden involuntary movement; "he awoke with a start" [syn:
         {startle}, {jump}]
     5: the act of starting something; "he was responsible for the
        beginning of negotiations" [syn: {beginning}, {commencement}]
        [ant: {finish}]
     6: a line indicating the location of the start of a race or a
        game [syn: {starting line}]
     7: a signal to begin (as in a race); "the starting signal was a
        green light"; "the runners awaited the start" [syn: {starting
        signal}]
     8: advantage gained by an early start as in a race; "with an
        hour's start he will be hard to catch" [syn: {head start}]
     v 1: take the first step or steps in carrying out an action; "We
          began working at dawn"; "Who will start?"; "Get working
          as soon as the sun rises!"; "The first tourists began to
          arrive in Cambodia"; "He began early in the day"; "Let's
          get down to work now" [syn: {get down}, {begin}, {get},
          {start out}, {set about}, {set out}, {commence}] [ant: {end}]
     2: set in motion, cause to start; "The U.S. started a war in
        the Middle East"; "The Iraqis began hostilities"; "begin a
        new chapter in your life" [syn: {begin}, {lead off}, {commence}]
        [ant: {end}]
     3: leave; "The family took off for Florida" [syn: {depart}, {part},
         {start out}, {set forth}, {set off}, {set out}, {take off}]
     4: have a beginning, in a temporal, spatial, or evaluative
        sense; "The DMZ begins right over the hill"; "The second
        movement begins after the Allegro"; "Prices for these
        homes start at $250,000" [syn: {begin}] [ant: {end}]
     5: bring into being; "He initiated a new program"; "Start a
        foundation" [syn: {originate}, {initiate}]
     6: get off the ground; "Who started this company?"; "We
        embarked on an exciting enterprise"; "I start my day with
        a good breakfast"; "We began the new semester"; "The
        afternoon session begins at 4 PM"; "The blood shed started
        when the partisans launched a surprise attack" [syn: {start
        up}, {embark on}, {commence}]
     7: move or jump suddenly, as if in surprise or alarm; "She
        startled when I walked into the room" [syn: {startle}, {jump}]
     8: get going or set in motion; "We simply could not start the
        engine"; "start up the computer" [syn: {start up}] [ant: {stop}]
     9: begin or set in motion; "I start at eight in the morning";
        "Ready, set, go!" [syn: {go}, {get going}] [ant: {stop}]
     10: begin work or acting in a certain capacity, office or job;
         "Take up a position"; "start a new job" [syn: {take up}]
     11: play in the starting line-up
     12: have a beginning characterized in some specified way; "The
         novel begins with a murder"; "My property begins with the
         three maple trees"; "Her day begins with a work-out";
         "The semester begins with a convocation ceremony" [syn: {begin}]
     13: begin an event that is implied and limited by the nature or
         inherent function of the direct object; "begin a cigar";
         "She started the soup while it was still hot"; "We
         started physics in 10th grade" [syn: {begin}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
