<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>state</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>state
     
        &lt;storage, architecture, jargon, theory&gt; How something is; its
        configuration, attributes, condition, or information content.
        The state of a system is usually temporary (i.e. it changes
        with time) and volatile (i.e. it will be lost or reset to some
        initial state if the system is switched off).
     
        A state may be considered to be a point in some {space} of all
        possible states.  A simple example is a light, which is either
        on or off.  A complex example is the electrical activation in
        a human brain while solving a problem.
     
        In computing and related fields, states, as in the light
        example, are often modelled as being {discrete} (rather than
        continuous) and the transition from one state to another is
        considered to be instantaneous.  Another (related) property of
        a system is the number of possible states it may exhibit.
        This may be finite or infinite.  A common model for a system
        with a finite number of discrete state is a {finite state
        machine}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1996-10-13)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>State \State\ (st[=a]t), n. [OE. stat, OF. estat, F. ['e]tat,
   fr. L. status a standing, position, fr. stare, statum, to
   stand. See {Stand}, and cf. {Estate}, {Status}.]
   1. The circumstances or condition of a being or thing at any
      given time.
      [1913 Webster]

            State is a term nearly synonymous with ``mode,'' but
            of a meaning more extensive, and is not exclusively
            limited to the mutable and contingent. --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Declare the past and present state of things.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Keep the state of the question in your eye. --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Rank; condition; quality; as, the state of honor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy honor, state, and seat is due to me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Condition of prosperity or grandeur; wealthy or prosperous
      circumstances; social importance.
      [1913 Webster]

            She instructed him how he should keep state, and yet
            with a modest sense of his misfortunes. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Can this imperious lord forget to reign,
            Quit all his state, descend, and serve again?
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Appearance of grandeur or dignity; pomp.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where least of state there most of love is shown.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A chair with a canopy above it, often standing on a dais;
      a seat of dignity; also, the canopy itself. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            His high throne, . . . under state
            Of richest texture spread.            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            When he went to court, he used to kick away the
            state, and sit down by his prince cheek by jowl.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Estate; possession. [Obs.] --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your state, my lord, again is yours.  --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A person of high rank. [Obs.] --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Any body of men united by profession, or constituting a
      community of a particular character; as, the civil and
      ecclesiastical states, or the lords spiritual and temporal
      and the commons, in Great Britain. Cf. {Estate}, n., 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The principal persons in a government.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bold design
            Pleased highly those infernal states. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The bodies that constitute the legislature of a country;
       as, the States-general of Holland.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A form of government which is not monarchial, as a
       republic. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

             Well monarchies may own religion's name,
             But states are atheists in their very fame.
                                                  --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A political body, or body politic; the whole body of
       people who are united under one government, whatever may
       be the form of the government; a nation.
       [1913 Webster]

             Municipal law is a rule of conduct prescribed by
             the supreme power in a state.        --Blackstone.
       [1913 Webster]

             The Puritans in the reign of Mary, driven from
             their homes, sought an asylum in Geneva, where they
             found a state without a king, and a church without
             a bishop.                            --R. Choate.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. In the United States, one of the commonwealths, or bodies
       politic, the people of which make up the body of the
       nation, and which, under the national constitution, stand
       in certain specified relations with the national
       government, and are invested, as commonwealths, with full
       power in their several spheres over all matters not
       expressly inhibited.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: The term State, in its technical sense, is used in
         distinction from the federal system, i. e., the
         government of the United States.
         [1913 Webster]

   14. Highest and stationary condition, as that of maturity
       between growth and decline, or as that of crisis between
       the increase and the abating of a disease; height; acme.
       [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: When state is joined with another word, or used
         adjectively, it denotes public, or what belongs to the
         community or body politic, or to the government; also,
         what belongs to the States severally in the American
         Union; as, state affairs; state policy; State laws of
         Iowa.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Nascent state}. (Chem.) See under {Nascent}.

   {Secretary of state}. See {Secretary}, n., 3.

   {State barge}a royal barge, or a barge belonging to a
      government.

   {State bed}, an elaborately carved or decorated bed.

   {State carriage}, a highly decorated carriage for officials
      going in state, or taking part in public processions.

   {State paper}, an official paper relating to the interests or
      government of a state. --Jay.

   {State prison}, a public prison or penitentiary; -- called
      also {State's prison}.

   {State prisoner}, one in confinement, or under arrest, for a
      political offense.

   {State rights}, or {States' rights}, the rights of the
      several independent States, as distinguished from the
      rights of the Federal government. It has been a question
      as to what rights have been vested in the general
      government. [U.S.]

   {State's evidence}. See {Probator}, 2, and under {Evidence}.
      

   {State sword}, a sword used on state occasions, being borne
      before a sovereign by an attendant of high rank.

   {State trial}, a trial of a person for a political offense.
      

   {States of the Church}. See under {Ecclesiastical}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: {State}, {Situation}, {Condition}.

   Usage: State is the generic term, and denotes in general the
          mode in which a thing stands or exists. The situation
          of a thing is its state in reference to external
          objects and influences; its condition is its internal
          state, or what it is in itself considered. Our
          situation is good or bad as outward things bear
          favorably or unfavorably upon us; our condition is
          good or bad according to the state we are actually in
          as respects our persons, families, property, and other
          things which comprise our sources of enjoyment.
          [1913 Webster]

                I do not, brother,
                Infer as if I thought my sister's state
                Secure without all doubt or controversy.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                We hoped to enjoy with ease what, in our
                situation, might be called the luxuries of life.
                                                  --Cook.
          [1913 Webster]

                And, O, what man's condition can be worse
                Than his whom plenty starves and blessings
                curse?                            --Cowley.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>State \State\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stated}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Stating}.]
   1. To set; to settle; to establish. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I myself, though meanest stated,
            And in court now almost hated.        --Wither.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who calls the council, states the certain day.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To express the particulars of; to set down in detail or in
      gross; to represent fully in words; to narrate; to recite;
      as, to state the facts of a case, one's opinion, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To state it}. To assume state or dignity. [Obs.] ``Rarely
      dressed up, and taught to state it.'' --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>State \State\ (st[=a]t), a.
   1. Stately. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Belonging to the state, or body politic; public.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>State \State\, n.
   A statement; also, a document containing a statement. [R.]
   --Sir W. Scott.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Argillaceous \Ar`gil*la"ceous\, a. [L. argillaceus, fr.
   argilla.]
   Of the nature of clay; consisting of, or containing, argil or
   clay; clayey.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Argillaceous sandstone} (Geol.), a sandstone containing much
      clay.

   {Argillaceous iron ore}, the clay ironstone.

   {Argillaceous schist} or {state}. See {Argillite}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>state n. 1. Condition, situation. "What's the state of your latest
   hack?" "It's winning away." "The system tried to read and write the disk
   simultaneously and got into a totally {wedged} state." The standard
   question "What's your state?" means "What are you doing?" or "What are
   you about to do?" Typical answers are "about to gronk out", or "hungry".
   Another standard question is "What's the state of the world?", meaning
   "What's new?" or "What's going on?". The more terse and humorous way of
   asking these questions would be "State-p?". Another way of phrasing the
   first question under sense 1 would be "state-p latest hack?". 2.
   Information being maintained in non-permanent memory (electronic or
   human).


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>state</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>state
     n 1: the group of people comprising the government of a sovereign
          state; "the state has lowered its income tax"
     2: the territory occupied by one of the constituent
        administrative districts of a nation; "his state is in the
        deep south" [syn: {province}]
     3: a politically organized body of people under a single
        government; "the state has elected a new president";
        "African nations"; "students who had come to the nation's
        capitol"; "the country's largest manufacturer"; "an
        industrialized land" [syn: {nation}, {country}, {land}, {commonwealth},
         {res publica}, {body politic}]
     4: the way something is with respect to its main attributes;
        "the current state of knowledge"; "his state of health";
        "in a weak financial state"
     5: the federal department in the UnitedStates that sets and
        maintains foreign policies; "the Department of State was
        created in 1789" [syn: {Department of State}, {State
        Department}, {DoS}]
     6: the territory occupied by a nation; "he returned to the land
        of his birth"; "he visited several European countries"
        [syn: {country}, {land}]
     7: a state of depression or agitation; "he was in such a state
        you just couldn't reason with him"
     8: (chemistry) the three traditional states of matter are
        solids (fixed shape and volume) and liquids (fixed volume
        and shaped by the container) and gases (filling the
        container); "the solid state of water is called ice" [syn:
         {state of matter}]
     v 1: express in words; "He said that he wanted to marry her";
          "tell me what is bothering you"; "state your opinion";
          "state your name" [syn: {say}, {tell}]
     2: put before; "I submit to you that the accused is guilty"
        [syn: {submit}, {put forward}, {posit}]
     3: indicate through a symbol, formula, etc.; "Can you express
        this distance in kilometers?" [syn: {express}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
