<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>steal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stale \Stale\ (st[=a]l), n. [OE. stale, stele, AS. st[ae]l,
   stel; akin to LG. &amp; D. steel, G. stiel; cf. L. stilus stake,
   stalk, stem, Gr. steleo`n a handle, and E. stall, stalk, n.]
   The stock or handle of anything; as, the stale of a rake.
   [Written also {steal}, {stele}, etc.]
   [1913 Webster]

         But seeing the arrow's stale without, and that the head
         did go
         No further than it might be seen.        --Chapman.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Steal \Steal\ (st[=e]l), n. [See {Stale} a handle.]
   A handle; a stale, or stele. [Archaic or Prov. Eng.]
   [1913 Webster]

         And in his hand a huge poleax did bear.
         Whose steale was iron-studded but not long. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Steal \Steal\ (st[=e]l), v. t. [imp. {Stole} (st[=o]l); p. p.
   {Stolen} (st[=o]"l'n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Stealing}.] [OE.
   stelen, AS. stelan; akin to OFries. stela, D. stelen, OHG.
   stelan, G. stehlen, Icel. stela, SW. stj["a]la, Dan.
   sti[ae]le, Goth. stilan.]
   1. To take, and carry away, feloniously; to take without
      right or leave, and with intent to keep wrongfully; as, to
      steal the personal goods of another.
      [1913 Webster]

            Maugre thy heed, thou must for indigence
            Or steal, or beg, or borrow, thy dispense.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The man who stole a goose and gave away the giblets
            in alms.                              --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To withdraw or convey clandestinely (reflexive); hence, to
      creep furtively, or to insinuate.
      [1913 Webster]

            They could insinuate and steal themselves under the
            same by their humble carriage and submission.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            He will steal himself into a man's favor. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To gain by insinuating arts or covert means.
      [1913 Webster]

            So Absalom stole the hearts of the men of Israel.
                                                  --2 Sam. xv.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To get into one's power gradually and by imperceptible
      degrees; to take possession of by a gradual and
      imperceptible appropriation; -- with away.
      [1913 Webster]

            Variety of objects has a tendency to steal away the
            mind from its steady pursuit of any subject. --I.
                                                  Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To accomplish in a concealed or unobserved manner; to try
      to carry out secretly; as, to steal a look.
      [1913 Webster]

            Always, when thou changest thine opinion or course,
            profess it plainly, . . . and do not think to steal
            it.                                   --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To steal a march}, to march in a covert way; to gain an
      advantage unobserved; -- formerly followed by of, but now
      by on or upon, and sometimes by over; as, to steal a march
      upon one's political rivals.
      [1913 Webster]

            She yesterday wanted to steal a march of poor Liddy.
                                                  --Smollett.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fifty thousand men can not easily steal a march over
            the sea.                              --Walpole.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To filch; pilfer; purloin; thieve.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Steal \Steal\ (st[=e]l), v. i.
   1. To practice, or be guilty of, theft; to commit larceny or
      theft.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt not steal.                 --Ex. xx. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To withdraw, or pass privily; to slip in, along, or away,
      unperceived; to go or come furtively. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fixed of mind to avoid further entreaty, and to fly
            all company, one night she stole away. --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

            From whom you now must steal, and take no leave.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A soft and solemn breathing sound
            Rose like a steam of rich, distilled perfumes,
            And stole upon the air.               --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>steal
     n 1: an advantageous purchase; "she got a bargain at the
          auction"; "the stock was a real buy at that price" [syn:
           {bargain}, {buy}]
     2: a stolen base; an instance in which a base runner advances
        safely during the delivery of a pitch (without the help of
        a hit or walk or passed ball or wild pitch)
     v 1: take without the owner's consent; "Someone stole my wallet
          on the train"; "This author stole entire paragraphs from
          my dissertation"
     2: move stealthily; "The ship slipped away in the darkness"
        [syn: {slip}]
     3: steal a base
     4: to go stealthily or furtively; "..stead of sneaking around
        spying on the neighbor's house" [syn: {sneak}, {mouse}, {creep},
         {pussyfoot}]
     [also: {stolen}, {stole}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
