<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>steel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Steel
   The "bow of steel" in (A.V.) 2 Sam. 22:35; Job 20:24; Ps. 18:34
   is in the Revised Version "bow of brass" (Heb.
   kesheth-nehushah). In Jer. 15:12 the same word is used, and is
   also rendered in the Revised Version "brass." But more correctly
   it is copper (q.v.), as brass in the ordinary sense of the word
   (an alloy of copper and zinc) was not known to the ancients.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Steel \Steel\ (st[=e]l), n. [AS. st[=e]l, st[=y]l, st[=y]le;
   akin to D. staal, G. stahl, OHG. stahal, Icel. st[=a]l, Dan.
   staal, Sw. st[*a]l, Old Prussian stakla.]
   1. (Metal) A variety of iron intermediate in composition and
      properties between wrought iron and cast iron (containing
      between one half of one per cent and one and a half per
      cent of carbon), and consisting of an alloy of iron with
      an iron carbide. Steel, unlike wrought iron, can be
      tempered, and retains magnetism. Its malleability
      decreases, and fusibility increases, with an increase in
      carbon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An instrument or implement made of steel; as: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) A weapon, as a sword, dagger, etc. ``Brave Macbeth . .
          . with his brandished steel.'' --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                While doubting thus he stood,
                Received the steel bathed in his brother's
                blood.                            --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) An instrument of steel (usually a round rod) for
          sharpening knives.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) A piece of steel for striking sparks from flint.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Fig.: Anything of extreme hardness; that which is
      characterized by sternness or rigor. ``Heads of steel.''
      --Johnson. ``Manhood's heart of steel.'' --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Med.) A chalybeate medicine. --Dunglison.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Steel is often used in the formation of compounds,
         generally of obvious meaning; as, steel-clad,
         steel-girt, steel-hearted, steel-plated, steel-pointed,
         etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Bessemer steel} (Metal.) See in the Vocabulary.

   {Blister steel}. (Metal.) See under {Blister}.

   {Cast steel} (Metal.), a fine variety of steel, originally
      made by smelting blister or cementation steel; hence,
      ordinarily, steel of any process of production when
      remelted and cast.

   {Chrome steel}, {Chromium steel} (Metal.), a hard, tenacious
      variety containing a little chromium, and somewhat
      resembling {tungsten steel}.

   {Mild steel} (Metal.), a kind of steel having a lower
      proportion of carbon than ordinary steel, rendering it
      softer and more malleable.

   {Puddled steel} (Metal.), a variety of steel produced from
      cast iron by the puddling process.

   {Steel duck} (Zo["o]l.), the goosander, or merganser. [Prov.
      Eng.]

   {Steel mill}.
      (a) (Firearms) See {Wheel lock}, under {Wheel}.
      (b) A mill which has steel grinding surfaces.
      (c) A mill where steel is manufactured.

   {Steel trap}, a trap for catching wild animals. It consists
      of two iron jaws, which close by means of a powerful steel
      spring when the animal disturbs the catch, or tongue, by
      which they are kept open.

   {Steel wine}, wine, usually sherry, in which steel filings
      have been placed for a considerable time, -- used as a
      medicine.

   {Tincture of steel} (Med.), an alcoholic solution of the
      chloride of iron.

   {Tungsten steel} (Metal.), a variety of steel containing a
      small amount of tungsten, and noted for its tenacity and
      hardness, as well as for its malleability and tempering
      qualities. It is also noted for its magnetic properties.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Steel \Steel\ (st[=e]l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Steeled}
   (st[=e]ld); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Steeling}.] [AS. st[=y]lan: cf.
   Icel. st[ae]la. See {Steel}, n.]
   1. To overlay, point, or edge with steel; as, to steel a
      razor; to steel an ax.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: To make hard or strong; hence, to make insensible or
      obdurate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lies well steeled with weighty arguments. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            O God of battles! steel my soldiers' hearts. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Why will you fight against so sweet a passion,
            And steel your heart to such a world of charms?
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fig.: To cause to resemble steel, as in smoothness,
      polish, or other qualities.
      [1913 Webster]

            These waters, steeled
            By breezeless air to smoothest polish. --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Elec.) To cover, as an electrotype plate, with a thin
      layer of iron by electrolysis. The iron thus deposited is
      very hard, like steel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>steel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>steel
     n 1: an alloy of iron with small amounts of carbon; widely used
          in construction; mechanical properties can be varied
          over a wide range
     2: a cutting or thrusting weapon with a long blade [syn: {sword},
         {blade}, {brand}]
     3: knife sharpener consisting of a ridged steel rod
     v 1: get ready for something difficult or unpleasant [syn: {nerve}]
     2: cover, plate, or edge with steel
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
