<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stereotype</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stereotype</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stereotype \Ste"re*o*type\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stereotyped};
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Stereotyping}.] [Cf. F. st['e]r['e]otyper.]
   1. To prepare for printing in stereotype; to make the
      stereotype plates of; as, to stereotype the Bible.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: To make firm or permanent; to fix.
      [1913 Webster]

            Powerful causes tending to stereotype and aggravate
            the poverty of old conditions.        --Duke of
                                                  Argyll (1887).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stereotype</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stereotype \Ste"re*o*type\, n. [Stereo- + -type: cf. F.
   st['e]r['e]otype.]
   1. A plate forming an exact faximile of a page of type or of
      an engraving, used in printing books, etc.; specifically,
      a plate with type-metal face, used for printing.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A stereotype, or stereotypr plate, is made by setting
         movable type as for ordinary printing; from these a
         cast is taken in plaster of Paris, paper pulp, or the
         like, and upon this cast melted type metal is poured,
         which, when hardened, makes a solid page or column,
         from which the impression is taken as from type.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The art or process of making such plates, or of executing
      work by means of them.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Stereotype block}, a block, usually of wood, to which a
      stereotype plate is attached while being used in printing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stereotype</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stereotype
     n : a conventional or formulaic conception or image; "regional
         stereotypes have been part of America since its founding"
     v : treat or classify according to a mental stereotype; "I was
         stereotyped as a lazy Southern European" [syn: {pigeonhole},
          {stamp}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
