<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stick</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stick \Stick\, n. [OE. sticke, AS. sticca; akin to stician to
   stab, prick, pierce, G. stecken a stick, staff, OHG. steccho,
   Icel. stik a stick. See {Stick}, v. t..]
   1. A small shoot, or branch, separated, as by a cutting, from
      a tree or shrub; also, any stem or branch of a tree, of
      any size, cut for fuel or timber.
      [1913 Webster]

            Withered sticks to gather, which might serve
            Against a winter's day.               --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any long and comparatively slender piece of wood, whether
      in natural form or shaped with tools; a rod; a wand; a
      staff; as, the stick of a rocket; a walking stick.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything shaped like a stick; as, a stick of wax.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A derogatory expression for a person; one who is inert or
      stupid; as, an odd stick; a poor stick. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Print.) A composing stick. See under {Composing}. It is
      usually a frame of metal, but for posters, handbills,
      etc., one made of wood is used.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A thrust with a pointed instrument; a stab.
      [1913 Webster]

   {A stick of eels}, twenty-five eels. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Stick chimney}, a chimney made of sticks laid crosswise, and
      cemented with clay or mud, as in some log houses. [U.S.]
      

   {Stick insect}, (Zo["o]l.), any one of various species of
      wingless orthopterous insects of the family {Phasmid[ae]},
      which have a long round body, resembling a stick in form
      and color, and long legs, which are often held rigidly in
      such positions as to make them resemble small twigs. They
      thus imitate the branches and twigs of the trees on which
      they live. The common American species is {Diapheromera
      femorata}. Some of the Asiatic species are more than a
      foot long.

   {To cut one's stick}, or {To cut stick}, to run away. [Slang]
      --De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stick \Stick\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stuck}(Obs. {Sticked}); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Sticking}.] [OE. stikien, v.t. &amp; i., combined
   with steken, whence E. stuck), AS. stician, v.t. &amp; i., and
   (assumed) stecan, v.t.; akin to OFries. steka, OS. stekan,
   OHG. stehhan, G. stechen, and to Gr. ? to prick, Skr. tij to
   be sharp. Cf. {Distinguish}, {Etiquette}, {Extinct},
   {Instigate}, {Instinct}, {Prestige}, {Stake}, {Steak},
   {Stick}, n., {Stigma}, {Stimulate}, {Sting}, {Stitch} in
   sewing, {Style} for or in writing.]
   1. To penetrate with a pointed instrument; to pierce; to
      stab; hence, to kill by piercing; as, to stick a beast.
      [1913 Webster]

            And sticked him with bodkins anon.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was a shame . . . to stick him under the other
            gentleman's arm while he was redding the fray. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to penetrate; to push, thrust, or drive, so as to
      pierce; as, to stick a needle into one's finger.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou stickest a dagger in me.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fasten, attach, or cause to remain, by thrusting in;
      hence, also, to adorn or deck with things fastened on as
      by piercing; as, to stick a pin on the sleeve.
      [1913 Webster]

            My shroud of white, stuck all with yew. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The points of spears are stuck within the shield.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To set; to fix in; as, to stick card teeth.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To set with something pointed; as, to stick cards.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To fix on a pointed instrument; to impale; as, to stick an
      apple on a fork.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To attach by causing to adhere to the surface; as, to
      stick on a plaster; to stick a stamp on an envelope; also,
      to attach in any manner.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Print.) To compose; to set, or arrange, in a composing
      stick; as, to stick type. [Cant]
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Joinery) To run or plane (moldings) in a machine, in
      contradistinction to working them by hand. Such moldings
      are said to be stuck.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To cause to stick; to bring to a stand; to pose; to
       puzzle; as, to stick one with a hard problem. [Colloq.]
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To impose upon; to compel to pay; sometimes, to cheat.
       [Slang]
       [1913 Webster]

   {To stick out}, to cause to project or protrude; to render
      prominent.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stick \Stick\, v. i.
   1. To adhere; as, glue sticks to the fingers; paste sticks to
      the wall.
      [1913 Webster]

            The green caterpillar breedeth in the inward parts
            of roses not blown, where the dew sticketh. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To remain where placed; to be fixed; to hold fast to any
      position so as to be moved with difficulty; to cling; to
      abide; to cleave; to be united closely.
      [1913 Webster]

            A friend that sticketh closer than a brother.
                                                  --Prov. xviii.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am a kind of bur; I shall stick.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If on your fame our sex a bolt has thrown,
            'T will ever stick through malice of your own.
                                                  --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be prevented from going farther; to stop by reason of
      some obstacle; to be stayed.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had most need of blessing, and ``Amen''
            Stuck in my throat.                   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The trembling weapon passed
            Through nine bull hides, . . . and stuck within the
            last.                                 --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be embarrassed or puzzled; to hesitate; to be deterred,
      as by scruples; to scruple; -- often with at.
      [1913 Webster]

            They will stick long at part of a demonstration for
            want of perceiving the connection of two ideas.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some stick not to say, that the parson and attorney
            forged a will.                        --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cause difficulties, scruples, or hesitation.
      [1913 Webster]

            This is the difficulty that sticks with the most
            reasonable.                           --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To stick by}.
      (a) To adhere closely to; to be firm in supporting. ``We
          are your only friends; stick by us, and we will stick
          by you.'' --Davenant.
      (b) To be troublesome by adhering. ``I am satisfied to
          trifle away my time, rather than let it stick by me.''
          --Pope.

   {To stick out}.
      (a) To project; to be prominent. ``His bones that were not
          seen stick out.'' --Job xxxiii. 21.
      (b) To persevere in a purpose; to hold out; as, the
          garrison stuck out until relieved. [Colloq.]

   {To stick to}, to be persevering in holding to; as, to stick
      to a party or cause. ``The advantage will be on our side
      if we stick to its essentials.'' --Addison.

   {To stick up}, to stand erect; as, his hair sticks up.

   {To stick up for}, to assert and defend; as, to stick up for
      one's rights or for a friend. [Colloq.]

   {To stick upon}, to dwell upon; not to forsake. ``If the
      matter be knotty, the mind must stop and buckle to it, and
      stick upon it with labor and thought.'' --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stick
     n 1: implement consisting of a length of wood; "he collected dry
          sticks for a campfire"; "the kid had a candied apple on
          a stick"
     2: a small thin branch of a tree
     3: a lever used by a pilot to control the ailerons and
        elevators of an airplane [syn: {control stick}, {joystick}]
     4: informal terms of the leg; "fever left him weak on his
        sticks" [syn: {pin}, {peg}]
     5: marijuana leaves rolled into a cigarette for smoking [syn: {joint},
         {marijuana cigarette}, {reefer}, {spliff}]
     6: threat of a penalty; "the policy so far is all stick and no
        carrot"
     v 1: fix, force, or implant; "lodge a bullet in the table" [syn:
          {lodge}, {wedge}, {deposit}] [ant: {dislodge}]
     2: stay put (in a certain place); "We are staying in Detroit;
        we are not moving to Cincinnati"; "Stay put in the corner
        here!"; "Stick around and you will learn something!" [syn:
         {stay}, {stick around}, {stay put}] [ant: {move}]
     3: cause to protrude or as if to protrude; "stick one's hand
        out of the window"; "stick one's nose into other people's
        business" [syn: {put forward}]
     4: stick to firmly; "Will this wallpaper adhere to the wall?"
        [syn: {adhere}, {hold fast}, {bond}, {bind}, {stick to}]
     5: be or become fixed; "The door sticks--we will have to plane
        it"
     6: endure; "The label stuck to her for the rest of her life"
     7: be a devoted follower or supporter; "The residents of this
        village adhered to Catholicism"; "She sticks to her
        principles" [syn: {adhere}]
     8: be loyal to; "She stood by her husband in times of trouble";
        "The friends stuck together through the war" [syn: {stand
        by}, {stick by}, {adhere}]
     9: cover and decorate with objects that pierce the surface;
        "stick some feathers in the turkey before you serve it"
     10: fasten with an adhesive material like glue; "stick the
         poster onto the wall"
     11: fasten with or as with pins or nails; "stick the photo onto
         the corkboard"
     12: fasten into place by fixing an end or point into something;
         "stick the corner of the sheet under the mattress"
     13: pierce with a thrust using a pointed instrument; "he stuck
         the cloth with the needle"
     14: pierce or penetrate or puncture with something pointed; "He
         stuck the needle into his finger"
     15: come or be in close contact with; stick or hold together and
         resist separation; "The dress clings to her body"; "The
         label stuck to the box"; "The sushi rice grains cohere"
         [syn: {cling}, {cleave}, {adhere}, {cohere}]
     16: saddle with something disagreeable or disadvantageous; "They
         stuck me with the dinner bill"; "I was stung with a huge
         tax bill" [syn: {sting}]
     17: be a mystery or bewildering to; "This beats me!"; "Got me--I
         don't know the answer!"; "a vexing problem"; "This
         question really stuck me" [syn: {perplex}, {vex}, {get},
         {puzzle}, {mystify}, {baffle}, {beat}, {pose}, {bewilder},
          {flummox}, {stupefy}, {nonplus}, {gravel}, {amaze}, {dumbfound}]
     [also: {stuck}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
