<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>still</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Still \Still\, a. [Compar. {Stiller}; superl. {Stillest}.] [OE.
   stille, AS. stille; akin to D. stil, OS. &amp; OHG. stilli, G.
   still, Dan. stille, Sw. stilla, and to E. stall; from the
   idea of coming to a stand, or halt. Cf. {Still}, adv.]
   1. Motionless; at rest; quiet; as, to stand still; to lie or
      sit still. ``Still as any stone.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Uttering no sound; silent; as, the audience is still; the
      animals are still.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sea that roared at thy command,
            At thy command was still.             --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not disturbed by noise or agitation; quiet; calm; as, a
      still evening; a still atmosphere. ``When all the woods
      are still.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Comparatively quiet or silent; soft; gentle; low. ``A
      still small voice.'' --1 Kings xix. 12.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Constant; continual. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            By still practice learn to know thy meaning. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Not effervescing; not sparkling; as, still wines.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Still life}. (Fine Arts)
      (a) Inanimate objects.
      (b) (Painting) The class or style of painting which
          represents inanimate objects, as fruit, flowers, dead
          game, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Quiet; calm; noiseless; serene; motionless; inert;
        stagnant.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Still \Still\, n. [Cf. G. stille.]
   1. Freedom from noise; calm; silence; as, the still of
      midnight. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A steep hill or ascent. [Obs.] --W. Browne.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Still \Still\, adv. [AS. stille quietly. See {Still}, a. The
   modern senses come from the idea of stopping and staying
   still, or motionless.]
   1. To this time; until and during the time now present; now
      no less than before; yet.
      [1913 Webster]

            It hath been anciently reported, and is still
            received.                             --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. In the future as now and before.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hourly joys be still upon you!        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. In continuation by successive or repeated acts; always;
      ever; constantly; uniformly.
      [1913 Webster]

            The desire of fame betrays an ambitious man into
            indecencies that lessen his reputation; he is still
            afraid lest any of his actions should be thrown away
            in private.                           --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Chemists would be rich if they could still do in
            great quantities what they have sometimes done in
            little.                               --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. In an increasing or additional degree; even more; -- much
      used with comparatives.
      [1913 Webster]

            The guilt being great, the fear doth still exceed.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Notwithstanding what has been said or done; in spite of
      what has occured; nevertheless; -- sometimes used as a
      conjunction. See Synonym of {But}.
      [1913 Webster]

            As sunshine, broken in the rill,
            Though turned astray, is sunshine still. --Moore.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. After that; after what is stated.
      [1913 Webster]

            In the primitive church, such as by fear being
            compelled to sacrifice to strange gods, after
            repented, and kept still the office of preaching the
            gospel.                               --Whitgift.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Still and anon}, at intervals and repeatedly; continually;
      ever and anon; now and then.
      [1913 Webster]

            And like the watchful minutes to the hour,
            Still and anon cheered up the heavy time. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Still \Still\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stilled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Stilling}.] [AS. stillan, from stille still, quiet, firm.
   See {Still}, a.]
   1. To stop, as motion or agitation; to cause to become quiet,
      or comparatively quiet; to check the agitation of; as, to
      still the raging sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            He having a full sway over the water, had power to
            still and compose it, as well as to move and disturb
            it.                                   --Woodward.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To stop, as noise; to silence.
      [1913 Webster]

            With his name the mothers still their babies.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To appease; to calm; to quiet, as tumult, agitation, or
      excitement; as, to still the passions. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Toil that would, at least, have stilled an unquiet
            impulse in me.                        --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To quiet; calm; allay; lull; pacify; appease; subdue;
        suppress; silence; stop; check; restrain.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Still \Still\, n. [Cf. OE. stillatorie. See {Still}, v., to
   distill.]
   1. A vessel, boiler, or copper used in the distillation of
      liquids; specifically, one used for the distillation of
      alcoholic liquors; a retort. The name is sometimes applied
      to the whole apparatus used in in vaporization and
      condensation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A house where liquors are distilled; a distillery.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Still watcher}, a device for indicating the progress of
      distillation by the density of the liquid given over.
      --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Still \Still\, v. t. [Abbreviated fr. distill.]
   1. To cause to fall by drops.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To expel spirit from by heat, or to evaporate and condense
      in a refrigeratory; to distill. --Tusser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Still \Still\, v. i. [L. stillare. Cf. {Distill}.]
   To drop, or flow in drops; to distill. [Obs.] --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wine \Wine\, n. [OE. win, AS. win, fr. L. vinum (cf. Icel.
   v[=i]n; all from the Latin); akin to Gr. o'i^nos, ?, and E.
   withy. Cf. {Vine}, {Vineyard}, {Vinous}, {Withy}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The expressed juice of grapes, esp. when fermented; a
      beverage or liquor prepared from grapes by squeezing out
      their juice, and (usually) allowing it to ferment. ``Red
      wine of Gascoigne.'' --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wine is a mocker, strong drink is raging, and
            whosoever is deceived thereby is not wise. --Prov.
                                                  xx. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bacchus, that first from out the purple grape
            Crushed the sweet poison of misused wine. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Wine is essentially a dilute solution of ethyl alcohol,
         containing also certain small quantities of ethers and
         ethereal salts which give character and bouquet.
         According to their color, strength, taste, etc., wines
         are called {red}, {white}, {spirituous}, {dry},
         {light}, {still}, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A liquor or beverage prepared from the juice of any fruit
      or plant by a process similar to that for grape wine; as,
      currant wine; gooseberry wine; palm wine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The effect of drinking wine in excess; intoxication.
      [1913 Webster]

            Noah awoke from his wine.             --Gen. ix. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Birch wine}, {Cape wine}, etc. See under {Birch}, {Cape},
      etc.

   {Spirit of wine}. See under {Spirit}.

   {To have drunk wine of ape} or {To have drunk wine ape}, to
      be so drunk as to be foolish. [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {Wine acid}. (Chem.) See {Tartaric acid}, under {Tartaric}.
      [Colloq.]

   {Wine apple} (Bot.), a large red apple, with firm flesh and a
      rich, vinous flavor.

   {Wine fly} (Zo["o]l.), small two-winged fly of the genus
      {Piophila}, whose larva lives in wine, cider, and other
      fermented liquors.

   {Wine grower}, one who cultivates a vineyard and makes wine.
      

   {Wine measure}, the measure by which wines and other spirits
      are sold, smaller than beer measure.

   {Wine merchant}, a merchant who deals in wines.

   {Wine of opium} (Pharm.), a solution of opium in aromatized
      sherry wine, having the same strength as ordinary
      laudanum; -- also {Sydenham's laudanum}.

   {Wine press}, a machine or apparatus in which grapes are
      pressed to extract their juice.

   {Wine skin}, a bottle or bag of skin, used, in various
      countries, for carrying wine.

   {Wine stone}, a kind of crust deposited in wine casks. See
      1st {Tartar}, 1.

   {Wine vault}.
      (a) A vault where wine is stored.
      (b) A place where wine is served at the bar, or at tables;
          a dramshop. --Dickens.

   {Wine vinegar}, vinegar made from wine.

   {Wine whey}, whey made from milk coagulated by the use of
      wine.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>still</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>still
     adj 1: not in physical motion; "the inertia of an object at rest"
            [syn: {inactive}, {motionless}, {static}]
     2: marked by absence of sound; "a silent house"; "soundless
        footsteps on the grass"; "the night was still" [syn: {silent},
         {soundless}]
     3: free from disturbance; "a ribbon of sand between the angry
        sea and the placid bay"; "the quiet waters of a lagoon";
        "a lake of tranquil blue water reflecting a tranquil blue
        sky"; "a smooth channel crossing"; "scarcely a ripple on
        the still water"; "unruffled water" [syn: {placid}, {quiet},
         {tranquil}, {unruffled}]
     4: used of pictures; of a single or static photograph not
        presented so as to create the illusion of motion; or
        representing objects not capable of motion; "a still
        photograph"; "Cezanne's still life of apples" [ant: {moving}]
     5: not sparkling; "a still wine"; "still mineral water" [syn: {noneffervescent}]
        [ant: {sparkling}]
     6: free from noticeable current; "a still pond"; "still waters
        run deep"
     n 1: a static photograph (especially one taken from a movie and
          used for advertising purposes); "he wanted some stills
          for a magazine ad"
     2: (poetic) tranquil silence; "the still of the night" [syn: {hush},
         {stillness}]
     3: an apparatus used for the distillation of liquids; consists
        of a vessel in which a substance is vaporized by heat and
        a condenser where the vapor is condensed
     4: a plant and works where alcoholic drinks are made by
        distillation [syn: {distillery}]
     adv 1: with reference to action or condition; without change,
            interruption, or cessation; "it's still warm outside";
            "will you still love me when we're old and grey?"
            [ant: {no longer}]
     2: despite anything to the contrary (usually following a
        concession); "although I'm a little afraid, however I'd
        like to try it"; "while we disliked each other,
        nevertheless we agreed"; "he was a stern yet fair master";
        "granted that it is dangerous, all the same I still want
        to go" [syn: {however}, {nevertheless}, {withal}, {yet}, {all
        the same}, {even so}, {nonetheless}, {notwithstanding}]
     3: to a greater degree or extent; used with comparisons;
        "looked sick and felt even worse"; "an even (or still)
        more interesting problem"; "still another problem must be
        solved"; "a yet sadder tale" [syn: {even}, {yet}]
     4: without moving or making a sound; "he sat still as a
        statue"; "time stood still"; "they waited stock-still
        outside the door"; "he couldn't hold still any longer"
        [syn: {stock-still}]
     v 1: make calm or still; "quiet the dragons of worry and fear"
          [syn: {calm}, {calm down}, {quiet}, {tranquilize}, {tranquillize},
           {tranquillise}, {quieten}, {lull}] [ant: {agitate}]
     2: cause to be quiet or not talk; "Please silence the children
        in the church!" [syn: {hush}, {quieten}, {silence}, {shut
        up}, {hush up}] [ant: {louden}]
     3: lessen the intensity of or calm; "The news eased my
        conscience"; "still the fears" [syn: {allay}, {relieve}, {ease}]
     4: make motionless
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
