<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stocking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stocking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stock \Stock\ (st[o^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stocked}
   (st[o^]kt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Stocking}.]
   1. To lay up; to put aside for future use; to store, as
      merchandise, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To provide with material requisites; to store; to fill; to
      supply; as, to stock a warehouse, that is, to fill it with
      goods; to stock a farm, that is, to supply it with cattle
      and tools; to stock land, that is, to occupy it with a
      permanent growth, especially of grass.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To suffer to retain milk for twenty-four hours or more
      previous to sale, as cows.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To put in the stocks. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To stock an anchor} (Naut.), to fit it with a stock, or to
      fasten the stock firmly in place.

   {To stock cards} (Card Playing), to arrange cards in a
      certain manner for cheating purposes; -- also called {to
      stack the deck}. [Cant]

   {To stock down} (Agric.), to sow, as plowed land, with grass
      seed, in order that it may become swarded, and produce
      grass.

   {To stock up}, to extirpate; to dig up.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stocking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stocking \Stock"ing\, n. [From {Stock}, which was formerly used
   of a covering for the legs and feet, combining breeches, or
   upper stocks, and stockings, or nether stocks.]
   1. A close-fitting covering for the foot and leg, usually
      knit or woven.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any of various things resembling, or likened to, a
      stocking[1]; as:
      (a) A broad ring of color, differing from the general
          color, on the lower part of the leg of a quadruped;
          esp., a white ring between the coronet and the hock or
          knee of a dark-colored horse.
      (b) A knitted hood of cotton thread which is eventually
          converted by a special process into an incandescent
          mantle for gas lighting.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Blue stocking}. See {Bluestocking}.

   {Stocking frame}, a machine for knitting stockings or other
      hosiery goods.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stocking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stocking \Stock"ing\, v. t.
   To dress in GBs. --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stocking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stocking
     adj : wearing stockings; "walks about in his stockinged (or
           stocking) feet" [syn: {stockinged}]
     n 1: close-fitting hosiery to cover the foot and leg; come in
          matched pairs (usually used in the plural)
     2: the activity of supplying a stock of something; "he
        supervised the stocking of the stream with trout"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
