<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stopmotion</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stopmotion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stop \Stop\, n.
   1. The act of stopping, or the state of being stopped;
      hindrance of progress or of action; cessation; repression;
      interruption; check; obstruction.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is doubtful . . . whether it contributed anything
            to the stop of the infection.         --De Foe.
      [1913 Webster]

            Occult qualities put a stop to the improvement of
            natural philosophy.                   --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is a great step toward the mastery of our desires
            to give this stop to them.            --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which stops, impedes, or obstructs; as obstacle; an
      impediment; an obstruction.
      [1913 Webster]

            A fatal stop traversed their headlong course.
                                                  --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

            So melancholy a prospect should inspire us with zeal
            to oppose some stop to the rising torrent. --Rogers.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.) A device, or piece, as a pin, block, pawl, etc.,
      for arresting or limiting motion, or for determining the
      position to which another part shall be brought.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mus.)
      (a) The closing of an aperture in the air passage, or
          pressure of the finger upon the string, of an
          instrument of music, so as to modify the tone; hence,
          any contrivance by which the sounds of a musical
          instrument are regulated.
          [1913 Webster]

                The organ sound a time survives the stop.
                                                  --Daniel.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) In the organ, one of the knobs or handles at each side
          of the organist, by which he can draw on or shut off
          any register or row of pipes; the register itself; as,
          the vox humana stop.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Arch.) A member, plain or molded, formed of a separate
      piece and fixed to a jamb, against which a door or window
      shuts. This takes the place, or answers the purpose, of a
      rebate. Also, a pin or block to prevent a drawer from
      sliding too far.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A point or mark in writing or printing intended to
      distinguish the sentences, parts of a sentence, or
      clauses; a mark of punctuation. See {Punctuation}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Opt.) The diaphragm used in optical instruments to cut
      off the marginal portions of a beam of light passing
      through lenses.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Zo["o]l.) The depression in the face of a dog between the
      skull and the nasal bones. It is conspicuous in the
      bulldog, pug, and some other breeds.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Phonetics) Some part of the articulating organs, as the
      lips, or the tongue and palate, closed
      (a) so as to cut off the passage of breath or voice
          through the mouth and the nose (distinguished as a
          lip-stop, or a front-stop, etc., as in p, t, d, etc.),
          or
      (b) so as to obstruct, but not entirely cut off, the
          passage, as in l, n, etc.; also, any of the consonants
          so formed. --H. Sweet.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Stop bead} (Arch.), the molding screwed to the inner side of
      a window frame, on the face of the pulley stile,
      completing the groove in which the inner sash is to slide.
      

   {Stop motion} (Mach.), an automatic device for arresting the
      motion of a machine, as when a certain operation is
      completed, or when an imperfection occurs in its
      performance or product, or in the material which is
      supplied to it, etc.

   {Stop plank}, one of a set of planks employed to form a sort
      of dam in some hydraulic works.

   {Stop valve}, a valve that can be closed or opened at will,
      as by hand, for preventing or regulating flow, as of a
      liquid in a pipe; -- in distinction from a valve which is
      operated by the action of the fluid it restrains.

   {Stop watch}, a watch the hands of which can be stopped in
      order to tell exactly the time that has passed, as in
      timing a race. See {Independent seconds watch}, under
      {Independent}, a.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Cessation; check; obstruction; obstacle; hindrance;
        impediment; interruption.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
