<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>storm</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>storm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Storm \Storm\, n. [AS. storm; akin to D. storm, G. sturm, Icel.
   stormr; and perhaps to Gr. ? assault, onset, Skr. s? to flow,
   to hasten, or perhaps to L. sternere to strew, prostrate (cf.
   {Stratum}). [root]166.]
   1. A violent disturbance of the atmosphere, attended by wind,
      rain, snow, hail, or thunder and lightning; hence, often,
      a heavy fall of rain, snow, or hail, whether accompanied
      with wind or not.
      [1913 Webster]

            We hear this fearful tempest sing,
            Yet seek no shelter to avoid the storm. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A violent agitation of human society; a civil, political,
      or domestic commotion; sedition, insurrection, or war;
      violent outbreak; clamor; tumult.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will stir up in England some black storm. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her sister
            Began to scold and raise up such a storm. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A heavy shower or fall, any adverse outburst of tumultuous
      force; violence.
      [1913 Webster]

            A brave man struggling in the storms of fate.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) A violent assault on a fortified place; a furious
      attempt of troops to enter and take a fortified place by
      scaling the walls, forcing the gates, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Storm is often used in the formation of self-explained
         compounds; as, storm-presaging, stormproof,
         storm-tossed, and the like.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Anticyclonic storm} (Meteor.), a storm characterized by a
      central area of high atmospheric pressure, and having a
      system of winds blowing spirally outward in a direction
      contrary to that cyclonic storms. It is attended by low
      temperature, dry air, infrequent precipitation, and often
      by clear sky. Called also {high-area storm},
      {anticyclone}. When attended by high winds, snow, and
      freezing temperatures such storms have various local
      names, as {blizzard}, {wet norther}, {purga}, {buran},
      etc.

   {Cyclonic storm}. (Meteor.) A cyclone, or low-area storm. See
      {Cyclone}, above.

   {Magnetic storm}. See under {Magnetic}.

   {Storm-and-stress period} [a translation of G. sturm und
      drang periode], a designation given to the literary
      agitation and revolutionary development in Germany under
      the lead of Goethe and Schiller in the latter part of the
      18th century.

   {Storm center} (Meteorol.), the center of the area covered by
      a storm, especially by a storm of large extent.

   {Storm door} (Arch.), an extra outside door to prevent the
      entrance of wind, cold, rain, etc.; -- usually removed in
      summer.

   {Storm path} (Meteorol.), the course over which a storm, or
      storm center, travels.

   {Storm petrel}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Stormy petrel}, under
      {Petrel}.

   {Storm sail} (Naut.), any one of a number of strong, heavy
      sails that are bent and set in stormy weather.

   {Storm scud}. See the Note under {Cloud}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Tempest; violence; agitation; calamity.

   Usage: {Storm}, {Tempest}. Storm is violent agitation, a
          commotion of the elements by wind, etc., but not
          necessarily implying the fall of anything from the
          clouds. Hence, to call a mere fall or rain without
          wind a storm is a departure from the true sense of the
          word. A tempest is a sudden and violent storm, such as
          those common on the coast of Italy, where the term
          originated, and is usually attended by a heavy rain,
          with lightning and thunder.
          [1913 Webster]

                Storms beat, and rolls the main;
                O! beat those storms, and roll the seas, in
                vain.                             --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]

                What at first was called a gust, the same
                Hath now a storm's, anon a tempest's name.
                                                  --Donne.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>storm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Storm \Storm\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stormed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Storming}.] (Mil.)
   To assault; to attack, and attempt to take, by scaling walls,
   forcing gates, breaches, or the like; as, to storm a
   fortified town.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>storm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Storm \Storm\, v. i. [Cf. AS. styrman.]
   1. To raise a tempest. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To blow with violence; also, to rain, hail, snow, or the
      like, usually in a violent manner, or with high wind; --
      used impersonally; as, it storms.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To rage; to be in a violent passion; to fume.
      [1913 Webster]

            The master storms, the lady scolds.   --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>storm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>STORM
     Statistically-Oriented Matrix Program
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>storm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>storm
     n 1: a violent weather condition with winds 64-72 knots (11 on
          the Beaufort scale) and precipitation and thunder and
          lightening [syn: {violent storm}]
     2: a violent commotion or disturbance; "the storms that had
        characterized their relationship had died away"; "it was
        only a tempest in a teapot" [syn: {tempest}]
     3: a direct and violent assault on a stronghold
     v 1: behave violently, as if in state of a great anger [syn: {ramp},
           {rage}]
     2: take by force; "Storm the fort" [syn: {force}]
     3: rain, hail, or snow hard and be very windy, often with
        thunder or lightning; "If it storms, we'll need shelter"
     4: blow hard; "It was storming all night"
     5: attack by storm; attack suddenly [syn: {surprise}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
