<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stove</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hydrocarbon \Hy`dro*car"bon\, n. [Hydro-, 2 + carbon.] (Chem.)
   A compound containing only hydrogen and carbon, as methane,
   benzene, etc.; also, by extension, any of their derivatives.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Hydrocarbon burner}, {furnace}, {stove}, a burner, furnace,
      or stove with which liquid fuel, as petroleum, is used.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stave \Stave\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Staved} (st[=a]vd) or
   {Stove} (st[=o]v); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Staving}.] [From {Stave},
   n., or {Staff}, n.]
   1. To break in a stave or the staves of; to break a hole in;
      to burst; -- often with in; as, to stave a cask; to stave
      in a boat.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To push, as with a staff; -- with off.
      [1913 Webster]

            The condition of a servant staves him off to a
            distance.                             --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To delay by force or craft; to drive away; -- usually with
      off; as, to stave off the execution of a project.
      [1913 Webster]

            And answered with such craft as women use,
            Guilty or guiltless, to stave off a chance
            That breaks upon them perilously.     --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To suffer, or cause, to be lost by breaking the cask.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the wine in the city has been staved. --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To furnish with staves or rundles. --Knolles.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To render impervious or solid by driving with a calking
      iron; as, to stave lead, or the joints of pipes into which
      lead has been run.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To stave and tail}, in bear baiting, (to stave) to interpose
      with the staff, doubtless to stop the bear; (to tail) to
      hold back the dog by the tail. --Nares.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stove \Stove\ (st[=o]v),
   imp. of {Stave}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stove \Stove\, n. [D. stoof a foot stove, originally, a heated
   room, a room for a bath; akin to G. stube room, OHG. stuba a
   heated room, AS. stofe, Icel. stofa a room, bathing room, Sw.
   stufva, stuga, a room, Dan. stue; of unknown origin. Cf.
   {Estufa}, {Stew}, {Stufa}.]
   1. A house or room artificially warmed or heated; a forcing
      house, or hothouse; a drying room; -- formerly,
      designating an artificially warmed dwelling or room, a
      parlor, or a bathroom, but now restricted, in this sense,
      to heated houses or rooms used for horticultural purposes
      or in the processes of the arts.
      [1913 Webster]

            When most of the waiters were commanded away to
            their supper, the parlor or stove being nearly
            emptied, in came a company of musketeers. --Earl of
                                                  Strafford.
      [1913 Webster]

            How tedious is it to them that live in stoves and
            caves half a year together, as in Iceland, Muscovy,
            or under the pole!                    --Burton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An apparatus, consisting essentially of a receptacle for
      fuel, made of iron, brick, stone, or tiles, and variously
      constructed, in which fire is made or kept for warming a
      room or a house, or for culinary or other purposes.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, in modern dwellings: An appliance having a top
      surface with fittings suitable for heating pots and pans
      for cooking, frying, or boiling food, most commonly heated
      by gas or electricity, and often combined with an oven in
      a single unit; a {cooking stove}. Such units commonly have
      two to six heating surfaces, called burners, even if they
      are heated by electricity rather than a gas flame.
      [PJC]

   {Cooking stove}, a stove with an oven, opening for pots,
      kettles, and the like, -- used for cooking.

   {Dry stove}. See under {Dry}.

   {Foot stove}. See under {Foot}.

   {Franklin stove}. See in the Vocabulary.

   {Stove plant} (Bot.), a plant which requires artificial heat
      to make it grow in cold or cold temperate climates.

   {Stove plate}, thin iron castings for the parts of stoves.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stove \Stove\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stoved}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Stoving}.]
   1. To keep warm, in a house or room, by artificial heat; as,
      to stove orange trees. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To heat or dry, as in a stove; as, to stove feathers.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stave
     n 1: (music) the system of five horizontal lines on which the
          musical notes are written [syn: {staff}]
     2: one of several thin slats of wood forming the sides of a
        barrel or bucket [syn: {lag}]
     3: a crosspiece between the legs of a chair [syn: {rung}, {round}]
     v 1: furnich with staves; "stave a ladder"
     2: burst or force (a hole) into something [syn: {stave in}]
     [also: {stove}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stove
     n 1: a kitchen appliance used for cooking food; "dinner was
          already on the stove" [syn: {kitchen stove}, {range}, {kitchen
          range}, {cooking stove}]
     2: any heating apparatus
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stove</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stove
     See {stave}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
