<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>strap</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>strap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Strap \Strap\, n. [OE. strope, AS. stropp, L. stroppus,
   struppus, perhaps fr. Gr. ? a band or cord, fr. ? to twist,
   to turn (cf. {Strophe}). Cf. {Strop} a strap, a piece of
   rope.]
   1. A long, narrow, pliable strip of leather, cloth, or the
      like; specifically, a strip of thick leather used in
      flogging.
      [1913 Webster]

            A lively cobbler that . . . had scarce passed a day
            without giving her [his wife] the discipline of the
            strap.                                --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Something made of such a strip, or of a part of one, or a
      combination of two or more for a particular use; as, a
      boot strap, shawl strap, stirrup strap.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A piece of leather, or strip of wood covered with a
      suitable material, for sharpening a razor; a strop.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A narrow strip of anything, as of iron or brass.
      Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) (Carp. &amp; Mach.) A band, plate, or loop of metal for
          clasping and holding timbers or parts of a machine.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) (Naut.) A piece of rope or metal passing around a
          block and used for fastening it to anything.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Bot.)
      (a) The flat part of the corolla in ligulate florets, as
          those of the white circle in the daisy.
      (b) The leaf, exclusive of its sheath, in some grasses.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. A shoulder strap. See under {Shoulder}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Strap bolt}, a bolt of which one end is a flat bar of
      considerable length.

   {Strap head} (Mach.), a journal box, or pair of brasses,
      secured to the end of a connecting rod by a strap. See
      Illust. of {Gib and key}, under {Gib}.

   {Strap hinge}, a hinge with long flaps by which it is
      fastened, as to a door or wall.

   {Strap rail} (Railroads), a flat rail formerly used.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>strap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Strap \Strap\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Strapped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Strapping}.]
   1. To beat or chastise with a strap.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fasten or bind with a strap. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To sharpen by rubbing on a strap, or strop; as, to strap a
      razor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>strap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>strap
     n 1: an elongated leather strip (or or strip of similar material)
          for binding things together or holding something in
          position
     2: hanger consisting of a loop of leather suspended from the
        ceiling of a bus or train; passengers hold onto it
     3: a band that goes over the shoulder and supports a garment or
        bag [syn: {shoulder strap}]
     4: whip consisting of a strip of leather used in flogging
     v 1: tie with a strap [ant: {unstrap}]
     2: beat severely with a whip or rod; "The teacher often flogged
        the students"; "The children were severely trounced" [syn:
         {flog}, {welt}, {whip}, {lather}, {lash}, {slash}, {trounce}]
     3: sharpen with a strap; "strap a razor"
     4: secure (a sprained joint) with a strap
     [also: {strapping}, {strapped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
