<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>street</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>street</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Street
   The street called "Straight" at Damascus (Acts 9:11) is "a long
   broad street, running from east to west, about a mile in length,
   and forming the principal thoroughfare in the city." In Oriental
   towns streets are usually narrow and irregular and filthy (Ps.
   18:42; Isa. 10:6). "It is remarkable," says Porter, "that all
   the important cities of Palestine and Syria Samaria, Caesarea,
   Gerasa, Bozrah, Damascus, Palmyra, had their 'straight streets'
   running through the centre of the city, and lined with stately
   rows of columns. The most perfect now remaining are those of
   Palmyra and Gerasa, where long ranges of the columns still
   stand.", Through Samaria, etc.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>street</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Street \Street\ (str[=e]t), n. [OE. strete, AS. str[=ae]t, fr.
   L. strata (sc. via) a paved way, properly fem. p. p. of
   sternere, stratum, to spread; akin to E. strew. See {Strew},
   and cf. {Stratum}, {Stray}, v. &amp; a.]
   1. Originally, a paved way or road; a public highway; now
      commonly, a thoroughfare in a city or village, bordered by
      dwellings or business houses.
      [1913 Webster]

            He removed [the body of] Amasa from the street unto
            the field.                            --Coverdale.
      [1913 Webster]

            At home or through the high street passing.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In an extended sense, street designates besides the
         roadway, the walks, houses, shops, etc., which border
         the thoroughfare.
         [1913 Webster]

               His deserted mansion in Duke Street. --Macaulay.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. the roadway of a street[1], as distinguished from the
      sidewalk; as, children playing in the street.
      [PJC]

   3. the inhabitants of a particular street; as, the whole
      street knew about their impending divorce.
      [PJC]

   {The street} (Broker's Cant), that thoroughfare of a city
      where the leading bankers and brokers do business; also,
      figuratively, those who do business there; as, the street
      would not take the bonds.

   {on the street},
      (a) homeless.
      (b) unemployed.
      (a) not in prison, or released from prison; the murderer
          is still on the street. 

   {Street Arab}, {Street broker}, etc. See under {Arab},
      {Broker}, etc.

   {Street door}, a door which opens upon a street, or is
      nearest the street.

   {street person}, a homeless person; a vagrant.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Syn: See {Way}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>street</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>street
     n 1: a thoroughfare (usually including sidewalks) that is lined
          with buildings; "they walked the streets of the small
          town"; "he lives on Nassau Street"
     2: the part of a thoroughfare between the sidewalks; the part
        of the thoroughfare on which vehicles travel; "be careful
        crossing the street"
     3: the streets of a city viewed as a depressed environment in
        which there is poverty and crime and prostitution and
        dereliction; "she tried to keep her children off the
        street"
     4: a situation offering opportunities; "he worked both sides of
        the street"; "cooperation is a two-way street"
     5: people living or working on the same street; "the whole
        street protested the absence of street lights"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
