<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>streetcar</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>streetcar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Car \Car\, n. [OF. car, char, F. cahr, fr. L. carrus, Wagon: a
   Celtic word; cf. W. car, Armor. karr, Ir. &amp; Gael. carr. cf.
   {Chariot}.]
   1. A small vehicle moved on wheels; usually, one having but
      two wheels and drawn by one horse; a cart.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A vehicle adapted to the rails of a railroad. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In England a railroad passenger car is called a railway
         carriage; a freight car a goods wagon; a platform car a
         goods truck; a baggage car a van. But styles of car
         introduced into England from America are called cars;
         as, tram car. Pullman car. See {Train}.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. A chariot of war or of triumph; a vehicle of splendor,
      dignity, or solemnity. [Poetic].
      [1913 Webster]

            The gilded car of day.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The towering car, the sable steeds.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Astron.) The stars also called Charles's Wain, the Great
      Bear, or the Dipper.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Pleiads, Hyads, and the Northern Car. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The cage of a lift or elevator.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The basket, box, or cage suspended from a balloon to
      contain passengers, ballast, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A floating perforated box for living fish. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Car coupling}, or {Car coupler}, a shackle or other device
      for connecting the cars in a railway train. [U. S.]

   {Dummy car} (Railroad), a car containing its own steam power
      or locomotive.

   {Freight car} (Railrood), a car for the transportation of
      merchandise or other goods. [U. S.]

   {Hand car} (Railroad), a small car propelled by hand, used by
      railroad laborers, etc. [U. S.]

   {Horse car}, or {Street car}, an omnibus car, draw by horses
      or other power upon rails laid in the streets. [U. S.]

   {Palace car}, {Drawing-room car}, {Sleeping car}, {Parlor
   car}, etc. (Railroad), cars especially designed and furnished
      for the comfort of travelers.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>streetcar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>streetcar
     n : a wheeled vehicle that runs on rails and is propelled by
         electricity; "`tram' and `tramcar' are British terms"
         [syn: {tram}, {tramcar}, {trolley}, {trolley car}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
