<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>striking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>striking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Strike \Strike\, v. t. [imp. {Struck}; p. p. {Struck},
   {Stricken}({Stroock}, {Strucken}, Obs.); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Striking}. Struck is more commonly used in the p. p. than
   stricken.] [OE. striken to strike, proceed, flow, AS.
   str[=i]can to go, proceed, akin to D. strijken to rub,
   stroke, strike, to move, go, G. streichen, OHG. str[=i]hhan,
   L. stringere to touch lightly, to graze, to strip off (but
   perhaps not to L. stringere in sense to draw tight), striga a
   row, a furrow. Cf. {Streak}, {Stroke}.]
   1. To touch or hit with some force, either with the hand or
      with an instrument; to smite; to give a blow to, either
      with the hand or with any instrument or missile.
      [1913 Webster]

            He at Philippi kept
            His sword e'en like a dancer; while I struck
            The lean and wrinkled Cassius.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To come in collision with; to strike against; as, a bullet
      struck him; the wave struck the boat amidships; the ship
      struck a reef.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give, as a blow; to impel, as with a blow; to give a
      force to; to dash; to cast.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shall take of the blood, and strike it on the
            two sideposts.                        --Ex. xii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who would be free, themselves must strike the blow.
                                                  --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To stamp or impress with a stroke; to coin; as, to strike
      coin from metal: to strike dollars at the mint.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To thrust in; to cause to enter or penetrate; to set in
      the earth; as, a tree strikes its roots deep.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To punish; to afflict; to smite.
      [1913 Webster]

            To punish the just is not good, nor strike princes
            for equity.                           --Prov. xvii.
                                                  26.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cause to sound by one or more beats; to indicate or
      notify by audible strokes; as, the clock strikes twelve;
      the drums strike up a march.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To lower; to let or take down; to remove; as, to strike
      sail; to strike a flag or an ensign, as in token of
      surrender; to strike a yard or a topmast in a gale; to
      strike a tent; to strike the centering of an arch.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To make a sudden impression upon, as by a blow; to affect
      sensibly with some strong emotion; as, to strike the mind,
      with surprise; to strike one with wonder, alarm, dread, or
      horror.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nice works of art strike and surprise us most on the
            first view.                           --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

            They please as beauties, here as wonders strike.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To affect in some particular manner by a sudden
       impression or impulse; as, the plan proposed strikes me
       favorably; to strike one dead or blind.
       [1913 Webster]

             How often has stricken you dumb with his irony!
                                                  --Landor.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To cause or produce by a stroke, or suddenly, as by a
       stroke; as, to strike a light.
       [1913 Webster]

             Waving wide her myrtle wand,
             She strikes a universal peace through sea and land.
                                                  --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To cause to ignite; as, to strike a match.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To make and ratify; as, to strike a bargain.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Probably borrowed from the L. f[oe]dus ferrire, to
         strike a compact, so called because an animal was
         struck and killed as a sacrifice on such occasions.
         [1913 Webster]

   14. To take forcibly or fraudulently; as, to strike money.
       [Old Slang]
       [1913 Webster]

   15. To level, as a measure of grain, salt, or the like, by
       scraping off with a straight instrument what is above the
       level of the top.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. (Masonry) To cut off, as a mortar joint, even with the
       face of the wall, or inward at a slight angle.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. To hit upon, or light upon, suddenly; as, my eye struck a
       strange word; they soon struck the trail.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. To borrow money of; to make a demand upon; as, he struck
       a friend for five dollars. [Slang]
       [1913 Webster]

   19. To lade into a cooler, as a liquor. --B. Edwards.
       [1913 Webster]

   20. To stroke or pass lightly; to wave.
       [1913 Webster]

             Behold, I thought, He will . . . strike his hand
             over the place, and recover the leper. --2 Kings v.
                                                  11.
       [1913 Webster]

   21. To advance; to cause to go forward; -- used only in past
       participle. ``Well struck in years.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To strike an attitude}, {To strike a balance}. See under
      {Attitude}, and {Balance}.

   {To strike a jury} (Law), to constitute a special jury
      ordered by a court, by each party striking out a certain
      number of names from a prepared list of jurors, so as to
      reduce it to the number of persons required by law.
      --Burrill.

   {To strike a lead}.
       (a) (Mining) To find a vein of ore.
       (b) Fig.: To find a way to fortune. [Colloq.]

   {To strike a ledger} or {To strike an account}, to balance
      it.

   {To strike hands with}.
       (a) To shake hands with. --Halliwell.
       (b) To make a compact or agreement with; to agree with.
           

   {To strike off}.
       (a) To erase from an account; to deduct; as, to strike
           off the interest of a debt.
       (b) (Print.) To impress; to print; as, to strike off a
           thousand copies of a book.
       (c) To separate by a blow or any sudden action; as, to
           strike off what is superfluous or corrupt.

   {To strike oil}, to find petroleum when boring for it;
      figuratively, to make a lucky hit financially. [Slang,
      U.S.]

   {To strike one luck}, to shake hands with one and wish good
      luck. [Obs.] --Beau. &amp; Fl.

   {To strike out}.
       (a) To produce by collision; to force out, as, to strike
           out sparks with steel.
       (b) To blot out; to efface; to erase. ``To methodize is
           as necessary as to strike out.'' --Pope.
       (c) To form by a quick effort; to devise; to invent; to
           contrive, as, to strike out a new plan of finance.
       (d) (Baseball) To cause a player to strike out; -- said
           of the pitcher. See {To strike out}, under {Strike},
           v. i.

   {To strike sail}. See under {Sail}.

   {To strike up}.
       (a) To cause to sound; to begin to beat. ``Strike up the
           drums.'' --Shak.
       (b) To begin to sing or play; as, to strike up a tune.
       (c) To raise (as sheet metal), in making diahes, pans,
           etc., by blows or pressure in a die.

   {To strike work}, to quit work; to go on a strike.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>striking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Striking \Strik"ing\,
   a. &amp; n. from {Strike}, v.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Striking distance}, the distance through which an object can
      be reached by striking; the distance at which a force is
      effective when directed to a particular object.

   {Striking plate}.
   (a) The plate against which the latch of a door lock strikes
       as the door is closed.
   (b) A part of the centering of an arch, which is driven back
       to loosen the centering in striking it.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>striking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Striking \Strik"ing\, a.
   Affecting with strong emotions; surprising; forcible;
   impressive; very noticeable; as, a striking representation or
   image; a striking resemblance. ``A striking fact.'' --De
   Quincey. -- {Strik"ing*ly}, adv. -- {Strik"ing*ness}, n.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>striking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>striking
     adj 1: sensational in appearance or thrilling in effect; "a
            dramatic sunset"; "a dramatic pause"; "a spectacular
            display of northern lights"; "it was a spectacular
            play"; "his striking good looks always created a
            sensation" [syn: {dramatic}, {spectacular}]
     2: having a quality that thrusts itself into attention; "an
        outstanding fact of our time is that nations poisoned by
        anti semitism proved less fortunate in regard to their own
        freedom"; "a new theory is the most prominent feature of
        the book"; "salient traits"; "a spectacular rise in
        prices"; "a striking thing about Picadilly Circus is the
        statue of Eros in the center"; "a striking resemblance
        between parent and child" [syn: {outstanding}, {prominent},
         {salient}, {spectacular}]
     n 1: the physical coming together of two or more things; "contact
          with the pier scraped paint from the hull" [syn: {contact},
           {impinging}]
     2: the act of contacting one thing with another; "repeated
        hitting raised a large bruise"; "after three misses she
        finally got a hit" [syn: {hit}, {hitting}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
