<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>string</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>string</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>string
     
        &lt;programming&gt; A sequence of {data} values, usually {bytes},
        which usually stand for {characters} (a "character string").
        The {mapping} between values and characters is determined by
        the {character set} which is itself specified implcitly or
        explicitly by the environment in which the string is being
        interpreted.
     
        The most common character set is {ASCII} but, since the late
        1990s, there has been increased interest in larger character
        sets such as {Unicode} where each character is represented by
        more than eight {bits}.
     
        Most programming languages consider strings (e.g.
        "124:shabooya:\n", "hello world") basically distinct from
        numbers which are typically stored in fixed-length {binary} or
        {floating-point} representation.
     
        A {bit string} is a sequence of {bit}s.
     
        (1999-12-21)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>string</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>String \String\ (str[i^]ng), n. [OE. string, streng, AS. streng;
   akin to D. streng, G. strang, Icel. strengr, Sw. str["a]ng,
   Dan. str[ae]ng; probably from the adj., E. strong (see
   {Strong}); or perhaps originally meaning, twisted, and akin
   to E. strangle.]
   1. A small cord, a line, a twine, or a slender strip of
      leather, or other substance, used for binding together,
      fastening, or tying things; a cord, larger than a thread
      and smaller than a rope; as, a shoe string; a bonnet
      string; a silken string. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Round Ormond's knee thou tiest the mystic string.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A thread or cord on which a number of objects or parts are
      strung or arranged in close and orderly succession; hence,
      a line or series of things arranged on a thread, or as if
      so arranged; a succession; a concatenation; a chain; as, a
      string of shells or beads; a string of dried apples; a
      string of houses; a string of arguments. ``A string of
      islands.'' --Gibbon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A strip, as of leather, by which the covers of a book are
      held together. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The cord of a musical instrument, as of a piano, harp, or
      violin; specifically (pl.), the stringed instruments of an
      orchestra, in distinction from the wind instruments; as,
      the strings took up the theme. ``An instrument of ten
      strings.'' --Ps. xxx. iii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Me softer airs befit, and softer strings
            Of lute, or viol still.               --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The line or cord of a bow. --Ps. xi. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            He twangs the grieving string.        --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A fiber, as of a plant; a little, fibrous root.
      [1913 Webster]

            Duckweed putteth forth a little string into the
            water, from the bottom.               --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A nerve or tendon of an animal body.
      [1913 Webster]

            The string of his tongue was loosed.  --Mark vii.
                                                  35.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Shipbuilding) An inside range of ceiling planks,
      corresponding to the sheer strake on the outside and
      bolted to it.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Bot.) The tough fibrous substance that unites the valves
      of the pericap of leguminous plants, and which is readily
      pulled off; as, the strings of beans.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mining) A small, filamentous ramification of a metallic
       vein. --Ure.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Arch.) Same as {Stringcourse}.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Billiards) The points made in a game.
       [1913 Webster]

   13.
       (a) In various indoor games, a score or tally, sometimes,
           as in American billiard games, marked by buttons
           threaded on a string or wire.
       (b) In various games, competitions, etc., a certain
           number of turns at play, of rounds, etc.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   14. (Billiards &amp; Pool)
       (a) The line from behind and over which the cue ball must
           be played after being out of play as by being
           pocketed or knocked off the table; -- called also
           {string line}.
       (b) Act of stringing for break.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   15. A hoax; a trumped-up or ``fake'' story. [Slang]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   16. a sequence of similar objects or events sufficiently
       close in time or space to be perceived as a group; a
       string of accidents; a string of restaurants on a
       highway.
       [PJC]

   17. (Physics) A one-dimensional string-like mathematical
       object used as a means of representing the properties of
       fundamental particles in {string theory}, one theory of
       particle physics; such hypothetical objects are
       one-dimensional and very small (10^{-33} cm) but exist in
       more than four spatial dimensions, and have various modes
       of vibration. Considering particles as strings avoids
       some of the problems of treating particles as points, and
       allows a unified treatment of gravity along with the
       other three forces (electromagnetism, the weak force, and
       the strong force) in a manner consistent with quantum
       mechanics. See also {string theory}.
       [PJC]

   {String band} (Mus.), a band of musicians using only, or
      chiefly, stringed instruments.

   {String beans}.
       (a) A dish prepared from the unripe pods of several kinds
           of beans; -- so called because the strings are
           stripped off.
       (b) Any kind of beans in which the pods are used for
           cooking before the seeds are ripe; usually, the low
           bush bean.

   {To have two strings to one's bow}, to have a means or
      expedient in reserve in case the one employed fails.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>string</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>String \String\, v. i.
   To form into a string or strings, as a substance which is
   stretched, or people who are moving along, etc.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>string</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>String \String\ (str[i^]ng), v. t. [imp. {Strung} (str[u^]ng);
   p. p. {Strung} (R. {Stringed} (str[i^]ngd)); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Stringing}.]
   1. To furnish with strings; as, to string a violin.
      [1913 Webster]

            Has not wise nature strung the legs and feet
            With firmest nerves, designed to walk the street?
                                                  --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put in tune the strings of, as a stringed instrument,
      in order to play upon it.
      [1913 Webster]

            For here the Muse so oft her harp has strung,
            That not a mountain rears its head unsung.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To put on a string; to file; as, to string beads.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make tense; to strengthen.
      [1913 Webster]

            Toil strung the nerves, and purified the blood.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To deprive of strings; to strip the strings from; as, to
      string beans. See {String}, n., 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To hoax; josh; jolly; often used with along; as, we strung
      him along all day until he realized we were kidding.
      [Slang]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>string</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>string
     n 1: a lightweight cord [syn: {twine}]
     2: stringed instruments that are played with a bow; "the
        strings played superlatively well" [syn: {bowed stringed
        instrument}]
     3: a tightly stretched cord of wire or gut, which makes sound
        when plucked, struck, or bowed
     4: a sequentially ordered set of things or events or ideas in
        which each successive member is related to the preceding;
        "a string of islands"; "train of mourners"; "a train of
        thought" [syn: {train}]
     5: a linear sequence of symbols (characters or words or
        phrases)
     6: a tie consisting of a cord that goes through a seam around
        an opening; "he pulled the drawstring and closed the bag"
        [syn: {drawstring}, {drawing string}]
     7: a collection of objects threaded on a single strand
     8: a necklace made by a stringing objects together; "a string
        of beads"; "a strand of pearls"; [syn: {chain}, {strand}]
     v 1: thread on or as if on a string; "string pearls on a string";
          "the child drew glass beads on a string"; "thread dried
          cranberries" [syn: {thread}, {draw}]
     2: add as if on a string; "string these ideas together";
        "string up these songs and you'll have a musical" [syn: {string
        up}]
     3: move or come along [syn: {string along}]
     4: stretch out or arrange like a string
     5: string together; tie or fasten with a string; "string the
        package"
     6: remove the stringy parts of; "string beans"
     7: provide with strings; "string my guitar" [ant: {unstring}]
     [also: {strung}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
