<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stroke</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stroke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stroke
     
        The oblique stroke character, "/", ASCII 47.
     
        See {ASCII} for other synonyms.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stroke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stroke \Stroke\, obs. imp. of {Strike}.
   Struck.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stroke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stroke \Stroke\, n. [OE. strok, strook, strak, fr. striken. See
   {Strike}, v. t.]
   1. The act of striking; a blow; a hit; a knock; esp., a
      violent or hostile attack made with the arm or hand, or
      with an instrument or weapon.
      [1913 Webster]

            His hand fetcheth a stroke with the ax to cut down
            the tree.                             --Deut. xix.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

            A fool's lips enter into contention and his mouth
            calleth for strokes.                  --Prov. xviii.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

            He entered and won the whole kingdom of Naples
            without striking a stroke.            --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The result of effect of a striking; injury or affliction;
      soreness.
      [1913 Webster]

            In the day that Lord bindeth up the breach of his
            people, and healeth the stroke of their wound.
                                                  --Isa. xxx.
                                                  26.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The striking of the clock to tell the hour.
      [1913 Webster]

            Well, but what's o'clock?
            - Upon the stroke of ten. -- Well, let is strike.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A gentle, caressing touch or movement upon something; a
      stroking. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A mark or dash in writing or printing; a line; the touch
      of a pen or pencil; as, an up stroke; a firm stroke.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, lasting as those colors may they shine,
            Free as thy stroke, yet faultless as thy line.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Hence, by extension, an addition or amandment to a written
      composition; a touch; as, to give some finishing strokes
      to an essay. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A sudden attack of disease; especially, a fatal attack; a
      severe disaster; any affliction or calamity, especially a
      sudden one; as, a stroke of apoplexy; the stroke of death.
      [1913 Webster]

            At this one stroke the man looked dead in law.
                                                  --Harte.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A throb or beat, as of the heart. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. One of a series of beats or movements against a resisting
      medium, by means of which movement through or upon it is
      accomplished; as, the stroke of a bird's wing in flying,
      or an oar in rowing, of a skater, swimmer, etc.; also:
      (Rowing)
      (a) The rate of succession of stroke; as, a quick stroke.
      (b) The oar nearest the stern of a boat, by which the
          other oars are guided; -- called also {stroke oar}.
      (c) The rower who pulls the stroke oar; the strokesman.
          [1913 Webster]

   10. A powerful or sudden effort by which something is done,
       produced, or accomplished; also, something done or
       accomplished by such an effort; as, a stroke of genius; a
       stroke of business; a master stroke of policy.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Mach.) The movement, in either direction, of the piston
       plunger, piston rod, crosshead, etc., as of a steam
       engine or a pump, in which these parts have a
       reciprocating motion; as, the forward stroke of a piston;
       also, the entire distance passed through, as by a piston,
       in such a movement; as, the piston is at half stroke.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: The respective strokes are distinguished as up and down
         strokes, outward and inward strokes, forward and back
         strokes, the forward stroke in stationary steam engines
         being toward the crosshead, but in locomotives toward
         the front of the vehicle.
         [1913 Webster]

   12. Power; influence. [Obs.] ``Where money beareth [hath] all
       the stroke.'' --Robynson (More's Utopia).
       [1913 Webster]

             He has a great stroke with the reader. --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Appetite. [Obs.] --Swift.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To keep stroke}, to make strokes in unison.
      [1913 Webster]

            The oars where silver,
            Which to the tune of flutes kept stroke. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stroke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stroke \Stroke\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Strokeed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Strokeing}.] [OE. stroken, straken, AS. str[=a]cian, fr.
   str[=i]can to go over, pass. See {Strike}, v. t., and cf.
   {Straggle}.]
   1. To strike. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye mote with the plat sword again
            Stroken him in the wound, and it will close.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To rib gently in one direction; especially, to pass the
      hand gently over by way of expressing kindness or
      tenderness; to caress; to soothe.
      [1913 Webster]

            He dried the falling drops, and, yet more kind,
            He stroked her cheeks.                --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make smooth by rubbing. --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Masonry) To give a finely fluted surface to.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To row the stroke oar of; as, to stroke a boat.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stroke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stroke n. Common name for the slant (`/', ASCII 0101111) character. See
   {ASCII} for other synonyms.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stroke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stroke
     n 1: (sports) the act of swinging or striking at a ball with a
          club or racket or bat or cue or hand; "it took two
          strokes to get out of the bunker"; "a good shot require
          good balance and tempo"; "he left me an almost
          impossible shot" [syn: {shot}]
     2: the maximum movement available to a pivoted or reciprocating
        piece by a cam [syn: {throw}, {cam stroke}]
     3: a sudden loss of consciousness resulting when the rupture or
        occlusion of a blood vessel leads to oxygen lack in the
        brain [syn: {apoplexy}, {cerebrovascular accident}, {CVA}]
     4: a light touch
     5: a light touch with the hands [syn: {stroking}]
     6: the oarsman nearest the stern of the shell who sets the pace
        for the rest of the crew
     7: a punctuation mark (/) used to separate related items of
        information [syn: {solidus}, {slash}, {virgule}, {diagonal},
         {separatrix}]
     8: a mark made by a writing implement (as in cursive writing)
     9: any one of the repeated movements of the limbs and body used
        for locomotion in swimming or rowing
     10: a single complete movement
     v 1: touch lightly and with affection, with brushing motions; "He
          stroked his long beard" [syn: {fondle}]
     2: strike a ball with a smooth blow
     3: row at a particular rate
     4: treat gingerly or carefully; "You have to stroke the boss"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
