<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>structure</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>structure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Structure \Struc"ture\, n. [L. structura, from struere,
   structum, to arrange, build, construct; perhaps akin to E.
   strew: cf. F. structure. Cf. {Construe}, {Destroy},
   {Instrument}, {Obstruct}.]
   1. The act of building; the practice of erecting buildings;
      construction. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            His son builds on, and never is content
            Till the last farthing is in structure spent. --J.
                                                  Dryden, Jr.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Manner of building; form; make; construction.
      [1913 Webster]

            Want of insight into the structure and constitution
            of the terraqueous globe.             --Woodward.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Arrangement of parts, of organs, or of constituent
      particles, in a substance or body; as, the structure of a
      rock or a mineral; the structure of a sentence.
      [1913 Webster]

            It [basalt] has often a prismatic structure. --Dana.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Biol.) Manner of organization; the arrangement of the
      different tissues or parts of animal and vegetable
      organisms; as, organic structure, or the structure of
      animals and plants; cellular structure.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is built; a building; esp., a building of some
      size or magnificence; an edifice.
      [1913 Webster]

            There stands a structure of majestic frame. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Columnar structure}. See under {Columnar}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>structure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>structure
     n 1: a thing constructed; a complex construction or entity; "the
          structure consisted of a series of arches"; "she wore
          her hair in an amazing construction of whirls and
          ribbons" [syn: {construction}]
     2: the manner of construction of something and the arrangement
        of its parts; "artists must study the structure of the
        human body"; "the structure of the benzene molecule"
     3: the complex composition of knowledge as elements and their
        combinations; "his lectures have no structure"
     4: a particular complex anatomical structure; "he has good bone
        structure" [syn: {anatomical structure}, {complex body
        part}, {bodily structure}, {body structure}]
     5: the people in a society considered as a system organized by
        a characteristic pattern of relationships; "the social
        organization of England and America is very different";
        "sociologists have studied the changing structure of the
        family" [syn: {social organization}, {social organisation},
         {social structure}, {social system}]
     v : give a structure to; "I need to structure my days"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
