<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stuffing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stuffing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stuffing \Stuff"ing\, n.
   1. That which is used for filling anything; as, the stuffing
      of a saddle or cushion.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Cookery) Any seasoning preparation used to stuff meat;
      especially, a composition of bread, condiments, spices,
      etc.; forcemeat; dressing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A mixture of oil and tallow used in softening and dressing
      leather.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Stuffing box}, a device for rendering a joint impervious
      where there is a hole through which a movable cylindrical
      body, as the paston rod of a steam engine, or the plunger
      of a pump, slides back and forth, or in which a shaft
      turns. It usually consists of a box or chamber, made by an
      enlargement of part of the hole, forming a space around
      the rod or shaft for containing packing which is
      compressed and made to fill the space closely by means of
      a sleeve, called the gland, which fits loosely around the
      rod, and is pressed upon the packing by bolts or other
      means.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stuffing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stuff \Stuff\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stuffed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Stuffing}.] [OE. stoffen; cf. OF. estoffer, F. ['e]toffer,
   to put stuff in, to stuff, to line, also, OF. estouffer to
   stifle, F. ['e]touffer; both perhaps of Teutonic origin, and
   akin to E. stop. Cf. {Stop}, v. t., {Stuff}, n.]
   1. To fill by crowding something into; to cram with
      something; to load to excess; as, to stuff a bedtick.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sometimes this crook drew hazel bought adown,
            And stuffed her apron wide with nuts so brown.
                                                  --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lest the gods, for sin,
            Should with a swelling dropsy stuff thy skin.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To thrust or crowd; to press; to pack.
      [1913 Webster]

            Put roses into a glass with a narrow mouth, stuffing
            them close together . . . and they retain smell and
            color.                                --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fill by being pressed or packed into.
      [1913 Webster]

            With inward arms the dire machine they load,
            And iron bowels stuff the dark abode. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Cookery) To fill with a seasoning composition of bread,
      meat, condiments, etc.; as, to stuff a turkey.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To obstruct, as any of the organs; to affect with some
      obstruction in the organs of sense or respiration.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'm stuffed, cousin; I can not smell. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To fill the skin of, for the purpose of preserving as a
      specimen; -- said of birds or other animals.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To form or fashion by packing with the necessary material.
      [1913 Webster]

            An Eastern king put a judge to death for an
            iniquitous sentence, and ordered his hide to be
            stuffed into a cushion, and placed upon the
            tribunal.                             --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To crowd with facts; to cram the mind of; sometimes, to
      crowd or fill with false or idle tales or fancies.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To put fraudulent votes into (a ballot box). [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stuffing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stuffing
     n 1: a mixture of seasoned ingredients used to stuff meats and
          vegetables [syn: {dressing}]
     2: padding put in mattresses and cushions and upholstered
        furniture
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
