<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>stuff</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stuff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stuff \Stuff\, n. [OF. estoffe, F. ['e]toffe; of uncertain
   origin, perhaps of Teutonic origin and akin to E. stop, v.t.
   Cf. {Stuff}, v. t.]
   1. Material which is to be worked up in any process of
      manufacture.
      [1913 Webster]

            For the stuff they had was sufficient for all the
            work to make it, and too much.        --Ex. xxxvi.
                                                  7.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ambitions should be made of sterner stuff. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The workman on his stuff his skill doth show,
            And yet the stuff gives not the man his skill. --Sir
                                                  J. Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The fundamental material of which anything is made up;
      elemental part; essence.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet do I hold it very stuff o' the conscience
            To do no contrived murder.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Woven material not made into garments; fabric of any kind;
      specifically, any one of various fabrics of wool or
      worsted; sometimes, worsted fiber.
      [1913 Webster]

            What stuff wilt have a kirtle of?     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            It [the arras] was of stuff and silk mixed, though,
            superior kinds were of silk exclusively. --F. G.
                                                  Lee.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Furniture; goods; domestic vessels or utensils.
      [1913 Webster]

            He took away locks, and gave away the king's stuff.
                                                  --Hayward.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A medicine or mixture; a potion. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Refuse or worthless matter; hence, also, foolish or
      irrational language; nonsense; trash.
      [1913 Webster]

            Anger would indite
            Such woeful stuff as I or Shadwell write. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Naut.) A melted mass of turpentine, tallow, etc., with
      which the masts, sides, and bottom of a ship are smeared
      for lubrication.                            --Ham. Nav.
                                                  Encyc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Paper stock ground ready for use.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When partly ground, called half stuff. --Knight.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Clear stuff}. See under {Clear}.

   {Small stuff} (Naut.), all kinds of small cordage. --Ham.
      Nav. Encyc.

   {Stuff gown}, the distinctive garb of a junior barrister;
      hence, a junior barrister himself. See {Silk gown}, under
      {Silk}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stuff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stuff \Stuff\, v. i.
   To feed gluttonously; to cram.
   [1913 Webster]

         Taught harmless man to cram and stuff.   --Swift.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stuff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Stuff \Stuff\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Stuffed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Stuffing}.] [OE. stoffen; cf. OF. estoffer, F. ['e]toffer,
   to put stuff in, to stuff, to line, also, OF. estouffer to
   stifle, F. ['e]touffer; both perhaps of Teutonic origin, and
   akin to E. stop. Cf. {Stop}, v. t., {Stuff}, n.]
   1. To fill by crowding something into; to cram with
      something; to load to excess; as, to stuff a bedtick.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sometimes this crook drew hazel bought adown,
            And stuffed her apron wide with nuts so brown.
                                                  --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lest the gods, for sin,
            Should with a swelling dropsy stuff thy skin.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To thrust or crowd; to press; to pack.
      [1913 Webster]

            Put roses into a glass with a narrow mouth, stuffing
            them close together . . . and they retain smell and
            color.                                --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fill by being pressed or packed into.
      [1913 Webster]

            With inward arms the dire machine they load,
            And iron bowels stuff the dark abode. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Cookery) To fill with a seasoning composition of bread,
      meat, condiments, etc.; as, to stuff a turkey.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To obstruct, as any of the organs; to affect with some
      obstruction in the organs of sense or respiration.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'm stuffed, cousin; I can not smell. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To fill the skin of, for the purpose of preserving as a
      specimen; -- said of birds or other animals.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To form or fashion by packing with the necessary material.
      [1913 Webster]

            An Eastern king put a judge to death for an
            iniquitous sentence, and ordered his hide to be
            stuffed into a cushion, and placed upon the
            tribunal.                             --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To crowd with facts; to cram the mind of; sometimes, to
      crowd or fill with false or idle tales or fancies.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To put fraudulent votes into (a ballot box). [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>stuff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>stuff
     n 1: the tangible substance that goes into the makeup of a
          physical object; "coal is a hard black material"; "wheat
          is the stuff they use to make bread" [syn: {material}]
     2: miscellaneous unspecified objects; "the trunk was full of
        stuff" [syn: {whatchamacallit}, {whatsis}, {sundry}, {sundries}]
     3: informal terms for personal possessions; "did you take all
        your clobber?" [syn: {clobber}]
     4: senseless talk; "don't give me that stuff" [syn: {stuff and
        nonsense}, {hooey}, {poppycock}]
     5: unspecified qualities required to do or be something; "the
        stuff of heros"; "you don't have the stuff to be a United
        States Marine"
     6: information in some unspecified form; "it was stuff I had
        heard before"; "there's good stuff in that book"
     7: a critically important or characteristic component;
        "suspense is the very stuff of narrative"
     v 1: fill completely; "The child stuffed his pockets with candy"
     2: press or force; "Stuff money into an envelope"; "She thrust
        the letter into his hand" [syn: {thrust}, {shove}, {squeeze}]
     3: obstruct; "My nose is all stuffed"; "Her arteries are
        blocked" [syn: {lug}, {choke up}, {block}] [ant: {unstuff}]
     4: overeat or eat immodestly; make a pig of oneself; "She
        stuffed herself at the dinner"; "The kids binged on
        icecream" [syn: {gorge}, {ingurgitate}, {overindulge}, {glut},
         {englut}, {engorge}, {overgorge}, {overeat}, {gormandize},
         {gormandise}, {gourmandize}, {binge}, {pig out}, {satiate},
         {scarf out}]
     5: treat with grease, fill, and prepare for mounting; "stuff a
        bearskin"
     6: fill tightly with a material; "stuff a pillow with
        feathers"; "The old lady wants to have her dead poodle
        stuffed by the taxidermist"
     7: fill with a stuffing while cooking; "Have you stuffed the
        turkey yet?"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
