<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>style</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>style</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Style \Style\, n. [OE. stile, F. style, Of. also stile, L.
   stilus a style or writing instrument, manner or writing, mode
   of expression; probably for stiglus, meaning, a pricking
   instrument, and akin to E. stick. See {Stick}, v. t., and cf.
   {Stiletto}. The spelling with y is due to a supposed
   connection with Gr. ? a pillar.]
   1. An instrument used by the ancients in writing on tablets
      covered with wax, having one of its ends sharp, and the
      other blunt, and somewhat expanded, for the purpose of
      making erasures by smoothing the wax.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, anything resembling the ancient style in shape or
      use. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) A pen; an author's pen. --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A sharp-pointed tool used in engraving; a graver.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) A kind of blunt-pointed surgical instrument.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) (Zo["o]l.) A long, slender, bristlelike process, as
          the anal styles of insects.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) [Perhaps fr. Gr. ? a pillar.] The pin, or gnomon, of a
          dial, the shadow of which indicates the hour. See
          {Gnomon}.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) [Probably fr. Gr. ? a pillar.] (Bot.) The elongated
          part of a pistil between the ovary and the stigma. See
          Illust. of {Stamen}, and of {Pistil}.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Mode of expressing thought in language, whether oral or
      written; especially, such use of language in the
      expression of thought as exhibits the spirit and faculty
      of an artist; choice or arrangement of words in discourse;
      rhetorical expression.
      [1913 Webster]

            High style, as when that men to kinges write.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Style is the dress of thoughts.       --Chesterfield.
      [1913 Webster]

            Proper words in proper places make the true
            definition of style.                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is style alone by which posterity will judge of a
            great work.                           --I. Disraeli.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Mode of presentation, especially in music or any of the
      fine arts; a characteristic of peculiar mode of developing
      in idea or accomplishing a result.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ornamental style also possesses its own peculiar
            merit.                                --Sir J.
                                                  Reynolds.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Conformity to a recognized standard; manner which is
      deemed elegant and appropriate, especially in social
      demeanor; fashion.
      [1913 Webster]

            According to the usual style of dedications. --C.
                                                  Middleton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Mode or phrase by which anything is formally designated;
      the title; the official designation of any important body;
      mode of address; as, the style of Majesty.
      [1913 Webster]

            One style to a gracious benefactor, another to a
            proud, insulting foe.                 --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Chron.) A mode of reckoning time, with regard to the
      Julian and Gregorian calendars.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Style is Old or New. The Old Style follows the Julian
         manner of computing the months and days, or the
         calendar as established by Julius C[ae]sar, in which
         every fourth year consists of 366 days, and the other
         years of 365 days. This is about 11 minutes in a year
         too much. Pope Georgy XIII. reformed the calendar by
         retrenching 10 days in October, 1582, in order to bring
         back the vernal equinox to the same day as at the time
         of the Council of Nice, a. d. 325. This reformation was
         adopted by act of the British Parliament in 1751, by
         which act 11 days in September, 1752, were retrenched,
         and the third day was reckoned the fourteenth. This
         mode of reckoning is called New Style, according to
         which every year divisible by 4, unless it is divisible
         by 100 without being divisible by 400, has 366 days,
         and any other year 365 days.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Style of court}, the practice or manner observed by a court
      in its proceedings. --Ayliffe.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Diction; phraseology; manner; course; title. See
        {Diction}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>style</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Style \Style\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Styled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Styling}.]
   To entitle; to term, name, or call; to denominate. ``Styled
   great conquerors.'' --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]

         How well his worth and brave adventures styled.
                                                  --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To call; name; denominate; designate; term;
        characterize.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>style</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>style
     n 1: a particular kind (as to appearance); "this style of shoe is
          in demand"
     2: how something is done or how it happens; "her dignified
        manner"; "his rapid manner of talking"; "their nomadic
        mode of existence"; "in the characteristic New York
        style"; "a lonely way of life"; "in an abrasive fashion"
        [syn: {manner}, {mode}, {way}, {fashion}]
     3: a way of expressing something (in language or art or music
        etc.) that is characteristic of a particular person or
        group of people or period; "all the reporters were
        expected to adopt the style of the newspaper" [syn: {expressive
        style}]
     4: distinctive and stylish elegance; "he wooed her with the
        confident dash of a cavalry officer" [syn: {dash}, {elan},
         {flair}, {panache}]
     5: the popular taste at a given time; "leather is the latest
        vogue"; "he followed current trends"; "the 1920s had a
        style of their own" [syn: {vogue}, {trend}]
     6: (botany) the narrow elongated part of the pistil between the
        ovary and the stigma
     7: editorial directions to be followed in spelling and
        punctuation and capitalization and typographical display
     8: a pointed tool for writing or drawing or engraving; "he drew
        the design on the stencil with a steel stylus" [syn: {stylus}]
     9: a slender bristlelike or tubular process; "a cartilaginous
        style"
     v 1: designate by an identifying term; "They styled their nation
          `The Confederate States'" [syn: {title}]
     2: make consistent with a certain fashion or style; "Style my
        hair"; "style the dress"
     3: make consistent with certain rules of style; "style a
        manuscript"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
