<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>subject</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>subject</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>subject
     
        &lt;programming&gt; In {subject-oriented programming}, a subject is
        a collection of {classes} or class fragments whose {class
        hierarchy} models its domain in its own, subjective way.  A
        subject may be a complete application in itself, or it may be
        an incomplete fragment that must be composed with other
        subjects to produce a complete application.  Subject
        composition combines class hierarchies to produce new subjects
        that incorporate functionality from existing subjects.
     
        (1999-08-31)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>subject</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Subject \Sub*ject"\, a. [OE. suget, OF. souzget, sougit (in
   which the first part is L. subtus below, fr. sub under),
   subgiet, subject, F. sujet, from L. subjectus lying under,
   subjected, p. p. of subjicere, subicere, to throw, lay,
   place, or bring under; sub under + jacere to throw. See {Jet}
   a shooting forth.]
   1. Placed or situated under; lying below, or in a lower
      situation. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Placed under the power of another; specifically
      (International Law), owing allegiance to a particular
      sovereign or state; as, Jamaica is subject to Great
      Britain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Esau was never subject to Jacob.      --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Exposed; liable; prone; disposed; as, a country subject to
      extreme heat; men subject to temptation.
      [1913 Webster]

            All human things are subject to decay. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Obedient; submissive.
      [1913 Webster]

            Put them in mind to be subject to principalities.
                                                  --Titus iii.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Liable; subordinate; inferior; obnoxious; exposed. See
        {Liable}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>subject</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Subject \Sub*ject"\, n. [From L. subjectus, through an old form
   of F. sujet. See {Subject}, a.]
   1. That which is placed under the authority, dominion,
      control, or influence of something else.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically: One who is under the authority of a ruler
      and is governed by his laws; one who owes allegiance to a
      sovereign or a sovereign state; as, a subject of Queen
      Victoria; a British subject; a subject of the United
      States.
      [1913 Webster]

            Was never subject longed to be a king,
            As I do long and wish to be a subject. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The subject must obey his prince, because God
            commands it, human laws require it.   --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In international law, the term subject is convertible
         with citizen.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is subjected, or submitted to, any physical
      operation or process; specifically (Anat.), a dead body
      used for the purpose of dissection.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is brought under thought or examination; that
      which is taken up for discussion, or concerning which
      anything is said or done. ``This subject for heroic
      song.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Make choice of a subject, beautiful and noble, which
            . . . shall afford an ample field of matter wherein
            to expatiate.                         --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The unhappy subject of these quarrels. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The person who is treated of; the hero of a piece; the
      chief character.
      [1913 Webster]

            Writers of particular lives . . . are apt to be
            prejudiced in favor of their subject. --C.
                                                  Middleton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Logic &amp; Gram.) That of which anything is affirmed or
      predicated; the theme of a proposition or discourse; that
      which is spoken of; as, the nominative case is the subject
      of the verb.
      [1913 Webster]

            The subject of a proposition is that concerning
            which anything is affirmed or denied. --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. That in which any quality, attribute, or relation, whether
      spiritual or material, inheres, or to which any of these
      appertain; substance; substratum.
      [1913 Webster]

            That which manifests its qualities -- in other
            words, that in which the appearing causes inhere,
            that to which they belong -- is called their subject
            or substance, or substratum.          --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Hence, that substance or being which is conscious of its
      own operations; the mind; the thinking agent or principal;
      the ego. Cf. {Object}, n., 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            The philosophers of mind have, in a manner, usurped
            and appropriated this expression to themselves.
            Accordingly, in their hands, the phrases conscious
            or thinking subject, and subject, mean precisely the
            same thing.                           --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mus.) The principal theme, or leading thought or phrase,
      on which a composition or a movement is based.
      [1913 Webster]

            The earliest known form of subject is the
            ecclesiastical cantus firmus, or plain song.
                                                  --Rockstro.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Fine Arts) The incident, scene, figure, group, etc.,
       which it is the aim of the artist to represent.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>subject</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Subject \Sub*ject"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Subjected}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Subjecting}.]
   1. To bring under control, power, or dominion; to make
      subject; to subordinate; to subdue.
      [1913 Webster]

            Firmness of mind that subjects every gratification
            of sense to the rule of right reason. --C.
                                                  Middleton.
      [1913 Webster]

            In one short view subjected to our eye,
            Gods, emperors, heroes, sages, beauties, lie.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is the most subjected, the most ?nslaved, who is
            so in his understanding.              --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To expose; to make obnoxious or liable; as, credulity
      subjects a person to impositions.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To submit; to make accountable.
      [1913 Webster]

            God is not bound to subject his ways of operation to
            the scrutiny of our thoughts.         --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make subservient.
      [1913 Webster]

            Subjected to his service angel wings. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cause to undergo; as, to subject a substance to a white
      heat; to subject a person to a rigid test.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>subject</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>subject
     adj 1: not exempt from tax; "the gift will be subject to taxation"
            [syn: {subject(p)}]
     2:  possibly accepting or permitting; "a passage capable of
        misinterpretation"; "open to interpretation"; "an issue
        open to question"; "the time is fixed by the director and
        players and therefore subject to much variation" [syn: {capable},
         {open}]
     3: being under the power or sovereignty of another or others;
        "subject peoples"; "a dependent prince" [syn: {dependent}]
     n 1: the subject matter of a conversation or discussion; "he
          didn't want to discuss that subject"; "it was a very
          sensitive topic"; "his letters were always on the theme
          of love" [syn: {topic}, {theme}]
     2: some situation or event that is thought about; "he kept
        drifting off the topic"; "he had been thinking about the
        subject for several years"; "it is a matter for the
        police" [syn: {topic}, {issue}, {matter}]
     3: a branch of knowledge; "in what discipline is his
        doctorate?"; "teachers should be well trained in their
        subject"; "anthropology is the study of human beings"
        [syn: {discipline}, {subject area}, {subject field}, {field},
         {field of study}, {study}, {bailiwick}, {branch of
        knowledge}]
     4: something (a person or object or scene) selected by an
        artist or photographer for graphic representation; "a
        moving picture of a train is more dramatic than a still
        picture of the same subject" [syn: {content}, {depicted
        object}]
     5: a person who is subjected to experimental or other
        observational procedures; someone who is an object of
        investigation; "the subjects for this investigation were
        selected randomly"; "the cases that we studied were drawn
        from two different communities" [syn: {case}, {guinea pig}]
     6: a person who owes allegiance to that nation; "a monarch has
        a duty to his subjects" [syn: {national}]
     7: (grammar) one of the two main constituents of a sentence;
        the grammatical constituent about which something is
        predicated
     8: (logic) the first term of a proposition
     v 1: cause to experience or suffer or make liable or vulnerable
          to; "He subjected me to his awful poetry"; "The sergeant
          subjected the new recruits to many drills"; "People in
          Chernobyl were subjected to radiation"
     2: make accountable for; "He did not want to subject himself to
        the judgments of his superiors"
     3: make subservient; force to submit or subdue [syn: {subjugate}]
     4: refer for judgment or consideration; "She submitted a
        proposal to the agency" [syn: {submit}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
