<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>submarine</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>submarine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Submarine \Sub`ma*rine"\, a.
   Being, acting, or growing, under water in the sea; as,
   submarine navigators; submarine plants.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Submarine armor}, a waterproof dress of strong material,
      having a helmet into which air for breathing is pumped
      through a tube leading from above the surface to enable a
      diver to remain under water.

   {Submarine cable}. See {Telegraph cable}, under {Telegraph}.
      

   {Submarine mine}. See {Torpedo}, 2
   (a) .
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>submarine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>submarine sandwich \sub`ma*rine" sand"wich\, n.
   A large sandwich on an elongated roll, usually incompletely
   cut into two halves, filed with various cold cuts, meatballs,
   lettuce, cheese, tomatoes, olives, etc., and spiced
   variously, and often having oil or other dressing applied;
   called also {hoagie}, {hero}, {hero sandwich}, {grinder},
   {sub}, {submarine}, {poor boy}, and {Italian sandwich}. A
   single such sandwich may consitute a substantial meal. Very
   large variants are sometimes prepared for social gatherings
   and cut into pieces for individual consumption.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>submarine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Submarine \Sub*ma*rine"\, n.
   A submarine plant or animal.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>submarine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Submarine \Sub`ma*rine"\, n.
   1. A submarine boat; a ship that can travel under the surface
      of the water. Most such ships are ships of war, as part of
      a navy, but submarines are also used for oceanic research.
      Also called {sub} and (from the German U-Boot) {U-boat}.
      esp., (Nav.), a submarine torpedo boat; -- called specif.
      {submergible submarine} when capable of operating at
      various depths and of traveling considerable distances
      under water, and {submersible submarine} when capable of
      being only partly submerged, i.e., so that the conning
      tower, etc., is still above water. The latter type and
      most of the former type are submerged as desired by
      regulating the amount of water admitted to the ballast
      tanks and sink on an even keel; some of the former type
      effect submersion while under way by means of horizontal
      rudders, in some cases also with admission of water to the
      ballast tanks.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   2. A stowaway on a seagoing vessel. [Colloq.]
      [PJC]

   3. A {submarine sandwich}.
      [PJC]

   {Nuclear submarine} A submarine powered by a nuclear reactor.

   {Attack submarine} A submarine designed to attack other
      ships, including other submarines.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>submarine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Armor \Ar"mor\, n. [OE. armure, fr. F. armure, OF. armeure, fr.
   L. armatura. See {Armature}.] [Spelt also {armour}.]
   1. Defensive arms for the body; any clothing or covering worn
      to protect one's person in battle.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In English statues, armor is used for the whole
         apparatus of war, including offensive as well as
         defensive arms. The statues of armor directed what arms
         every man should provide.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Steel or iron covering, whether of ships or forts,
      protecting them from the fire of artillery.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Coat armor}, the escutcheon of a person or family, with its
      several charges and other furniture, as mantling, crest,
      supporters, motto, etc.

   {Submarine}, a water-tight dress or covering for a diver. See
      under {Submarine}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>submarine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hoagie \hoagie\, hoagy \hoagy\n.
   a large sandwich on a long crusty roll that is split
   lengthwise and filled with meats and cheese (and tomato and
   onion and lettuce and condiments); different names are used
   in different sections of the U. S., such as {hero},
   {grinder}, and {submarine}.

   Syn: bomber, grinder, hero, hero sandwich, hoagie, Cuban
        sandwich, Italian sandwich, poor boy, sub, submarine,
        submarine sandwich, torpedo, wedge, zep.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>submarine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>submarine
     adj : beneath the surface of the sea [syn: {undersea}]
     n 1: a submersible warship usually armed with torpedoes [syn: {pigboat},
           {sub}, {U-boat}]
     2: a large sandwich made of a long crusty roll split lengthwise
        and filled with meats and cheese (and tomato and onion and
        lettuce and condiments); different names are used in
        different sections of the United States [syn: {bomber}, {grinder},
         {hero}, {hero sandwich}, {hoagie}, {hoagy}, {Cuban
        sandwich}, {Italian sandwich}, {poor boy}, {sub}, {submarine
        sandwich}, {torpedo}, {wedge}, {zep}]
     v 1: move forward or under in a sliding motion; "The child was
          injured when he submarined under the safety belt of the
          car"
     2: throw with an underhand motion
     3: bring down with a blow to the legs
     4: control a submarine
     5: attack by submarine; "The Germans submarined the Allies"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
