<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>subscription</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>subscription</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Subscription \Sub*scrip"tion\, n. [L. subscriptio: cf. F.
   souscription.]
   1. The act of subscribing.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is subscribed. Specifically:
      (a) A paper to which a signature is attached.
      (b) The signature attached to a paper.
      (c) Consent or attestation by underwriting the name.
      (d) Sum subscribed; amount of sums subscribed; as, an
          individual subscription to a fund.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Eccl.) The acceptance of articles, or other tests tending
      to promote uniformity; esp. (Ch. of Eng.), formal assent
      to the Thirty-nine Articles and the Book of Common Prayer,
      required before ordination.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Submission; obedience. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            You owe me no subscription.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Pharm.) That part of a prescription which contains the
      direction to the apothecary.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A method of purchasing items produced periodically in a
      series, as newspapers or magazines, in which a certain
      number of the items are delivered as produced, without
      need for ordering each item individually; also, the
      purchase thus executed.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The right to attend a series of public performances of
         ballet, opera, or music are also often sold by
         subscription. The payment for a subscription may be
         made prior to delivery of any items (common with
         magazines and performances), or after a certain number
         of the items have been delivered (common with
         newspapers or works of art produced in a series).
         [1913 Webster] 7. An application to purchase a certain
         number of securities to be delivered when they are
         newly issued. --&gt;
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>subscription</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>subscription
     n 1: a payment for consecutive issues of a newspaper or magazine
          for a given period of time
     2: agreement expressed by (or as if expressed by) signing your
        name
     3: a pledged contribution
     4: the act of signing your name; writing your signature (as on
        a document); "the deed was attested by the subscription of
        his signature"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
