<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>such</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>such</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Such \Such\, a. [OE. such, sich, sech, sik, swich, swilch,
   swulch, swilc, swulc, AS. swelc, swilc, swylc; akin to
   OFries. selik, D. zulk, OS. sulic, OHG. sulih, solih, G.
   solch, Icel. sl[=i]kr, OSw. salik, Sw. slik, Dan. slig, Goth.
   swaleiks; originally meaning, so shaped. [root]192. See {So},
   {Like}, a., and cf. {Which}.]
   1. Of that kind; of the like kind; like; resembling; similar;
      as, we never saw such a day; -- followed by that or as
      introducing the word or proposition which defines the
      similarity, or the standard of comparison; as, the books
      are not such that I can recommend them, or, not such as I
      can recommend; these apples are not such as those we saw
      yesterday; give your children such precepts as tend to
      make them better.
      [1913 Webster]

            And in his time such a conqueror
            That greater was there none under the sun.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            His misery was such that none of the bystanders
            could refrain from weeping.           --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The indefinite article a or an never precedes such, but
         is placed between it and the noun to which it refers;
         as, such a man; such an honor. The indefinite adjective
         some, several, one, few, many, all, etc., precede such;
         as, one such book is enough; all such people ought to
         be avoided; few such ideas were then held.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Having the particular quality or character specified.
      [1913 Webster]

            That thou art happy, owe to God;
            That thou continuest such, owe to thyself. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The same that; -- with as; as, this was the state of the
      kingdom at such time as the enemy landed. ``[It] hath such
      senses as we have.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Certain; -- representing the object as already
      particularized in terms which are not mentioned.
      [1913 Webster]

            In rushed one and tells him such a knight
            Is new arrived.                       --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

            To-day or to-morrow we will go into such a city, and
            continue there a year.                --James iv.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Such is used pronominally. ``He was the father of such
         as dwell in tents.'' --Gen. iv. 20. ``Such as I are
         free in spirit when our limbs are chained.'' --Sir W.
         Scott. Such is also used before adjectives joined to
         substantives; as, the fleet encountered such a terrible
         storm that it put back. ``Everything was managed with
         so much care, and such excellent order was observed.''
         --De Foe.
         [1913 Webster]

               Temple sprung from a family which . . . long
               after his death produced so many eminent men, and
               formed such distinguished alliances, that, etc.
                                                  --Macaulay.
         [1913 Webster] Such is used emphatically, without the
         correlative.
         [1913 Webster]

               Now will he be mocking:
               I shall have such a life.          --Shak.
         [1913 Webster] Such was formerly used with numerals in
         the sense of times as much or as many; as, such ten, or
         ten times as many.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Such and such}, or {Such or such}, certain; some; -- used to
      represent the object indefinitely, as already
      particularized in one way or another, or as being of one
      kind or another. ``In such and such a place shall be my
      camp.'' --2 Kings vi. 8. ``Sovereign authority may enact a
      law commanding such and such an action.'' --South.

   {Such like} or {Such character}, of the like kind.
      [1913 Webster]

            And many other such like things ye do. --Mark vii.
                                                  8.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>such</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>such
     adj 1: of a kind specified or understood; "it's difficult to please
            such people"; "on such a night as this"; "animals such
            as lions and tigers" [syn: {such(a)}, {such as}]
     2: of a degree or quality specified (by the `that' clause);
        "their anxiety was such that they could not sleep" [syn: {such(p)},
         {such that}]
     3: of so extreme a degree or extent; "such weeping"; "so much
        weeping"; "such a help"; "such grief"; "never dreamed of
        such beauty" [syn: {such(a)}, {so much}]
     adv : to so extreme a degree; "he is such a baby"; "Such rich
           people!"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
