<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sucking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suck \Suck\ (s[u^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sucked} (s[u^]kt); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Sucking}.] [OE. suken, souken, AS. s[=u]can,
   s[=u]gan; akin to D. zuigen, G. saugen, OHG. s[=u]gan, Icel.
   s[=u]ga, sj[=u]ga, Sw. suga, Dan. suge, L. sugere. Cf.
   {Honeysuckle}, {Soak}, {Succulent}, {Suction}.]
   1. To draw, as a liquid, by the action of the mouth and
      tongue, which tends to produce a vacuum, and causes the
      liquid to rush in by atmospheric pressure; to draw, or
      apply force to, by exhausting the air.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw liquid from by the action of the mouth; as, to
      suck an orange; specifically, to draw milk from (the
      mother, the breast, etc.) with the mouth; as, the young of
      an animal sucks the mother, or dam; an infant sucks the
      breast.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To draw in, or imbibe, by any process resembles sucking;
      to inhale; to absorb; as, to suck in air; the roots of
      plants suck water from the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To draw or drain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Old ocean, sucked through the porous globe.
                                                  --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To draw in, as a whirlpool; to swallow up.
      [1913 Webster]

            As waters are by whirlpools sucked and drawn.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To suck in}, to draw into the mouth; to imbibe; to absorb.
      

   {To suck out}, to draw out with the mouth; to empty by
      suction.

   {To suck up}, to draw into the mouth; to draw up by suction
      or absorption.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sucking \Suck"ing\, a.
   Drawing milk from the mother or dam; hence, colloquially,
   young, inexperienced, as, a sucking infant; a sucking calf.
   [1913 Webster]

         I suppose you are a young barrister, sucking lawyer, or
         that sort of thing.                      --Thackeray.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Sucking bottle}, a feeding bottle. See under {Bottle}.

   {Sucking fish} (Zo["o]l.), the remora. See {Remora}. --Baird.

   {Sucking pump}, a suction pump. See under {Suction}.

   {Sucking stomach} (Zo["o]l.), the muscular first stomach of
      certain insects and other invertebrates which suck liquid
      food.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sucking
     n : the act of sucking [syn: {suck}, {suction}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
