<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sucker</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hag \Hag\ (h[a^]g), n. [OE. hagge, hegge, witch, hag, AS.
   h[ae]gtesse; akin to OHG. hagazussa, G. hexe, D. heks, Dan.
   hex, Sw. h["a]xa. The first part of the word is prob. the
   same as E. haw, hedge, and the orig. meaning was perh., wood
   woman, wild woman. [root]12.]
   1. A witch, sorceress, or enchantress; also, a wizard. [Obs.]
      ``[Silenus] that old hag.'' --Golding.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An ugly old woman. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A fury; a she-monster. --Crashaw.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) An eel-like marine marsipobranch ({Myxine
      glutinosa}), allied to the lamprey. It has a suctorial
      mouth, with labial appendages, and a single pair of gill
      openings. It is the type of the order {Hyperotreta}.
      Called also {hagfish}, {borer}, {slime eel}, {sucker}, and
      {sleepmarken}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.) The hagdon or shearwater.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An appearance of light and fire on a horse's mane or a
      man's hair. --Blount.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Hag moth} (Zo["o]l.), a moth ({Phobetron pithecium}), the
      larva of which has curious side appendages, and feeds on
      fruit trees.

   {Hag's tooth} (Naut.), an ugly irregularity in the pattern of
      matting or pointing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sucker \Suck"er\ (s[u^]k"[~e]r), n.
   1. One who, or that which, sucks; esp., one of the organs by
      which certain animals, as the octopus and remora, adhere
      to other bodies.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A suckling; a sucking animal. --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The embolus, or bucket, of a pump; also, the valve of a
      pump basket. --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A pipe through which anything is drawn.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A small piece of leather, usually round, having a string
      attached to the center, which, when saturated with water
      and pressed upon a stone or other body having a smooth
      surface, adheres, by reason of the atmospheric pressure,
      with such force as to enable a considerable weight to be
      thus lifted by the string; -- used by children as a
      plaything.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Bot.) A shoot from the roots or lower part of the stem of
      a plant; -- so called, perhaps, from diverting nourishment
      from the body of the plant.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any one of numerous species of North American
          fresh-water cyprinoid fishes of the family
          {Catostomid[ae]}; so called because the lips are
          protrusile. The flesh is coarse, and they are of
          little value as food. The most common species of the
          Eastern United States are the northern sucker
          ({Catostomus Commersoni}), the white sucker ({C.
          teres}), the hog sucker ({C. nigricans}), and the
          chub, or sweet sucker ({Erimyzon sucetta}). Some of
          the large Western species are called {buffalo fish},
          {red horse}, {black horse}, and {suckerel}.
      (b) The remora.
      (c) The lumpfish.
      (d) The hagfish, or myxine.
      (e) A California food fish ({Menticirrus undulatus})
          closely allied to the kingfish
      (a); -- called also {bagre}.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. A parasite; a sponger. See def. 6, above.
      [1913 Webster]

            They who constantly converse with men far above
            their estates shall reap shame and loss thereby; if
            thou payest nothing, they will count thee a sucker,
            no branch.                            --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A hard drinker; a soaker. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A greenhorn; someone easily cheated, gulled, or deceived.
       [Slang, U.S.]
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A nickname applied to a native of Illinois. [U. S.]
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A person strongly attracted to something; -- usually used
       with for; as, he's a sucker for tall blondes.
       [PJC]

   11. Any thing or person; -- usually implying annoyance or
       dislike; as, I went to change the blade and cut my finger
       on the sucker. [Slang]
       [PJC]

   {Carp sucker}, {Cherry sucker}, etc. See under {Carp},
      {Cherry}, etc.

   {Sucker fish}. See {Sucking fish}, under {Sucking}.

   {Sucker rod}, a pump rod. See under {Pump}.

   {Sucker tube} (Zo["o]l.), one of the external ambulacral
      tubes of an echinoderm, -- usually terminated by a sucker
      and used for locomotion. Called also {sucker foot}. See
      {Spatangoid}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sucker \Suck"er\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Suckered}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Suckering}.]
   1. To strip off the suckers or shoots from; to deprive of
      suckers; as, to sucker maize.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cheat or deceive (a gullible person); to make a sucker
      of (someone).
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sucker \Suck"er\, v. i.
   To form suckers; as, corn suckers abundantly.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sucker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sucker
     n 1: a person who is gullible and easy to take advantage of [syn:
           {chump}, {fool}, {gull}, {mark}, {patsy}, {fall guy}, {soft
          touch}, {mug}]
     2: a shoot arising from a plant's roots
     3: a drinker who sucks (as at a nipple or through a straw)
     4: flesh of any of numerous North American food fishes with
        toothless jaws
     5: hard candy on a stick [syn: {lollipop}, {all-day sucker}]
     6: an organ specialized for sucking nourishment or for adhering
        to objects by suction
     7: mostly North American freshwater fishes with a thick-lipped
        mouth for feeding by suction; related to carps
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
