<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>suck</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suck \Suck\ (s[u^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sucked} (s[u^]kt); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Sucking}.] [OE. suken, souken, AS. s[=u]can,
   s[=u]gan; akin to D. zuigen, G. saugen, OHG. s[=u]gan, Icel.
   s[=u]ga, sj[=u]ga, Sw. suga, Dan. suge, L. sugere. Cf.
   {Honeysuckle}, {Soak}, {Succulent}, {Suction}.]
   1. To draw, as a liquid, by the action of the mouth and
      tongue, which tends to produce a vacuum, and causes the
      liquid to rush in by atmospheric pressure; to draw, or
      apply force to, by exhausting the air.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw liquid from by the action of the mouth; as, to
      suck an orange; specifically, to draw milk from (the
      mother, the breast, etc.) with the mouth; as, the young of
      an animal sucks the mother, or dam; an infant sucks the
      breast.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To draw in, or imbibe, by any process resembles sucking;
      to inhale; to absorb; as, to suck in air; the roots of
      plants suck water from the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To draw or drain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Old ocean, sucked through the porous globe.
                                                  --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To draw in, as a whirlpool; to swallow up.
      [1913 Webster]

            As waters are by whirlpools sucked and drawn.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To suck in}, to draw into the mouth; to imbibe; to absorb.
      

   {To suck out}, to draw out with the mouth; to empty by
      suction.

   {To suck up}, to draw into the mouth; to draw up by suction
      or absorption.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suck \Suck\, v. i.
   1. To draw, or attempt to draw, something by suction, as with
      the mouth, or through a tube.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where the bee sucks, there suck I.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw milk from the breast or udder; as, a child, or the
      young of an animal, is first nourished by sucking.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To draw in; to imbibe; to partake.
      [1913 Webster]

            The crown had sucked too hard, and now, being full,
            was like to draw less.                --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be objectionable, of very poor quality, or offensive;
      as, telemarketing calls really suck; he's a good actor,
      but his singing sucks. [Colloq.]
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suck \Suck\, n.
   1. The act of drawing with the mouth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is drawn into the mouth by sucking;
      specifically, mikl drawn from the breast. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A small draught. [Colloq.] --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Juice; succulence. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>suck
     n : the act of sucking [syn: {sucking}, {suction}]
     v 1: draw into the mouth by creating a practical vacuum in the
          mouth; "suck the poison from the place where the snake
          bit"; "suck on a straw"; "the baby sucked on the
          mother's breast"
     2: draw something in by or as if by a vacuum; "Mud was sucking
        at her feet"
     3: attract by using an inexorable force, inducement, etc.; "The
        current boom in the economy sucked many workers in from
        abroad" [syn: {suck in}]
     4: take in, also metaphorically; "The sponge absorbs water
        well"; "She drew strength from the minister's words" [syn:
         {absorb}, {imbibe}, {soak up}, {sop up}, {suck up}, {draw},
         {take in}, {take up}]
     5: give suck to; "The wetnurse suckled the infant"; "You cannot
        nurse your baby in public in some places" [syn: {breastfeed},
         {bottle-feed}, {suckle}, {nurse}, {wet-nurse}, {lactate},
         {give suck}] [ant: {bottlefeed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
