<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>suit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>suit
     
        1. Ugly and uncomfortable "business clothing" often worn by
        non-hackers.  Invariably worn with a "tie", a strangulation
        device that partially cuts off the blood supply to the brain.
        It is thought that this explains much about the behaviour of
        suit-wearers.
     
        2. A person who habitually wears suits, as distinct from a
        techie or hacker.
     
        See {loser}, {burble}, {management}, {Stupids}, {SNAFU
        principle}, and {brain-damaged}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1998-07-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suit \Suit\ (s[=u]t), n. [OE. suite, F. suite, OF. suite,
   sieute, fr. suivre to follow, OF. sivre; perhaps influenced
   by L. secta. See {Sue} to follow, and cf. {Sect}, {Suite}.]
   1. The act of following or pursuing, as game; pursuit. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of suing; the process by which one endeavors to
      gain an end or an object; an attempt to attain a certain
      result; pursuit; endeavor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thenceforth the suit of earthly conquest shone.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The act of wooing in love; the solicitation of a woman in
      marriage; courtship.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rebate your loves, each rival suit suspend,
            Till this funereal web my labors end. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) The attempt to gain an end by legal process; an
      action or process for the recovery of a right or claim;
      legal application to a court for justice; prosecution of
      right before any tribunal; as, a civil suit; a criminal
      suit; a suit in chancery.
      [1913 Webster]

            I arrest thee at the suit of Count Orsino. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In England the several suits, or remedial
            instruments of justice, are distinguished into three
            kinds -- actions personal, real, and mixed.
                                                  --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which follows as a retinue; a company of attendants
      or followers; the assembly of persons who attend upon a
      prince, magistrate, or other person of distinction; --
      often written {suite}, and pronounced sw[=e]t.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Things that follow in a series or succession; the
      individual objects, collectively considered, which
      constitute a series, as of rooms, buildings, compositions,
      etc.; -- often written {suite}, and pronounced sw[=e]t.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A number of things used together, and generally necessary
      to be united in order to answer their purpose; a number of
      things ordinarily classed or used together; a set; as, a
      suit of curtains; a suit of armor; a suit of clothes; a
      three-piece business suit. ``Two rogues in buckram
      suits.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   8. (Playing Cards) One of the four sets of cards which
      constitute a pack; -- each set consisting of thirteen
      cards bearing a particular emblem, as hearts, spades,
      clubs, or diamonds; also, the members of each such suit
      held by a player in certain games, such as bridge; as,
      hearts were her long suit.
      [1913 Webster]

            To deal and shuffle, to divide and sort
            Her mingled suits and sequences.      --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Regular order; succession. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Every five and thirty years the same kind and suit
            of weather comes again.               --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Hence: (derived from def 7) Someone who dresses in a
       business suit, as contrasted with more informal attire;
       specifically, a person, such as business executive, or
       government official, who is apt to view a situation
       formalistically, bureaucratically, or according to formal
       procedural criteria; -- used derogatively for one who is
       inflexible, esp. when a more humanistic or imaginative
       approach would be appropriate.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Out of suits}, having no correspondence. [Obs.] --Shak.

   {Suit and service} (Feudal Law), the duty of feudatories to
      attend the courts of their lords or superiors in time of
      peace, and in war to follow them and do military service;
      -- called also {suit service}. --Blackstone.

   {Suit broker}, one who made a trade of obtaining the suits of
      petitioners at court. [Obs.]

   {Suit court} (O. Eng. Law), the court in which tenants owe
      attendance to their lord.

   {Suit covenant} (O. Eng. Law), a covenant to sue at a certain
      court.

   {Suit custom} (Law), a service which is owed from time
      immemorial.

   {Suit service}. (Feudal Law) See {Suit and service}, above.
      

   {To bring suit}. (Law)
       (a) To bring secta, followers or witnesses, to prove the
           plaintiff's demand. [Obs.]
       (b) In modern usage, to institute an action.

   {To follow suit}.
       (a) (Card Playing) See under {Follow}, v. t.
       (b) To mimic the action of another person; to perform an
           action similar to what has preceded; as, when she
           walked in, John left the room and his wife followed
           suit.

   {long suit}
       (a) (Card Playing) the suit[8] of which a player has the
           largest number of cards in his hand; as, his long
           suit was clubs, but his partner insisted on making
           hearts trumps.. Hence: [fig.] that quality or
           capability which is a person's best asset; as, we
           could see from the mess in his room that neatness was
           not his long suit.

   {strong suit} same as {long suit},
       (b) . ``I think our strong suit is that we can score from
           both the perimeter and the post.'' --Bill Disbrow
           (basketball coach) 1998. ``Rigid ideological
           consistency has never been a strong suit of the Whole
           Earth Catalogue.'' --Bruce Sterling (The Hacker
           Crackdown, 1994)
           [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suit \Suit\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Suited}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Suiting}.]
   1. To fit; to adapt; to make proper or suitable; as, to suit
      the action to the word. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be fitted to; to accord with; to become; to befit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ill suits his cloth the praise of railing well.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Raise her notes to that sublime degree
            Which suits song of piety and thee.   --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To dress; to clothe. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            So went he suited to his watery tomb. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To please; to make content; as, he is well suited with his
      place; to suit one's taste.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suit \Suit\, v. i.
   To agree; to accord; to be fitted; to correspond; -- usually
   followed by with or to.
   [1913 Webster]

         The place itself was suiting to his care. --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]

         Give me not an office
         That suits with me so ill.               --Addison.
   [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To agree; accord; comport; tally; correspond; match;
        answer.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>suit n. 1. Ugly and uncomfortable `business clothing' often worn by
   non-hackers. Invariably worn with a `tie', a strangulation device that
   partially cuts off the blood supply to the brain. It is thought that
   this explains much about the behavior of suit-wearers. Compare {droid}.
   2. A person who habitually wears suits, as distinct from a techie or
   hacker. See {pointy-haired}, {burble}, {management}, {Stupids}, {SNAFU
   principle}, {PHB}, and {brain-damaged}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>suit
     n 1: a comprehensive term for any proceeding in a court of law
          whereby an individual seeks a legal remedy; "the family
          brought suit against the landlord" [syn: {lawsuit}, {case},
           {cause}, {causa}]
     2: a set of garments (usually including a jacket and trousers
        or skirt) for outerwear all of the same fabric and color;
        "they buried him in his best suit" [syn: {suit of clothes}]
     3: playing card in any of four sets of 13 cards in a pack; each
        set has its own symbol and color; "a flush is five cards
        in the same suit"; "in bridge you must follow suit"; "what
        suit is trumps?"
     4: a businessman dressed in a business suit; "all the suits
        care about is the bottom line"
     5: a man's courting of a woman; seeking the affections of a
        woman (usually with the hope of marriage); "its was a
        brief and intense courtship" [syn: {courtship}, {wooing},
        {courting}]
     6: a petition or appeal made to a person of superior status or
        rank
     v 1: be agreeable or acceptable to; "This suits my needs" [syn: {accommodate},
           {fit}]
     2: be agreeable or acceptable; "This time suits me"
     3: accord or comport with; "This kind of behavior does not suit
        a young woman!" [syn: {befit}, {beseem}]
     4: enhance the appearance of; "Mourning becomes Electra"; "This
        behavior doesn't suit you!" [syn: {become}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
