<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>sulphur</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sulphur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>elements</Id>
        <Name>Elements database 20001107</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sulphur
Symbol: S
Atomic number: 16
Atomic weight: 32.064
Yellow, nonmetallic element belonging to group 16 of the periodic table.
It is an essential element in living organisms, needed in the amino acids
cysteine and methionine, and hence in many proteins. Absorbed by plants
from the soil as sulphate ion.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sulphur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sulphur, IN
  Zip code(s): 47174
Sulphur, KY
  Zip code(s): 40070
Sulphur, LA (city, FIPS 73640)
  Location: 30.22950 N, 93.35645 W
  Population (1990): 20125 (7812 housing units)
  Area: 25.2 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 70663
Sulphur, OK (city, FIPS 71350)
  Location: 34.50673 N, 96.97698 W
  Population (1990): 4824 (2199 housing units)
  Area: 10.9 sq km (land), 0.4 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 73086
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sulphur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sulphur \Sul"phur\, n. [L., better sulfur: cf. F. soufre.]
   1. (Chem.) A nonmetallic element occurring naturally in large
      quantities, either combined as in the sulphides (as
      pyrites) and sulphates (as gypsum), or native in volcanic
      regions, in vast beds mixed with gypsum and various earthy
      materials, from which it is melted out. Symbol S. Atomic
      weight 32. The specific gravity of ordinary octohedral
      sulphur is 2.05; of prismatic sulphur, 1.96.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: It is purified by distillation, and is obtained as a
         lemon-yellow powder (by sublimation), called flour, or
         flowers, of sulphur, or in cast sticks called roll
         sulphur, or brimstone. It burns with a blue flame and a
         peculiar suffocating odor. It is an ingredient of
         gunpowder, is used on friction matches, and in medicine
         (as a laxative and insecticide), but its chief use is
         in the manufacture of sulphuric acid. Sulphur can be
         obtained in two crystalline modifications, in
         orthorhombic octahedra, or in monoclinic prisms, the
         former of which is the more stable at ordinary
         temperatures. Sulphur is the type, in its chemical
         relations, of a group of elements, including selenium
         and tellurium, called collectively the sulphur group,
         or family. In many respects sulphur resembles oxygen.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Zo["o]l.) Any one of numerous species of yellow or orange
      butterflies of the subfamily {Pierin[ae]}; as, the clouded
      sulphur ({Eurymus philodice} syn. {Colias philodice}),
      which is the common yellow butterfly of the Eastern United
      States.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Amorphous sulphur} (Chem.), an elastic variety of sulphur of
      a resinous appearance, obtained by pouring melted sulphur
      into water. On standing, it passes back into a brittle
      crystalline modification.

   {Liver of sulphur}. (Old Chem.) See {Hepar}.

   {Sulphur acid}. (Chem.) See {Sulphacid}.

   {Sulphur alcohol}. (Chem.) See {Mercaptan}.

   {Sulphur auratum} [L.] (Old Chem.), a golden yellow powder,
      consisting of antimonic sulphide, {Sb2S5}, -- formerly a
      famous nostrum.

   {Sulphur base} (Chem.), an alkaline sulphide capable of
      acting as a base in the formation of sulphur salts
      according to the old dual theory of salts. [Archaic]

   {Sulphur dioxide} (Chem.), a colorless gas, {SO2}, of a
      pungent, suffocating odor, produced by the burning of
      sulphur. It is employed chiefly in the production of
      sulphuric acid, and as a reagent in bleaching; -- called
      also {sulphurous anhydride}, and formerly {sulphurous
      acid}.

   {Sulphur ether} (Chem.), a sulphide of hydrocarbon radicals,
      formed like the ordinary ethers, which are oxides, but
      with sulphur in the place of oxygen.

   {Sulphur salt} (Chem.), a salt of a sulphacid; a sulphosalt.
      

   {Sulphur showers}, showers of yellow pollen, resembling
      sulphur in appearance, often carried from pine forests by
      the wind to a great distance.

   {Sulphur trioxide} (Chem.), a white crystalline solid, {SO3},
      obtained by oxidation of sulphur dioxide. It dissolves in
      water with a hissing noise and the production of heat,
      forming sulphuric acid, and is employed as a dehydrating
      agent. Called also {sulphuric anhydride}, and formerly
      {sulphuric acid}.

   {Sulphur whale}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Sulphur-bottom}.

   {Vegetable sulphur} (Bot.), lycopodium powder. See under
      {Lycopodium}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>sulphur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>sulphur
     n : an abundant tasteless odorless multivalent nonmetallic
         element; best known in yellow crystals; occurs in many
         sulphide and sulphate minerals and even in native form
         (especially in volcanic regions) [syn: {sulfur}, {S}, {atomic
         number 16}]
     v : treat with sulphur in order to preserve; "These dried fruits
         are sulphured" [syn: {sulfur}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
