<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>supply</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>supply</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Supply, VA
  Zip code(s): 22559
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>supply</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Supply \Sup*ply"\, a.
   Serving to contain, deliver, or regulate a supply of
   anything; as, a supply tank or valve.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Supply system} (Zo["o]l.), the system of tubes and canals in
      sponges by means of which food and water are absorbed. See
      Illust. of {Spongi[ae]}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>supply</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Supply \Sup*ply"\, n.; pl. {Supplies}.
   1. The act of supplying; supplial. --A. Tucker.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which supplies a want; sufficiency of things for use
      or want. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) Auxiliary troops or re["e]nforcements. ``My promised
          supply of horsemen.'' --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) The food, and the like, which meets the daily
          necessities of an army or other large body of men;
          store; -- used chiefly in the plural; as, the army was
          discontented for lack of supplies.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) An amount of money provided, as by Parliament or
          Congress, to meet the annual national expenditures;
          generally in the plural; as, to vote supplies.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) A person who fills a place for a time; one who
          supplies the place of another; a substitute; esp., a
          clergyman who supplies a vacant pulpit.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Stated supply} (Eccl.), a clergyman employed to supply a
      pulpit for a definite time, but not settled as a pastor.
      [U.S.]

   {Supply and demand}. (Polit. Econ.) ``Demand means the
      quantity of a given article which would be taken at a
      given price. Supply means the quantity of that article
      which could be had at that price.'' --F. A. Walker.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>supply</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Supply \Sup*ply"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Supplied}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Supplying}.] [For older supploy, F. suppl['e]er, OF. also
   supployer, (assumed) LL. suppletare, from L. supplere,
   suppletum; sub under + plere to fill, akin to plenus full.
   See {Plenty}.]
   1. To fill up, or keep full; to furnish with what is wanted;
      to afford, or furnish with, a sufficiency; as, rivers are
      supplied by smaller streams; an aqueduct supplies an
      artificial lake; -- often followed by with before the
      thing furnished; as, to supply a furnace with fuel; to
      supply soldiers with ammunition.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To serve instead of; to take the place of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Burning ships the banished sun supply. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sun was set, and Vesper, to supply
            His absent beams, had lighted up the sky. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fill temporarily; to serve as substitute for another
      in, as a vacant place or office; to occupy; to have
      possession of; as, to supply a pulpit.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To give; to bring or furnish; to provide; as, to supply
      money for the war. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To furnish; provide; administer; minister; contribute;
        yield; accommodate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>supply</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>supply
     n 1: an amount of something available for use
     2: offering goods and services for sale [ant: {demand}]
     3: the activity of supplying or providing something [syn: {provision},
         {supplying}]
     v 1: provide or furnish with; "We provided the room with an
          electrical heater" [syn: {provide}, {render}, {furnish}]
     2: circulate or distribute or equip with; "issue a new uniform
        to the children"; "supply blankets for the beds" [syn: {issue}]
        [ant: {recall}]
     3: provide what is desired or needed, especially support, food
        or sustenance; "The hostess provided lunch for all the
        guests" [syn: {provide}, {ply}, {cater}]
     4: state or say further; "`It doesn't matter,' he supplied"
        [syn: {add}, {append}]
     [also: {supplied}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
