<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>supported</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>supported</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Support \Sup*port"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Supported}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Supporting}.] [F. supporter, L. supportare to carry
   on, to convey, in LL., to support, sustain; sub under +
   portare to carry. See {Port} demeanor.]
   1. To bear by being under; to keep from falling; to uphold;
      to sustain, in a literal or physical sense; to prop up; to
      bear the weight of; as, a pillar supports a structure; an
      abutment supports an arch; the trunk of a tree supports
      the branches.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To endure without being overcome, exhausted, or changed in
      character; to sustain; as, to support pain, distress, or
      misfortunes.
      [1913 Webster]

            This fierce demeanor and his insolence
            The patience of a god could not support. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To keep from failing or sinking; to solace under affictive
      circumstances; to assist; to encourage; to defend; as, to
      support the courage or spirits.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To assume and carry successfully, as the part of an actor;
      to represent or act; to sustain; as, to support the
      character of King Lear.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To furnish with the means of sustenance or livelihood; to
      maintain; to provide for; as, to support a family; to
      support the ministers of the gospel.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To carry on; to enable to continue; to maintain; as, to
      support a war or a contest; to support an argument or a
      debate.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To verify; to make good; to substantiate; to establish; to
      sustain; as, the testimony is not sufficient to support
      the charges; the evidence will not support the statements
      or allegations.
      [1913 Webster]

            To urge such arguments, as though they were
            sufficient to support and demonstrate a whole scheme
            of moral philosophy.                  --J. Edwards.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To vindicate; to maintain; to defend successfully; as, to
      be able to support one's own cause.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To uphold by aid or countenance; to aid; to help; to back
      up; as, to support a friend or a party; to support the
      present administration.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wherefore, bold pleasant,
            Darest thou support a published traitor? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A attend as an honorary assistant; as, a chairman
       supported by a vice chairman; O'Connell left the prison,
       supported by his two sons.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Support arms} (Mil.), a command in the manual of arms in
      responce to which the piece is held vertically at the
      shoulder, with the hammer resting on the left forearm,
      which is passed horizontally across the body in front;
      also, the position assumed in response to this command.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To maintain; endure; verify; substantiate; countenance;
        patronize; help; back; second; succor; relieve; uphold;
        encourage; favor; nurture; nourish; cherish; shield;
        defend; protect; stay; assist; forward.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>supported</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>supported
     adj 1: sustained or maintained by aid (as distinct from physical
            support); "a club entirely supported by membership
            dues"; "well-supported allegations" [ant: {unsupported}]
     2: held up or having the weight borne especially from below;
        "supported joints in a railroad track have ties directly
        under the rail ends" [ant: {unsupported}, {unsupported}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
