<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>surface</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surface</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Surface \Sur"face\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Surfaced}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Surfacing}.]
   1. To give a surface to; especially, to cause to have a
      smooth or plain surface; to make smooth or plain.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To work over the surface or soil of, as ground, in hunting
      for gold.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surface</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Surface \Sur"face\, v. i.
   1. To rise from the depths of a liquid to the surface; as,
      the submarine surfaced to recharge its batteries.
      [PJC]

   2. To become known or public; -- said of information.
      [PJC]

   3. To show up, as a person who was in hiding; as, he
      absconded with the payroll and surfaced in Argentina.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surface</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Surface \Sur"face`\, n. [F. See {Sur-}, and {Face}, and cf.
   {Superficial}.]
   1. The exterior part of anything that has length and breadth;
      one of the limits that bound a solid, esp. the upper face;
      superficies; the outside; as, the surface of the earth;
      the surface of a diamond; the surface of the body.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bright surface of this ethereous mold. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, outward or external appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Vain and weak understandings, which penetrate no
            deeper than the surface.              --V. Knox.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Geom.) A magnitude that has length and breadth without
      thickness; superficies; as, a plane surface; a spherical
      surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Fort.) That part of the side which is terminated by the
      flank prolonged, and the angle of the nearest bastion.
      --Stocqueler.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Caustic surface}, {Heating surface}, etc. See under
      {Caustic}, {Heating}, etc.

   {Surface condensation}, {Surface condenser}. See under
      {Condensation}, and {Condenser}.

   {Surface gauge} (Mach.), an instrument consisting of a
      standard having a flat base and carrying an adjustable
      pointer, for gauging the evenness of a surface or its
      height, or for marking a line parallel with a surface.

   {Surface grub} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of the great yellow
      underwing moth ({Triph[oe]na pronuba}). It is often
      destructive to the roots of grasses and other plants.

   {Surface plate} (Mach.), a plate having an accurately dressed
      flat surface, used as a standard of flatness by which to
      test other surfaces.

   {Surface printing}, printing from a surface in relief, as
      from type, in distinction from plate printing, in which
      the ink is contained in engraved lines.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surface</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>surface
     adj 1: on the surface; "surface materials of the moon" [ant: {subsurface},
             {overhead}]
     2: involving a surface only; "her beauty is only skin-deep";
        "superficial bruising"; "a surface wound" [syn: {skin-deep},
         {superficial}, {surface(a)}]
     n 1: the outer boundary of an artifact or a material layer
          constituting or resembling such a boundary; "there is a
          special cleaner for these surfaces"; "the cloth had a
          pattern of red dots on a white surface"
     2: the extended two-dimensional outer boundary of a
        three-dimensional object; "they skimmed over the surface
        of the water"; "a brush small enough to clean every dental
        surface"; "the sun has no distinct surface"
     3: the outermost level of the land or sea; "earthquakes
        originate far below the surface"; "three quarters of the
        Earth's surface is covered by water" [syn: {Earth's
        surface}]
     4: a superficial aspect as opposed to the real nature of
        something; "it was not what it appeared to be on the
        surface"
     5: information that has become public; "all the reports were
        out in the open"; "the facts had been brought to the
        surface" [syn: {open}]
     6: a device that provides reactive force when in motion
        relative to the surrounding air; can lift or control a
        plane in flight [syn: {airfoil}, {aerofoil}, {control
        surface}]
     v 1: come to the surface [syn: {come up}, {rise up}, {rise}]
     2: put a coat on; cover the surface of; furnish with a surface;
        "coat the cake with chocolate" [syn: {coat}]
     3: appear or become visible; make a showing; "She turned up at
        the funeral"; "I hope the list key is going to surface
        again" [syn: {come on}, {come out}, {turn up}, {show up}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
