<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>surrender</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surrender</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Surrender \Sur*ren"der\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Surrendered}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Surrendering}.] [OF. surrendre to deliver; sur
   over + rendre to render. See {Sur-}, and {Render}.]
   1. To yield to the power of another; to give or deliver up
      possession of (anything) upon compulsion or demand; as, to
      surrender one's person to an enemy or to an officer; to
      surrender a fort or a ship.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give up possession of; to yield; to resign; as, to
      surrender a right, privilege, or advantage.
      [1913 Webster]

            To surrender up that right which otherwise their
            founders might have in them.          --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To yield to any influence, emotion, passion, or power; --
      used reflexively; as, to surrender one's self to grief, to
      despair, to indolence, or to sleep.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) To yield; to render or deliver up; to give up; as, a
      principal surrendered by his bail, a fugitive from justice
      by a foreign state, or a particular estate by the tenant
      thereof to him in remainder or reversion.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surrender</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Surrender \Sur*ren"der\, v. i.
   To give up one's self into the power of another; to yield;
   as, the enemy, seeing no way of escape, surrendered at the
   first summons.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surrender</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Surrender \Sur*ren"der\, n.
   1. The act of surrendering; the act of yielding, or resigning
      one's person, or the possession of something, into the
      power of another; as, the surrender of a castle to an
      enemy; the surrender of a right.
      [1913 Webster]

            That he may secure some liberty he makes a surrender
            in trust of the whole of it.          --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law)
      (a) The yielding of a particular estate to him who has an
          immediate estate in remainder or reversion.
      (b) The giving up of a principal into lawful custody by
          his bail.
      (c) The delivery up of fugitives from justice by one
          government to another, as by a foreign state. See
          {Extradition}. --Wharton.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Insurance) The voluntary cancellation of the legal
      liability of the company by the insured and beneficiary
      for a consideration (called the

   {surrender value}).
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>surrender</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>surrender
     n 1: acceptance of despair [syn: {resignation}]
     2: a verbal act of admitting defeat [syn: {giving up}, {yielding}]
     3: the delivery of a principal into lawful custody
     4: the act of surrendering (under agreed conditions); "they
        were protected until the capitulation of the fort" [syn: {capitulation},
         {fall}]
     v 1: give up or agree to forego to the power or possession of
          another; "The last Taleban fighters finally surrendered"
          [syn: {give up}] [ant: {resist}]
     2: relinquish possession or control over; "The squatters had to
        surrender the building after the police moved in" [syn: {cede},
         {deliver}, {give up}]
     3: relinquish to the power of another; yield to the control of
        another [syn: {relinquish}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
