<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>survey</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>survey</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Survey \Sur"vey\, n. [Formerly accentuated universally on the
   last syllable, and still so accented by many speakers.]
   1. The act of surveying; a general view, as from above.
      [1913 Webster]

            Under his proud survey the city lies. --Sir J.
                                                  Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A particular view; an examination, especially an official
      examination, of all the parts or particulars of a thing,
      with a design to ascertain the condition, quantity, or
      quality; as, a survey of the stores of a ship; a survey of
      roads and bridges; a survey of buildings.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The operation of finding the contour, dimensions,
      position, or other particulars of, as any part of the
      earth's surface, whether land or water; also, a measured
      plan and description of any portion of country, or of a
      road or line through it.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Survey of dogs}. See {Court of regard}, under {Regard}.

   {Trigonometrical survey}, a survey of a portion of country by
      measuring a single base, and connecting it with various
      points in the tract surveyed by a series of triangles, the
      angles of which are carefully measured, the relative
      positions and distances of all parts being computed from
      these data.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Review; retrospect; examination; prospect.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>survey</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Survey \Sur*vey"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Surveyed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Surveying}.] [OF. surveoir, surveer; sur, sor, over, E.
   sur + veoir, veeir, to see, F. voir, L. videre. See {Sur-},
   and {Vision}, and cf. {Supervise}.]
   1. To inspect, or take a view of; to view with attention, as
      from a high place; to overlook; as, to stand on a hill,
      and survey the surrounding country.
      [1913 Webster]

            Round he surveys and well might, where he stood,
            So high above.                        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To view with a scrutinizing eye; to examine.
      [1913 Webster]

            With such altered looks, . . .
            All pale and speechless, he surveyed me round.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To examine with reference to condition, situation, value,
      etc.; to examine and ascertain the state of; as, to survey
      a building in order to determine its value and exposure to
      loss by fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To determine the form, extent, position, etc., of, as a
      tract of land, a coast, harbor, or the like, by means of
      linear and angular measurments, and the application of the
      principles of geometry and trigonometry; as, to survey
      land or a coast.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To examine and ascertain, as the boundaries and royalties
      of a manor, the tenure of the tenants, and the rent and
      value of the same. [Eng.] --Jacob (Law Dict.).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>survey</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>survey
     n 1: a detailed critical inspection [syn: {study}]
     2: short descriptive summary (of events) [syn: {sketch}, {resume}]
     3: the act of looking or seeing or observing; "he tried to get
        a better view of it"; "his survey of the battlefield was
        limited" [syn: {view}, {sight}]
     v 1: consider in a comprehensive way; "He appraised the situation
          carefully before acting" [syn: {appraise}]
     2: look over in a comprehensively, inspect; "He surveyed his
        new classmates"
     3: keep under surveillance; "The police had been following him
        for weeks but they could not prove his involvement in the
        bombing" [syn: {surveil}, {follow}]
     4: hold a review (of troops) [syn: {review}, {go over}]
     5: make a survey of; for statistical purposes
     6: plot a map of (land)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
