<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>suspending</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>suspending</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Suspend \Sus*pend"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Suspended}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Suspending}.] [F. suspendre, or OF. souspendre (where
   the prefix is L. subtus below, from sub under), L.
   suspendere, suspensum; pref. sus- (see {Sub-}) + pendere to
   hang. See {Pedant}, and cf. {Suspense}, n.]
   1. To attach to something above; to hang; as, to suspend a
      ball by a thread; to suspend a needle by a loadstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make to depend; as, God hath suspended the promise of
      eternal life on the condition of obedience and holiness of
      life. [Archaic] --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to cease for a time; to hinder from proceeding;
      to interrupt; to delay; to stay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Suspend your indignation against my brother. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The guard nor fights nor fies; their fate so near
            At once suspends their courage and their fear.
                                                  --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To hold in an undetermined or undecided state; as, to
      suspend one's judgment or opinion. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To debar, or cause to withdraw temporarily, from any
      privilege, from the execution of an office, from the
      enjoyment of income, etc.; as, to suspend a student from
      college; to suspend a member of a club.
      [1913 Webster]

            Good men should not be suspended from the exercise
            of their ministry and deprived of their livelihood
            for ceremonies which are on all hands acknowledged
            indifferent.                          --Bp.
                                                  Sanderson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cause to cease for a time from operation or effect; as,
      to suspend the habeas corpus act; to suspend the rules of
      a legislative body.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Chem.) To support in a liquid, as an insoluble powder, by
      stirring, to facilitate chemical action.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To suspend payment} (Com.), to cease paying debts or
      obligations; to fail; -- said of a merchant, a bank, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To hang; interrupt; delay; intermit; stay; hinder;
        debar.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
