<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>swell</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Swell \Swell\, v. i. [imp. {Swelled}; p. p. {Swelled} or
   {Swollen}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Swelling}.] [AS. swellan; akin to
   D. zwellen, OS. &amp; OHG. swellan, G. schwellen, Icel. svella,
   Sw. sv["a]lla.]
   1. To grow larger; to dilate or extend the exterior surface
      or dimensions, by matter added within, or by expansion of
      the inclosed substance; as, the legs swell in dropsy; a
      bruised part swells; a bladder swells by inflation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To increase in size or extent by any addition; to increase
      in volume or force; as, a river swells, and overflows its
      banks; sounds swell or diminish.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To rise or be driven into waves or billows; to heave; as,
      in tempest, the ocean swells into waves.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be puffed up or bloated; as, to swell with pride.
      [1913 Webster]

            You swell at the tartan, as the bull is said to do
            at scarlet.                           --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be inflated; to belly; as, the sails swell.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To be turgid, bombastic, or extravagant; as, swelling
      words; a swelling style.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To protuberate; to bulge out; as, a cask swells in the
      middle.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To be elated; to rise arrogantly.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your equal mind yet swells not into state. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To grow upon the view; to become larger; to expand.
      ``Monarchs to behold the swelling scene!'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To become larger in amount; as, many little debts added,
       swell to a great amount.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To act in a pompous, ostentatious, or arrogant manner; to
       strut; to look big.
       [1913 Webster]

             Here he comes, swelling like a turkey cock. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Swell \Swell\, v. t.
   1. To increase the size, bulk, or dimensions of; to cause to
      rise, dilate, or increase; as, rains and dissolving snow
      swell the rivers in spring; immigration swells the
      population.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The Church] swells her high, heart-cheering tone.
                                                  --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To aggravate; to heighten.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is low ebb with his accuser when such
            peccadilloes are put to swell the charge.
                                                  --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To raise to arrogance; to puff up; to inflate; as, to be
      swelled with pride or haughtiness.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mus.) To augment gradually in force or loudness, as the
      sound of a note.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Swell \Swell\, n.
   1. The act of swelling.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Gradual increase. Specifically:
      (a) Increase or augmentation in bulk; protuberance.
      (b) Increase in height; elevation; rise.
          [1913 Webster]

                Little River affords navigation during a swell
                to within three miles of the Miami. --Jefferson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) Increase of force, intensity, or volume of sound.
          [1913 Webster]

                Music arose with its voluptuous swell. --Byron.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) Increase of power in style, or of rhetorical force.
          [1913 Webster]

                The swell and subsidence of his periods.
                                                  --Landor.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. A gradual ascent, or rounded elevation, of land; as, an
      extensive plain abounding with little swells.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A wave, or billow; especially, a succession of large
      waves; the roll of the sea after a storm; as, a heavy
      swell sets into the harbor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The swell
            Of the long waves that roll in yonder bay.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gigantic swells and billows of the snow.
                                                  --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.) A gradual increase and decrease of the volume of
      sound; the crescendo and diminuendo combined; -- generally
      indicated by the sign.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A showy, dashing person; a dandy. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ground swell}. See under {Ground}.

   {Organ swell} (Mus.), a certain number of pipes inclosed in a
      box, the uncovering of which by means of a pedal produces
      increased sound.

   {Swell shark} (Zo["o]l.), a small shark ({Scyllium
      ventricosum}) of the west coast of North America, which
      takes in air when caught, and swells up like a swellfish.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Swell \Swell\, a.
   Having the characteristics of a person of rank and
   importance; showy; dandified; distinguished; as, a swell
   person; a swell neighborhood. [Slang]
   [1913 Webster]

   {Swell mob}. See under {Mob}. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swell</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>swell
     adj : very good; "he did a bully job"; "a neat sports car"; "had a
           great time at the party"; "you look simply smashing"
           [syn: {bang-up}, {bully}, {corking}, {cracking}, {dandy},
            {great}, {groovy}, {keen}, {neat}, {nifty}, {not
           bad(p)}, {peachy}, {slap-up}, {smashing}]
     n 1: the undulating movement of the surface of the open sea [syn:
           {crestless wave}]
     2: a rounded elevation (especially one on an ocean floor)
     3: a crescendo followed by a decrescendo
     4: a man who is much concerned with his dress and appearance
        [syn: {dandy}, {dude}, {fop}, {gallant}, {sheik}, {beau},
        {fashion plate}, {clotheshorse}]
     v 1: increase in size, magnitude, number, or intensity; "The
          music swelled to a crescendo"
     2: become filled with pride, arrogance, or anger; "The mother
        was swelling with importance when she spoke of her son"
        [syn: {puff up}]
     3: expand abnormally; "The bellies of the starving children are
        swelling" [syn: {swell up}, {intumesce}, {tumefy}, {tumesce}]
     4: as of feelings and thoughts, or other ephemeral things;
        "Strong emotions welled up"; "Smoke swelled from it" [syn:
         {well up}]
     5: come up; "Tears well in her eyes" [syn: {well}]
     6: cause to become swollen; "The water swells the wood"
     [also: {swollen}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
