<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>swelling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swelling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Swelling
   of Jordan (Jer. 12:5), literally the "pride" of Jordan (as in
   R.V.), i.e., the luxuriant thickets of tamarisks, poplars,
   reeds, etc., which were the lair of lions and other beasts of
   prey. The reference is not to the overflowing of the river
   banks. (Comp. 49:19; 50:44; Zech. 11:3).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swelling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Swell \Swell\, v. i. [imp. {Swelled}; p. p. {Swelled} or
   {Swollen}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Swelling}.] [AS. swellan; akin to
   D. zwellen, OS. &amp; OHG. swellan, G. schwellen, Icel. svella,
   Sw. sv["a]lla.]
   1. To grow larger; to dilate or extend the exterior surface
      or dimensions, by matter added within, or by expansion of
      the inclosed substance; as, the legs swell in dropsy; a
      bruised part swells; a bladder swells by inflation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To increase in size or extent by any addition; to increase
      in volume or force; as, a river swells, and overflows its
      banks; sounds swell or diminish.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To rise or be driven into waves or billows; to heave; as,
      in tempest, the ocean swells into waves.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be puffed up or bloated; as, to swell with pride.
      [1913 Webster]

            You swell at the tartan, as the bull is said to do
            at scarlet.                           --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be inflated; to belly; as, the sails swell.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To be turgid, bombastic, or extravagant; as, swelling
      words; a swelling style.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To protuberate; to bulge out; as, a cask swells in the
      middle.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To be elated; to rise arrogantly.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your equal mind yet swells not into state. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To grow upon the view; to become larger; to expand.
      ``Monarchs to behold the swelling scene!'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To become larger in amount; as, many little debts added,
       swell to a great amount.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To act in a pompous, ostentatious, or arrogant manner; to
       strut; to look big.
       [1913 Webster]

             Here he comes, swelling like a turkey cock. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swelling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Swelling \Swell"ing\, n.
   1. The act of that which swells; as, the swelling of rivers
      in spring; the swelling of the breast with pride.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rise to the swelling of the voiceless sea.
                                                  --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A protuberance; a prominence; especially (Med.), an
      unnatural prominence or protuberance; as, a scrofulous
      swelling.
      [1913 Webster]

            The superficies of such plates are not even, but
            have many cavities and swellings.     --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>swelling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>swelling
     adj : becoming puffy as from internal bleeding or accumulation of
           other fluids; "put ice on the swelling ankle"
     n 1: abnormal protuberance or localized enlargement [syn: {puffiness},
           {lump}]
     2: the swelling of certain substances when they are heated
        (often accompanied by release of water) [syn: {intumescence},
         {intumescency}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
