<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>symphony</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>symphony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Symphony
     
        &lt;tool, product&gt; {Lotus Development}'s successor to their
        {Lotus 1-2-3} spreadsheet.  Unlike 1-2-3, Symphony allowed a
        limited form of {multitasking}.  The user could switch
        manually between it and {MS-DOS} and separate graph and
        spreadsheet windows could be opened simultaneously and would
        be updated automatically when cells were changed.  In
        addition, a small word processor could be opened in a third
        window.  These all could be printed out on the same report.
        Symphony could read and write Lotus 1-2-3 files and had
        interactive graphical output and a word processor, thus making
        it effectively a report generator.  Unlike 1-2-3, Symphony was
        not a great commercial success.
     
        (1995-03-28)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>symphony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Symphony \Sym"pho*ny\, n.; pl. {Symphonies}. [F. symphonie (cf.
   It. sinfonia), L. symphonia, Gr. ?; sy`n with + ? a sound,
   the voice. See {Phonetic}.]
   1. A consonance or harmony of sounds, agreeable to the ear,
      whether the sounds are vocal or instrumental, or both.
      [1913 Webster]

            The trumpets sound,
            And warlike symphony in heard around. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A stringed instrument formerly in use, somewhat resembling
      the virginal.
      [1913 Webster]

            With harp and pipe and symphony.      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.)
      (a) An elaborate instrumental composition for a full
          orchestra, consisting usually, like the sonata, of
          three or four contrasted yet inwardly related
          movements, as the allegro, the adagio, the minuet and
          trio, or scherzo, and the finale in quick time. The
          term has recently been applied to large orchestral
          works in freer form, with arguments or programmes to
          explain their meaning, such as the ``symphonic poems''
          of Liszt. The term was formerly applied to any
          composition for an orchestra, as overtures, etc., and
          still earlier, to certain compositions partly vocal,
          partly instrumental.
      (b) An instrumental passage at the beginning or end, or in
          the course of, a vocal composition; a prelude,
          interlude, or postude; a ritornello.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>symphony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>symphony
     n 1: a long and complex sonata for symphony orchestra [syn: {symphonic
          music}]
     2: a large orchestra; can perform symphonies; "we heard the
        Vienna symphony" [syn: {symphony orchestra}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
