<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>oath</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>OATH, n.  In law, a solemn appeal to the Deity, made binding upon the
conscience by a penalty for perjury.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Oath
   a solemn appeal to God, permitted on fitting occasions (Deut.
   6:13; Jer. 4:2), in various forms (Gen. 16:5; 2 Sam. 12:5; Ruth
   1:17; Hos. 4:15; Rom. 1:9), and taken in different ways (Gen.
   14:22; 24:2; 2 Chr. 6:22). God is represented as taking an oath
   (Heb. 6:16-18), so also Christ (Matt. 26:64), and Paul (Rom.
   9:1; Gal. 1:20; Phil. 1:8). The precept, "Swear not at all,"
   refers probably to ordinary conversation between man and man
   (Matt. 5:34,37). But if the words are taken as referring to
   oaths, then their intention may have been to show "that the
   proper state of Christians is to require no oaths; that when
   evil is expelled from among them every yea and nay will be as
   decisive as an oath, every promise as binding as a vow."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>OATH
     
        Object-oriented Abstract Type Hierarchy, a class library for
        C++ from {Texas Instruments}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Oath \Oath\ ([=o]th), n.; pl. {Oaths} ([=o][th]z). [OE. othe,
   oth, ath, AS. [=a][eth]; akin to D. eed, OS. [=e][eth], G.
   eid, Icel. ei[eth]r, Sw. ed, Dan. eed, Goth. ai[thorn]s; cf.
   OIr. oeth.]
   1. A solemn affirmation or declaration, made with a reverent
      appeal to God for the truth of what is affirmed. ``I have
      an oath in heaven'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            An oath of secrecy for the concealing of those
            [inventions] which we think fit to keep secret.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A solemn affirmation, connected with a sacred object, or
      one regarded as sacred, as the temple, the altar, the
      blood of Abel, the Bible, the Koran, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) An appeal (in verification of a statement made) to a
      superior sanction, in such a form as exposes the party
      making the appeal to an indictment for perjury if the
      statement be false.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A careless and blasphemous use of the name of the divine
      Being, or anything divine or sacred, by way of appeal or
      as a profane exclamation or ejaculation; an expression of
      profane swearing. ``A terrible oath'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>oath
     n 1: profane or obscene expression usually of surprise or anger;
          "expletives were deleted" [syn: {curse}, {curse word}, {expletive},
           {swearing}, {swearword}, {cuss}]
     2: a commitment to tell the truth (especially in a court of
        law); to lie under oath is to become subject to
        prosecution for perjury [syn: {swearing}]
     3: a solemn promise, usually invoking a divine witness,
        regarding your future acts or behavior; "they took an oath
        of allegience"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
