<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>object</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>object</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>object
     
        In {object-oriented programming}, a unique instance of a data
        structure defined according to the template provided by its
        {class}.  Each object has its own values for the variables
        belonging to its class and can respond to the messages
        ({method}s) defined by its class.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>object</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Object \Ob*ject"\, v. i.
   To make opposition in words or argument; to express one's
   displeasure; -- usually followed by to; as, she objected to
   his vulgar language. --Sir. T. More.
   [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>object</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Object \Ob"ject\ ([o^]b"j[e^]kt), n. [L. objectus. See {Object},
   v. t.]
   1. That which is put, or which may be regarded as put, in the
      way of some of the senses; something visible or tangible
      and persists for an appreciable time; as, he observed an
      object in the distance; all the objects in sight; he
      touched a strange object in the dark.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything which is set, or which may be regarded as set,
      before the mind so as to be apprehended or known; that of
      which the mind by any of its activities takes cognizance,
      whether a thing external in space or a conception formed
      by the mind itself; as, an object of knowledge, wonder,
      fear, thought, study, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Object is a term for that about which the knowing
            subject is conversant; what the schoolmen have
            styled the ``materia circa quam.''    --Sir. W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The object of their bitterest hatred. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That toward which the mind, or any of its activities, is
      directed; that on which the purpose are fixed as the end
      of action or effort; that which is sought for; goal; end;
      aim; motive; final cause.
      [1913 Webster]

            Object, beside its proper signification, came to be
            abusively applied to denote motive, end, final cause
            . . . . This innovation was probably borrowed from
            the French.                           --Sir. W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let our object be, our country, our whole country,
            and nothing but our country.          --D. Webster.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Sight; show; appearance; aspect. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He, advancing close
            Up to the lake, past all the rest, arose
            In glorious object.                   --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Gram.) A word, phrase, or clause toward which an action
      is directed, or is considered to be directed; as, the
      object of a transitive verb.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Computers) Any set of data that is or can be manipulated
      or referenced by a computer program as a single entity; --
      the term may be used broadly, to include files, images
      (such as icons on the screen), or small data structures.
      More narrowly, anything defined as an object within an
      object-oriented programming language.
      [PJC]

   7. (Ontology) Anything which exists and which has attributes;
      distinguished from {attributes}, {processes}, and
      {relations}.
      [PJC]

   {Object glass}, the lens, or system of lenses, placed at the
      end of a telescope, microscope, etc., which is toward the
      object. Its function is to form an image of the object,
      which is then viewed by the eyepiece. Called also
      {objective} or {objective lens}. See Illust. of
      {Microscope}.

   {Object lesson}, a lesson in which object teaching is made
      use of.

   {Object staff}. (Leveling) Same as {Leveling staff}.

   {Object teaching}, a method of instruction, in which
      illustrative objects are employed, each new word or idea
      being accompanied by a representation of that which it
      signifies; -- used especially in the kindergarten, for
      young children.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>object</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Object \Ob*ject"\ ([o^]b*j[e^]kt"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Objected}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Objecting}.] [L. objectus, p. p.
   of objicere, obicere, to throw or put before, to oppose; ob
   (see {Ob-}) + jacere to throw: cf. objecter. See {Jet} a
   shooting forth.]
   1. To set before or against; to bring into opposition; to
      oppose. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Of less account some knight thereto object,
            Whose loss so great and harmful can not prove.
                                                  --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some strong impediment or other objecting itself.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pallas to their eyes
            The mist objected, and condensed the skies. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To offer in opposition as a criminal charge or by way of
      accusation or reproach; to adduce as an objection or
      adverse reason.
      [1913 Webster]

            He gave to him to object his heinous crime.
                                                  --Spencer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Others object the poverty of the nation. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            The book . . . giveth liberty to object any crime
            against such as are to be ordered.    --Whitgift.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>object</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Object \Ob*ject"\, a. [L. objectus, p. p.]
   Opposed; presented in opposition; also, exposed. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>object</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>object
     n 1: a tangible and visible entity; an entity that can cast a
          shadow; "it was full of rackets, balls and other
          objects" [syn: {physical object}]
     2: the goal intended to be attained (and which is believed to
        be attainable); "the sole object of her trip was to see
        her children" [syn: {aim}, {objective}, {target}]
     3: (grammar) a constituent that is acted upon; "the object of
        the verb"
     4: the focus of cognitions or feelings; "objects of thought";
        "the object of my affection"
     v 1: express or raise an objection or protest or criticism or
          express dissent; "She never objected to the amount of
          work her boss charged her with"; "When asked to drive
          the truck, she objected that she did not have a driver's
          license"
     2: be averse to or express disapproval of; "My wife objects to
        modern furniture"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
