<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>oblique</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oblique</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Oblique \Ob*lique"\, a. [F., fr. L. obliquus; ob (see {Ob-}) +
   liquis oblique; cf. licinus bent upward, Gr. le`chrios
   slanting.] [Written also {oblike}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Not erect or perpendicular; neither parallel to, nor at
      right angles from, the base; slanting; inclined.
      [1913 Webster]

            It has a direction oblique to that of the former
            motion.                               --Cheyne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not straightforward; indirect; obscure; hence,
      disingenuous; underhand; perverse; sinister.
      [1913 Webster]

            The love we bear our friends . . .
            Hath in it certain oblique ends.      --Drayton.
      [1913 Webster]

            This mode of oblique research, when a more direct
            one is denied, we find to be the only one in our
            power.                                --De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then would be closed the restless, oblique eye.
            That looks for evil, like a treacherous spy.
                                                  --Wordworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not direct in descent; not following the line of father
      and son; collateral.
      [1913 Webster]

            His natural affection in a direct line was strong,
            in an oblique but weak.               --Baker.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Oblique angle}, {Oblique ascension}, etc. See under {Angle},
      {Ascension}, etc.

   {Oblique arch} (Arch.), an arch whose jambs are not at right
      angles with the face, and whose intrados is in consequence
      askew.

   {Oblique bridge}, a skew bridge. See under {Bridge}, n.

   {Oblique case} (Gram.), any case except the nominative. See
      {Case}, n.

   {Oblique circle} (Projection), a circle whose plane is
      oblique to the axis of the primitive plane.

   {Oblique fire} (Mil.), a fire the direction of which is not
      perpendicular to the line fired at.

   {Oblique flank} (Fort.), that part of the curtain whence the
      fire of the opposite bastion may be discovered. --Wilhelm.

   {Oblique leaf}. (Bot.)
      (a) A leaf twisted or inclined from the normal position.
      (b) A leaf having one half different from the other.

   {Oblique line} (Geom.), a line that, meeting or tending to
      meet another, makes oblique angles with it.

   {Oblique motion} (Mus.), a kind of motion or progression in
      which one part ascends or descends, while the other
      prolongs or repeats the same tone, as in the accompanying
      example.

   {Oblique muscle} (Anat.), a muscle acting in a direction
      oblique to the mesial plane of the body, or to the
      associated muscles; -- applied especially to two muscles
      of the eyeball.

   {Oblique narration}. See {Oblique speech}.

   {Oblique planes} (Dialing), planes which decline from the
      zenith, or incline toward the horizon.

   {Oblique sailing} (Naut.), the movement of a ship when she
      sails upon some rhumb between the four cardinal points,
      making an oblique angle with the meridian.

   {Oblique speech} (Rhet.), speech which is quoted indirectly,
      or in a different person from that employed by the
      original speaker.

   {Oblique sphere} (Astron. &amp; Geog.), the celestial or
      terrestrial sphere when its axis is oblique to the horizon
      of the place; or as it appears to an observer at any point
      on the earth except the poles and the equator.

   {Oblique step} (Mil.), a step in marching, by which the
      soldier, while advancing, gradually takes ground to the
      right or left at an angle of about 25[deg]. It is not now
      practiced. --Wilhelm.

   {Oblique system of co["o]rdinates} (Anal. Geom.), a system in
      which the co["o]rdinate axes are oblique to each other.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oblique</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Oblique \Ob*lique"\, n. (Geom.)
   An oblique line.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oblique</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Oblique \Ob*lique"\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Obliqued}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Obliquing}.]
   1. To deviate from a perpendicular line; to move in an
      oblique direction.
      [1913 Webster]

            Projecting his person towards it in a line which
            obliqued from the bottom of his spine. --Sir. W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) To march in a direction oblique to the line of the
      column or platoon; -- formerly accomplished by oblique
      steps, now by direct steps, the men half-facing either to
      the right or left.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oblique</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>oblique
     adj 1: slanting or inclined in direction or course or
            position--neither parallel nor perpendicular nor
            right-angular; "the oblique rays of the winter sun";
            "acute and obtuse angles are oblique angles"; "the
            axis of an oblique cone is not perpendicular to its
            base" [ant: {parallel}, {perpendicular}]
     2: indirect in departing from the accepted or proper way;
        misleading; "used devious means to achieve success"; "gave
        oblique answers to direct questions"; "oblique political
        maneuvers" [syn: {devious}]
     n 1: any grammatical case other than the nominative [syn: {oblique
          case}] [ant: {nominative}]
     2: a diagonally arranged abdominal muscle on either side of the
        torso [syn: {external oblique muscle}, {musculus obliquus
        externus abdominis}, {abdominal external oblique muscle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
