<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>obligation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>obligation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Obligation \Ob"li*ga"tion\, n. [F. obligation. L. obligatio. See
   {Oblige}.]
   1. The act of obligating.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which obligates or constrains; the binding power of a
      promise, contract, oath, or vow, or of law; that which
      constitutes legal or moral duty.
      [1913 Webster]

            A tender conscience is a stronger obligation than a
            proson.                               --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any act by which a person becomes bound to do something to
      or for another, or to forbear something; external duties
      imposed by law, promise, or contract, by the relations of
      society, or by courtesy, kindness, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every man has obligations which belong to his
            station. Duties extend beyond obligation, and direct
            the affections, desires, and intentions, as well as
            the actions.                          --Whewell.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The state of being obligated or bound; the state of being
      indebted for an act of favor or kindness; -- often used
      with under to indicate being in that state; as, to place
      others under obligations to one.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) A bond with a condition annexed, and a penalty for
      nonfulfillment. In a larger sense, it is an acknowledgment
      of a duty to pay a certain sum or do a certain things.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Days of obligation}. See under {Day}.

   {under obligation}, {under an obligation}. in a state of
      obligation[4].
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>obligation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>obligation
     n 1: the social force that binds you to your obligations and the
          courses of action demanded by that force; "we must
          instill a sense of duty in our children"; "every right
          implies a responsibility; every opportunity, an
          obligation; every possession, a duty"- John
          D.Rockefeller Jr [syn: {duty}, {responsibility}]
     2: the state of being obligated to do or pay something; "he is
        under an obligation to finish the job"
     3: a personal relation in which one is indebted for a service
        or favor
     4: a legal agreement specifying a payment or action and the
        penalty for failure to comply
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
