<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>offering</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>offering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Offering
   an oblation, dedicated to God. Thus Cain consecrated to God of
   the first-fruits of the earth, and Abel of the firstlings of the
   flock (Gen. 4:3, 4). Under the Levitical system different kinds
   of offerings are specified, and laws laid down as to their
   presentation. These are described under their distinctive names.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>offering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Offer \Of"fer\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Offered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Offering}.] [OE. offren, {AS}. offrian to sacrifice, fr. L.
   offerre; ob (see {OB-}) + ferre to bear, bring. The English
   word was influenced by F. offrir to offer, of the same
   origin. See 1st {Bear}.]
   1. To present, as an act of worship; to immolate; to
      sacrifice; to present in prayer or devotion; -- often with
      up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt offer every day a bullock for a sin
            offering for atonement.               --Ex. xxix.
                                                  36.
      [1913 Webster]

            A holy priesthood to offer up spiritual sacrifices.
                                                  --1 Pet. ii.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring to or before; to hold out to; to present for
      acceptance or rejection; as, to offer a present, or a
      bribe; to offer one's self in marriage.
      [1913 Webster]

            I offer thee three things.            --2 Sam. xxiv.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To present in words; to proffer; to make a proposal of; to
      suggest; as, to offer an opinion. With the infinitive as
      an objective: To make an offer; to declare one's
      willingness; as, he offered to help me.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To attempt; to undertake.
      [1913 Webster]

            All that offer to defend him.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To bid, as a price, reward, or wages; as, to offer a
      guinea for a ring; to offer a salary or reward.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To put in opposition to; to manifest in an offensive way;
      to threaten; as, to offer violence, attack, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To propose; propound; move; proffer; tender; sacrifice;
        immolate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>offering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Offering \Of"fer*ing\, n.
   1. The act of an offerer; a proffering.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is offered, esp. in divine service; that which
      is presented as an expiation or atonement for sin, or as a
      free gift; a sacrifice; an oblation; as, sin offering.
      [1913 Webster]

            They are polluted offerings more abhorred
            Than spotted livers in the sacrifice. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sum of money offered, as in church service; as, a
      missionary offering. Specif.: (Ch. of Eng.) Personal
      tithes payable according to custom, either at certain
      seasons as Christmas or Easter, or on certain occasions as
      marriages or christenings.
      [1913 Webster]

            [None] to the offering before her should go.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Burnt offering}, {Drink offering}, etc. See under {Burnt}.
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>offering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>offering
     n 1: something offered (as a proposal or bid); "noteworthy new
          offerings for investors included several index funds"
          [syn: {offer}]
     2: money contributed to a religious organization
     3: the verbal act of offering; "a generous offer of assistance"
        [syn: {offer}]
     4: the act of contributing to the funds of a church or charity;
        "oblations for aid to the poor" [syn: {oblation}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
