<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>offense</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>offense</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Offense \Of*fense"\, Offence \Of*fence"\, n. [F., fr. L.
   offensa. See {Offend}.]
   1. The act of offending in any sense; esp., a crime or a sin,
      an affront or an injury.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who was delivered for our offenses, and was raised
            again for our justification.          --Rom. iv. 25.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have given my opinion against the authority of two
            great men, but I hope without offense to their
            memories.                             --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being offended or displeased; anger;
      displeasure; as, to cause offense.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was content to give them just cause of offense,
            when they had power to make just revenge. --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A cause or occasion of stumbling or of sin. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Woe to that man by whom the offense cometh! --Matt.
                                                  xviii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. In any contest, the act or process of attacking as
      contrasted with the act of defending; the offensive; as,
      to go on the offense.
      [PJC]

   5. (Sports) The members of a team who have the primary
      responsibility to score goals, in contrast to those who
      have the responsibility to defend, i.e. to prevent the
      opposing team from scoring goal.
      [PJC]

   Note: This word, like expense, is often spelled with a c. It
         ought, however, to undergo the same change with
         expense, the reasons being the same, namely, that s
         must be used in offensive as in expensive, and is found
         in the Latin offensio, and the French offense.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To take offense}, to feel, or assume to be, injured or
      affronted; to become angry or hostile.

   {Weapons of offense}, those which are used in attack, in
      distinction from those of defense, which are used to
      repel.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Displeasure; umbrage; resentment; misdeed; misdemeanor;
        trespass; transgression; delinquency; fault; sin; crime;
        affront; indignity; outrage; insult.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>offense</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>offense
     n 1: a lack of politeness; a failure to show regard for others;
          wounding the feelings or others [syn: {discourtesy}, {offence},
           {offensive activity}]
     2: a feeling of anger caused by being offended; "he took
        offence at my question" [syn: {umbrage}, {offence}]
     3: a crime less serious than a felony [syn: {misdemeanor}, {misdemeanour},
         {infraction}, {offence}, {violation}, {infringement}]
     4: the team that has the ball (or puck) and is trying to score
        [syn: {offence}] [ant: {defense}, {defense}]
     5: the action of attacking an enemy [syn: {offence}, {offensive}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
