<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>office</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>office</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Office
     
        {Microsoft Office}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>office</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Office \Of`fice\, v. t.
   To perform, as the duties of an office; to discharge. [Obs.]
   --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>office</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Office \Of"fice\, n. [F., fr. L. officium, for opificium; ops
   ability, wealth, help + facere to do or make. See {Opulent},
   {Fact}.]
   1. That which a person does, either voluntarily or by
      appointment, for, or with reference to, others; customary
      duty, or a duty that arises from the relations of man to
      man; as, kind offices, pious offices.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would I could do a good office between you.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A special duty, trust, charge, or position, conferred by
      authority and for a public purpose; a position of trust or
      authority; as, an executive or judical office; a municipal
      office.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A charge or trust, of a sacred nature, conferred by God
      himself; as, the office of a priest under the old
      dispensation, and that of the apostles in the new.
      [1913 Webster]

            Inasmuch as I am the apostle of the Gentiles, I
            magnify mine office.                  --Rom. xi. 13.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is performed, intended, or assigned to be done,
      by a particular thing, or that which anything is fitted to
      perform; a function; -- answering to duty in intelligent
      beings.
      [1913 Webster]

            They [the eyes] resign their office and their light.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hesperus, whose office is to bring
            Twilight upon the earth.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            In this experiment the several intervals of the
            teeth of the comb do the office of so many prisms.
                                                  --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The place where any kind of business or service for others
      is transacted; a building, suite of rooms, or room in
      which public officers or workers in any organization
      transact business; as, the register's office; a lawyer's
      office; the doctor's office; the Mayor's office.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   6. The company or corporation, or persons collectively, whose
      place of business is in an office; as, I have notified the
      office.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. The apartments or outhouses in which the domestics
      discharge the duties attached to the service of a house,
      as kitchens, pantries, stables, etc. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

            As for the offices, let them stand at distance.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Eccl.) Any service other than that of ordination and the
      Mass; any prescribed religious service.
      [1913 Webster]

            This morning was read in the church, after the
            office was done, the declaration setting forth the
            late conspiracy against the king's person. --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Holy office}. Same as {Inquisition}, n., 3.

   {Houses of office}. Same as def. 7 above. --Chaucer.

   {Little office} (R. C. Ch.), an office recited in honor of
      the Virgin Mary.

   {Office bearer}, an officer; one who has a specific office or
      duty to perform.

   {Office copy} (Law), an authenticated or certified copy of a
      record, from the proper office. See {Certified copies},
      under {Copy}. --Abbott.

   {Office-found} (Law), the finding of an inquest of office.
      See under {Inquest}.

   {Office holder}. See {Officeholder} in the Vocabulary

   {Office hours}. the hours of the day during which business is
      transacted at an office[5].

   {Office seeker}. a person who is attempting to get elected to
      an elected office, or to get an appointment to an
      appointive public office.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>office</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>office
     n 1: place of business where professional or clerical duties are
          performed; "he rented an office in the new building"
          [syn: {business office}]
     2: an administrative unit of government; "the Central
        Intelligence Agency"; "the Census Bureau"; "Office of
        Management and Budget"; "Tennessee Valley Authority" [syn:
         {agency}, {federal agency}, {government agency}, {bureau},
         {authority}]
     3: the actions and activities assigned to or required or
        expected of a person or group; "the function of a
        teacher"; "the government must do its part"; "play its
        role" [syn: {function}, {part}, {role}]
     4: (of a government or government official) holding an office
        means being in power; "being in office already gives a
        candidate a great advantage"; "during his first year in
        office"; "during his first year in power"; "the power of
        the president" [syn: {power}]
     5: professional or clerical workers in an office; "the whole
        office was late the morning of the blizzard" [syn: {office
        staff}]
     6: a religious rite or service prescribed by ecclesiastical
        authorities; "the offices of the mass"
     7: a job in an organization; "he occupied a post in the
        treasury" [syn: {position}, {post}, {berth}, {spot}, {billet},
         {place}, {situation}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
