<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>oh</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oh</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-ol \-ol\ (-[=o]l or -[o^]l) suff. [From alcohol.] (Chem.)
   A suffix denoting that the substance in the name of which it
   appears belongs to the series of alcohols or hydroxyl
   derivatives, as ethanol, carbinol, phenol, glycerol, etc.
   Such compounds contain the hydroxy radical ({-OH}).
   [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oh</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Oh \Oh\ ([=o]), interj. [See {O}, interj.]
   An exclamation expressing various emotions, according to the
   tone and manner, especially surprise, pain, sorrow, anxiety,
   or a wish. See the Note under {O}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oh</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>molecular formula \mo*lec"u*lar form"u*la\, n. (Chem.)
   An expression representing the composition of elements in a
   chemical substance, commonly consisting of a series of
   letters and numbers comprising the atomic symbols of each
   element present in a compound followed by the number of atoms
   of that element present in one molecule of the substance.
   Thus the molecular formula for common alcohol (ethyl alcohol)
   is {C2H6O}, meaning that each molecule contains two carbon
   atoms, six hydrogen atoms, and one oxygen atom. The molecular
   formula may be written to provide some indication of the
   actual structure of the molecule, in which case structural
   units may be written separately. Thus, ethyl alcohol can also
   be written as {CH3.CH2.OH} or {CH3-CH2-OH}, in which the
   period or dash between functional groups indicates a single
   bond between the principle atoms of each group. This formula
   shows that in ethyl alcohol, the carbon of a methyl group
   ({CH3-}) is attached to the carbon of a methylene group
   ({-CH2-}), which is attached to the oxygen of a hydroxyl
   group ({-OH}). A {structural formula} is a graphical
   depiction of the relative positions of atoms in a molecule,
   and may be very complicated.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oh</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>OH
     Off-Hook (MODEM)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>oh</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>OH
     n : a midwestern state in north central United States in the
         Great Lakes region [syn: {Ohio}, {Buckeye State}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
