<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>onboard</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>onboard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>On \On\ ([o^]n), prep. [OE. on, an, o, a, AS. on, an; akin to D.
   aan, OS. &amp; G. an, OHG. ana, Icel. [=a], Sw. [*a], Goth. ana,
   Russ. na, L. an-, in anhelare to pant, Gr. 'ana`, Zend ana.
   [root]195. Cf. {A-}, 1, {Ana-}, {Anon}.]
   The general signification of on is situation, motion, or
   condition with respect to contact or support beneath; as: 
   [1913 Webster]

   1. At, or in contact with, the surface or upper part of a
      thing, and supported by it; placed or lying in contact
      with the surface; as, the book lies on the table, which
      stands on the floor of a house on an island.
      [1913 Webster]

            I stood on the bridge at midnight.    --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To or against the surface of; -- used to indicate the
      motion of a thing as coming or falling to the surface of
      another; as, rain falls on the earth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whosoever shall fall on this stone shall be broken.
                                                  --Matt. xxi.
                                                  44.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Denoting performance or action by contact with the
      surface, upper part, or outside of anything; hence, by
      means of; with; as, to play on a violin or piano. Hence,
      figuratively, to work on one's feelings; to make an
      impression on the mind.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. At or near; adjacent to; -- indicating situation, place,
      or position; as, on the one hand, on the other hand; the
      fleet is on the American coast.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. In addition to; besides; -- indicating multiplication or
      succession in a series; as, heaps on heaps; mischief on
      mischief; loss on loss; thought on thought. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Indicating dependence or reliance; with confidence in; as,
      to depend on a person for assistance; to rely on; hence,
      indicating the ground or support of anything; as, he will
      promise on certain conditions; to bet on a horse; based on
      certain assumptions.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   7. At or in the time of; during; as, on Sunday we abstain
      from labor. See {At} (synonym).
      [1913 Webster]

   8. At the time of; -- often conveying some notion of cause or
      motive; as, on public occasions, the officers appear in
      full dress or uniform; the shop is closed on Sundays.
      Hence, in consequence of, or following; as, on the
      ratification of the treaty, the armies were disbanded;
      start on the count of three.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   9. Toward; for; -- indicating the object of some passion; as,
      have pity or compassion on him.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. At the peril of, or for the safety of. ``Hence, on thy
       life.'' --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. By virtue of; with the pledge of; -- denoting a pledge or
       engagement, and put before the thing pledged; as, he
       affirmed or promised on his word, or on his honor.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To the account of; -- denoting imprecation or invocation,
       or coming to, falling, or resting upon; as, on us be all
       the blame; a curse on him.
       [1913 Webster]

             His blood be on us and on our children. --Matt.
                                                  xxvii. 25.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. In reference or relation to; as, on our part expect
       punctuality; a satire on society.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Of. [Obs.] ``Be not jealous on me.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             Or have we eaten on the insane root
             That takes the reason prisoner?      --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Instances of this usage are common in our older
         writers, and are sometimes now heard in illiterate
         speech.
         [1913 Webster]

   15. Occupied with; in the performance of; as, only three
       officers are on duty; on a journey; on the job; on an
       assignment; on a case; on the alert.
       [1913 Webster +PJC]

   16. In the service of; connected with; a member of; as, he is
       on a newspaper; on a committee.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: On and upon are in general interchangeable. In some
         applications upon is more euphonious, and is therefore
         to be preferred; but in most cases on is preferable.
         [1913 Webster]

   17. In reference to; about; concerning; as, to think on it;
       to meditate on it.
       [PJC]

   {On a bowline}. (Naut.) Same as {Closehauled}.

   {On a wind}, or {On the wind} (Naut.), sailing closehauled.
      

   {On a sudden}. See under {Sudden}.

   {On board}, {On draught}, {On fire}, etc. See under {Board},
      {Draught}, {Fire}, etc.

   {On it}, {On't}, of it. [Obs. or Colloq.] --Shak.

   {On shore}, on land; to the shore.

   {On the road}, {On the way}, {On the wing}, etc. See under
      {Road}, {Way}, etc.

   {On to}, upon; on; to; -- sometimes written as one word,
      onto, and usually called a colloquialism; but it may be
      regarded in analogy with into.
      [1913 Webster]

            They have added the -en plural form on to an elder
            plural.                               --Earle.
      [1913 Webster]

            We see the strength of the new movement in the new
            class of ecclesiastics whom it forced on to the
            stage.                                --J. R. Green.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>onboard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Board \Board\ (b[=o]rd), n. [OE. bord, AS. bord board,
   shipboard; akin to bred plank, Icel. bor[eth] board, side of
   a ship, Goth. f[=o]tu-baurd footstool, D. bord board, G.
   brett, bort. See def. 8. [root]92.]
   1. A piece of timber sawed thin, and of considerable length
      and breadth as compared with the thickness, -- used for
      building, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When sawed thick, as over one and a half or two inches,
         it is usually called a plank.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A table to put food upon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The term board answers to the modern table, but it was
         often movable, and placed on trestles. --Halliwell.
         [1913 Webster]

               Fruit of all kinds . . .
               She gathers, tribute large, and on the board
               Heaps with unsparing hand.         --Milton.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: What is served on a table as food; stated meals;
      provision; entertainment; -- usually as furnished for pay;
      as, to work for one's board; the price of board.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A table at which a council or court is held. Hence: A
      council, convened for business, or any authorized assembly
      or meeting, public or private; a number of persons
      appointed or elected to sit in council for the management
      or direction of some public or private business or trust;
      as, the Board of Admiralty; a board of trade; a board of
      directors, trustees, commissioners, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Both better acquainted with affairs than any other
            who sat then at that board.           --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

            We may judge from their letters to the board.
                                                  --Porteus.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A square or oblong piece of thin wood or other material
      used for some special purpose, as, a molding board; a
      board or surface painted or arranged for a game; as, a
      chessboard; a backgammon board.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Paper made thick and stiff like a board, for book covers,
      etc.; pasteboard; as, to bind a book in boards.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. The stage in a theater; as, to go upon the boards, to
      enter upon the theatrical profession.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. [In this use originally perh. a different word meaning
      border, margin; cf. D. boord, G. bord, shipboard, and G.
      borte trimming; also F. bord (fr. G.) the side of a ship.
      Cf. {Border}.] The border or side of anything. (Naut.)
      (a) The side of a ship. ``Now board to board the rival
          vessels row.'' --Dryden. See {On board}, below.
      (b) The stretch which a ship makes in one tack.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Board is much used adjectively or as the last part of a
         compound; as, fir board, clapboard, floor board,
         shipboard, sideboard, ironing board, chessboard,
         cardboard, pasteboard, seaboard; board measure.
         [1913 Webster]

   {The American Board}, a shortened form of ``The American
      Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions'' (the foreign
      missionary society of the American Congregational
      churches).

   {Bed and board}. See under {Bed}.

   {Board and board} (Naut.), side by side.

   {Board of control}, six privy councilors formerly appointed
      to superintend the affairs of the British East Indies.
      --Stormonth.

   {Board rule}, a figured scale for finding without calculation
      the number of square feet in a board. --Haldeman.

   {Board of trade}, in England, a committee of the privy
      council appointed to superintend matters relating to
      trade. In the United States, a body of men appointed for
      the advancement and protection of their business
      interests; a chamber of commerce.

   {Board wages}.
      (a) Food and lodging supplied as compensation for
          services; as, to work hard, and get only board wages.
      (b) Money wages which are barely sufficient to buy food
          and lodging.
      (c) A separate or special allowance of wages for the
          procurement of food, or food and lodging. --Dryden.

   {By the board}, over the board, or side. ``The mast went by
      the board.'' --Totten. Hence (Fig.),

   {To go by the board}, to suffer complete destruction or
      overthrow.

   {To enter on the boards}, to have one's name inscribed on a
      board or tablet in a college as a student. [Cambridge,
      England.] ``Having been entered on the boards of Trinity
      college.'' --Hallam.

   {To make a good board} (Naut.), to sail in a straight line
      when close-hauled; to lose little to leeward.

   {To make short boards}, to tack frequently.

   {On board}.
      (a) On shipboard; in a ship or a boat; on board of; as, I
          came on board early; to be on board ship.
      (b) In or into a railway car or train. [Colloq. U. S.]

   {Returning board}, a board empowered to canvass and make an
      official statement of the votes cast at an election.
      [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>onboard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>onboard
     adv : on a ship, train, plane or other vehicle [syn: {aboard}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
