<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>operation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>operation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Operation \Op`er*a"tion\, n. [L. operatio: cf. F. op['e]ration.]
   1. The act or process of operating; agency; the exertion of
      power, physical, mechanical, or moral.
      [1913 Webster]

            The pain and sickness caused by manna are the
            effects of its operation on the stomach. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Speculative painting, without the assistance of
            manual operation, can never attain to perfection.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The method of working; mode of action.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is operated or accomplished; an effect brought
      about in accordance with a definite plan; as, military or
      naval operations.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Effect produced; influence. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The bards . . . had great operation on the vulgar.
                                                  --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) Something to be done; some transformation to be
      made upon quantities or mathematical objects, the
      transformation being indicated either by rules or symbols.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Surg.) Any methodical action of the hand, or of the hand
      with instruments, on the human body, to produce a curative
      or remedial effect, as in amputation, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Calculus of operations}. See under {Calculus}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>operation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>operation
     n 1: a business especially one run on a large scale; "a
          large-scale farming operation"; "a multinational
          operation"; "they paid taxes on every stage of the
          operation"; "they had to consolidate their operations"
     2: a planned activity involving many people performing various
        actions; "they organized a rescue operation"; "the biggest
        police operation in French history"; "running a restaurant
        is quite an operation"; "consolidate the companies various
        operations"
     3: a process or series of acts especially of a practical or
        mechanical nature involved in a particular form of work;
        "the operations in building a house"; "certain machine
        tool operations" [syn: {procedure}]
     4: the state of being in effect or being operative; "that rule
        is no longer in operation"
     5: a medical procedure involving an incision with instruments;
        performed to repair damage or arrest disease in a living
        body; "they will schedule the operation as soon as an
        operating room is available"; "he died while undergoing
        surgery" [syn: {surgery}, {surgical operation}, {surgical
        procedure}, {surgical process}]
     6: activity by a military or naval force (as a maneuver or
        campaign); "it was a joint operation of the navy and air
        force" [syn: {military operation}]
     7: (computer science) data processing in which the result is
        completely specified by a rule (especially the processing
        that results from a single instruction); "it can perform
        millions of operations per second"
     8: process or manner of functioning or operating; "the power of
        its engine determine its operation"; "the plane's
        operation in high winds"; "they compared the cooking
        performance of each oven"; "the jet's performance
        conformed to high standards" [syn: {functioning}, {performance}]
     9: (mathematics) calculation by mathematical methods; "the
        problems at the end of the chapter demonstrated the
        mathematical processes involved in the derivation"; "they
        were learning the basic operations of arithmetic" [syn: {mathematical
        process}, {mathematical operation}]
     10: (psychology) the performance of some composite cognitive
         activity; an operation that affects mental contents; "the
         process of thinking"; "the cognitive operation of
         remembering" [syn: {process}, {cognitive process}, {mental
         process}, {cognitive operation}]
     11: the activity of operating something (a machine or business
         etc.); "her smooth operation of the vehicle gave us a
         surprisingly comfortable ride"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
