<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>opinion</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>opinion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Opinion \O*pin"ion\, v. t.
   To opine. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>opinion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Opinion \O*pin"ion\, n. [F., from L. opinio. See {Opine}.]
   1. That which is opined; a notion or conviction founded on
      probable evidence; belief stronger than impression, less
      strong than positive knowledge; settled judgment in regard
      to any point of knowledge or action.
      [1913 Webster]

            Opinion is when the assent of the understanding is
            so far gained by evidence of probability, that it
            rather inclines to one persuasion than to another,
            yet not without a mixture of incertainty or
            doubting.                             --Sir M. Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

            I can not put off my opinion so easily. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The judgment or sentiment which the mind forms of persons
      or things; estimation.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have bought golden opinions from all sorts of
            people.                               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Friendship . . . gives a man a peculiar right and
            claim to the good opinion of his friend. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            However, I have no opinion of those things. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Favorable estimation; hence, consideration; reputation;
      fame; public sentiment or esteem. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou hast redeemed thy lost opinion.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            This gained Agricola much opinion, who . . . had
            made such early progress into laborious . . .
            enterprises.                          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Obstinacy in holding to one's belief or impression;
      opiniativeness; conceitedness. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law.) The formal decision, or expression of views, of a
      judge, an umpire, a counselor, or other party officially
      called upon to consider and decide upon a matter or point
      submitted.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To be of opinion}, to think; to judge.

   {To hold opinion with}, to agree with. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Sentiment; notion; persuasion; idea; view; estimation.
        See {Sentiment}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>opinion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>opinion
     n 1: a personal belief or judgment that is not founded on proof
          or certainty; "my opinion differs from yours"; "what are
          your thoughts on Haiti?" [syn: {sentiment}, {persuasion},
           {view}, {thought}]
     2: a belief or sentiment shared by most people; the voice of
        the people; "he asked for a poll of public opinion" [syn:
        {public opinion}, {popular opinion}, {vox populi}]
     3: a message expressing a belief about something; the
        expression of a belief that is held with confidence but
        not substantiated by positive knowledge or proof; "his
        opinions appeared frequently on the editorial page" [syn:
        {view}]
     4: the legal document stating the reasons for a judicial
        decision; "opinions are usually written by a single judge"
        [syn: {legal opinion}, {judgment}, {judgement}]
     5: the reason for a court's judgment (as opposed to the
        decision itself) [syn: {ruling}]
     6: a vague idea in which some confidence is placed; "his
        impression of her was favorable"; "what are your feelings
        about the crisis?"; "it strengthened my belief in his
        sincerity"; "I had a feeling that she was lying" [syn: {impression},
         {feeling}, {belief}, {notion}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
