<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>order</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>order</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Series \Se"ries\, n. [L. series, fr. serere, sertum, to join or
   bind together; cf. Gr. ??? to fasten, Skr. sarit thread. Cf.
   {Assert}, {Desert} a solitude, {Exert}, {Insert},
   {Seraglio}.]
   1. A number of things or events standing or succeeding in
      order, and connected by a like relation; sequence; order;
      course; a succession of things; as, a continuous series of
      calamitous events.
      [1913 Webster]

            During some years his life a series of triumphs.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Biol.) Any comprehensive group of animals or plants
      including several subordinate related groups.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sometimes a series includes several classes; sometimes
         only orders or families; in other cases only species.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) In Engler's system of plant classification, a group
      of families showing certain structural or morphological
      relationships. It corresponds to the {cohort} of some
      writers, and to the {order} of many modern systematists.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. (Math.) An indefinite number of terms succeeding one
      another, each of which is derived from one or more of the
      preceding by a fixed law, called the law of the series;
      as, an arithmetical series; a geometrical series.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Elec.) A mode of arranging the separate parts of a
      circuit by connecting them successively end to end to form
      a single path for the current; -- opposed to {parallel}.
      The parts so arranged are said to be

   {in series}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. (Com.) A parcel of rough diamonds of assorted qualities.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>order</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Order \Or"der\, n. [OE. ordre, F. ordre, fr. L. ordo, ordinis.
   Cf. {Ordain}, {Ordinal}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Regular arrangement; any methodical or established
      succession or harmonious relation; method; system; as:
      (a) Of material things, like the books in a library.
      (b) Of intellectual notions or ideas, like the topics of a
          discource.
      (c) Of periods of time or occurrences, and the like.
          [1913 Webster]

                The side chambers were . . . thirty in order.
                                                  --Ezek. xli.
                                                  6.
          [1913 Webster]

                Bright-harnessed angels sit in order
                serviceable.                      --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                Good order is the foundation of all good things.
                                                  --Burke.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Right arrangement; a normal, correct, or fit condition;
      as, the house is in order; the machinery is out of order.
      --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The customary mode of procedure; established system, as in
      the conduct of debates or the transaction of business;
      usage; custom; fashion. --Dantiel.
      [1913 Webster]

            And, pregnant with his grander thought,
            Brought the old order into doubt.     --Emerson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Conformity with law or decorum; freedom from disturbance;
      general tranquillity; public quiet; as, to preserve order
      in a community or an assembly.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which prescribes a method of procedure; a rule or
      regulation made by competent authority; as, the rules and
      orders of the senate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The church hath authority to establish that for an
            order at one time which at another time it may
            abolish.                              --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A command; a mandate; a precept; a direction.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon this new fright, an order was made by both
            houses for disarming all the papists in England.
                                                  --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence: A commission to purchase, sell, or supply goods; a
      direction, in writing, to pay money, to furnish supplies,
      to admit to a building, a place of entertainment, or the
      like; as, orders for blankets are large.
      [1913 Webster]

            In those days were pit orders -- beshrew the
            uncomfortable manager who abolished them. --Lamb.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A number of things or persons arranged in a fixed or
      suitable place, or relative position; a rank; a row; a
      grade; especially, a rank or class in society; a group or
      division of men in the same social or other position;
      also, a distinct character, kind, or sort; as, the higher
      or lower orders of society; talent of a high order.
      [1913 Webster]

            They are in equal order to their several ends.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Various orders various ensigns bear.  --Granville.
      [1913 Webster]

            Which, to his order of mind, must have seemed little
            short of crime.                       --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A body of persons having some common honorary distinction
      or rule of obligation; esp., a body of religious persons
      or aggregate of convents living under a common rule; as,
      the Order of the Bath; the Franciscan order.
      [1913 Webster]

            Find a barefoot brother out,
            One of our order, to associate me.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The venerable order of the Knights Templars. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. An ecclesiastical grade or rank, as of deacon, priest, or
       bishop; the office of the Christian ministry; -- often
       used in the plural; as, to take orders, or to take holy
       orders, that is, to enter some grade of the ministry.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Arch.) The disposition of a column and its component
       parts, and of the entablature resting upon it, in
       classical architecture; hence (as the column and
       entablature are the characteristic features of classical
       architecture) a style or manner of architectural
       designing.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: The Greeks used three different orders, easy to
         distinguish, Doric, Ionic, and Corinthian. The Romans
         added the Tuscan, and changed the Doric so that it is
         hardly recognizable, and also used a modified
         Corinthian called Composite. The Renaissance writers on
         architecture recognized five orders as orthodox or
         classical, -- Doric (the Roman sort), Ionic, Tuscan,
         Corinthian, and Composite. See Illust. of {Capital}.
         [1913 Webster]

   12. (Nat. Hist.) An assemblage of genera having certain
       important characters in common; as, the Carnivora and
       Insectivora are orders of Mammalia.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: The Linn[ae]an artificial orders of plants rested
         mainly on identity in the numer of pistils, or
         agreement in some one character. Natural orders are
         groups of genera agreeing in the fundamental plan of
         their flowers and fruit. A natural order is usually (in
         botany) equivalent to a family, and may include several
         tribes.
         [1913 Webster]

   13. (Rhet.) The placing of words and members in a sentence in
       such a manner as to contribute to force and beauty or
       clearness of expression.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Math.) Rank; degree; thus, the order of a curve or
       surface is the same as the degree of its equation.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Artificial order} or {Artificial system}. See {Artificial
      classification}, under {Artificial}, and Note to def. 12
      above.

   {Close order} (Mil.), the arrangement of the ranks with a
      distance of about half a pace between them; with a
      distance of about three yards the ranks are in {open
      order}.

   {The four Orders}, {The Orders four}, the four orders of
      mendicant friars. See {Friar}. --Chaucer.

   {General orders} (Mil.), orders issued which concern the
      whole command, or the troops generally, in distinction
      from {special orders}.

   {Holy orders}.
       (a) (Eccl.) The different grades of the Christian
           ministry; ordination to the ministry. See def. 10
           above.
       (b) (R. C. Ch.) A sacrament for the purpose of conferring
           a special grace on those ordained.

   {In order to}, for the purpose of; to the end; as means to.

            The best knowledge is that which is of greatest use
            in order to our eternal happiness.    --Tillotson.

   {Minor orders} (R. C. Ch.), orders beneath the diaconate in
      sacramental dignity, as acolyte, exorcist, reader,
      doorkeeper.

   {Money order}. See under {Money}.

   {Natural order}. (Bot.) See def. 12, Note.

   {Order book}.
       (a) A merchant's book in which orders are entered.
       (b) (Mil.) A book kept at headquarters, in which all
           orders are recorded for the information of officers
           and men.
       (c) A book in the House of Commons in which proposed
           orders must be entered. [Eng.]

   {Order in Council}, a royal order issued with and by the
      advice of the Privy Council. [Great Britain]

   {Order of battle} (Mil.), the particular disposition given to
      the troops of an army on the field of battle.

   {Order of the day}, in legislative bodies, the special
      business appointed for a specified day.

   {Order of a differential equation} (Math.), the greatest
      index of differentiation in the equation.

   {Sailing orders} (Naut.), the final instructions given to the
      commander of a ship of war before a cruise.

   {Sealed orders}, orders sealed, and not to be opened until a
      certain time, or arrival at a certain place, as after a
      ship is at sea.

   {Standing order}.
       (a) A continuing regulation for the conduct of
           parliamentary business.
       (b) (Mil.) An order not subject to change by an officer
           temporarily in command.

   {To give order}, to give command or directions. --Shak.

   {To take order for}, to take charge of; to make arrangements
      concerning.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whiles I take order for mine own affairs. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Arrangement; management. See {Direction}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>order</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Order \Or"der\, v. i.
   To give orders; to issue commands.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>order</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Order \Or"der\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Ordered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Ordering}.] [From {Order}, n.]
   1. To put in order; to reduce to a methodical arrangement; to
      arrange in a series, or with reference to an end. Hence,
      to regulate; to dispose; to direct; to rule.
      [1913 Webster]

            To him that ordereth his conversation aright. --Ps.
                                                  1. 23.
      [1913 Webster]

            Warriors old with ordered spear and shield.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give an order to; to command; as, to order troops to
      advance.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give an order for; to secure by an order; as, to order
      a carriage; to order groceries.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Eccl.) To admit to holy orders; to ordain; to receive
      into the ranks of the ministry.
      [1913 Webster]

            These ordered folk be especially titled to God.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Persons presented to be ordered deacons. --Bk. of
                                                  Com. Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Order arms} (Mil.), the command at which a rifle is brought
      to a position with its butt resting on the ground; also,
      the position taken at such a command.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>order</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>order
     n 1: (often plural) a command given by a superior (e.g., a
          military or law enforcement officer) that must be
          obeyed; "the British ships dropped anchor and waited for
          orders from London"
     2: a degree in a continuum of size or quantity; "it was on the
        order of a mile"; "an explosion of a low order of
        magnitude" [syn: {order of magnitude}]
     3: established customary state (especially of society); "order
        ruled in the streets"; "law and order" [ant: {disorder}]
     4: logical or comprehensible arrangement of separate elements;
        "we shall consider these questions in the inverse order of
        their presentation" [syn: {ordering}, {ordination}]
     5: a condition of regular or proper arrangement; "he put his
        desk in order"; "the machine is now in working order"
        [syn: {orderliness}] [ant: {disorderliness}, {disorderliness}]
     6: a legally binding command or decision entered on the court
        record (as if issued by a court or judge); "a friend in
        New Mexico said that the order caused no trouble out
        there" [syn: {decree}, {edict}, {fiat}, {rescript}]
     7: a commercial document used to request someone to supply
        something in return for payment and providing
        specifications and quantities; "IBM received an order for
        a hundred computers" [syn: {purchase order}]
     8: a formal association of people with similar interests; "he
        joined a golf club"; "they formed a small lunch society";
        "men from the fraternal order will staff the soup kitchen
        today" [syn: {club}, {society}, {guild}, {gild}, {lodge}]
     9: a body of rules followed by an assembly [syn: {rules of
        order}, {parliamentary law}, {parliamentary procedure}]
     10: (usually plural) the status or rank or office of a Christian
         clergyman in an ecclesiastical hierarchy; "theologians
         still disagree over whether `bishop' should or should not
         be a separate order" [syn: {holy order}]
     11: a group of person living under a religious rule; "the order
         of Saint Benedict" [syn: {monastic order}]
     12: (biology) taxonomic group containing one or more families
     13: a request for food or refreshment (as served in a restaurant
         or bar etc.); "I gave the waiter my order"
     14: (architecture) one of original three styles of Greek
         architecture distinguished by the type of column and
         entablature used or a style developed from the original
         three by the Romans
     15: putting in order; "there were mistakes in the ordering of
         items on the list" [syn: {ordering}]
     v 1: give instructions to or direct somebody to do something with
          authority; "I said to him to go home"; "She ordered him
          to do the shopping"; "The mother told the child to get
          dressed" [syn: {tell}, {enjoin}, {say}]
     2: make a request for something; "Order me some flowers";
        "order a work stoppage"
     3: issue commands or orders for [syn: {prescribe}, {dictate}]
     4: bring into conformity with rules or principles or usage;
        impose regulations; "We cannot regulate the way people
        dress"; "This town likes to regulate" [syn: {regulate}, {regularize},
         {regularise}, {govern}] [ant: {deregulate}]
     5: bring order to or into; "Order these files" [ant: {disorder}]
     6: place in a certain order; "order these files"
     7: appoint to a clerical posts; "he was ordained in the Church"
        [syn: {ordain}, {consecrate}, {ordinate}]
     8: arrange thoughts, ideas, temporal events, etc.; "arrange my
        schedule"; "set up one's life"; "I put these memories with
        those of bygone times" [syn: {arrange}, {set up}, {put}]
     9: assign a rank or rating to; "how would you rank these
        students?"; "The restaurant is rated highly in the food
        guide" [syn: {rate}, {rank}, {range}, {grade}, {place}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
