<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ordinary</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ordinary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ordinary \Or"di*na*ry\, n.; pl. {Ordinaries} (-r[i^]z).
   1. (Law)
      (a) (Roman Law) An officer who has original jurisdiction
          in his own right, and not by deputation.
      (b) (Eng. Law) One who has immediate jurisdiction in
          matters ecclesiastical; an ecclesiastical judge; also,
          a deputy of the bishop, or a clergyman appointed to
          perform divine service for condemned criminals and
          assist in preparing them for death.
      (c) (Am. Law) A judicial officer, having generally the
          powers of a judge of probate or a surrogate.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. The mass; the common run. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I see no more in you than in the ordinary
            Of nature's salework.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is so common, or continued, as to be considered
      a settled establishment or institution. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Spain had no other wars save those which were grown
            into an ordinary.                     --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything which is in ordinary or common use.
      [1913 Webster]

            Water buckets, wagons, cart wheels, plow socks, and
            other ordinaries.                     --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A dining room or eating house where a meal is prepared for
      all comers, at a fixed price for the meal, in distinction
      from one where each dish is separately charged; a table
      d'h[^o]te; hence, also, the meal furnished at such a
      dining room. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the odd words they have picked up in a
            coffeehouse, or a gaming ordinary, are produced as
            flowers of style.                     --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            He exacted a tribute for licenses to hawkers and
            peddlers and to ordinaries.           --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Her.) A charge or bearing of simple form, one of nine or
      ten which are in constant use. The {bend}, {chevron},
      {chief}, {cross}, {fesse}, {pale}, and {saltire} are
      uniformly admitted as ordinaries. Some authorities include
      bar, bend sinister, pile, and others. See {Subordinary}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In ordinary}.
      (a) In actual and constant service; statedly attending and
          serving; as, a physician or chaplain in ordinary. An
          ambassador in ordinary is one constantly resident at a
          foreign court.
      (b) (Naut.) Out of commission and laid up; -- said of a
          naval vessel.

   {Ordinary of the Mass} (R. C. Ch.), the part of the Mass
      which is the same every day; -- called also the {canon of
      the Mass}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ordinary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ordinary \Or"di*na*ry\, a. [L. ordinarius, fr. ordo, ordinis,
   order: cf. F. ordinaire. See {Order}.]
   1. According to established order; methodical; settled;
      regular. ``The ordinary forms of law.'' --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Common; customary; usual. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Method is not less requisite in ordinary
            conversation that in writing.         --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Of common rank, quality, or ability; not distinguished by
      superior excellence or beauty; hence, not distinguished in
      any way; commonplace; inferior; of little merit; as, men
      of ordinary judgment; an ordinary book.
      [1913 Webster]

            An ordinary lad would have acquired little or no
            useful knowledge in such a way.       --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ordinary seaman} (Naut.), one not expert or fully skilled,
      and hence ranking below an {able seaman}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Normal; common; usual; customary.

   Usage: See {Normal}. -- {Ordinary}, {Common}. A thing is
          common in which many persons share or partake; as, a
          common practice. A thing is ordinary when it is apt to
          come round in the regular common order or succession
          of events.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ordinary</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ordinary
     adj 1: not exceptional in any way especially in quality or ability
            or size or degree; "ordinary everyday objects";
            "ordinary decency"; "an ordinary day"; "an ordinary
            wine" [ant: {extraordinary}]
     2: lacking special distinction, rank, or status; commonly
        encountered; "average people"; "the ordinary (or common)
        man in the street" [syn: {average}]
     n 1: a judge of a probate court
     2: the expected or commonplace condition or situation; "not out
        of the ordinary"
     3: a clergyman appointed to prepare condemned prisoners for
        death
     4: an early bicycle with a very large front wheel and small
        back wheel [syn: {ordinary bicycle}]
     5: (heraldry) any of several conventional figures used on
        shields
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
