<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>organ</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>organ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Organ
   some kind of wind instrument, probably a kind of Pan's pipes
   (Gen. 4:21; Job 21:12; Ps. 150:4), which consisted of seven or
   eight reeds of unequal length.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>organ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Organ \Or"gan\, n. [L. organum, Gr. ?; akin to ? work, and E.
   work: cf. F. organe. See {Work}, and cf. {Orgue}, {Orgy}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. An instrument or medium by which some important action is
      performed, or an important end accomplished; as,
      legislatures, courts, armies, taxgatherers, etc., are
      organs of government.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Biol.) A natural part or structure in an animal or a
      plant, capable of performing some special action (termed
      its function), which is essential to the life or
      well-being of the whole; as, the heart, lungs, etc., are
      organs of animals; the root, stem, foliage, etc., are
      organs of plants.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In animals the organs are generally made up of several
         tissues, one of which usually predominates, and
         determines the principal function of the organ. Groups
         of organs constitute a system. See {System}.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. A component part performing an essential office in the
      working of any complex machine; as, the cylinder, valves,
      crank, etc., are organs of the steam engine.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A medium of communication between one person or body and
      another; as, the secretary of state is the organ of
      communication between the government and a foreign power;
      a newspaper is the organ of its editor, or of a party,
      sect, etc. A newsletter distributed within an organization
      is often called its {house organ}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   5. [Cf. AS. organ, fr. L. organum.] (Mus.) A wind instrument
      containing numerous pipes of various dimensions and kinds,
      which are filled with wind from a bellows, and played upon
      by means of keys similar to those of a piano, and
      sometimes by foot keys or pedals; -- formerly used in the
      plural, each pipe being considered an organ.
      [1913 Webster]

            The deep, majestic, solemn organs blow. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Chaucer used the form orgon as a plural.
         [1913 Webster]

               The merry orgon . . . that in the church goon
               [go].
         [1913 Webster]

   {Barrel organ}, {Choir organ}, {Great organ}, etc. See under
      {Barrel}, {Choir}, etc.

   {Cabinet organ} (Mus.), an organ of small size, as for a
      chapel or for domestic use; a reed organ.

   {Organ bird} (Zo["o]l.), a Tasmanian crow shrike ({Gymnorhina
      organicum}). It utters discordant notes like those of a
      hand organ out of tune.

   {Organ fish} (Zo["o]l.), the drumfish.

   {Organ gun}. (Mil.) Same as {Orgue}
      (b) .

   {Organ harmonium} (Mus.), an harmonium of large capacity and
      power.

   {Organ of Corti} (Anat.), a complicated structure in the
      cochlea of the ear, including the auditory hair cells, the
      rods or fibers of Corti, the membrane of Corti, etc. See
      Note under {Ear}.

   {Organ pipe}. See {Pipe}, n., 1.

   {Organ-pipe coral}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Tubipora}.

   {Organ point} (Mus.), a passage in which the tonic or
      dominant is sustained continuously by one part, while the
      other parts move.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>organ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Organ \Or"gan\, v. t.
   To supply with an organ or organs; to fit with organs; to
   organize. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Thou art elemented and organed for other apprehensions.
                                                  --Bp.
                                                  Mannyngham.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>organ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>organ
     n 1: a fully differentiated structural and functional unit in an
          animal that is specialized for some particular function
     2: a government agency or instrument devoted to the performance
        of some specific function; "The Census Bureau is an organ
        of the Commerce Department"
     3: (music) an electronic simulation of a pipe organ [syn: {electric
        organ}, {electronic organ}, {Hammond organ}]
     4: a periodical that is published by a special interest group;
        "the organ of the communist party"
     5: wind instrument whose sound is produced by means of pipes
        arranged in sets supplied with air from a bellows and
        controlled from a large complex musical keyboard [syn: {pipe
        organ}]
     6: a free-reed instrument in which air is forced through the
        reeds by bellows [syn: {harmonium}, {reed organ}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
