<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>organic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>organic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Organic \Or*gan"ic\, a. [L. organicus, Gr. ?: cf. F. organique.]
   1. (Biol.) Of or pertaining to an organ or its functions, or
      to objects composed of organs; consisting of organs, or
      containing them; as, the organic structure of animals and
      plants; exhibiting characters peculiar to living
      organisms; as, organic bodies, organic life, organic
      remains. Cf. {Inorganic}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Produced by the organs; as, organic pleasure. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Instrumental; acting as instruments of nature or of art to
      a certain destined function or end. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Those organic arts which enable men to discourse and
            write perspicuously.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Forming a whole composed of organs. Hence: Of or
      pertaining to a system of organs; inherent in, or
      resulting from, a certain organization; as, an organic
      government; his love of truth was not inculcated, but
      organic.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Chem.) Of or pertaining to compounds which are
      derivatives of hydrocarbons; pertaining to, or denoting,
      any one of a large series of carbon-containing compounds
      which are related to the carbon compounds produced by
      biological processes (such as methane, oils, fats, sugars,
      alcohols, ethers, proteins, etc.) and include many
      substances of artificial production which may or may not
      occur in animals or plants; -- contrasted with
      {inorganic}.

   Note: Borderline cases exist which may be classified as
         either organic or inorganic, such as carbon
         terachloride (which may be viewed as a derivative of
         methane), but in general a compound must have a carbon
         with a hydrogen atom or another carbon atom attached to
         it to be viewed as truly organic, i.e. included in the
         subject matter of organic chemistry.
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: The principles of organic and inorganic chemistry are
         identical; but the enormous number and the completeness
         of related series of organic compounds, together with
         their remarkable facility of exchange and substitution,
         offer an illustration of chemical reaction and homology
         not to be paralleled in inorganic chemistry.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Organic analysis} (Chem.), the analysis of organic
      compounds, concerned chiefly with the determination of
      carbon as carbon dioxide, hydrogen as water, oxygen as the
      difference between the sum of the others and 100 per cent,
      and nitrogen as free nitrogen, ammonia, or nitric oxide;
      -- formerly called ultimate analysis, in distinction from
      proximate analysis.

   {Organic chemistry}. See under {Chemistry}.

   {Organic compounds}. (Chem.) Chemical substances which are
      organic[5]. See {Carbon compounds}, under {Carbon}.

   {Organic description of a curve} (Geom.), the description of
      a curve on a plane by means of instruments. --Brande &amp; C.

   {Organic disease} (Med.), a disease attended with morbid
      changes in the structure of the organs of the body or in
      the composition of its fluids; -- opposed to {functional
      disease}.

   {Organic electricity}. See under {Electricity}.

   {Organic law} or {Organic laws}, a law or system of laws, or
      declaration of principles fundamental to the existence and
      organization of a political or other association; a
      constitution.

   {Organic stricture} (Med.), a contraction of one of the
      natural passages of the body produced by structural
      changes in its walls, as distinguished from a {spasmodic
      stricture}, which is due to muscular contraction.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>organic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>integrated \integrated\ adj.
   1. Formed or united into a whole.

   Syn: incorporate, incorporated, merged, unified.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. Formed into a whole or introduced into another entity; as,
      an integrated Europe. Opposite of {nonintegrated}.
      [Narrower terms: {coordinated}, {interconnected},
      {unified}; {embedded}; {incorporated}; {tight-knit},
      {tightly knit}]

            a more closely integrated economic and political
            system                                --Dwight D.
                                                  Eisenhower
      [WordNet 1.5]

   3. Having different groups treated together as equals in one
      group; as, racially integrated schools. [Narrower terms:
      {co-ed, coeducational}; {desegrated, nonsegregated,
      unsegregated}; {interracial}; {mainstreamed}] Also See:
      {integrative}, {joint}, {united}. Antonym: {segregated}.
      [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]

   4. Resembling a living organism in organization or
      development. [Narrower terms: {organic} (vs. inorganic)]

   Syn: structured.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   5. combined. Opposite of {uncombined}.
      [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]

   6. having constituent parts mixed to form a single unit.
      Opposite of {unmixed}. [Narrower terms: {blended[2]}]

   Syn: amalgamated, intermingled, mixed.
        [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>organic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>organic
     adj 1: relating or belonging to the class of chemical compounds
            having a carbon basis; "hydrocarbons are organic
            compounds" [ant: {inorganic}]
     2: of or relating to or derived from living organisms; "organic
        soil"
     3: being or relating to or derived from or having properties
        characteristic of living organisms; "organic life";
        "organic growth"; "organic remains found in rock" [ant: {inorganic}]
     4: involving or affecting physiology or bodily organs; "an
        organic disease" [ant: {functional}]
     5: of or relating to foodstuff grown or raised without
        synthetic fertilizers or pesticides or hormones; "organic
        eggs"; "organic vegetables"; "organic chicken"
     6: simple and healthful and close to nature; "an organic
        lifestyle"
     7: constitutional in the structure of something (especially
        your physical makeup) [syn: {constituent(a)}, {constitutional},
         {constitutive(a)}]
     n : a fertilizer that is derived from animal or vegetable matter
         [syn: {organic fertilizer}, {organic fertiliser}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
