<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>original</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>original</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Original \O*rig"i*nal\, n. [Cf. F. original.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Origin; commencement; source.
      [1913 Webster]

            It hath it original from much grief.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And spangled heavens, a shining frame,
            Their great Original proclaim.        --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which precedes all others of its class; archetype;
      first copy; hence, an original work of art, manuscript,
      text, and the like, as distinguished from a copy,
      translation, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Scriptures may be now read in their own
            original.                             --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An original thinker or writer; an originator. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Men who are bad at copying, yet are good originals.
                                                  --C. G.
                                                  Leland.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A person of marked eccentricity. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l. &amp; Bot.) The natural or wild species from which a
      domesticated or cultivated variety has been derived; as,
      the wolf is thought by some to be the original of the dog,
      the blackthorn the original of the plum.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>original</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Original \O*rig"i*nal\, a. [F. original, L. originalis.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Pertaining to the origin or beginning; preceding all
      others; first in order; primitive; primary; pristine; as,
      the original state of man; the original laws of a country;
      the original inventor of a process.
      [1913 Webster]

            His form had yet not lost
            All her original brightness.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not copied, imitated, or translated; new; fresh; genuine;
      as, an original thought; an original process; the original
      text of Scripture.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Having the power to suggest new thoughts or combinations
      of thought; inventive; as, an original genius.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Before unused or unknown; new; as, a book full of original
      matter.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Original sin} (Theol.), the first sin of Adam, as related to
      its consequences to his descendants of the human race; --
      called also {total depravity}. See {Calvinism}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>original</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>original
     adj 1: preceding all others in time or being as first made or
            performed; "the original inhabitants of the Americas";
            "the book still has its original binding"; "restored
            the house to its original condition"; "the original
            performance of the opera"; "the original cast";
            "retracted his original statement"
     2: (of e.g. information) not secondhand or by way of something
        intermediary; "his work is based on only original, not
        secondary, sources"
     3: being or productive of something fresh and unusual; or being
        as first made or thought of; "a truly original approach";
        "with original music"; "an original mind" [ant: {unoriginal}]
     4: not derived or copied or translated from something else;
        "the play is original; not an adaptation"; "he kept the
        original copy and gave her only a xerox"; "the translation
        misses much of the subtlety of the original French"
     n 1: an original creation (i.e., an audio recording) from which
          copies can be made [syn: {master}, {master copy}]
     2: an original model on which something is patterned [syn: {archetype},
         {pilot}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
