<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>out</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>OUT-:OF:-:DOORS:, n.  That part of one's environment upon which no
government has been able to collect taxes.  Chiefly useful to inspire
poets.

    I climbed to the top of a mountain one day
        To see the sun setting in glory,
    And I thought, as I looked at his vanishing ray,
        Of a perfectly splendid story.

    'Twas about an old man and the ass he bestrode
        Till the strength of the beast was o'ertested;
    Then the man would carry him miles on the road
        Till Neddy was pretty well rested.

    The moon rising solemnly over the crest
        Of the hills to the east of my station
    Displayed her broad disk to the darkening west
        Like a visible new creation.

    And I thought of a joke (and I laughed till I cried)
        Of an idle young woman who tarried
    About a church-door for a look at the bride,
        Although 'twas herself that was married.

    To poets all Nature is pregnant with grand
        Ideas -- with thought and emotion.
    I pity the dunces who don't understand
        The speech of earth, heaven and ocean.
                                                       Stromboli Smith


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sell \Sell\ (s[e^]l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Sold} (s[=o]ld); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Selling}.] [OE. sellen, sillen, AS. sellan,
   syllan, to give, to deliver; akin to OS. sellian, OFries.
   sella, OHG. sellen, Icel. selja to hand over, to sell, Sw.
   s["a]lja to sell, Dan. s[ae]lge, Goth. saljan to offer a
   sacrifice; all from a noun akin to E. sale. Cf. {Sale}.]
   1. To transfer to another for an equivalent; to give up for a
      valuable consideration; to dispose of in return for
      something, especially for money. It is the correlative of
      buy.
      [1913 Webster]

            If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that thou hast,
            and give to the poor.                 --Matt. xix.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am changed; I'll go sell all my land. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sell is corellative to buy, as one party buys what the
         other sells. It is distinguished usually from exchange
         or barter, in which one commodity is given for another;
         whereas in selling the consideration is usually money,
         or its representative in current notes.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To make a matter of bargain and sale of; to accept a price
      or reward for, as for a breach of duty, trust, or the
      like; to betray.
      [1913 Webster]

            You would have sold your king to slaughter. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To impose upon; to trick; to deceive; to make a fool of;
      to cheat. [Slang] --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To sell one's life dearly}, to cause much loss to those who
      take one's life, as by killing a number of one's
      assailants.

   {To sell} (anything) {out}, to dispose of it wholly or
      entirely; as, he had sold out his corn, or his interest in
      a business.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Out \Out\ (out), adv. [OE. out, ut, oute, ute, AS. [=u]t, and
   [=u]te, [=u]tan, fr. [=u]t; akin to D. uit, OS. [=u]t, G.
   aus, OHG. [=u]z, Icel. [=u]t, Sw. ut, Dan. ud, Goth. ut, Skr.
   ud. [root]198. Cf. {About}, {But}, prep., {Carouse}, {Utter},
   a.]
   In its original and strict sense, out means from the interior
   of something; beyond the limits or boundary of somethings; in
   a position or relation which is exterior to something; --
   opposed to {in} or {into}. The something may be expressed
   after of, from, etc. (see {Out of}, below); or, if not
   expressed, it is implied; as, he is out; or, he is out of the
   house, office, business, etc.; he came out; or, he came out
   from the ship, meeting, sect, party, etc. Out is used in a
   variety of applications, as: 
   [1913 Webster]

   1. Away; abroad; off; from home, or from a certain, or a
      usual, place; not in; not in a particular, or a usual,
      place; as, the proprietor is out, his team was taken out.
      Opposite of {in}. ``My shoulder blade is out.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hath been out (of the country) nine years.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Beyond the limits of concealment, confinement, privacy,
      constraint, etc., actual or figurative; hence, not in
      concealment, constraint, etc., in, or into, a state of
      freedom, openness, disclosure, publicity, etc.; a matter
      of public knowledge; as, the sun shines out; he laughed
      out, to be out at the elbows; the secret has leaked out,
      or is out; the disease broke out on his face; the book is
      out.
      [1913 Webster]

            Leaves are out and perfect in a month. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            She has not been out [in general society] very long.
                                                  --H. James.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Beyond the limit of existence, continuance, or supply; to
      the end; completely; hence, in, or into, a condition of
      extinction, exhaustion, completion; as, the fuel, or the
      fire, has burned out; that style is on the way out. ``Hear
      me out.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Deceitful men shall not live out half their days.
                                                  --Ps. iv. 23.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the butt is out, we will drink water. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Beyond possession, control, or occupation; hence, in, or
      into, a state of want, loss, or deprivation; -- used of
      office, business, property, knowledge, etc.; as, the
      Democrats went out and the Whigs came in; he put his money
      out at interest. ``Land that is out at rack rent.''
      --Locke. ``He was out fifty pounds.'' --Bp. Fell.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have forgot my part, and I am out.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Beyond the bounds of what is true, reasonable, correct,
      proper, common, etc.; in error or mistake; in a wrong or
      incorrect position or opinion; in a state of disagreement,
      opposition, etc.; in an inharmonious relation. ``Lancelot
      and I are out.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wicked men are strangely out in the calculating of
            their own interest.                   --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            Very seldom out, in these his guesses. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Not in the position to score in playing a game; not in the
      state or turn of the play for counting or gaining scores.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Out of fashion; unfashionable; no longer in current vogue;
      unpopular.
      [PJC]

   Note: Out is largely used in composition as a prefix, with
         the same significations that it has as a separate word;
         as outbound, outbreak, outbuilding, outcome, outdo,
         outdoor, outfield. See also the first Note under
         {Over}, adv.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Day in, day out}, from the beginning to the limit of each of
      several days; day by day; every day.

   {Out at}, {Out in}, {Out on}, etc., elliptical phrases, that
      to which out refers as a source, origin, etc., being
      omitted; as, out (of the house and) at the barn; out (of
      the house, road, fields, etc., and) in the woods.

            Three fishers went sailing out into the west,
            Out into the west, as the sun went down. --C.
                                                  Kingsley.

   Note: In these lines after out may be understood, ``of the
         harbor,'' ``from the shore,'' ``of sight,'' or some
         similar phrase. The complete construction is seen in
         the saying: ``Out of the frying pan into the fire.''

   {Out from}, a construction similar to {out of} (below). See
      {Of} and {From}.

   {Out of}, a phrase which may be considered either as composed
      of an adverb and a preposition, each having its
      appropriate office in the sentence, or as a compound
      preposition. Considered as a preposition, it denotes, with
      verbs of movement or action, from the interior of; beyond
      the limit: from; hence, origin, source, motive, departure,
      separation, loss, etc.; -- opposed to {in} or {into}; also
      with verbs of being, the state of being derived, removed,
      or separated from. Examples may be found in the phrases
      below, and also under Vocabulary words; as, out of breath;
      out of countenance.

   {Out of cess}, beyond measure, excessively. --Shak.

   {Out of character}, unbecoming; improper.

   {Out of conceit with}, not pleased with. See under {Conceit}.
      

   {Out of date}, not timely; unfashionable; antiquated.

   {Out of door}, {Out of doors}, beyond the doors; from the
      house; not inside a building; in, or into, the open air;
      hence, figuratively, shut out; dismissed. See under
      {Door}, also, {Out-of-door}, {Outdoor}, {Outdoors}, in the
      Vocabulary. ``He 's quality, and the question's out of
      door,'' --Dryden.

   {Out of favor}, disliked; under displeasure.

   {Out of frame}, not in correct order or condition; irregular;
      disarranged. --Latimer.

   {Out of hand}, immediately; without delay or preparation;
      without hesitation or debate; as, to dismiss a suggestion
      out of hand. ``Ananias . . . fell down and died out of
      hand.'' --Latimer.

   {Out of harm's way}, beyond the danger limit; in a safe
      place.

   {Out of joint}, not in proper connection or adjustment;
      unhinged; disordered. ``The time is out of joint.''
      --Shak.

   {Out of mind}, not in mind; forgotten; also, beyond the limit
      of memory; as, time out of mind.

   {Out of one's head}, beyond commanding one's mental powers;
      in a wandering state mentally; delirious. [Colloq.]

   {Out of one's time}, beyond one's period of minority or
      apprenticeship.

   {Out of order}, not in proper order; disarranged; in
      confusion.

   {Out of place}, not in the usual or proper place; hence, not
      proper or becoming.

   {Out of pocket}, in a condition of having expended or lost
      more money than one has received.

   {Out of print}, not in market, the edition printed being
      exhausted; -- said of books, pamphlets, etc.

   {Out of the question}, beyond the limits or range of
      consideration; impossible to be favorably considered.

   {Out of reach}, beyond one's reach; inaccessible.

   {Out of season}, not in a proper season or time; untimely;
      inopportune.

   {Out of sorts}, wanting certain things; unsatisfied; unwell;
      unhappy; cross. See under {Sort}, n.

   {Out of temper}, not in good temper; irritated; angry.

   {Out of time}, not in proper time; too soon, or too late.

   {Out of time}, not in harmony; discordant; hence, not in an
      agreeing temper; fretful.

   {Out of twist}, {Out of winding}, or {Out of wind}, not in
      warped condition; perfectly plain and smooth; -- said of
      surfaces.

   {Out of use}, not in use; unfashionable; obsolete.

   {Out of the way}.
      (a) On one side; hard to reach or find; secluded.
      (b) Improper; unusual; wrong.

   {Out of the woods}, not in a place, or state, of obscurity or
      doubt; free from difficulty or perils; safe. [Colloq.]

   {Out to out}, from one extreme limit to another, including
      the whole length, breadth, or thickness; -- applied to
      measurements.

   {Out West}, in or towards, the West; specifically, in some
      Western State or Territory. [U. S.]

   {To come out}, {To cut out}, {To fall out}, etc. See under
      {Come}, {Cut}, {Fall}, etc.

   {To make out} See {to make out} under {make}, v. t. and v.
      i..

   {To put out of the way}, to kill; to destroy.

   {Week in, week out}. See {Day in, day out} (above).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Out \Out\ (out), n.
   1. One who, or that which, is out; especially, one who is out
      of office; -- generally in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A place or space outside of something; a nook or corner;
      an angle projecting outward; an open space; -- chiefly
      used in the phrase ins and outs; as, the ins and outs of a
      question. See under {In}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Print.) A word or words omitted by the compositor in
      setting up copy; an omission.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To make an out} (Print.),
      (a) to omit something, in setting or correcting type,
          which was in the copy.
      (b) (Baseball) to be put out in one's turn at bat, such as
          to {strike out}, to {ground out}, or to {fly out}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Out \Out\, v. t.
   1. To cause to be out; to eject; to expel.
      [1913 Webster]

            A king outed from his country.        --Selden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The French have been outed of their holds. --Heylin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To come out with; to make known. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give out; to dispose of; to sell. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Out \Out\, v. i.
   To come or go out; to get out or away; to become public.
   ``Truth will out.'' --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Out \Out\, interj.
   Expressing impatience, anger, a desire to be rid of; -- with
   the force of command; go out; begone; away; off.
   [1913 Webster]

         Out, idle words, servants to shallow fools! --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Out upon!} or {Out on!} equivalent to ``shame upon!'' ``away
      with!'' as, out upon you!
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Outer \Out"er\ (out"[~e]r), a. [Compar. of {Out}.] [AS. [=u]tor,
   compar. of [=u]t, adv., out. See {Out}, {Utter}, a.]
   Being on the outside; external; farthest or farther from the
   interior, from a given station, or from any space or position
   regarded as a center or starting place; -- opposed to
   {inner}; as, the outer wall; the outer court or gate; the
   outer stump in cricket; the outer world.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Outer bar}, in England, the body of junior (or utter)
      barristers; -- so called because in court they occupy a
      place beyond the space reserved for Queen's counsel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bowl \Bowl\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bowled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bowling}.]
   1. To roll, as a bowl or cricket ball.
      [1913 Webster]

            Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel,
            And bowl the round nave down the hill of heaven.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To roll or carry smoothly on, or as on, wheels; as, we
      were bowled rapidly along the road.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pelt or strike with anything rolled.
      [1913 Webster]

            Alas, I had rather be set quick i' the earth,
            And bowled to death with turnips?     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To bowl} (a player) {out}, in cricket, to put out a striker
      by knocking down a bail or a stump in bowling.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>out</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>out
     adj 1: not allowed to continue to bat or run; "he was tagged out at
            second on a close play"; "he fanned out" [syn: {out(p)},
             {retired}] [ant: {safe(p)}]
     2: of a fire; being out or having grown cold; "threw his
        extinct cigarette into the stream";  "the fire is out"
        [syn: {extinct}, {out(p)}]
     3: not worth considering as a possibility; "a picnic is out
        because of the weather" [syn: {out(p)}]
     4: out of power; especially having been unsuccessful in an
        election; "now the Democrats are out" [syn: {out(a)}]
     5: excluded from use or mention; "forbidden fruit"; "in our
        house dancing and playing cards were out"; "a taboo
        subject" [syn: {forbidden}, {out(p)}, {prohibited}, {proscribed},
         {taboo}, {tabu}, {verboten}]
     6: directed outward or serving to direct something outward;
        "the out doorway"; "the out basket" [syn: {out(a)}]
     7: no longer fashionable; "that style is out these days"
     8: outside or external; "the out surface of a ship's hull"
        [syn: {out(a)}]
     9: outer or outlying; "the out islands"
     10: knocked unconscious by a heavy blow [syn: {knocked out(p)},
         {kayoed}, {KO'd}, {out(p)}, {stunned}]
     n : (baseball) a failure by a batter or runner to reach a base
         safely in baseball; "you only get 3 outs per inning"
     adv 1: outside of an enclosed space; "she is out" [ant: {in}]
     2: outward from a reference point; "he kicked his legs out"
     3: away from home; "they went out last night"
     4: from one's possession; "he gave out money to the poor";
        "gave away the tickets" [syn: {away}]
     v 1: to state openly and publicly one's homosexuality; "This
          actor outed last year" [syn: {come out of the closet}, {come
          out}]
     2: reveal somebody else's homosexuality; "This actor was outed
        last week"
     3: be made known; be disclosed or revealed; "The truth will
        out" [syn: {come out}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
