<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>overall</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>overall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Over \O"ver\ ([=o]"v[~e]r), prep. [AS. ofer; akin to D. over, G.
   ["u]ber, OHG. ubir, ubar, Dan. over, Sw. ["o]fver, Icel.
   yfir, Goth. ufar, L. super, Gr. "ype`r, Skr. upari.
   [root]199. Cf. {Above}, {Eaves}, {Hyper-}, {Orlop}, {Super-},
   {Sovereign}, {Up}.]
   1. Above, or higher than, in place or position, with the idea
      of covering; -- opposed to {under}; as, clouds are over
      our heads; the smoke rises over the city.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mercy seat that is over the testimony. --Ex.
                                                  xxx. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Over them gleamed far off the crimson banners of
            morning.                              --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Across; from side to side of; -- implying a passing or
      moving, either above the substance or thing, or on the
      surface of it; as, a dog leaps over a stream or a table.
      [1913 Webster]

            Certain lakes . . . poison birds which fly over
            them.                                 --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Upon the surface of, or the whole surface of; hither and
      thither upon; throughout the whole extent of; as, to
      wander over the earth; to walk over a field, or over a
      city.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Above; -- implying superiority in excellence, dignity,
      condition, or value; as, the advantages which the
      Christian world has over the heathen. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Above in authority or station; -- implying government,
      direction, care, attention, guard, responsibility, etc.;
      -- opposed to {under}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt be over my house.          --Gen. xli.
                                                  40.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will make thee rules over many things. --Matt.
                                                  xxv. 23.
      [1913 Webster]

            Dost thou not watch over my sin ?     --Job xiv. 16.
      [1913 Webster]

            His tender mercies are over all his works. --Ps.
                                                  cxlv. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Across or during the time of; from beginning to end of;
      as, to keep anything over night; to keep corn over winter.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Above the perpendicular height or length of, with an idea
      of measurement; as, the water, or the depth of water, was
      over his head, over his shoes.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Beyond; in excess of; in addition to; more than; as, it
      cost over five dollars. ``Over all this.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Above, implying superiority after a contest; in spite of;
      notwithstanding; as, he triumphed over difficulties; the
      bill was passed over the veto.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Over, in poetry, is often contracted into o'er.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: Over his signature (or name) is a substitute for the
         idiomatic English form, under his signature (name, hand
         and seal, etc.), the reference in the latter form being
         to the authority under which the writing is made,
         executed, or published, and not the place of the
         autograph, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Over all} (Her.), placed over or upon other bearings, and
      therefore hinding them in part; -- said of a charge.

   {Over one's head}, {Over head and ears}, beyond one's depth;
      completely; wholly; hopelessly; as, over head and ears in
      debt.

   {head over heels}
      (a) completely; intensely; as, head over heels in love.
          [Colloq.]
      (b) in a tumbling manner; as, to fall head over heels down
          the stairs.
      (c) precipitously and without forethought; impulsively.

   {Over the left}. See under {Left}.

   {To run over} (Mach.), to have rotation in such direction
      that the crank pin traverses the upper, or front, half of
      its path in the forward, or outward, stroke; -- said of a
      crank which drives, or is driven by, a reciprocating
      piece.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>overall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>All \All\, n.
   The whole number, quantity, or amount; the entire thing;
   everything included or concerned; the aggregate; the whole;
   totality; everything or every person; as, our all is at
   stake.
   [1913 Webster]

         Death, as the Psalmist saith, is certain to all.
                                                  --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         All that thou seest is mine.             --Gen. xxxi.
                                                  43.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: All is used with of, like a partitive; as, all of a
         thing, all of us.
         [1913 Webster]

   {After all}, after considering everything to the contrary;
      nevertheless.

   {All in all}, a phrase which signifies all things to a
      person, or everything desired; (also adverbially) wholly;
      altogether.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt be all in all, and I in thee,
            Forever.                              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Trust me not at all, or all in all.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {All in the wind} (Naut.), a phrase denoting that the sails
      are parallel with the course of the wind, so as to shake.
      

   {All told}, all counted; in all.

   {And all}, and the rest; and everything connected. ``Bring
      our crown and all.'' --Shak.

   {At all}.
   (a) In every respect; wholly; thoroughly. [Obs.] ``She is a
       shrew at al(l).'' --Chaucer.
   (b) A phrase much used by way of enforcement or emphasis,
       usually in negative or interrogative sentences, and
       signifying in any way or respect; in the least degree or
       to the least extent; in the least; under any
       circumstances; as, he has no ambition at all; has he any
       property at all? ``Nothing at all.'' --Shak. ``If thy
       father at all miss me.'' --1 Sam. xx. 6.

   {Over all}, everywhere. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: All is much used in composition to enlarge the meaning,
         or add force to a word. In some instances, it is
         completely incorporated into words, and its final
         consonant is dropped, as in almighty, already, always:
         but, in most instances, it is an adverb prefixed to
         adjectives or participles, but usually with a hyphen,
         as, all-bountiful, all-glorious, allimportant,
         all-surrounding, etc. In others it is an adjective; as,
         allpower, all-giver. Anciently many words, as, alabout,
         alaground, etc., were compounded with all, which are
         now written separately.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>overall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Overall \O"ver*all\, adv.
   Everywhere. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>overall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>overall
     adj 1: involving only main features; "the overall pattern of his
            life"
     2: including everything; "the overall cost"; "the total amount
        owed" [syn: {total}]
     n 1: work clothing consisting of denim trousers (usually with a
          bib and shoulder straps)
     2: a loose protective coverall or smock worn over ordinary
        clothing for dirty work [syn: {boilersuit}, {boilers suit}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
