<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>overlooked</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>overlooked</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Overlook \O`ver*look"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Overlooked}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Overlooking}.]
   1. To look down upon from a place that is over or above; to
      look over or view from a higher position; to be situated
      above, so as to command a view of; as, to overlook a
      valley from a hill; a hotel room that overlooks the
      marketplace. ``The pile o'erlooked the town.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            [Titan] with burning eye did hotly overlook them.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: To supervise; to watch over; sometimes, to observe
      secretly; as, to overlook a gang of laborers; to overlook
      one who is writing a letter.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To inspect; to examine; to look over carefully or
      repeatedly. ``Overlook this pedigree.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The time and care that are required
            To overlook and file and polish well. --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To look upon with an evil eye; to bewitch by looking upon;
      to fascinate. [Obs. or Prov. Eng.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If you trouble me I will overlook you, and then your
            pigs will die.                        --C. Kingsley.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To look over and beyond (anything) without seeing it; to
      miss or omit in looking; to fail to notice; to fail to
      observe; as, to overlook a mistake in addition; to
      overlook a missing bolt.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   6. Hence: To refrain from bestowing notice or attention upon;
      to disregard or deliberately ignore; to pass over without
      censure or punishment; to excuse or pardon (a fault,
      error, or misdeed).
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            The times of ignorance therefore God overlooked.
                                                  --Acts xvii.
                                                  30 (Rev. Ver.
                                                  )
      [1913 Webster]

            They overlook truth in the judgments they pass.
                                                  --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

            The pardoning and overlooking of faults. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>overlooked</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>overlooked
     adj : not taken into account; "his retirement was not allowed to
           go unmarked" [syn: {unmarked}, {unnoted}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
