<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>owe</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>owe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>OWE, v.  To have (and to hold) a debt.  The word formerly signified
not indebtedness, but possession; it meant "own," and in the minds of
debtors there is still a good deal of confusion between assets and
liabilities.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>owe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Owe \Owe\ ([=o]), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Owed} ([=o]d), ({Ought}
   ([add]t) obs.); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Owing} ([=o]"[i^]ng).] [OE.
   owen, awen, aghen, to have, own, have (to do), hence, owe,
   AS. [=a]gan to have; akin to G. eigen, a., own, Icel. eiga to
   have, Dan. eie, Sw. ["a]ga, Goth. ['a]igan, Skr. [imac][,c].
   [root]110. Cf. {Ought}, v., 2d {Own}, {Fraught}.]
   1. To possess; to have, as the rightful owner; to own. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou dost here usurp
            The name thou ow'st not.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To have or possess, as something derived or bestowed; to
      be obliged to ascribe (something to some source); to be
      indebted or obliged for; as, he owed his wealth to his
      father; he owed his victory to his lieutenants. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            O deem thy fall not owed to man's decree. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: To have or be under an obigation to restore, pay,
      or render (something) in return or compensation for
      something received; to be indebted in the sum of; as, the
      subject owes allegiance; the fortunate owe assistance to
      the unfortunate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The one ought five hundred pence, and the other
            fifty.                                --Bible
                                                  (1551).
      [1913 Webster]

            A son owes help and honor to his father. --Holyday.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Owe was sometimes followed by an objective clause
         introduced by the infinitive. ``Ye owen to incline and
         bow your heart.'' --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. To have an obligation to (some one) on account of
      something done or received; to be indebted to; as, to owe
      the grocer for supplies, or a laborer for services.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>owe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>owe
     v 1: be obliged to pay or repay
     2: be indebted to, in an abstract or intellectual sense; "This
        new theory owes much to Einstein's Relativity Theory"
     3: be in debt; "She owes me $200"; "The thesis owes much to his
        adviser"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
