<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bachelor</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bachelor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Holluschickie \Hol"lus*chick`ie\, n. sing. &amp; pl. [Prob. of Russ.
   goluishka bare of possessions, offspring, etc., fr. golui[i^]
   naked.] (Zo["o]l.)
   A young male fur seal, esp. one from three to six years old;
   -- called also {bachelor}, because prevented from breeding by
   the older full-grown males.

   Note: The holluschickie are the seals that may legally be
         killed for their skins.

               But he'll lie down on the killing grounds where
               the holluschickie go.              --Kipling.
         [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bachelor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bachelor \Bach"e*lor\ (b[a^]ch"[-e]*l[~e]r), n. [OF. bacheler
   young man, F. bachelier (cf. Pr. bacalar, Sp. bachiller, Pg.
   bacharel, It. baccalare), LL. baccalarius the tenant of a
   kind of farm called baccalaria, a soldier not old or rich
   enough to lead his retainers into battle with a banner, a
   person of an inferior academical degree aspiring to a
   doctorate. In the latter sense, it was afterward changed to
   baccalaureus. See {Baccalaureate}, n.]
   1. A man of any age who has not been married.
      [1913 Webster]

            As merry and mellow an old bachelor as ever followed
            a hound.                              --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An unmarried woman. [Obs.] --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A person who has taken the first or lowest degree in the
      liberal arts, or in some branch of science, at a college
      or university; as, a bachelor of arts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A knight who had no standard of his own, but fought under
      the standard of another in the field; often, a young
      knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. In the companies of London tradesmen, one not yet admitted
      to wear the livery; a junior member. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Zo["o]l.) A kind of bass, an edible fresh-water fish
      ({Pomoxys annularis}) of the southern United States.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bachelor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bachelor
     n 1: a man who has never been married [syn: {unmarried man}]
     2: a knight of the lowest order; could display only a pennon
        [syn: {knight bachelor}, {bachelor-at-arms}]
     v : lead a bachelor's existence [syn: {bach}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
