<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>backing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Back \Back\ (b[a^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Backed} (b[a^]kt); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Backing}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To get upon the back of; to mount.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will back him [a horse] straight.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To place or seat upon the back. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Great Jupiter, upon his eagle backed,
            Appeared to me.                       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To drive or force backward; to cause to retreat or recede;
      as, to back oxen.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make a back for; to furnish with a back; as, to back
      books.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To adjoin behind; to be at the back of.
      [1913 Webster]

            A garden . . . with a vineyard backed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The chalk cliffs which back the beach. --Huxley.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To write upon the back of; as, to back a letter; to
      indorse; as, to back a note or legal document.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To support; to maintain; to second or strengthen by aid or
      influence; as, to back a friend. ``The Parliament would be
      backed by the people.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Have still found it necessary to back and fortify
            their laws with rewards and punishments. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mate backed the captain manfully. --Blackw. Mag.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To bet on the success of; -- as, to back a race horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To back an anchor} (Naut.), to lay down a small anchor ahead
      of a large one, the cable of the small one being fastened
      to the crown of the large one.

   {To back the field}, in horse racing, to bet against a
      particular horse or horses, that some one of all the other
      horses, collectively designated ``the field'', will win.
      

   {To back the oars}, to row backward with the oars.

   {To back a rope}, to put on a preventer.

   {To back the sails}, to arrange them so as to cause the ship
      to move astern.

   {To back up}, to support; to sustain; as, to back up one's
      friends.

   {To back a warrant} (Law), is for a justice of the peace, in
      the county where the warrant is to be executed, to sign or
      indorse a warrant, issued in another county, to apprehend
      an offender.

   {To back water} (Naut.), to reverse the action of the oars,
      paddles, or propeller, so as to force the boat or ship
      backward.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Backing \Back"ing\, n.
   1. The act of moving backward, or of putting or moving
      anything backward.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is behind, and forms the back of, anything,
      usually giving strength or stability.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Support or aid given to a person or cause.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bookbinding) The preparation of the back of a book with
      glue, etc., before putting on the cover.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>backing
     n 1: the act of providing approval and support; "his vigorous
          backing of the conservatives got him in trouble with
          progressives" [syn: {backup}, {championship}, {patronage}]
     2: something forming a back that is added for strengthening
        [syn: {mount}]
     3: financial resources provided to make some project possible;
        "the foundation provided support for the experiment" [syn:
         {support}, {financial support}, {funding}, {financial
        backing}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
