<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>backup</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>backup
     
        &lt;operating system&gt; (Sometimes "back up" when used as a verb) A
        spare copy of a file, file system or other resource for use in
        the event of failure or loss of the original.
     
        The term is most commonly used to refer to a copy of all the
        files on a computer's {disks} which is made periodically and
        kept on {magnetic tape} or other removable medium (also called
        a "{dump}").
     
        This essential precaution is neglected by most new computer
        users until the first time they experience a {disk crash} or
        accidentally delete the only copy of the file they have been
        working on for the last six months.
     
        Ideally the backup copies should be kept at a different site
        or in a fire safe since, though your hardware may be insured
        against fire, the data on it is almost certainly neither
        insured nor easily replaced.
     
        See also {differential backup}, {incremental backup}, {full
        backup}.  Compare {archive}.
     
        (2003-06-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>back up \back" up\, v. i.
   1. to move in a reverse direction; -- used of vehicles or
      animals.
      [PJC]

   2. to accumulate due to a blockage of flow; as, a traffic
      backup due to an accident; a sewage backup.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>back up \back" up\, v. t.
   1. to serve as a backup[3] for (another person or persons);
      as, the patrolmen backed up the detectives as they went
      inside to make the arrest; the center fielder backed up
      the shortstop on the play.
      [PJC]

   2. (Computers) to make a backup[5] of; as, the sysop backed
      up the purchasing data files every night.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>backup \back"up\, n.
   1. anything kept in reserve to serve as a substitute in case
      of failure or unavailability of the normal or primary
      object; -- used for devices, plans, people, etc. Also used
      attributively; as, there was no backup for the electrical
      supply; a backup motor; a backup generator.
      [PJC]

   2. (Music) a musician or group of musicians accompanying a
      soloist, whether vocalists or instrumentalists.

   Syn: accompaniment. [PJC]

   3. a person or group of persons serving as reinforcement for
      another or others; as, the policeman called for backup
      when he was fired on.
      [PJC]

   4. an accumulation, overflow, or reverse flow (in traffic or
      a liquid flow system) caused by a stoppage or other
      malfunction.
      [PJC]

   5. (Computers) A copy of a program or data from a computer
      onto a data-storage medium, usually one that may be
      removed to safe storage at a distance from the computer;
      it is used to preserve data for use in the contingency
      that the original data on the computer may be lost or
      become unusable. A backup that is removed from the
      building housing the computer system (to provide
      protection against loss of data in a disastrous event such
      as a fire) is called off-site backup. Also used
      attributively; as, backup copy.
      [PJC]

   6. (Computers) The act or process of creating a backup[5];
      as, they performed a full system backup every weekend.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>back up
     v 1: give moral or psychological support, aid, or courage to;
          "She supported him during the illness"; "Her children
          always backed her up" [syn: {support}]
     2: move backwards from a certain position; "The bully had to
        back down" [syn: {back off}, {back down}]
     3: establish as valid or genuine; "Can you back up your
        claims?" [syn: {back}]
     4: make a copy of (a computer file) especially for storage in
        another place as a security cop; "You'd better back up
        these files!"
     5: become or cause to become obstructed; "The leaves clog our
        drains in the Fall"; "The water pipe is backed up" [syn: {clog},
         {choke off}, {clog up}, {congest}, {choke}, {foul}] [ant:
         {unclog}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>backup</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>backup
     n 1: an accumulation caused by clogging or a stoppage; "a traffic
          backup on the main street"; "he discovered a backup in
          the toilet"
     2: someone who takes the place of another (as when things get
        dangerous or difficult); "the star had a stand-in for
        dangerous scenes"; "we need extra employees for summer
        fill-ins" [syn: {stand-in}, {substitute}, {relief}, {reliever},
         {backup man}, {fill-in}]
     3: a subordinate musical part; provides background for more
        important parts [syn: {accompaniment}, {musical
        accompaniment}, {support}]
     4: (computer science) a copy of a file or directory on a
        separate storage device; "he made a backup in case the
        original was accidentally damaged or erased" [syn: {computer
        backup}]
     5: the act of providing approval and support; "his vigorous
        backing of the conservatives got him in trouble with
        progressives" [syn: {backing}, {championship}, {patronage}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
