<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ball</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ball</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ball, LA (town, FIPS 4055)
  Location: 31.41825 N, 92.41005 W
  Population (1990): 3305 (1260 housing units)
  Area: 20.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ball</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ball \Ball\ (b[add]l), n. [OE. bal, balle; akin to OHG. balla,
   palla, G. ball, Icel. b["o]llr, ball; cf. F. balle. Cf. 1st
   {Bale}, n., {Pallmall}.]
   1. Any round or roundish body or mass; a sphere or globe; as,
      a ball of twine; a ball of snow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A spherical body of any substance or size used to play
      with, as by throwing, knocking, kicking, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A general name for games in which a ball is thrown,
      kicked, or knocked. See {Baseball}, and {Football}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any solid spherical, cylindrical, or conical projectile of
      lead or iron, to be discharged from a firearm; as, a
      cannon ball; a rifle ball; -- often used collectively; as,
      powder and ball. Spherical balls for the smaller firearms
      are commonly called {bullets}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Pyrotechnics &amp; Mil.) A flaming, roundish body shot into
      the air; a case filled with combustibles intended to burst
      and give light or set fire, or to produce smoke or stench;
      as, a fire ball; a stink ball.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Print.) A leather-covered cushion, fastened to a handle
      called a ballstock; -- formerly used by printers for
      inking the form, but now superseded by the roller.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A roundish protuberant portion of some part of the body;
      as, the ball of the thumb; the ball of the foot.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Far.) A large pill, a form in which medicine is commonly
      given to horses; a bolus. --White.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The globe or earth. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Move round the dark terrestrial ball. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Baseball) A pitched ball, not struck at by the batter,
       which fails to pass over the home plate at a height not
       greater than the batter's shoulder nor less than his knee
       (i.e. it is outside the strike zone). If the pitcher
       pitches four balls before three strikes are called, the
       batter advances to first base, and the action of pitching
       four balls is called a walk.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   10. a testicle; usually used in the plural. [vulgar]
       [PJC]

   11. pl. courage; nerve. [vulgar]
       [PJC]

   {Ball and socket joint}, a joint in which a ball moves within
      a socket, so as to admit of motion in every direction
      within certain limits.

   {Ball bearings}, a mechanical device for lessening the
      friction of axle bearings by means of small loose metal
      balls.

   {Ball cartridge}, a cartridge containing a ball, as
      distinguished from a blank cartridge, containing only
      powder.

   {Ball cock}, a faucet or valve which is opened or closed by
      the fall or rise of a ball floating in water at the end of
      a lever.

   {Ball gudgeon}, a pivot of a spherical form, which permits
      lateral deflection of the arbor or shaft, while retaining
      the pivot in its socket. --Knight.

   {Ball lever}, the lever used in a ball cock.

   {Ball of the eye}, the eye itself, as distinguished from its
      lids and socket; -- formerly, the pupil of the eye.

   {Ball valve} (Mach.), a contrivance by which a ball, placed
      in a circular cup with a hole in its bottom, operates as a
      valve.

   {Ball vein} (Mining), a sort of iron ore, found in loose
      masses of a globular form, containing sparkling particles.
      

   {Three balls}, or {Three golden balls}, a pawnbroker's sign
      or shop.

   {on the ball} alert; competent and knowledgeable.

   {to carry the ball} to carry on the task; to assume the
      responsibility.

   {to drop the ball} to fail to perform as expected; to fail to
      live up to a responsibility.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See {Globe}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ball</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ball \Ball\, n. [F. bal, fr. OF. baler to dance, fr. LL.
   ballare. Of uncertain origin; cf. Gr. ba`llein to toss or
   throw, or pa`llein, pa`llesqai, to leap, bound, balli`zein to
   dance, jump about; or cf. 1st {Ball}, n.]
   1. A social assembly for the purpose of dancing; -- usually
      applied to an occasion lavish or formal.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. A very enjoyable time; as, we had a ball at the wedding.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ball</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ball \Ball\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Balled} (b[add]ld); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Balling}.]
   To gather balls which cling to the feet, as of damp snow or
   clay; to gather into balls; as, the horse balls; the snow
   balls.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ball</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ball \Ball\, v. t.
   1. (Metal.) To heat in a furnace and form into balls for
      rolling.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form or wind into a ball; as, to ball cotton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ball</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ball
     n 1: round object that is hit or thrown or kicked in games; "the
          ball travelled 90 mph on his serve"; "the mayor threw
          out the first ball"; "the ball rolled into the corner
          pocket"
     2: a solid ball shot by a musket; "they had to carry a ramrod
        as well as powder and ball" [syn: {musket ball}]
     3: an object with a spherical shape; "a ball of fire" [syn: {globe},
         {orb}]
     4: the people assembled at a lavish formal dance; "the ball was
        already emptying out before the fire alarm sounded"
     5: one of the two male reproductive glands that produce
        spermatozoa and secrete androgens; "she kicked him in the
        balls and got away" [syn: {testis}, {testicle}, {orchis},
        {ballock}, {bollock}, {nut}, {egg}]
     6: a spherical object used as a plaything; "he played with his
        rubber ball in the bathtub"
     7: United States comedienne best known as the star of a popular
        television program (1911-1989) [syn: {Lucille Ball}]
     8: a compact mass; "a ball of mud caught him on the shoulder"
        [syn: {clod}, {glob}, {lump}, {clump}, {chunk}]
     9: a lavish formal dance
     10: a more or less rounded anatomical body or mass; ball of the
         human foot or ball at the base of the thumb; "he stood on
         the balls of his feet"
     11: a ball game played with a bat and ball between two teams of
         9 players; teams take turns at bat trying to score run;
         "he played baseball in high school"; "there was a
         baseball game on every empy lot"; "there was a desire for
         National League ball in the area"; "play ball!" [syn: {baseball},
          {baseball game}]
     12: a pitch that is not in the strike zone; "he threw nine
         straight balls before the manager yanked him"
     v : form into a ball by winding or rolling; "ball wool"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
