<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>band</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>band</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Band \Band\ (b[a^]nd), n. [OE. band, bond, Icel. band; akin to
   G., Sw., &amp; D. band, OHG. bant, Goth. bandi, Skr. bandha a
   binding, bandh to bind, for bhanda, bhandh, also to E. bend,
   bind. In sense 7, at least, it is fr. F. bande, from OHG.
   bant. [root]90. See {Bind}, v. t., and cf. {Bend}, {Bond},
   1st {Bandy}.]
   1. A fillet, strap, or any narrow ligament with which a thing
      is encircled, or fastened, or by which a number of things
      are tied, bound together, or confined; a fetter.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every one's bands were loosed.        --Acts xvi.
                                                  26.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.)
      (a) A continuous tablet, stripe, or series of ornaments,
          as of carved foliage, of color, or of brickwork, etc.
      (b) In Gothic architecture, the molding, or suite of
          moldings, which encircles the pillars and small
          shafts.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. That which serves as the means of union or connection
      between persons; a tie. ``To join in Hymen's bands.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A linen collar or ruff worn in the 16th and 17th
      centuries.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. Two strips of linen hanging from the neck in front as
      part of a clerical, legal, or academic dress.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A narrow strip of cloth or other material on any article
      of dress, to bind, strengthen, ornament, or complete it.
      ``Band and gusset and seam.'' --Hood.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A company of persons united in any common design,
      especially a body of armed men.
      [1913 Webster]

            Troops of horsemen with his bands of foot. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A number of musicians who play together upon portable
      musical instruments, especially those making a loud sound,
      as certain wind instruments (trumpets, clarinets, etc.),
      and drums, or cymbals; as, a high school's marching band.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Bot.) A space between elevated lines or ribs, as of the
      fruits of umbelliferous plants.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Zo["o]l.) A stripe, streak, or other mark transverse to
       the axis of the body.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Mech.) A belt or strap.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A bond. [Obs.] ``Thy oath and band.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Pledge; security. [Obs.] --Spenser.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Band saw}, a saw in the form of an endless steel belt, with
      teeth on one edge, running over wheels.

   {big band}, a band that is the size of an orchestra, usually
      playing mostly jazz or swing music. The big band typically
      features both ensemble and solo playing, sometimes has a
      lead singer, and is often located in a night club where
      the patrons may dance to its music. The big bands were
      popular from the late 1920's to the 1940's. Contrasted
      with {combo}, which has fewer players.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>band</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Band \Band\ (b[a^]nd), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Banded}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Banding}.]
   1. To bind or tie with a band.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mark with a band.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To unite in a troop, company, or confederacy. ``Banded
      against his throne.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Banded architrave}, {Banded pier}, {Banded shaft}, etc.
      (Arch.), an architrave, pier, shaft, etc., of which the
      regular profile is interrupted by blocks or projections
      crossing it at right angles.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>band</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Band \Band\, v. i.
   To confederate for some common purpose; to unite; to conspire
   together.
   [1913 Webster]

         Certain of the Jews banded together.     --Acts xxiii.
                                                  12.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>band</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Band \Band\, v. t.
   To bandy; to drive away. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>band</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Band \Band\,
   imp. of {Bind}. [Obs.]                         --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>band</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>band
     n 1: an unofficial association of people or groups; "the smart
          set goes there"; "they were an angry lot" [syn: {set}, {circle},
           {lot}]
     2: instrumentalists not including string players
     3: a stripe of contrasting color; "chromosomes exhibit
        characteristic bands" [syn: {stria}, {striation}]
     4: a strip or stripe of a contrasting color or material [syn: {banding},
         {stripe}]
     5: a group of musicians playing popular music for dancing [syn:
         {dance band}, {dance orchestra}]
     6: a range of frequencies between two limits
     7: something elongated that is worn around the body or one of
        the limbs
     8: jewelry consisting of a circlet of precious metal (often set
        with jewels) worn on the finger; "she had rings on every
        finger"; "he noted that she wore a wedding band" [syn: {ring}]
     9: a strip of material attached to the leg of a bird to
        identify it (as in studies of bird migration) [syn: {ring}]
     10: a restraint put around something to hold it together
     v 1: bind or tie together, as with a band
     2: attach a ring to the foot of, in order to identify; "ring
        birds"; "band the geese to observe their migratory
        patterns" [syn: {ring}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
