<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bandwidth</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bandwidth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bandwidth
     
        &lt;communications&gt; The difference between the highest and lowest
        frequencies of a transmission channel (the width of its
        allocated band of frequencies).
     
        The term is often used erroneously to mean {data rate} or
        capacity - the amount of {data} that is, or can be, sent
        through a given communications circuit per second.
     
        [How is data capacity related to bandwidth?]
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2001-04-24)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bandwidth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bandwidth \band"width`\ n.
   The maximum rate of information transfer (measured in
   bits/second) that can be carried by a communication channel.
   ``The bandwidth of an analog telephone line is less than 100
   kilobits per second.''
   [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bandwidth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bandwidth n. 1. [common] Used by hackers (in a generalization of its
   technical meaning) as the volume of information per unit time that a
   computer, person, or transmission medium can handle. "Those are amazing
   graphics, but I missed some of the detail -- not enough bandwidth, I
   guess." Compare {low-bandwidth}; see also {brainwidth}. This generalized
   usage began to go mainstream after the Internet population explosion of
   1993-1994. 2. Attention span. 3. On {Usenet}, a measure of network
   capacity that is often wasted by people complaining about how items
   posted by others are a waste of bandwidth.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bandwidth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bandwidth
     n : a data transmission rate; the maximum amount of information
         (bits/second) that can be transmitted along a channel
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
