<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bank</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banc \Banc\, ||Bancus \Ban"cus\, Bank \Bank\, n. [OF. banc, LL.
   bancus. See {Bank}, n.]
   A bench; a high seat, or seat of distinction or judgment; a
   tribunal or court.
   [1913 Webster]

   {In banc}, {In banco} (the ablative of bancus), {In bank}, in
      full court, or with full judicial authority; as, sittings
      in banc (distinguished from sittings at {nisi prius}).
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bank \Bank\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Banked}(b[a^][ng]kt); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Banking}.]
   1. To raise a mound or dike about; to inclose, defend, or
      fortify with a bank; to embank. ``Banked well with
      earth.'' --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To heap or pile up; as, to bank sand.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass by the banks of. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Engineering) To build (a roadway or railroad) with an
      inclination at a curve in the road, so as to counteract
      centrifugal forces acting on vehicles moving rapiudly
      around the curve, thus reducing the danger of vehicles
      overturning at a curve; as, the raceway was steeply banked
      at the curves.
      [PJC]

   {To bank a fire}, {To bank up a fire}, to cover the coals or
      embers with ashes or cinders, thus keeping the fire low
      but alive.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bank \Bank\ (b[a^][ng]k), n. [OE. banke; akin to E. bench, and
   prob. of Scand. origin; cf. Icel. bakki. See {Bench}.]
   1. A mound, pile, or ridge of earth, raised above the
      surrounding level; hence, anything shaped like a mound or
      ridge of earth; as, a bank of clouds; a bank of snow.
      [1913 Webster]

            They cast up a bank against the city. --2 Sam. xx.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A steep acclivity, as the slope of a hill, or the side of
      a ravine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The margin of a watercourse; the rising ground bordering a
      lake, river, or sea, or forming the edge of a cutting, or
      other hollow.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tiber trembled underneath her banks.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An elevation, or rising ground, under the sea; a shoal,
      shelf, or shallow; as, the banks of Newfoundland.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mining)
      (a) The face of the coal at which miners are working.
      (b) A deposit of ore or coal, worked by excavations above
          water level.
      (c) The ground at the top of a shaft; as, ores are brought
          to bank.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (A["e]ronautics) The lateral inclination of an
      a["e]roplane as it rounds a curve; as, a bank of 45[deg]
      is easy; a bank of 90[deg] is dangerous.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. A group or series of objects arranged near together; as, a
      bank of electric lamps, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. The tilt of a roadway or railroad, at a curve in the road,
      designed to counteract centrifugal forces acting on
      vehicles moving rapiudly around the curve, thus reducing
      the danger of overturning during a turn.
      [PJC]

   {Bank beaver} (Zo["o]l.), the otter. [Local, U.S.]

   {Bank swallow}, a small American and European swallow
      ({Clivicola riparia}) that nests in a hole which it
      excavates in a bank.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bank \Bank\, v. i. (A["e]ronautics)
   To tilt sidewise in rounding a curve; -- said of a flying
   machine, an a["e]rocurve, or the like.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bank \Bank\, n. [Prob. fr. F. banc. Of German origin, and akin
   to E. bench. See {Bench}.]
   1. A bench, as for rowers in a galley; also, a tier of oars.
      [1913 Webster]

            Placed on their banks, the lusty Trojan sweep
            Neptune's smooth face, and cleave the yielding deep.
                                                  --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law)
      (a) The bench or seat upon which the judges sit.
      (b) The regular term of a court of law, or the full court
          sitting to hear arguments upon questions of law, as
          distinguished from a sitting at Nisi Prius, or a court
          held for jury trials. See {Banc}. --Burrill.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Printing) A sort of table used by printers.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Music) A bench, or row of keys belonging to a keyboard,
      as in an organ. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bank \Bank\, n. [F. banque, It. banca, orig. bench, table,
   counter, of German origin, and akin to E. bench; cf. G. bank
   bench, OHG. banch. See {Bench}, and cf. {Banco}, {Beach}.]
   1. An establishment for the custody, loan, exchange, or
      issue, of money, and for facilitating the transmission of
      funds by drafts or bills of exchange; an institution
      incorporated for performing one or more of such functions,
      or the stockholders (or their representatives, the
      directors), acting in their corporate capacity.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The building or office used for banking purposes.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A fund to be used in transacting business, especially a
      joint stock or capital.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let it be no bank or common stock, but every man be
            master of his own money.              --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Gaming) The sum of money or the checks which the dealer
      or banker has as a fund, from which to draw his stakes and
      pay his losses.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. In certain games, as dominos, a fund of pieces from which
      the players are allowed to draw; in Monopoly, the fund of
      money used to pay bonuses due to the players, or to which
      they pay fines.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   6. a place where something is stored and held available for
      future use; specifically, an organization that stores
      biological products for medical needs; as, a blood bank,
      an organ bank, a sperm bank.
      [PJC]

   {Bank credit}, a credit by which a person who has given the
      required security to a bank has liberty to draw to a
      certain extent agreed upon.

   {Bank of deposit}, a bank which receives money for safe
      keeping.

   {Bank of issue}, a bank which issues its own notes payable to
      bearer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bank \Bank\, v. t.
   To deposit in a bank. --Johnson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bank \Bank\, v. i.
   1. To keep a bank; to carry on the business of a banker.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To deposit money in a bank; to have an account with a
      banker.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bank
     n 1: a financial institution that accepts deposits and channels
          the money into lending activities; "he cashed a check at
          the bank"; "that bank holds the mortgage on my home"
          [syn: {depository financial institution}, {banking
          concern}, {banking company}]
     2: sloping land (especially the slope beside a body of water);
        "they pulled the canoe up on the bank"; "he sat on the
        bank of the river and watched the currents"
     3: a supply or stock held in reserve for future use (especially
        in emergencies)
     4: a building in which commercial banking is transacted; "the
        bank is on the corner of Nassau and Witherspoon" [syn: {bank
        building}]
     5: an arrangement of similar objects in a row or in tiers; "he
        operated a bank of switches"
     6: a container (usually with a slot in the top) for keeping
        money at home; "the coin bank was empty" [syn: {savings
        bank}, {coin bank}, {money box}]
     7: a long ridge or pile; "a huge bank of earth"
     8: the funds held by a gambling house or the dealer in some
        gambling games; "he tried to break the bank at Monte
        Carlo"
     9: a slope in the turn of a road or track; the outside is
        higher than the inside in order to reduce the effects of
        centrifugal force [syn: {cant}, {camber}]
     10: a flight maneuver; aircraft tips laterally about its
         longitudinal axis (especially in turning); "the plane
         went into a steep bank"
     v 1: tip laterally; "the pilot had to bank the aircraft"
     2: enclose with a bank; "bank roads"
     3: do business with a bank or keep an account at a bank; "Where
        do you bank in this town?"
     4: act as the banker in a game or in gambling
     5: be in the banking business
     6: put into a bank account; "She deposites her paycheck every
        month" [syn: {deposit}] [ant: {withdraw}]
     7: cover with ashes so to control the rate of burning; "bank a
        fire"
     8: have confidence or faith in; "We can trust in God"; "Rely on
        your friends"; "bank on your good education"; "I swear by
        my grandmother's recipes" [syn: {trust}, {swear}, {rely}]
        [ant: {distrust}, {distrust}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
