<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>banner</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banner
   (1.) The flag or banner of the larger kind, serving for three
   tribes marching together. These standards, of which there were
   four, were worked with embroidery and beautifully ornamented
   (Num. 1:52; 2:2, 3, 10, 18, 25; Cant. 2:4; 6:4, 10).
   
     (2.) The flag borne by each separate tribe, of a smaller form.
   Probably it bore on it the name of the tribe to which it
   belonged, or some distinguishing device (Num. 2:2,34).
   
     (3.) A lofty signal-flag, not carried about, but stationary.
   It was usually erected on a mountain or other lofty place. As
   soon as it was seen the war-trumpets were blown (Ps. 60:4; Isa.
   5:26; 11:12; 13:2; 18:3; 30:17; Jer. 4:6 21; Ezek. 27:7).
   
     (4.) A "sign of fire" (Jer. 6:1) was sometimes used as a
   signal.
   
     The banners and ensigns of the Roman army had idolatrous
   images upon them, and hence they are called the "abomination of
   desolation" (q.v.). The principal Roman standard, however, was
   an eagle. (See Matt. 24:28; Luke 17:37, where the Jewish nation
   is compared to a dead body, which the eagles gather together to
   devour.)
   
     God's setting up or giving a banner (Ps. 20:5; 60:4; Cant.
   2:4) imports his presence and protection and aid extended to his
   people.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>banner
     
        1. The title page added to printouts by most {print spoolers}.
        Typically includes user or account ID information in very
        large character-graphics capitals.  Also called a "burst
        page", because it indicates where to burst (tear apart)
        fanfold paper to separate one user's printout from the next.
     
        2. A similar printout generated (typically on multiple pages
        of fan-fold paper) from user-specified text, e.g. by a program
        such as {Unix}'s "banner".
     
        3. {splash screen}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1994-11-28)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banner, IL (village, FIPS 3571)
  Location: 40.51469 N, 89.91043 W
  Population (1990): 160 (74 housing units)
  Area: 0.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Banner, KY
  Zip code(s): 41603
Banner, MS
  Zip code(s): 38913
Banner, WY
  Zip code(s): 82832
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banner \Ban"ner\ (b[a^]n"n[~e]r), n. [OE. banere, OF. baniere,
   F. banni[`e]re, bandi[`e]re, fr. LL. baneria, banderia, fr.
   bandum banner, fr. OHG. bant band, strip of cloth; cf. bindan
   to bind, Goth. bandwa, bandwo, a sign. See {Band}, n.]
   1. A kind of flag attached to a spear or pike by a
      crosspiece, and used by a chief as his standard in battle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hang out our banners on the outward walls. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A large piece of silk or other cloth, with a device or
      motto, extended on a crosspiece, and borne in a
      procession, or suspended in some conspicuous place.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any flag or standard; as, the star-spangled banner.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Banner fish} (Zo["o]l.), a large fish of the genus
      {Histiophorus}, of the Swordfish family, having a broad
      bannerlike dorsal fin; the sailfish. One species
      ({Histiophorus Americanus}) inhabits the North Atlantic.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>banner n. 1. The title page added to printouts by most print spoolers
   (see {spool}). Typically includes user or account ID information in very
   large character-graphics capitals. Also called a `burst page', because
   it indicates where to burst (tear apart) fanfold paper to separate one
   user's printout from the next. 2. A similar printout generated
   (typically on multiple pages of fan-fold paper) from user-specified
   text, e.g., by a program such as Unix's `banner({1,6})'. 3. On
   interactive software, a first screen containing a logo and/or author
   credits and/or a copyright notice. This is probably now the commonest
   sense.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>banner
     adj : unusually good; outstanding; "a banner year for the company"
     n 1: long strip of cloth for decoration or advertising [syn: {streamer}]
     2: a newspaper headline that runs across the full page [syn: {streamer}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
