<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>banquet</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banquet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banquet
   a feast provided for the entertainment of a company of guests
   (Esther 5; 7; 1 Pet. 4:3); such as was provided for our Lord by
   his friends in Bethany (Matt. 26:6; Mark 14:3; comp. John 12:2).
   These meals were in the days of Christ usually called "suppers,"
   after the custom of the Romans, and were partaken of toward the
   close of the day. It was usual to send a second invitation
   (Matt. 22:3; Luke 14:17) to those who had been already invited.
   When the whole company was assembled, the master of the house
   shut the door with his own hands (Luke 13:25; Matt. 25:10).
   
     The guests were first refreshed with water and fragrant oil
   (Luke 7:38; Mark 7:4). A less frequent custom was that of
   supplying each guest with a robe to be worn during the feast
   (Eccles. 9:8; Rev. 3:4, 5; Matt. 22:11). At private banquets the
   master of the house presided; but on public occasions a
   "governor of the feast" was chosen (John 2:8). The guests were
   placed in order according to seniority (Gen. 43:33), or
   according to the rank they held (Prov. 25:6,7; Matt. 23:6; Luke
   14:7).
   
     As spoons and knives and forks are a modern invention, and
   were altogether unknown in the East, the hands alone were
   necessarily used, and were dipped in the dish, which was common
   to two of the guests (John 13:26). In the days of our Lord the
   guests reclined at table; but the ancient Israelites sat around
   low tables, cross-legged, like the modern Orientals. Guests were
   specially honoured when extra portions were set before them
   (Gen. 43:34), and when their cup was filled with wine till it
   ran over (Ps. 23:5). The hands of the guests were usually
   cleaned by being rubbed on bread, the crumbs of which fell to
   the ground, and were the portion for dogs (Matt. 15:27; Luke
   16:21).
   
     At the time of the three annual festivals at Jerusalem family
   banquets were common. To these the "widow, and the fatherless,
   and the stranger" were welcome (Deut. 16:11). Sacrifices also
   included a banquet (Ex. 34:15; Judg. 16:23). Birthday banquets
   are mentioned (Gen. 40:20; Matt. 14:6). They were sometimes
   protracted, and attended with revelry and excess (Gen. 21:8;
   29:22; 1 Sam. 25:2,36; 2 Sam. 13:23). Portions were sometimes
   sent from the table to poorer friends (Neh. 8:10; Esther 9:19,
   22). (See {MEALS}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banquet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banquet \Ban"quet\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Banqueted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Banqueting}.]
   To treat with a banquet or sumptuous entertainment of food;
   to feast.
   [1913 Webster]

         Just in time to banquet
         The illustrious company assembled there. --Coleridge.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banquet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banquet \Ban"quet\, v. i.
   1. To regale one's self with good eating and drinking; to
      feast.
      [1913 Webster]

            Were it a draught for Juno when she banquets,
            I would not taste thy treasonous offer. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To partake of a dessert after a feast. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Where they did both sup and banquet.  --Cavendish.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banquet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Banquet \Ban"quet\, n. [F., a feast, prop. a dim. of banc bench;
   cf. It. banchetto, dim. of banco a bench, counter. See {Bank}
   a bench, and cf. {Banquette}.]
   1. A feast; a sumptuous entertainment of eating and drinking;
      often, a complimentary or ceremonious feast, followed by
      speeches.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A dessert; a course of sweetmeats; a sweetmeat or
      sweetmeats. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We'll dine in the great room, but let the music
            And banquet be prepared here.         --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>banquet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>banquet
     n 1: a ceremonial dinner party for many people [syn: {feast}]
     2: a meal that is well prepared and greatly enjoyed; "a banquet
        for the graduating seniors"; "the Thanksgiving feast";
        "they put out quite a spread" [syn: {feast}, {spread}]
     v 1: provide a feast or banquet for [syn: {feast}, {junket}]
     2: partake in a feast or banquet [syn: {feast}, {junket}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
