<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bar</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bar
   used to denote the means by which a door is bolted (Neh. 3:3); a
   rock in the sea (Jonah 2:6); the shore of the sea (Job 38:10);
   strong fortifications and powerful impediments, etc. (Isa. 45:2;
   Amos 1:5); defences of a city (1 Kings 4:13). A bar for a door
   was of iron (Isa. 45:2), brass (Ps. 107:16), or wood (Nah.
   3:13).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bar
     
        1. &lt;programming, convention&gt; /bar/ The second {metasyntactic
        variable}, after {foo} and before {baz}.  E.g. "Suppose
        function FOO calls functions BAR..."
     
        2. Often appended to {foo} to produce {foobar}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-03-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bar \Bar\ (b[aum]r), n. [OE. barre, F. barre, fr. LL. barra, W.
   bar the branch of a tree, bar, baren branch, Gael. &amp; Ir.
   barra bar. [root]91.]
   1. A piece of wood, metal, or other material, long in
      proportion to its breadth or thickness, used as a lever
      and for various other purposes, but especially for a
      hindrance, obstruction, or fastening; as, the bars of a
      fence or gate; the bar of a door.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt make bars of shittim wood. --Ex. xxvi.
                                                  26.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An indefinite quantity of some substance, so shaped as to
      be long in proportion to its breadth and thickness; as, a
      bar of gold or of lead; a bar of soap.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything which obstructs, hinders, or prevents; an
      obstruction; a barrier.
      [1913 Webster]

            Must I new bars to my own joy create? --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A bank of sand, gravel, or other matter, esp. at the mouth
      of a river or harbor, obstructing navigation.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Any railing that divides a room, or office, or hall of
      assembly, in order to reserve a space for those having
      special privileges; as, the bar of the House of Commons.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law)
      (a) The railing that incloses the place which counsel
          occupy in courts of justice. Hence, the phrase at the
          bar of the court signifies in open court.
      (b) The place in court where prisoners are stationed for
          arraignment, trial, or sentence.
      (c) The whole body of lawyers licensed in a court or
          district; the legal profession.
      (d) A special plea constituting a sufficient answer to
          plaintiff's action.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. Any tribunal; as, the bar of public opinion; the bar of
      God.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A barrier or counter, over which liquors and food are
      passed to customers; hence, the portion of the room behind
      the counter where liquors for sale are kept.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Her.) An ordinary, like a fess but narrower, occupying
      only one fifth part of the field.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A broad shaft, or band, or stripe; as, a bar of light; a
       bar of color.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Mus.) A vertical line across the staff. Bars divide the
       staff into spaces which represent measures, and are
       themselves called measures.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: A double bar marks the end of a strain or main division
         of a movement, or of a whole piece of music; in
         psalmody, it marks the end of a line of poetry. The
         term bar is very often loosely used for measure, i.e.,
         for such length of music, or of silence, as is included
         between one bar and the next; as, a passage of eight
         bars; two bars' rest.
         [1913 Webster]

   12. (Far.) pl.
       (a) The space between the tusks and grinders in the upper
           jaw of a horse, in which the bit is placed.
       (b) The part of the crust of a horse's hoof which is bent
           inwards towards the frog at the heel on each side,
           and extends into the center of the sole.
           [1913 Webster]

   13. (Mining)
       (a) A drilling or tamping rod.
       (b) A vein or dike crossing a lode.
           [1913 Webster]

   14. (Arch.)
       (a) A gatehouse of a castle or fortified town.
       (b) A slender strip of wood which divides and supports
           the glass of a window; a sash bar.
           [1913 Webster]

   {Bar shoe} (Far.), a kind of horseshoe having a bar across
      the usual opening at the heel, to protect a tender frog
      from injury.

   {Bar shot}, a double headed shot, consisting of a bar, with a
      ball or half ball at each end; -- formerly used for
      destroying the masts or rigging in naval combat.

   {Bar sinister} (Her.), a term popularly but erroneously used
      for baton, a mark of illegitimacy. See {Baton}.

   {Bar tracery} (Arch.), ornamental stonework resembling bars
      of iron twisted into the forms required.

   {Blank bar} (Law). See {Blank}.

   {Case at bar} (Law), a case presently before the court; a
      case under argument.

   {In bar of}, as a sufficient reason against; to prevent.

   {Matter in bar}, or {Defence in bar}, any matter which is a
      final defense in an action.

   {Plea in bar}, a plea which goes to bar or defeat the
      plaintiff's action absolutely and entirely.

   {Trial at bar} (Eng. Law), a trial before all the judges of
      one the superior courts of Westminster, or before a quorum
      representing the full court.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bar \Bar\ (b[aum]r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Barred} (b[aum]rd); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Barring}.] [ F. barrer. See {Bar}, n.]
   1. To fasten with a bar; as, to bar a door or gate.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To restrict or confine, as if by a bar; to hinder; to
      obstruct; to prevent; to prohibit; as, to bar the entrance
      of evil; distance bars our intercourse; the statute bars
      my right; the right is barred by time; a release bars the
      plaintiff's recovery; -- sometimes with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            He barely looked the idea in the face, and hastened
            to bar it in its dungeon.             --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To except; to exclude by exception.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nay, but I bar to-night: you shall not gauge me
            By what we do to-night.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cross with one or more stripes or lines.
      [1913 Webster]

            For the sake of distinguishing the feet more
            clearly, I have barred them singly.   --Burney.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bar /bar/ n. 1. [very common] The second {metasyntactic variable},
   after {foo} and before {baz}. "Suppose we have two functions: FOO and
   BAR. FOO calls BAR...." 2. Often appended to {foo} to produce {foobar}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BAR
     Base Address Register (IC)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bar</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bar
     n 1: a room or establishment where alcoholic drinks are served
          over a counter; "he drowned his sorrows in whiskey at
          the bar" [syn: {barroom}, {saloon}, {ginmill}, {taproom}]
     2: a counter where you can obtain food or drink; "he bought a
        hot dog and a coke at the bar"
     3: a rigid piece of metal or wood; usually used as a fastening
        or obstruction or weapon; "there were bars in the windows
        to prevent escape"
     4: musical notation for a repeating pattern of musical beats;
        "the orchestra omitted the last twelve bars of the song"
        [syn: {measure}]
     5: an obstruction (usually metal) placed at the top of a goal;
        "it was an excellent kick but the ball hit the bar"
     6: the act of preventing; "there was no bar against leaving";
        "money was allocated to study the cause and prevention of
        influenza" [syn: {prevention}]
     7: (meteorology) a unit of pressure equal to a million dynes
        per square centimeter; "unfortunately some writers have
        used bar for one dyne per square centimeter"
     8: a submerged (or partly submerged) ridge in a river or along
        a shore; "the boat ran aground on a submerged bar in the
        river"
     9: the body of individuals qualified to practice law in a
        particular jurisdiction; "he was admitted to the bar in
        New Jersey" [syn: {legal profession}, {legal community}]
     10: a block of solid substance (such as soap or wax); "a bar of
         chocolate" [syn: {cake}]
     11: a portable .30 caliber magazine-fed automatic rifle operated
         by gas pressure; used by United States troops in World
         War I and in World War II and in the Korean War [syn: {Browning
         automatic rifle}]
     12: a horizontal rod that serves as a support for gymnasts as
         they perform exercises
     13: a heating element in an electric fire; "an electric fire
         with three bars"
     14: (law) a railing that encloses the part of the courtroom
         where the judges and lawyers sit and the case is tried;
         "spectators were not allowed past the bar"
     v 1: prevent from entering; keep out; "He was barred from
          membership in the club" [syn: {debar}, {exclude}]
     2: render unsuitable for passage; "block the way"; "barricade
        the streets"; "stop the busy road" [syn: {barricade}, {block},
         {blockade}, {stop}, {block off}, {block up}]
     3: expel, as if by official decree; "he was banished from his
        own country" [syn: {banish}, {relegate}]
     4: secure with, or as if with, bars; "He barred the door" [ant:
         {unbar}]
     [also: {barring}, {barred}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
