<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bargain</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bargain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bargain \Bar"gain\, v. i. [OE. barganien, OF. bargaigner, F.
   barguigner, to hesitate, fr. LL. barcaniare. See {Bargain},
   n.]
   To make a bargain; to make a contract for the exchange of
   property or services; -- followed by with and for; as, to
   bargain with a farmer for a cow.
   [1913 Webster]

         So worthless peasants bargain for their wives. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bargain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bargain \Bar"gain\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bargained} (?); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Bargaining}.]
   To transfer for a consideration; to barter; to trade; as, to
   bargain one horse for another.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To bargain away}, to dispose of in a bargain; -- usually
      with a sense of loss or disadvantage; as, to bargain away
      one's birthright. ``The heir . . . had somehow bargained
      away the estate.'' --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bargain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bargain \Bar"gain\, n. [OE. bargayn, bargany, OF. bargaigne,
   bargagne, prob. from a supposed LL. barcaneum, fr. barca a
   boat which carries merchandise to the shore; hence, to
   traffic to and fro, to carry on commerce in general. See
   {Bark} a vessel. ]
   1. An agreement between parties concerning the sale of
      property; or a contract by which one party binds himself
      to transfer the right to some property for a
      consideration, and the other party binds himself to
      receive the property and pay the consideration.
      [1913 Webster]

            A contract is a bargain that is legally binding.
                                                  --Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An agreement or stipulation; mutual pledge.
      [1913 Webster]

            And whon your honors mean to solemnize
            The bargain of your faith.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A purchase; also ( when not qualified), a gainful
      transaction; an advantageous purchase; as, to buy a thing
      at a bargain.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The thing stipulated or purchased; also, anything bought
      cheap.
      [1913 Webster]

            She was too fond of her most filthy bargain. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bargain and sale} (Law), a species of conveyance, by which
      the bargainor contracts to convey the lands to the
      bargainee, and becomes by such contract a trustee for and
      seized to the use of the bargainee. The statute then
      completes the purchase; i. e., the bargain vests the use,
      and the statute vests the possession. --Blackstone.

   {Into the bargain}, over and above what is stipulated;
      besides.

   {To sell bargains}, to make saucy (usually indelicate)
      repartees. [Obs.] --Swift.

   {To strike a bargain}, to reach or ratify an agreement. ``A
      bargain was struck.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Contract; stipulation; purchase; engagement.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bargain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bargain
     n 1: an agreement between parties (usually arrived at after
          discussion) fixing obligations of each; "he made a
          bargain with the devil"; "he rose to prominence through
          a series of shady deals" [syn: {deal}]
     2: an advantageous purchase; "she got a bargain at the
        auction"; "the stock was a real buy at that price" [syn: {buy},
         {steal}]
     v 1: negotiate the terms of an exchange; "We bargained for a
          beautiful rug in the bazaar" [syn: {dicker}]
     2: come to terms; arrive at an agreement
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
