<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>basic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>basic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BASIC
     
        &lt;language&gt; Beginner's All-purpose Symbolic Instruction Code.
        A simple language oroginally designed for ease of programming
        by students and beginners.
     
        BASIC exists in many dialects, and is popular on
        {microcomputers} with sound and graphics support.  Most micro
        versions are {interactive} and {interpreted}.
     
        BASIC has become the leading cause of brain-damage in
        proto-hackers.  This is another case (like {Pascal}) of the
        cascading lossage that happens when a language deliberately
        designed as an educational toy gets taken too seriously.  A
        novice can write short BASIC programs (on the order of 10-20
        lines) very easily; writing anything longer is (a) very
        painful, and (b) encourages bad habits that will make it
        harder to use more powerful languages well.  This wouldn't be
        so bad if historical accidents hadn't made BASIC so common on
        low-end micros.  As it is, it ruins thousands of potential
        wizards a year.
     
        Originally, all references to code, both {GOTO} and GOSUB
        (subroutine call) referred to the destination by its line
        number.  This allowed for very simple editing in the days
        before {text editors} were considered essential.  Just typing
        the line number deleted the line and to edit a line you just
        typed the new line with the same number.  Programs were
        typically numbered in steps of ten to allow for insertions.
        Later versions, such as {BASIC V}, allow {GOTO}-less
        {structured programming} with named {procedures} and
        {functions}, IF-THEN-ELSE-ENDIF constructs and {WHILE} loops
        etc.
     
        Early BASICs had no graphic operations except with graphic
        characters.  In the 1970s BASIC {interpreters} became standard
        features in {mainframes} and {minicomputers}.  Some versions
        included {matrix} operations as language {primitives}.
     
        A {public domain} {interpreter} for a mixture of {DEC}'s
        {MU-Basic} and {Microsoft Basic} is {here
        (ftp://oak.oakland.edu/pub/Unix-c/languages/basic/basic.tar-z)}.
        A {yacc} {parser} and {interpreter} were in the
        comp.sources.unix archives volume 2.
     
        See also {ANSI Minimal BASIC}, {bournebasic}, {bwBASIC},
        {ubasic}, {Visual Basic}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-03-15)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>basic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BASIC \BASIC\ n.
   1. (Computers) [Beginner's All-purpose Symbolic Iruction C.]
      an artificial computer language with a relatively
      simplified instruction set.

   Note: Writing a program in BASIC or other higher computer
         languages is simpler than writing in assembly language.
         See also {programming language}, {FORTRAN}.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>basic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Basic \Ba"sic\, a.
   1. (Chem.)
      (a) Relating to a base; performing the office of a base in
          a salt.
      (b) Having the base in excess, or the amount of the base
          atomically greater than that of the acid, or exceeding
          in proportion that of the related neutral salt.
      (c) Apparently alkaline, as certain normal salts which
          exhibit alkaline reactions with test paper.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. (Min.) Said of crystalline rocks which contain a
      relatively low percentage of silica, as basalt.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Basic salt} (Chem.), a salt formed from a base or hydroxide
      by the partial replacement of its hydrogen by a negative
      or acid element or radical.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>basic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>higher programming language \higher programming language\ n.
   (Computers)
   a computer programming language with an instruction set
   allowing one instruction to code for several assembly
   language instructions.

   Note: The aggregation of several assembly-language
         instructions into one instruction allows much greater
         efficiency in writing computer programs. Most programs
         are now written in some higher programming language,
         such as {BASIC}, {FORTRAN}, {COBOL}, {C}, {C++}, or
         {JAVA}.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>basic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BASIC /bay'-sic/ n. A programming language, originally designed for
   Dartmouth's experimental timesharing system in the early 1960s, which
   for many years was the leading cause of brain damage in proto-hackers.
   Edsger W. Dijkstra observed in "Selected Writings on Computing: A
   Personal Perspective" that "It is practically impossible to teach good
   programming style to students that have had prior exposure to BASIC: as
   potential programmers they are mentally mutilated beyond hope of
   regeneration." This is another case (like {Pascal}) of the cascading
   {lossage} that happens when a language deliberately designed as an
   educational toy gets taken too seriously. A novice can write short BASIC
   programs (on the order of 10-20 lines) very easily; writing anything
   longer (a) is very painful, and (b) encourages bad habits that will make
   it harder to use more powerful languages well. This wouldn't be so bad
   if historical accidents hadn't made BASIC so common on low-end micros in
   the 1980s. As it is, it probably ruined tens of thousands of potential
   wizards.

   [1995: Some languages called `BASIC' aren't quite this nasty any more,
   having acquired Pascal- and C-like procedures and control structures and
   shed their line numbers. --ESR]

   BASIC stands for "Beginner's All-purpose Symbolic Instruction Code".
   Earlier versions of this entry claiming this was a later {backronym}
   were incorrect.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>basic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BASIC
     Beginner's All-purpose Symbolic Instruction Code
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>basic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>basic
     adj 1: pertaining to or constituting a base or basis; "a basic
            fact"; "the basic ingredients"; "basic changes in
            public opinion occur because of changes in priorities"
            [ant: {incidental}]
     2: reduced to the simplest and most significant form possible
        without loss of generality; "a basic story line"; "a
        canonical syllable pattern" [syn: {canonic}, {canonical}]
     3: of primary importance; "basic truths" [syn: {basal}, {primary}]
     4: serving as a base or starting point; "a basic course in
        Russian"; "basic training for raw recruits"; "a set of
        basic tools"; "an introductory art course" [syn: {introductory}]
     5: of or denoting or of the nature of or containing a base
     n 1: a popular programming language that is relatively easy to
          learn; an acronym for beginner's all-purpose symbolic
          instruction code; no longer in general use
     2: (usually plural) a necessary commodity for which demand is
        constant [syn: {staple}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
