<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bass</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bass, AR
  Zip code(s): 72612
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Base \Base\ (b[=a]s), a. [OE. bass, F. bas, low, fr. LL. bassus
   thick, fat, short, humble; cf. L. Bassus, a proper name, and
   W. bas shallow. Cf. {Bass} a part in music.]
   1. Of little, or less than the usual, height; of low growth;
      as, base shrubs. [Archaic] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Low in place or position. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Of humble birth; or low degree; lowly; mean. [Archaic] ``A
      peasant and base swain.'' --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Illegitimate by birth; bastard. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Why bastard? wherefore base?          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Of little comparative value, as metal inferior to gold and
      silver, the precious metals.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Alloyed with inferior metal; debased; as, base coin; base
      bullion.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Morally low. Hence: Low-minded; unworthy; without dignity
      of sentiment; ignoble; mean; illiberal; menial; as, a base
      fellow; base motives; base occupations. ``A cruel act of a
      base and a cowardish mind.'' --Robynson (More's Utopia).
      ``Base ingratitude.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Not classical or correct. ``Base Latin.'' --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Deep or grave in sound; as, the base tone of a violin. [In
      this sense, commonly written {bass.}]
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Law) Not held by honorable service; as, a base estate,
       one held by services not honorable; held by villenage.
       Such a tenure is called base, or low, and the tenant, a
       base tenant.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Base fee}, formerly, an estate held at the will of the lord;
      now, a qualified fee. See note under {Fee}, n., 4.

   {Base metal}. See under {Metal}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Dishonorable; worthless; ignoble; low-minded; infamous;
        sordid; degraded.

   Usage: {Base}, {Vile}, {Mean}. These words, as expressing
          moral qualities, are here arranged in the order of
          their strength, the strongest being placed first. Base
          marks a high degree of moral turpitude; vile and mean
          denote, in different degrees, the lack of what is
          valuable or worthy of esteem. What is base excites our
          abhorrence; what is vile provokes our disgust or
          indignation; what is mean awakens contempt. Base is
          opposed to high-minded; vile, to noble; mean, to
          liberal or generous. Ingratitude is base; sycophancy
          is vile; undue compliances are mean.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Base \Base\, n. [F. base, L. basis, fr. Gr. ba`sis a stepping,
   step, a base, pedestal, fr. bai`nein to go, step, akin to E.
   come. Cf. {Basis}, and see {Come}.]
   1. The bottom of anything, considered as its support, or that
      on which something rests for support; the foundation; as,
      the base of a statue. ``The base of mighty mountains.''
      --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: The fundamental or essential part of a thing; the
      essential principle; a groundwork.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.)
      (a) The lower part of a wall, pier, or column, when
          treated as a separate feature, usually in projection,
          or especially ornamented.
      (b) The lower part of a complete architectural design, as
          of a monument; also, the lower part of any elaborate
          piece of furniture or decoration.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bot.) That extremity of a leaf, fruit, etc., at which it
      is attached to its support.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Chem.) The positive, or non-acid component of a salt; a
      substance which, combined with an acid, neutralizes the
      latter and forms a salt; -- applied also to the hydroxides
      of the positive elements or radicals, and to certain
      organic bodies resembling them in their property of
      forming salts with acids.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Pharmacy) The chief ingredient in a compound.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Dyeing) A substance used as a mordant. --Ure.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Fort.) The exterior side of the polygon, or that
      imaginary line which connects the salient angles of two
      adjacent bastions.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Geom.) The line or surface constituting that part of a
      figure on which it is supposed to stand.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Math.) The number from which a mathematical table is
       constructed; as, the base of a system of logarithms.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. [See {Base} low.] A low, or deep, sound. (Mus.)
       (a) The lowest part; the deepest male voice.
       (b) One who sings, or the instrument which plays, base.
           [Now commonly written {bass}.]
           [1913 Webster]

                 The trebles squeak for fear, the bases roar.
                                                  --Dryden.
           [1913 Webster]

   12. (Mil.) A place or tract of country, protected by
       fortifications, or by natural advantages, from which the
       operations of an army proceed, forward movements are
       made, supplies are furnished, etc.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Mil.) The smallest kind of cannon. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Zo["o]l.) That part of an organ by which it is attached
       to another more central organ.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Crystallog.) The basal plane of a crystal.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. (Geol.) The ground mass of a rock, especially if not
       distinctly crystalline.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Her.) The lower part of the field. See {Escutcheon}.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. The housing of a horse. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

   19. pl. A kind of skirt (often of velvet or brocade, but
       sometimes of mailed armor) which hung from the middle to
       about the knees, or lower. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

   20. The lower part of a robe or petticoat. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

   21. An apron. [Obs.] ``Bakers in their linen bases.''
       --Marston.
       [1913 Webster]

   22. The point or line from which a start is made; a starting
       place or a goal in various games.
       [1913 Webster]

             To their appointed base they went.   --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   23. (Surv.) A line in a survey which, being accurately
       determined in length and position, serves as the origin
       from which to compute the distances and positions of any
       points or objects connected with it by a system of
       triangles. --Lyman.
       [1913 Webster]

   24. A rustic play; -- called also {prisoner's base}, {prison
       base}, or {bars}. ``To run the country base.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   25. (Baseball) Any one of the four bounds which mark the
       circuit of the infield.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Altern base}. See under {Altern}.

   {Attic base}. (Arch.) See under {Attic}.

   {Base course}. (Arch.)
       (a) The first or lower course of a foundation wall, made
           of large stones or a mass of concrete; -- called also
           {foundation course}.
       (b) The architectural member forming the transition
           between the basement and the wall above.

   {Base hit} (Baseball), a hit, by which the batsman, without
      any error on the part of his opponents, is able to reach
      the first base without being put out.

   {Base line}.
       (a) A main line taken as a base, as in surveying or in
           military operations.
       (b) A line traced round a cannon at the rear of the vent.
           

   {Base plate}, the foundation plate of heavy machinery, as of
      the steam engine; the bed plate.

   {Base ring} (Ordnance), a projecting band of metal around the
      breech, connected with the body of the gun by a concave
      molding. --H. L. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bass \Bass\, v. t.
   To sound in a deep tone. [R.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bass \Bass\, n. [A corruption of bast.]
   1. (Bot.) The linden or lime tree, sometimes wrongly called
      {whitewood}; also, its bark, which is used for making
      mats. See {Bast}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Pron. ?) A hassock or thick mat.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bass \Bass\ (b[=a]s), n. [F. basse, fr. bas low. See {Base}, a.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A bass, or deep, sound or tone.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mus.)
      (a) The lowest part in a musical composition.
      (b) One who sings, or the instrument which plays, bass.
          [Written also {base}.]
          [1913 Webster]

   {Thorough bass}. See {Thorough bass}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bass \Bass\ (b[.a]s), n.; pl. {Bass}, and sometimes {Basses}
   (b[.a]s"[e^]z). [A corruption of barse.] (Zo["o]l.)
   1. An edible, spiny-finned fish, esp. of the genera {Roccus},
      {Labrax}, and related genera. There are many species.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The common European bass is {Labrax lupus}. American
         species are: the striped bass ({Roccus lineatus});
         white or silver bass of the lakes ({Roccus chrysops});
         brass or yellow bass ({Roccus interruptus}).
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The two American fresh-water species of black bass (genus
      {Micropterus}). See {Black bass}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Species of {Serranus}, the sea bass and rock bass. See
      {Sea bass}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The southern, red, or channel bass ({Sci[ae]na ocellata}).
      See {Redfish}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The name is also applied to many other fishes. See
         {Calico bass}, under {Calico}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bass \Bass\ (b[.a]s), n.; pl. {Bass}, and sometimes {Basses}
   (b[.a]s"[e^]z). [A corruption of barse.] (Zo["o]l.)
   1. An edible, spiny-finned fish, esp. of the genera {Roccus},
      {Labrax}, and related genera. There are many species.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The common European bass is {Labrax lupus}. American
         species are: the striped bass ({Roccus lineatus});
         white or silver bass of the lakes ({Roccus chrysops});
         brass or yellow bass ({Roccus interruptus}).
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The two American fresh-water species of black bass (genus
      {Micropterus}). See {Black bass}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Species of {Serranus}, the sea bass and rock bass. See
      {Sea bass}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The southern, red, or channel bass ({Sci[ae]na ocellata}).
      See {Redfish}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The name is also applied to many other fishes. See
         {Calico bass}, under {Calico}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bass \Bass\, a.
   Deep or grave in tone.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Bass clef} (Mus.), the character placed at the beginning of
      the staff containing the bass part of a musical
      composition. [See Illust. under {Clef}.]

   {Bass voice}, a deep-sounding voice; a voice fitted for
      singing bass.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bass
     adj : having or denoting a low vocal or instrumental range; "a
           deep voice"; "a bass voice is lower than a baritone
           voice"; "a bass clarinet" [syn: {deep}]
     n 1: the lowest part of the musical range
     2: the lowest part in polyphonic music [syn: {bass part}]
     3: an adult male singer with the lowest voice [syn: {basso}]
     4: the lean flesh of a saltwater fish of the family Serranidae
        [syn: {sea bass}]
     5: any of various North American freshwater fish with lean
        flesh (especially of the genus Micropterus) [syn: {freshwater
        bass}]
     6: the lowest adult male singing voice [syn: {bass voice}, {basso}]
     7: the member with the lowest range of a family of musical
        instruments
     8: nontechnical name for any of numerous edible marine and
        freshwater spiny-finned fishes
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
