<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bastard</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bastard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bastard
   In the Old Testament the rendering of the Hebrew word _mamzer'_,
   which means "polluted." In Deut. 23:2, it occurs in the ordinary
   sense of illegitimate offspring. In Zech. 9:6, the word is used
   in the sense of foreigner. From the history of Jephthah we learn
   that there were bastard offspring among the Jews (Judg. 11:1-7).
   In Heb. 12:8, the word (Gr. nothoi) is used in its ordinary
   sense, and denotes those who do not share the privileges of
   God's children.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bastard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bastard \Bas"tard\, a.
   1. Begotten and born out of lawful matrimony; illegitimate.
      See {Bastard}, n., note.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Lacking in genuineness; spurious; false; adulterate; --
      applied to things which resemble those which are genuine,
      but are really not so.
      [1913 Webster]

            That bastard self-love which is so vicious in
            itself, and productive of so many vices. --Barrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Of an unusual or irregular make or proportion; as, a
      bastard musket; a bastard culverin. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Print.) Abbreviated, as the half title in a page
      preceding the full title page of a book.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bastard ashlar} (Arch.), stones for ashlar work, roughly
      squared at the quarry.

   {Bastard file}, a file intermediate between the coarsest and
      the second cut.

   {Bastard type} (Print.), type having the face of a larger or
      a smaller size than the body; e. g., a nonpareil face on a
      brevier body.

   {Bastard wing} (Zo["o]l.), three to five quill feathers on a
      small joint corresponding to the thumb in some mammalia;
      the alula.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bastard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bastard \Bas"tard\, n. [OF. bastard, bastart, F. b?tard, prob.
   fr. OF. bast, F. b?t, a packsaddle used as a bed by the
   muleteers (fr. LL. bastum) + -ard. OF. fils de bast son of
   the packsaddle; as the muleteers were accustomed to use their
   saddles for beds in the inns. See Cervantes, ``Don Quixote,''
   chap. 16; and cf. G. bankert, fr. bank bench.]
   1. A ``natural'' child; a child begotten and born out of
      wedlock; an illegitimate child; one born of an illicit
      union.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: By the civil and canon laws, and by the laws of many of
         the United States, a bastard becomes a legitimate child
         by the intermarriage of the parents at any subsequent
         time. But by those of England, and of some states of
         the United States, a child, to be legitimate, must at
         least be born after the lawful marriage. --Kent.
         Blackstone.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Sugar Refining)
      (a) An inferior quality of soft brown sugar, obtained from
          the sirups that have already had several boilings.
      (b) A large size of mold, in which sugar is drained.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. A sweet Spanish wine like muscatel in flavor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Brown bastard is your only drink.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A writing paper of a particular size. See {Paper}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bastard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bastard \Bas"tard\, v. t.
   To bastardize. [Obs.] --Bacon.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bastard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cod \Cod\, n. [Cf. G. gadde, and (in Heligoland) gadden, L.
   gadus merlangus.] (Zo["o]l.)
   An important edible fish ({Gadus morrhua}), taken in immense
   numbers on the northern coasts of Europe and America. It is
   especially abundant and large on the Grand Bank of
   Newfoundland. It is salted and dried in large quantities.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: There are several varieties; as {shore cod}, from
         shallow water; {bank cod}, from the distant banks; and
         {rock cod}, which is found among ledges, and is often
         dark brown or mottled with red. The {tomcod} is a
         distinct species of small size. The {bastard}, {blue},
         {buffalo}, or {cultus cod} of the Pacific coast belongs
         to a distinct family. See {Buffalo cod}, under
         {Buffalo}.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Cod fishery}, the business of fishing for cod.

   {Cod line}, an eighteen-thread line used in catching codfish.
      --McElrath.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bastard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bastard
     adj 1: born out of wedlock; "the dominions of both rulers passed
            away to their spurious or doubtful offspring"-
            E.A.Freeman [syn: {bastardly}, {misbegot}, {misbegotten},
             {spurious}]
     2: fraudulent; having a misleading appearance [syn: {bogus}, {fake},
         {phony}, {phoney}]
     n 1: insulting terms of address for people who are stupid or
          irritating or ridiculous [syn: {asshole}, {cocksucker},
          {dickhead}, {shit}, {mother fucker}, {motherfucker}, {prick},
           {whoreson}, {son of a bitch}, {SOB}]
     2: the illegitimate offspring of unmarried parents [syn: {by-blow},
         {love child}, {illegitimate child}, {illegitimate}, {whoreson}]
     3: derogatory term for a variation that is not genuine;
        something irregular or inferior or of dubious origin; "the
        architecture was a kind of bastard suggesting Gothic but
        not true Gothic" [syn: {mongrel}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
