<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>baths</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>baths</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Baths
   The use of the bath was very frequent among the Hebrews (Lev.
   14:8; Num. 19:19, ect.). The high priest at his inauguration
   (Lev. 8:6), and on the day of atonement, was required to bathe
   himself (16:4, 24). The "pools" mentioned in Neh. 3:15, 16, 2
   Kings 20:20, Isa. 22:11, John 9:7, were public bathing-places.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>baths</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bath \Bath\ (b[.a]th; 61), n.; pl. {Baths} (b[.a][th]z). [AS.
   b[ae][eth]; akin to OS. &amp; Icel. ba[eth], Sw., Dan., D., &amp; G.
   bad, and perh. to G. b["a]hen to foment.]
   1. The act of exposing the body, or part of the body, for
      purposes of cleanliness, comfort, health, etc., to water,
      vapor, hot air, or the like; as, a cold or a hot bath; a
      medicated bath; a steam bath; a hip bath.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Water or other liquid for bathing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A receptacle or place where persons may immerse or wash
      their bodies in water.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A building containing an apartment or a series of
      apartments arranged for bathing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Among the ancients, the public baths were of amazing
            extent and magnificence.              --Gwilt.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Chem.) A medium, as heated sand, ashes, steam, hot air,
      through which heat is applied to a body.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Photog.) A solution in which plates or prints are
      immersed; also, the receptacle holding the solution.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Bath is used adjectively or in combination, in an
         obvious sense of or for baths or bathing; as, bathroom,
         bath tub, bath keeper.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Douche bath}. See {Douche}.

   {Order of the Bath}, a high order of British knighthood,
      composed of three classes, viz., knights grand cross,
      knights commanders, and knights companions, abbreviated
      thus: G. C. B., K. C. B., K. B.

   {Russian bath}, a kind of vapor bath which consists in a
      prolonged exposure of the body to the influence of the
      steam of water, followed by washings and shampooings.

   {Turkish bath}, a kind of bath in which a profuse
      perspiration is produced by hot air, after which the body
      is washed and shampooed.

   {Bath house}, a house used for the purpose of bathing; --
      also a small house, near a bathing place, where a bather
      undresses and dresses.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
