<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bath</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BATH, n.  A kind of mystic ceremony substituted for religious worship,
with what spiritual efficacy has not been determined.

    The man who taketh a steam bath
    He loseth all the skin he hath,
    And, for he's boiled a brilliant red,
    Thinketh to cleanliness he's wed,
    Forgetting that his lungs he's soiling
    With dirty vapors of the boiling.
                                                          Richard Gwow


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bath
   a Hebrew liquid measure, the tenth part of an homer (1 Kings
   7:26, 38; Ezek. 45:10, 14). It contained 8 gallons 3 quarts of
   our measure. "Ten acres of vineyard shall yield one bath" (Isa.
   5:10) denotes great unproductiveness.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bath, IL (village, FIPS 4156)
  Location: 40.19113 N, 90.14238 W
  Population (1990): 388 (216 housing units)
  Area: 0.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Bath, IN
  Zip code(s): 47010
Bath, ME (city, FIPS 3355)
  Location: 43.93807 N, 69.83742 W
  Population (1990): 9799 (4236 housing units)
  Area: 23.7 sq km (land), 10.6 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 04530
Bath, MI
  Zip code(s): 48808
Bath, NC (town, FIPS 3840)
  Location: 35.46541 N, 76.81506 W
  Population (1990): 154 (108 housing units)
  Area: 0.8 sq km (land), 1.6 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 27808
Bath, NH
  Zip code(s): 03740
Bath, NY (village, FIPS 4759)
  Location: 42.33700 N, 77.31843 W
  Population (1990): 5801 (2640 housing units)
  Area: 7.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Bath, PA (borough, FIPS 4432)
  Location: 40.72758 N, 75.39179 W
  Population (1990): 2358 (914 housing units)
  Area: 2.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 18014
Bath, SD
  Zip code(s): 57427
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bath \Bath\ (b[.a]th; 61), n.; pl. {Baths} (b[.a][th]z). [AS.
   b[ae][eth]; akin to OS. &amp; Icel. ba[eth], Sw., Dan., D., &amp; G.
   bad, and perh. to G. b["a]hen to foment.]
   1. The act of exposing the body, or part of the body, for
      purposes of cleanliness, comfort, health, etc., to water,
      vapor, hot air, or the like; as, a cold or a hot bath; a
      medicated bath; a steam bath; a hip bath.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Water or other liquid for bathing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A receptacle or place where persons may immerse or wash
      their bodies in water.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A building containing an apartment or a series of
      apartments arranged for bathing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Among the ancients, the public baths were of amazing
            extent and magnificence.              --Gwilt.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Chem.) A medium, as heated sand, ashes, steam, hot air,
      through which heat is applied to a body.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Photog.) A solution in which plates or prints are
      immersed; also, the receptacle holding the solution.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Bath is used adjectively or in combination, in an
         obvious sense of or for baths or bathing; as, bathroom,
         bath tub, bath keeper.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Douche bath}. See {Douche}.

   {Order of the Bath}, a high order of British knighthood,
      composed of three classes, viz., knights grand cross,
      knights commanders, and knights companions, abbreviated
      thus: G. C. B., K. C. B., K. B.

   {Russian bath}, a kind of vapor bath which consists in a
      prolonged exposure of the body to the influence of the
      steam of water, followed by washings and shampooings.

   {Turkish bath}, a kind of bath in which a profuse
      perspiration is produced by hot air, after which the body
      is washed and shampooed.

   {Bath house}, a house used for the purpose of bathing; --
      also a small house, near a bathing place, where a bather
      undresses and dresses.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bath \Bath\, n. [Heb.]
   A Hebrew measure containing the tenth of a homer, or five
   gallons and three pints, as a measure for liquids; and two
   pecks and five quarts, as a dry measure.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bath \Bath\, n.
   A city in the west of England, resorted to for its hot
   springs, which has given its name to various objects.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Bath brick}, a preparation of calcareous earth, in the form
      of a brick, used for cleaning knives, polished metal, etc.
      

   {Bath chair}, a kind of chair on wheels, as used by invalids
      at Bath. ``People walked out, or drove out, or were pushed
      out in their Bath chairs.'' --Dickens.

   {Bath metal}, an alloy consisting of four and a half ounces
      of zinc and one pound of copper.

   {Bath note}, a folded writing paper, 8 1/2 by 14 inches.

   {Bath stone}, a species of limestone (o["o]lite) found near
      Bath, used for building.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bath
     n 1: a vessel containing liquid in which something is immersed
          (as to process it or to maintain it at a constant
          temperature or to lubricate it); "she soaked the etching
          in an acid bath"
     2: you soak your body in a bathtub; "he has a good bath every
        morning"
     3: a relatively large open container that you fill with water
        and use to wash the body [syn: {bathtub}, {bathing tub}, {tub}]
     4: an ancient Hebrew liquid measure equal to about 10 gallons
     5: a town in southwestern England on the River Avon; famous for
        its hot springs and Roman remains
     6: a room (as in a residence) containing a bath or shower and
        usually a washbasin and toilet [syn: {bathroom}]
     v : clean one's body by immersion into water; "The child should
         bathe every day" [syn: {bathe}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
