<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>battle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>battle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BATTLE, n.  A method of untying with the teeth of a political knot
that would not yield to the tongue.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>battle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Battle \Bat"tle\, a.
   Fertile. See {Battel}, a. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>battle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Battle \Bat"tle\, n. [OE. bataille, bataile, F. bataille battle,
   OF., battle, battalion, fr. L. battalia, battualia, the
   fighting and fencing exercises of soldiers and gladiators,
   fr. batuere to strike, beat. Cf. {Battalia}, 1st {Battel},
   and see {Batter}, v. t. ]
   1. A general action, fight, or encounter, in which all the
      divisions of an army are or may be engaged; an engagement;
      a combat.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A struggle; a contest; as, the battle of life.
      [1913 Webster]

            The whole intellectual battle that had at its center
            the best poem of the best poet of that day. --H.
                                                  Morley.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A division of an army; a battalion. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The king divided his army into three battles.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cavalry, by way of distinction, was called the
            battle, and on it alone depended the fate of every
            action.                               --Robertson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The main body, as distinct from the van and rear;
      battalia. [Obs.] --Hayward.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Battle is used adjectively or as the first part of a
         self-explaining compound; as, battle brand, a ``brand''
         or sword used in battle; battle cry; battlefield;
         battle ground; battle array; battle song.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Battle piece}, a painting, or a musical composition,
      representing a battle.

   {Battle royal}.
      (a) A fight between several gamecocks, where the one that
          stands longest is the victor. --Grose.
      (b) A contest with fists or cudgels in which more than two
          are engaged; a m[^e]l['e]e. --Thackeray.

   {Drawn battle}, one in which neither party gains the victory.
      

   {To give battle}, to attack an enemy.

   {To join battle}, to meet the attack; to engage in battle.

   {Pitched battle}, one in which the armies are previously
      drawn up in form, with a regular disposition of the
      forces.

   {Wager of battle}. See under {Wager}, n.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Conflict; encounter; contest; action.

   Usage: {Battle}, {Combat}, {Fight}, {Engagement}. These words
          agree in denoting a close encounter between contending
          parties. Fight is a word of less dignity than the
          others. Except in poetry, it is more naturally applied
          to the encounter of a few individuals, and more
          commonly an accidental one; as, a street fight. A
          combat is a close encounter, whether between few or
          many, and is usually premeditated. A battle is
          commonly more general and prolonged. An engagement
          supposes large numbers on each side, engaged or
          intermingled in the conflict.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>battle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Battle \Bat"tle\ (b[a^]t"t'l), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Battled}
   (-tl'd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Battling}.] [F. batailler, fr.
   bataille. See {Battle}, n.]
   To join in battle; to contend in fight; as, to battle over
   theories.
   [1913 Webster]

         To meet in arms, and battle in the plain. --Prior.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>battle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Battle \Bat"tle\, v. t.
   To assail in battle; to fight.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>battle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>battle
     n 1: a hostile meeting of opposing military forces in the course
          of a war; "Grant won a decisive victory in the battle of
          Chickamauga"; "he lost his romantic ideas about war when
          he got into a real engagement" [syn: {conflict}, {fight},
           {engagement}]
     2: an energetic attempt to achieve something; "getting through
        the crowd was a real struggle"; "he fought a battle for
        recognition" [syn: {struggle}]
     3: an open clash between two opposing groups (or individuals);
        "the harder the conflict the more glorious the
        triumph"--Thomas Paine; "police tried to control the
        battle between the pro- and anti-abortion mobs" [syn: {conflict},
         {struggle}]
     v : battle or contend against in or as if in a battle; "The
         Kurds are combating Iraqi troops in Nothern Iraq"; "We
         must combat the prejudices against other races"; "they
         battled over the budget" [syn: {combat}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
