<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bead</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bead \Bead\ (b[=e]d), n. [OE. bede prayer, prayer bead, AS. bed,
   gebed, prayer; akin to D. bede, G. bitte, AS. biddan, to ask,
   bid, G. bitten to ask, and perh. to Gr. pei`qein to persuade,
   L. fidere to trust. Beads are used by the Roman Catholics to
   count their prayers, one bead being dropped down a string
   every time a prayer is said. Cf. Sp. cuenta bead, fr. contar
   to count. See {Bid}, in to bid beads, and {Bide}.]
   1. A prayer. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A little perforated ball, to be strung on a thread, and
      worn for ornament; or used in a rosary for counting
      prayers, as by Roman Catholics and Mohammedans, whence the
      phrases to tell beads,

   {to be at one's beads},

   {to bid beads}, etc., meaning, to be at prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any small globular body; as,
      (a) A bubble in spirits.
      (b) A drop of sweat or other liquid. ``Cold beads of
          midnight dew.'' --Wordsworth.
      (c) A small knob of metal on a firearm, used for taking
          aim (whence the expression to draw a bead, for, to
          take aim).
      (d) (Arch.) A small molding of rounded surface, the
          section being usually an arc of a circle. It may be
          continuous, or broken into short embossments.
      (e) (Chem.) A glassy drop of molten flux, as borax or
          microcosmic salt, used as a solvent and color test for
          several mineral earths and oxides, as of iron,
          manganese, etc., before the blowpipe; as, the borax
          bead; the iron bead, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Bead and butt} (Carp.), framing in which the panels are
      flush, having beads stuck or run upon the two edges.
      --Knight.

   {Bead mold}, a species of fungus or mold, the stems of which
      consist of single cells loosely jointed together so as to
      resemble a string of beads. [Written also {bead mould}.]
      

   {Bead tool}, a cutting tool, having an edge curved so as to
      make beads or beading.

   {Bead tree} (Bot.), a tree of the genus {Melia}, the best
      known species of which ({Melia azedarach}), has blue
      flowers which are very fragrant, and berries which are
      poisonous.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bead \Bead\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Beaded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Beading}.]
   To ornament with beads or beading.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bead \Bead\, v. i.
   To form beadlike bubbles.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bead
     n 1: a small ball with a hole through the middle
     2: a shape that is small and round; "he studied the shapes of
        low-viscosity drops"; "beads of sweat on his forehead"
        [syn: {drop}, {pearl}]
     3: a beaded molding for edging or decorating furniture [syn: {beading},
         {beadwork}, {astragal}]
     v 1: form into beads, as of water or sweat, for example
     2: decorate by sewing beads onto; "bead the wedding gown"
     3: string together like beads
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
