<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>beak</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beak</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Beak \Beak\ (b[=e]k), n. [OE. bek, F. bec, fr. Celtic; cf. Gael.
   &amp; Ir. bac, bacc, hook, W. bach.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The bill or nib of a bird, consisting of a horny
          sheath, covering the jaws. The form varies much
          according to the food and habits of the bird, and is
          largely used in the classification of birds.
      (b) A similar bill in other animals, as the turtles.
      (c) The long projecting sucking mouth of some insects, and
          other invertebrates, as in the Hemiptera.
      (d) The upper or projecting part of the shell, near the
          hinge of a bivalve.
      (e) The prolongation of certain univalve shells containing
          the canal.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything projecting or ending in a point, like a beak, as
      a promontory of land. --Carew.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Antiq.) A beam, shod or armed at the end with a metal
      head or point, and projecting from the prow of an ancient
      galley, in order to pierce the vessel of an enemy; a
      beakhead.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Naut.) That part of a ship, before the forecastle, which
      is fastened to the stem, and supported by the main knee.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Arch.) A continuous slight projection ending in an arris
      or narrow fillet; that part of a drip from which the water
      is thrown off.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Bot.) Any process somewhat like the beak of a bird,
      terminating the fruit or other parts of a plant.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Far.) A toe clip. See {Clip}, n. (Far.).
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A magistrate or policeman. [Slang, Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beak</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Clip \Clip\, n.
   1. An embrace. --Sir P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A cutting; a shearing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The product of a single shearing of sheep; a season's crop
      of wool.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A clasp or holder for letters, papers, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An embracing strap for holding parts together; the iron
      strap, with loop, at the ends of a whiffletree. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Far.) A projecting flange on the upper edge of a
      horseshoe, turned up so as to embrace the lower part of
      the hoof; -- called also {toe clip} and {beak}. --Youatt.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A blow or stroke with the hand; as, he hit him a clip.
      [Colloq. U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mach.) A part, attachment, or appendage, for seizing,
      clasping, or holding, an object, as a cable, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Angling) A gaff or hook for landing the fish, as in
      salmon fishing. [Scot. &amp; Prov. Eng.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. A rapid gait. ``A three-minute clip.'' --Kipling.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beak</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>beak
     n 1: beaklike mouth of animals other than birds (e.g., turtles)
     2: horny projecting mouth of a bird [syn: {bill}, {neb}, {nib},
         {pecker}]
     3: informal terms for the nose [syn: {honker}, {hooter}, {nozzle},
         {snoot}, {snout}, {schnozzle}, {schnoz}]
     v : hit lightly with a picking motion [syn: {peck}, {pick}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
