<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bed
   (Heb. mittah), for rest at night (Ex. 8:3; 1 Sam. 19:13, 15, 16,
   etc.); during sickness (Gen. 47:31; 48:2; 49:33, etc.); as a
   sofa for rest (1 Sam. 28:23; Amos 3:12). Another Hebrew word
   (er'es) so rendered denotes a canopied bed, or a bed with
   curtains (Deut. 3:11; Ps. 132:3), for sickness (Ps. 6:6; 41:3).
   
     In the New Testament it denotes sometimes a litter with a
   coverlet (Matt. 9:2, 6; Luke 5:18; Acts 5:15).
   
     The Jewish bedstead was frequently merely the divan or
   platform along the sides of the house, sometimes a very slight
   portable frame, sometimes only a mat or one or more quilts. The
   only material for bed-clothes is mentioned in 1 Sam. 19:13.
   Sleeping in the open air was not uncommon, the sleeper wrapping
   himself in his outer garment (Ex. 22:26,27; Deut. 24:12,13).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bed \Bed\, n. [AS. bed, bedd; akin to OS. bed, D. bed, bedde,
   Icel. be?r, Dan. bed, Sw. b["a]dd, Goth. badi, OHG. betti, G.
   bett, bette, bed, beet a plat of ground; all of uncertain
   origin.]
   1. An article of furniture to sleep or take rest in or on; a
      couch. Specifically: A sack or mattress, filled with some
      soft material, in distinction from the bedstead on which
      it is placed (as, a feather bed), or this with the
      bedclothes added. In a general sense, any thing or place
      used for sleeping or reclining on or in, as a quantity of
      hay, straw, leaves, or twigs.
      [1913 Webster]

            And made for him [a horse] a leafy bed. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

            I wash, wring, brew, bake, . . . make the beds.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In bed he slept not for my urging it. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Used as the symbol of matrimony) Marriage.
      [1913 Webster]

            George, the eldest son of his second bed.
                                                  --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A plat or level piece of ground in a garden, usually a
      little raised above the adjoining ground. ``Beds of
      hyacinth and roses.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A mass or heap of anything arranged like a bed; as, a bed
      of ashes or coals.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The bottom of a watercourse, or of any body of water; as,
      the bed of a river.
      [1913 Webster]

            So sinks the daystar in the ocean bed. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Geol.) A layer or seam, or a horizontal stratum between
      layers; as, a bed of coal, iron, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Gun.) See {Gun carriage}, and {Mortar bed}.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Masonry)
      (a) The horizontal surface of a building stone; as, the
          upper and lower beds.
      (b) A course of stone or brick in a wall.
      (c) The place or material in which a block or brick is
          laid.
      (d) The lower surface of a brick, slate, or tile.
          --Knight.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mech.) The foundation or the more solid and fixed part or
      framing of a machine; or a part on which something is laid
      or supported; as, the bed of an engine.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The superficial earthwork, or ballast, of a railroad.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Printing) The flat part of the press, on which the form
       is laid.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Bed is much used adjectively or in combination; as, bed
         key or bedkey; bed wrench or bedwrench; bedchamber;
         bedmaker, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Bed of justice} (French Hist.), the throne (F. lit bed)
      occupied by the king when sitting in one of his
      parliaments (judicial courts); hence, a session of a
      refractory parliament, at which the king was present for
      the purpose of causing his decrees to be registered.

   {To be brought to bed}, to be delivered of a child; -- often
      followed by of; as, to be brought to bed of a son.

   {To make a bed}, to prepare a bed; to arrange or put in order
      a bed and its bedding.

   {From bed and board} (Law), a phrase applied to a separation
      by partial divorce of man and wife, without dissolving the
      bonds of matrimony. If such a divorce (now commonly called
      a judicial separation) be granted at the instance of the
      wife, she may have alimony.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bed \Bed\, v. i.
   To go to bed; to cohabit.
   [1913 Webster]

         If he be married, and bed with his wife. --Wiseman.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bed \Bed\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bedded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bedding}.]
   1. To place in a bed. [Obs.] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make partaker of one's bed; to cohabit with.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll to the Tuscan wars, and never bed her. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To furnish with a bed or bedding.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To plant or arrange in beds; to set, or cover, as in a bed
      of soft earth; as, to bed the roots of a plant in mold.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To lay or put in any hollow place, or place of rest and
      security, surrounded or inclosed; to embed; to furnish
      with or place upon a bed or foundation; as, to bed a
      stone; it was bedded on a rock.
      [1913 Webster]

            Among all chains or clusters of mountains where
            large bodies of still water are bedded.
                                                  --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Masonry) To dress or prepare the surface of stone) so as
      to serve as a bed.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To lay flat; to lay in order; to place in a horizontal or
      recumbent position. ``Bedded hair.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BED
     Bookmark Exploring Dabbler (VRML)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bed
     n 1: a piece of furniture that provides a place to sleep; "he sat
          on the edge of the bed"; "the room had only a bed and
          chair"
     2: a plot of ground in which plants are growing; "the gardener
        planted a bed of roses"
     3: a depression forming the ground under a body of water; "he
        searched for treasure on the ocean bed" [syn: {bottom}]
     4: (geology) a stratum of rock (especially sedimentary rock);
        "they found a bed of standstone"
     5: a stratum of ore or coal thick enough to be mined with
        profit; "he worked in the coal beds" [syn: {seam}]
     6: single thickness of usually some homogeneous substance;
        "slices of hard-boiled egg on a bed of spinach" [syn: {layer}]
     7: the flat surface of a printing press on which the type form
        is laid in the last stage of producing a newspaper or
        magazine or book etc.
     8: a foundation of earth or rock supporting a road or railroad
        track; "the track bed had washed away"
     v 1: furnish with a bed; "The inn keeper could bed all the new
          arrivals"
     2: place (plants) in a prepared bed of soil
     3: put to bed; "The children were bedded at ten o'clock"
     4: have sexual intercourse with; "This student sleeps with
        everyone in her dorm"; "Adam knew Eve"; "Were you ever
        intimate with this man?" [syn: {roll in the hay}, {love},
        {make out}, {make love}, {sleep with}, {get laid}, {have
        sex}, {know}, {do it}, {be intimate}, {have intercourse},
        {have it away}, {have it off}, {screw}, {fuck}, {jazz}, {eff},
         {hump}, {lie with}, {have a go at it}, {bang}, {get it on},
         {bonk}]
     5: go to bed in order to sleep; "I usually turn in at
        midnight"; "He turns out at the crack of dawn" [syn: {go
        to bed}, {turn in}, {crawl in}, {kip down}, {hit the hay},
         {hit the sack}, {sack out}, {go to sleep}, {retire}]
        [ant: {get up}, {get up}]
     [also: {bedding}, {bedded}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
