<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>beg</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BEG, v.  To ask for something with an earnestness proportioned to the
belief that it will not be given.

    Who is that, father?

                          A mendicant, child,
    Haggard, morose, and unaffable -- wild!
    See how he glares through the bars of his cell!
    With Citizen Mendicant all is not well.

    Why did they put him there, father?

                                         Because
    Obeying his belly he struck at the laws.

    His belly?

                Oh, well, he was starving, my boy --
    A state in which, doubtless, there's little of joy.
    No bite had he eaten for days, and his cry
    Was "Bread!" ever "Bread!"

                                What's the matter with pie?

    With little to wear, he had nothing to sell;
    To beg was unlawful -- improper as well.

    Why didn't he work?

                         He would even have done that,
    But men said:  "Get out!" and the State remarked:  "Scat!"
    I mention these incidents merely to show
    That the vengeance he took was uncommonly low.
    Revenge, at the best, is the act of a Siou,
    But for trifles --

                        Pray what did bad Mendicant do?

    Stole two loaves of bread to replenish his lack
    And tuck out the belly that clung to his back.

    Is that _all_ father dear?

                                There's little to tell:
    They sent him to jail, and they'll send him to -- well,
    The company's better than here we can boast,
    And there's --

                    Bread for the needy, dear father?

                                                       Um -- toast.
                                                              Atka Mip


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Beg
   That the poor existed among the Hebrews we have abundant
   evidence (Ex. 23:11; Deut. 15:11), but there is no mention of
   beggars properly so called in the Old Testament. The poor were
   provided for by the law of Moses (Lev. 19:10; Deut. 12:12;
   14:29). It is predicted of the seed of the wicked that they
   shall be beggars (Ps. 37:25; 109:10).
   
     In the New Testament we find not seldom mention made of
   beggars (Mark 10:46; Luke 16:20, 21; Acts 3:2), yet there is no
   mention of such a class as vagrant beggars, so numerous in the
   East. "Beggarly," in Gal. 4:9, means worthless.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BEG
     
        {Back End Generator}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Beg \Beg\, n. [Turk. beg, pronounced bay. Cf. {Bey}, {Begum}.]
   A title of honor in Turkey and in some other parts of the
   East; a bey.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Beg \Beg\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Begged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Begging}.] [OE. beggen, perh. fr. AS. bedecian (akin to
   Goth. bedagwa beggar), biddan to ask. (Cf. {Bid}, v. t.); or
   cf. beghard, beguin.]
   1. To ask earnestly for; to entreat or supplicate for; to
      beseech.
      [1913 Webster]

            I do beg your good will in this case. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            [Joseph] begged the body of Jesus.    --Matt. xxvii.
                                                  58.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Sometimes implying deferential and respectful, rather
         than earnest, asking; as, I beg your pardon; I beg
         leave to disagree with you.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To ask for as a charity, esp. to ask for habitually or
      from house to house.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet have I not seen the righteous forsaken, nor his
            seed begging bread.                   --Ps. xxxvii.
                                                  25.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make petition to; to entreat; as, to beg a person to
      grant a favor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To take for granted; to assume without proof.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Old Law) To ask to be appointed guardiln for, or to aso
      to havo a guardian appointed for.
      [1913 Webster]

            Else some will beg thee, in the court of wards.
                                                  --Harrington.
      [1913 Webster] Hence:

   {To beg (one) for a fool}, to take him for a fool.
      [1913 Webster]

   {I beg to}, is an elliptical expression for I beg leave to;
      as, I beg to inform you.

   {To beg the question}, to assume that which was to be proved
      in a discussion, instead of adducing the proof or
      sustaining the point by argument.

   {To go a-begging}, a figurative phrase to express the absence
      of demand for something which elsewhere brings a price;
      as, grapes are so plentiful there that they go a-begging.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To {Beg}, {Ask}, {Request}.

   Usage: To ask (not in the sense of inquiring) is the generic
          term which embraces all these words. To request is
          only a polite mode of asking. To beg, in its original
          sense, was to ask with earnestness, and implied
          submission, or at least deference. At present,
          however, in polite life, beg has dropped its original
          meaning, and has taken the place of both ask and
          request, on the ground of its expressing more of
          deference and respect. Thus, we beg a person's
          acceptance of a present; we beg him to favor us with
          his company; a tradesman begs to announce the arrival
          of new goods, etc. Crabb remarks that, according to
          present usage, ``we can never talk of asking a
          person's acceptance of a thing, or of asking him to do
          us a favor.'' This can be more truly said of usage in
          England than in America.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Beg \Beg\, v. i.
   To ask alms or charity, especially to ask habitually by the
   wayside or from house to house; to live by asking alms.
   [1913 Webster]

         I can not dig; to beg I am ashamed.      --Luke xvi. 3.
   [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>beg
     v 1: call upon in supplication; entreat; "I beg you to stop!"
          [syn: {implore}, {pray}]
     2: make a solicitation or entreaty for something; request
        urgently or persistently; "Henry IV solicited the Pope for
        a divorce"; "My neighbor keeps soliciting money for
        different charities" [syn: {solicit}, {tap}]
     3: ask to obtain free; "beg money and food"
     [also: {begging}, {begged}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
