<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bend</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bend, OR (city, FIPS 5800)
  Location: 44.06605 N, 121.31105 W
  Population (1990): 20469 (9004 housing units)
  Area: 34.8 sq km (land), 0.4 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 97701, 97702
Bend, TX
  Zip code(s): 76824
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ordinary \Or"di*na*ry\, n.; pl. {Ordinaries} (-r[i^]z).
   1. (Law)
      (a) (Roman Law) An officer who has original jurisdiction
          in his own right, and not by deputation.
      (b) (Eng. Law) One who has immediate jurisdiction in
          matters ecclesiastical; an ecclesiastical judge; also,
          a deputy of the bishop, or a clergyman appointed to
          perform divine service for condemned criminals and
          assist in preparing them for death.
      (c) (Am. Law) A judicial officer, having generally the
          powers of a judge of probate or a surrogate.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. The mass; the common run. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I see no more in you than in the ordinary
            Of nature's salework.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is so common, or continued, as to be considered
      a settled establishment or institution. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Spain had no other wars save those which were grown
            into an ordinary.                     --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything which is in ordinary or common use.
      [1913 Webster]

            Water buckets, wagons, cart wheels, plow socks, and
            other ordinaries.                     --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A dining room or eating house where a meal is prepared for
      all comers, at a fixed price for the meal, in distinction
      from one where each dish is separately charged; a table
      d'h[^o]te; hence, also, the meal furnished at such a
      dining room. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the odd words they have picked up in a
            coffeehouse, or a gaming ordinary, are produced as
            flowers of style.                     --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            He exacted a tribute for licenses to hawkers and
            peddlers and to ordinaries.           --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Her.) A charge or bearing of simple form, one of nine or
      ten which are in constant use. The {bend}, {chevron},
      {chief}, {cross}, {fesse}, {pale}, and {saltire} are
      uniformly admitted as ordinaries. Some authorities include
      bar, bend sinister, pile, and others. See {Subordinary}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In ordinary}.
      (a) In actual and constant service; statedly attending and
          serving; as, a physician or chaplain in ordinary. An
          ambassador in ordinary is one constantly resident at a
          foreign court.
      (b) (Naut.) Out of commission and laid up; -- said of a
          naval vessel.

   {Ordinary of the Mass} (R. C. Ch.), the part of the Mass
      which is the same every day; -- called also the {canon of
      the Mass}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bend \Bend\, v. i.
   1. To be moved or strained out of a straight line; to crook
      or be curving; to bow.
      [1913 Webster]

            The green earth's end
            Where the bowed welkin slow doth bend. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To jut over; to overhang.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is a cliff, whose high and bending head
            Looks fearfully in the confined deep. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be inclined; to be directed.
      [1913 Webster]

            To whom our vows and wished bend.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To bow in prayer, or in token of submission.
      [1913 Webster]

            While each to his great Father bends. --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bend \Bend\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bended} or {Bent}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Bending}.] [AS. bendan to bend, fr. bend a band,
   bond, fr. bindan to bind. See {Bind}, v. t., and cf. 3d &amp; 4th
   {Bend}.]
   1. To strain or move out of a straight line; to crook by
      straining; to make crooked; to curve; to make ready for
      use by drawing into a curve; as, to bend a bow; to bend
      the knee.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To turn toward some certain point; to direct; to incline.
      ``Bend thine ear to supplication.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Towards Coventry bend we our course.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bending her eyes . . . upon her parent. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To apply closely or with interest; to direct.
      [1913 Webster]

            To bend his mind to any public business. --Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

            But when to mischief mortals bend their will.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cause to yield; to render submissive; to subdue.
      ``Except she bend her humor.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) To fasten, as one rope to another, or as a sail to
      its yard or stay; or as a cable to the ring of an anchor.
      --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To bend the brow}, to knit the brow, as in deep thought or
      in anger; to scowl; to frown. --Camden.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To lean; stoop; deflect; bow; yield.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bend \Bend\, n. [See {Bend}, v. t., and cf. {Bent}, n.]
   1. A turn or deflection from a straight line or from the
      proper direction or normal position; a curve; a crook; as,
      a slight bend of the body; a bend in a road.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Turn; purpose; inclination; ends. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Farewell, poor swain; thou art not for my bend.
                                                  --Fletcher.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) A knot by which one rope is fastened to another or
      to an anchor, spar, or post. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Leather Trade) The best quality of sole leather; a butt.
      See {Butt}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mining) Hard, indurated clay; bind.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. pl. (Med.) same as {caisson disease}. Usually referred to
      as {the bends}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bends of a ship}, the thickest and strongest planks in her
      sides, more generally called wales. They have the beams,
      knees, and foothooks bolted to them. Also, the frames or
      ribs that form the ship's body from the keel to the top of
      the sides; as, the midship bend.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bend \Bend\, n. [AS. bend. See {Band}, and cf. the preceding
   noun.]
   1. A band. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [OF. bende, bande, F. bande. See {Band}.] (Her.) One of
      the honorable ordinaries, containing a third or a fifth
      part of the field. It crosses the field diagonally from
      the dexter chief to the sinister base.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bend sinister} (Her.), an honorable ordinary drawn from the
      sinister chief to the dexter base.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bend
     n 1: a circular segment of a curve; "a bend in the road"; "a
          crook in the path" [syn: {crook}, {turn}]
     2: movement that causes the formation of a curve [syn: {bending}]
     3: curved segment (of a road or river or railroad track etc.)
        [syn: {curve}]
     4: an angular or rounded shape made by folding; "a fold in the
        napkin"; "a crease in his trousers"; "a plication on her
        blouse"; "a flexure of the colon"; "a bend of his elbow"
        [syn: {fold}, {crease}, {plication}, {flexure}, {crimp}]
     5: a town in central Oregon at the eastern foot of the Cascade
        Range
     6: diagonal line traversing a shield from the upper right
        corner to the lower left [syn: {bend dexter}]
     v 1: form a curve; "The stick does not bend" [syn: {flex}] [ant:
          {straighten}]
     2: change direction; "The road bends"
     3: cause (a plastic object) to assume a crooked or angular
        form; "bend the rod"; "twist the dough into a braid"; "the
        strong man could turn an iron bar" [syn: {flex}, {deform},
         {twist}, {turn}] [ant: {unbend}]
     4: bend one's back forward from the waist on down; "he crouched
        down"; "She bowed before the Queen"; "The young man
        stooped to pick up the girl's purse" [syn: {crouch}, {stoop},
         {bow}]
     5: turn from a straight course , fixed direction, or line of
        interest [syn: {deflect}, {turn away}]
     6: bend a joint; "flex your wrists"; "bend your knees" [syn: {flex}]
     [also: {bent}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
