<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>beside</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beside</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Beside \Be*side"\, prep. [OE. biside, bisiden, bisides, prep.
   and adv., beside, besides; pref. be- by + side. Cf. Besides,
   and see {Side}, n.]
   1. At the side of; on one side of. ``Beside him hung his
      bow.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Aside from; out of the regular course or order of; in a
      state of deviation from; out of.
      [1913 Webster]

            [You] have done enough
            To put him quite beside his patience. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Over and above; distinct from; in addition to.

   Note: [In this use besides is now commoner.]
         [1913 Webster]

               Wise and learned men beside those whose names are
               in the Christian records.          --Addison.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To be beside one's self}, to be out of one's wits or senses.
      [1913 Webster]

            Paul, thou art beside thyself.        --Acts xxvi.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: {Beside}, {Besides}.

   Usage: These words, whether used as prepositions or adverbs,
          have been considered strictly synonymous, from an
          early period of our literature, and have been freely
          interchanged by our best writers. There is, however, a
          tendency, in present usage, to make the following
          distinction between them: 1. That beside be used only
          and always as a preposition, with the original meaning
          ``by the side of; '' as, to sit beside a fountain; or
          with the closely allied meaning ``aside from'',
          ``apart from'', or ``out of''; as, this is beside our
          present purpose; to be beside one's self with joy. The
          adverbial sense to be wholly transferred to the
          cognate word. 2. That besides, as a preposition, take
          the remaining sense ``in addition to'', as, besides
          all this; besides the considerations here offered.
          ``There was a famine in the land besides the first
          famine.'' --Gen. xxvi. 1. And that it also take the
          adverbial sense of ``moreover'', ``beyond'', etc.,
          which had been divided between the words; as, besides,
          there are other considerations which belong to this
          case. The following passages may serve to illustrate
          this use of the words:

                Lovely Thais sits beside thee.    --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

                Only be patient till we have appeased
                The multitude, beside themselves with fear.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                It is beside my present business to enlarge on
                this speculation.                 --Locke.
          [1913 Webster]

                Besides this, there are persons in certain
                situations who are expected to be charitable.
                                                  --Bp. Porteus.
          [1913 Webster]

                And, besides, the Moor
                May unfold me to him; there stand I in much
                peril.                            --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                That man that does not know those things which
                are of necessity for him to know is but an
                ignorant man, whatever he may know besides.
                                                  --Tillotson.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: See {Moreover}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>beside</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Besides \Be*sides"\, Beside \Be*side"\, adv. [OE. Same as
   beside, prep.; the ending -s is an adverbial one, prop. a
   genitive sign.]
   1. On one side. [Obs.] --Chaucer. Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. More than that; over and above; not included in the
      number, or in what has been mentioned; moreover; in
      addition.
      [1913 Webster]

            The men said unto Lot, Hast thou here any besides ?
                                                  --Gen. xix.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            To all beside, as much an empty shade,
            An Eugene living, as a C[ae]sar dead. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: These sentences may be considered as elliptical.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
