<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>between</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>between</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Between, GA (town, FIPS 7640)
  Location: 33.81305 N, 83.80891 W
  Population (1990): 82 (36 housing units)
  Area: 2.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>between</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Between \Be*tween"\, n.
   Intermediate time or space; interval. [Poetic &amp; R.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>between</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Between \Be*tween"\, prep. [OE. bytwene, bitweonen, AS.
   betwe['o]nan, betwe['o]num; prefix be- by + a form fr. AS.
   tw[=a] two, akin to Goth. tweihnai two apiece. See {Twain},
   and cf. {Atween}, {Betwixt}.]
   1. In the space which separates; betwixt; as, New York is
      between Boston and Philadelphia.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Used in expressing motion from one body or place to
      another; from one to another of two.
      [1913 Webster]

            If things should go so between them.  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Belonging in common to two; shared by both.
      [1913 Webster]

            Castor and Pollux with only one soul between them.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Belonging to, or participated in by, two, and involving
      reciprocal action or affecting their mutual relation; as,
      opposition between science and religion.
      [1913 Webster]

            An intestine struggle, open or secret, between
            authority and liberty.                --Hume.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. With relation to two, as involved in an act or attribute
      of which another is the agent or subject; as, to judge
      between or to choose between courses; to distinguish
      between you and me; to mediate between nations.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. In intermediate relation to, in respect to time, quantity,
      or degree; as, between nine and ten o'clock.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Between decks}, the space, or in the space, between the
      decks of a vessel.

   {Between ourselves}, {Between you and me}, {Between
   themselves}, in confidence; with the understanding that the
      matter is not to be communicated to others.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: {Between}, {Among}.

   Usage: Between etymologically indicates only two; as, a
          quarrel between two men or two nations; to be between
          two fires, etc. It is however extended to more than
          two in expressing a certain relation.

                I . . . hope that between public business,
                improving studies, and domestic pleasures,
                neither melancholy nor caprice will find any
                place for entrance.               --Johnson.
          [1913 Webster] Among implies a mass or collection of
          things or persons, and always supposes more than two;
          as, the prize money was equally divided among the
          ship's crew.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>between</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>between
     adv 1: in the interval; "dancing all the dances with little rest
            between" [syn: {betwixt}]
     2: in between; "two houses with a tree between" [syn: {'tween}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
