<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>binding</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>binding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bind \Bind\, v. t. [imp. {Bound}; p. p. {Bound}, formerly
   {Bounden}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Binding}.] [AS. bindan, perfect
   tense band, bundon, p. p. bunden; akin to D. &amp; G. binden,
   Dan. binde, Sw. &amp; Icel. binda, Goth. bindan, Skr. bandh (for
   bhandh) to bind, cf. Gr. ? (for ?) cable, and L. offendix.
   [root]90.]
   1. To tie, or confine with a cord, band, ligature, chain,
      etc.; to fetter; to make fast; as, to bind grain in
      bundles; to bind a prisoner.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To confine, restrain, or hold by physical force or
      influence of any kind; as, attraction binds the planets to
      the sun; frost binds the earth, or the streams.
      [1913 Webster]

            He bindeth the floods from overflowing. --Job
                                                  xxviii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whom Satan hath bound, lo, these eighteen years.
                                                  --Luke xiii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cover, as with a bandage; to bandage or dress; --
      sometimes with up; as, to bind up a wound.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make fast ( a thing) about or upon something, as by
      tying; to encircle with something; as, to bind a belt
      about one; to bind a compress upon a part.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To prevent or restrain from customary or natural action;
      as, certain drugs bind the bowels.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To protect or strengthen by a band or binding, as the edge
      of a carpet or garment.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To sew or fasten together, and inclose in a cover; as, to
      bind a book.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Fig.: To oblige, restrain, or hold, by authority, law,
      duty, promise, vow, affection, or other moral tie; as, to
      bind the conscience; to bind by kindness; bound by
      affection; commerce binds nations to each other.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who made our laws to bind us, not himself. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Law)
      (a) To bring (any one) under definite legal obligations;
          esp. under the obligation of a bond or covenant.
          --Abbott.
      (b) To place under legal obligation to serve; to
          indenture; as, to bind an apprentice; -- sometimes
          with out; as, bound out to service.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To bind over}, to put under bonds to do something, as to
      appear at court, to keep the peace, etc.

   {To bind to}, to contract; as, to bind one's self to a wife.
      

   {To bind up in}, to cause to be wholly engrossed with; to
      absorb in.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To fetter; tie; fasten; restrain; restrict; oblige.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>binding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Binding \Bind"ing\, a.
   That binds; obligatory.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Binding beam} (Arch.), the main timber in double flooring.
      

   {Binding joist} (Arch.), the secondary timber in
      double-framed flooring.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Obligatory; restraining; restrictive; stringent;
        astringent; costive; styptic.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>binding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Binding \Bind"ing\, n.
   1. The act or process of one who, or that which, binds.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything that binds; a bandage; the cover of a book, or
      the cover with the sewing, etc.; something that secures
      the edge of cloth from raveling.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. (Naut.) The transoms, knees, beams, keelson, and other
      chief timbers used for connecting and strengthening the
      parts of a vessel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>binding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>binding
     adj 1: executed with proper legal authority; "a binding contract"
     2: hindering freedom of movement; "tight garments are
        uncomfortably binding" [syn: {constricting}]
     3: causing constipation [syn: {constipating}]
     n 1: the capacity to attract and hold something
     2: strip sewn over or along an edge for reinforcement or
        decoration
     3: the act of applying a bandage [syn: {dressing}, {bandaging}]
     4: the front and back covering of a book; "the book had a
        leather binding" [syn: {book binding}, {cover}, {back}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
