<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bind</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BIND
     
        {Berkeley Internet Name Domain}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bind \Bind\, v. t. [imp. {Bound}; p. p. {Bound}, formerly
   {Bounden}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Binding}.] [AS. bindan, perfect
   tense band, bundon, p. p. bunden; akin to D. &amp; G. binden,
   Dan. binde, Sw. &amp; Icel. binda, Goth. bindan, Skr. bandh (for
   bhandh) to bind, cf. Gr. ? (for ?) cable, and L. offendix.
   [root]90.]
   1. To tie, or confine with a cord, band, ligature, chain,
      etc.; to fetter; to make fast; as, to bind grain in
      bundles; to bind a prisoner.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To confine, restrain, or hold by physical force or
      influence of any kind; as, attraction binds the planets to
      the sun; frost binds the earth, or the streams.
      [1913 Webster]

            He bindeth the floods from overflowing. --Job
                                                  xxviii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whom Satan hath bound, lo, these eighteen years.
                                                  --Luke xiii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cover, as with a bandage; to bandage or dress; --
      sometimes with up; as, to bind up a wound.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make fast ( a thing) about or upon something, as by
      tying; to encircle with something; as, to bind a belt
      about one; to bind a compress upon a part.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To prevent or restrain from customary or natural action;
      as, certain drugs bind the bowels.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To protect or strengthen by a band or binding, as the edge
      of a carpet or garment.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To sew or fasten together, and inclose in a cover; as, to
      bind a book.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Fig.: To oblige, restrain, or hold, by authority, law,
      duty, promise, vow, affection, or other moral tie; as, to
      bind the conscience; to bind by kindness; bound by
      affection; commerce binds nations to each other.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who made our laws to bind us, not himself. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Law)
      (a) To bring (any one) under definite legal obligations;
          esp. under the obligation of a bond or covenant.
          --Abbott.
      (b) To place under legal obligation to serve; to
          indenture; as, to bind an apprentice; -- sometimes
          with out; as, bound out to service.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To bind over}, to put under bonds to do something, as to
      appear at court, to keep the peace, etc.

   {To bind to}, to contract; as, to bind one's self to a wife.
      

   {To bind up in}, to cause to be wholly engrossed with; to
      absorb in.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To fetter; tie; fasten; restrain; restrict; oblige.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bind \Bind\, v. i.
   1. To tie; to confine by any ligature.
      [1913 Webster]

            They that reap must sheaf and bind.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To contract; to grow hard or stiff; to cohere or stick
      together in a mass; as, clay binds by heat. --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be restrained from motion, or from customary or natural
      action, as by friction.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To exert a binding or restraining influence. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bind \Bind\, n.
   1. That which binds or ties.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any twining or climbing plant or stem, esp. a hop vine; a
      bine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Metal.) Indurated clay, when much mixed with the oxide of
      iron. --Kirwan.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mus.) A ligature or tie for grouping notes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BIND
     Berkeley Internet Name DOMAIN [software] (Unix)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bind
     n : something that hinders as if with bonds
     v 1: stick to firmly; "Will this wallpaper adhere to the wall?"
          [syn: {adhere}, {hold fast}, {bond}, {stick}, {stick to}]
     2: create social or emotional ties; "The grandparents want to
        bond with the child" [syn: {tie}, {attach}, {bond}]
     3: make fast; tie or secure, with or as if with a rope; "The
        Chinese would bind the feet of their women" [ant: {unbind}]
     4: wrap around with something so as to cover or enclose [syn: {bandage}]
     5: secure with or as if with ropes; "tie down the prisoners";
        "tie up the old newspapes and bring them to the recycling
        shed" [syn: {tie down}, {tie up}, {truss}]
     6: bind by an obligation; cause to be indebted; "He's held by a
        contract"; "I'll hold you by your promise" [syn: {oblige},
         {hold}, {obligate}]
     7: form a chemical bond with; "The hydrogen binds the oxygen"
     8: provide with a binding; "bind the books in leather"
     9: fasten or secure with a rope, string, or cord; "They tied
        their victim to the chair" [syn: {tie}] [ant: {untie}]
     10: cause to be constipated; "These foods tend to constipate
         you" [syn: {constipate}]
     [also: {bound}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
