<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>birthright</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>birthright</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Birthright
   (1.) This word denotes the special privileges and advantages
   belonging to the first-born son among the Jews. He became the
   priest of the family. Thus Reuben was the first-born of the
   patriarchs, and so the priesthood of the tribes belonged to him.
   That honour was, however, transferred by God from Reuben to Levi
   (Num. 3:12, 13; 8:18).
   
     (2.) The first-born son had allotted to him also a double
   portion of the paternal inheritance (Deut. 21:15-17). Reuben
   was, because of his undutiful conduct, deprived of his
   birth-right (Gen. 49:4; 1 Chr. 5:1). Esau transferred his
   birth-right to Jacob (Gen. 25:33).
   
     (3.) The first-born inherited the judicial authority of his
   father, whatever it might be (2 Chr. 21:3). By divine
   appointment, however, David excluded Adonijah in favour of
   Solomon.
   
     (4.) The Jews attached a sacred importance to the rank of
   "first-born" and "first-begotten" as applied to the Messiah
   (Rom. 8:29; Col. 1:18; Heb. 1:4-6). As first-born he has an
   inheritance superior to his brethren, and is the alone true
   priest.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>birthright</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Birthright \Birth"right`\, n.
   Any right, privilege, or possession to which a person is
   entitled by birth, such as an estate descendible by law to an
   heir, or civil liberty under a free constitution; esp. the
   rights or inheritance of the first born.
   [1913 Webster]

         Lest there be any . . . profane person, as Esau, who
         for one morsel of meat sold his birthright. --Heb. xii.
                                                  16.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>birthright</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>birthright
     n 1: a right or privilege that you are entitled to at birth;
          "free public education is the birthright of every
          American child"
     2: an inheritance coming by right of birth (especially by
        primogeniture) [syn: {patrimony}]
     3: personal characteristics that are inherited at birth
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
