<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bishop</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bishop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bishop
   an overseer. In apostolic times, it is quite manifest that there
   was no difference as to order between bishops and elders or
   presbyters (Acts 20:17-28; 1 Pet. 5:1, 2; Phil. 1:1; 1 Tim. 3).
   The term bishop is never once used to denote a different office
   from that of elder or presbyter. These different names are
   simply titles of the same office, "bishop" designating the
   function, namely, that of oversight, and "presbyter" the dignity
   appertaining to the office. Christ is figuratively called "the
   bishop [episcopos] of souls" (1 Pet. 2:25).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bishop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bishop, CA (city, FIPS 6798)
  Location: 37.36770 N, 118.39680 W
  Population (1990): 3475 (1779 housing units)
  Area: 4.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Bishop, GA (town, FIPS 8200)
  Location: 33.81624 N, 83.43642 W
  Population (1990): 158 (71 housing units)
  Area: 2.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 30621
Bishop, TX (city, FIPS 8392)
  Location: 27.58477 N, 97.79759 W
  Population (1990): 3337 (1286 housing units)
  Area: 6.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 78343
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bishop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bishop \Bish"op\, n. [OE. bischop, biscop, bisceop, AS. bisceop,
   biscop, L. episcopus overseer, superintendent, bishop, fr.
   Gr. ?, ? over + ? inspector, fr. root of ?, ?, to look to,
   perh. akin to L. specere to look at. See {Spy}, and cf.
   {Episcopal}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A spiritual overseer, superintendent, or director.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye were as sheep going astray; but are now returned
            unto the Shepherd and Bishop of your souls. --1 Pet.
                                                  ii. 25.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is a fact now generally recognized by theologians
            of all shades of opinion, that in the language of
            the New Testament the same officer in the church is
            called indifferently ``bishop'' ( ? ) and ``elder''
            or ``presbyter.''                     --J. B.
                                                  Lightfoot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. In the Roman Catholic, Greek, and Anglican or Protestant
      Episcopal churches, one ordained to the highest order of
      the ministry, superior to the priesthood, and generally
      claiming to be a successor of the Apostles. The bishop is
      usually the spiritual head or ruler of a diocese,
      bishopric, or see.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bishop in partibus [infidelium]} (R. C. Ch.), a bishop of a
      see which does not actually exist; one who has the office
      of bishop, without especial jurisdiction. --Shipley.

   {Titular bishop} (R. C. Ch.), a term officially substituted
      in 1882 for bishop in partibus.

   {Bench of Bishops}. See under {Bench}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. In the Methodist Episcopal and some other churches, one of
      the highest church officers or superintendents.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A piece used in the game of chess, bearing a
      representation of a bishop's miter; -- formerly called
      archer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A beverage, being a mixture of wine, oranges or lemons,
      and sugar. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An old name for a woman's bustle. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

            If, by her bishop, or her ``grace'' alone,
            A genuine lady, or a church, is known. --Saxe.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bishop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bishop \Bish"op\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bishoped}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Bishoping}.]
   To admit into the church by confirmation; to confirm; hence,
   to receive formally to favor.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bishop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bishop \Bish"op\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bishoped}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Bishoping}.] [From the name of the scoundrel who first
   practiced it. Youatt.] (Far.)
   To make seem younger, by operating on the teeth; as, to
   bishop an old horse or his teeth.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The plan adopted is to cut off all the nippers with a
         saw to the proper length, and then with a cutting
         instrument the operator scoops out an oval cavity in
         the corner nippers, which is afterwards burnt with a
         hot iron until it is black. --J. H. Walsh.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bishop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bustle \Bus"tle\, n.
   A kind of pad or cushion worn on the back below the waist, by
   women, to give fullness to the skirts; -- called also
   {bishop}, and {tournure}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bishop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bishop
     n 1: a clergyman having spiritual and administrative authority;
          appointed in Christian churches to oversee priests or
          ministers; considered in some churches to be successors
          of the twelve apostles of Christ
     2: port wine mulled with oranges and cloves
     3: (chess) a piece that can be moved diagonally over unoccupied
        squares of the same color
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
