<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>blank</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BLANK-:VERSE:, n.  Unrhymed iambic pentameters -- the most difficult
kind of English verse to write acceptably; a kind, therefore, much
affected by those who cannot acceptably write any kind.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blank \Blank\, a. [OE. blank, blonc, blaunc, blaunche, fr. F.
   blanc, fem. blanche, fr. OHG. blanch shining, bright, white,
   G. blank; akin to E. blink, cf. also AS. blanc white. ?98.
   See {Blink}, and cf. 1st {Blanch}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Of a white or pale color; without color.
      [1913 Webster]

            To the blank moon
            Her office they prescribed.           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Free from writing, printing, or marks; having an empty
      space to be filled in with some special writing; -- said
      of checks, official documents, etc.; as, blank paper; a
      blank check; a blank ballot.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Utterly confounded or discomfited.
      [1913 Webster]

            Adam . . . astonied stood, and blank. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Empty; void; without result; fruitless; as, a blank space;
      a blank day.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Lacking characteristics which give variety; as, a blank
      desert; a blank wall; destitute of interests, affections,
      hopes, etc.; as, to live a blank existence; destitute of
      sensations; as, blank unconsciousness.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Lacking animation and intelligence, or their associated
      characteristics, as expression of face, look, etc.;
      expressionless; vacant. ``Blank and horror-stricken
      faces.'' --C. Kingsley.
      [1913 Webster]

            The blank . . . glance of a half returned
            consciousness.                        --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Absolute; downright; unmixed; as, blank terror.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Blank bar} (Law), a plea put in to oblige the plaintiff in
      an action of trespass to assign the certain place where
      the trespass was committed; -- called also {common bar}.
      

   {Blank cartridge}, a cartridge containing no ball.

   {Blank deed}. See {Deed}.

   {Blank door}, or {Blank window} (Arch.), a depression in a
      wall of the size of a door or window, either for
      symmetrical effect, or for the more convenient insertion
      of a door or window at a future time, should it be needed.
      

   {Blank indorsement} (Law), an indorsement which omits the
      name of the person in whose favor it is made; it is
      usually made by simply writing the name of the indorser on
      the back of the bill.

   {Blank line} (Print.), a vacant space of the breadth of a
      line, on a printed page; a line of quadrats.

   {Blank tire} (Mech.), a tire without a flange.

   {Blank tooling}. See {Blind tooling}, under {Blind}.

   {Blank verse}. See under {Verse}.

   {Blank wall}, a wall in which there is no opening; a dead
      wall.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blank \Blank\, n.
   1. Any void space; a void space on paper, or in any written
      instrument; an interval void of consciousness, action,
      result, etc; a void.
      [1913 Webster]

            I can not write a paper full, I used to do; and yet
            I will not forgive a blank of half an inch from you.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            From this time there ensues a long blank in the
            history of French legislation.        --Hallam.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was ill. I can't tell how long -- it was a blank.
                                                  --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lot by which nothing is gained; a ticket in a lottery on
      which no prize is indicated.
      [1913 Webster]

            In Fortune's lottery lies
            A heap of blanks, like this, for one small prize.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A paper unwritten; a paper without marks or characters a
      blank ballot; -- especially, a paper on which are to be
      inserted designated items of information, for which spaces
      are left vacant; a bland form.
      [1913 Webster]

            The freemen signified their approbation by an
            inscribed vote, and their dissent by a blank.
                                                  --Palfrey.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A paper containing the substance of a legal instrument, as
      a deed, release, writ, or execution, with spaces left to
      be filled with names, date, descriptions, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The point aimed at in a target, marked with a white spot;
      hence, the object to which anything is directed.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let me still remain
            The true blank of thine eye.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Aim; shot; range. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I have stood . . . within the blank of his
            displeasure
            For my free speech.                   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A kind of base silver money, first coined in England by
      Henry V., and worth about 8 pence; also, a French coin of
      the seventeenth century, worth about 4 pence. --Nares.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mech.) A piece of metal prepared to be made into
      something by a further operation, as a coin, screw, nuts.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Dominoes) A piece or division of a piece, without spots;
      as, the ``double blank''; the ``six blank.''
      [1913 Webster]

   {In blank}, with an essential portion to be supplied by
      another; as, to make out a check in blank.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blank \Blank\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Blanked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Blanking}.] [Cf. 3d {Blanch}.]
   1. To make void; to annul. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To blanch; to make blank; to damp the spirits of; to
      dispirit or confuse. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Each opposite that blanks the face of joy. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>blank
     adj 1: of a surface; not written or printed on; "blank pages";
            "fill in the blank spaces"; "a clean page"; "wide
            white margins" [syn: {clean}, {white}]
     2: void of expression; "a blank stare"
     3: not charged with a bullet; "a blank cartridge"
     n 1: a blank character used to separate successive words in
          writing or printing; "he said the space is the most
          important character in the alphabet" [syn: {space}]
     2: a substitute for a taboo word; "I hit the blank blank car"
     3: a blank gap or missing part [syn: {lacuna}]
     4: a piece of material ready to be made into something
     5: a cartridge containing an explosive charge but no bullet
        [syn: {dummy}, {blank shell}]
     v : keep the opposing (baseball) team from winning
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
