<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>blind</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blind
   Blind beggars are frequently mentioned (Matt. 9:27; 12:22;
   20:30; John 5:3). The blind are to be treated with compassion
   (Lev. 19:14; Deut. 27:18). Blindness was sometimes a punishment
   for disobedience (1 Sam. 11:2; Jer. 39:7), sometimes the effect
   of old age (Gen. 27:1; 1 Kings 14:4; 1 Sam. 4:15). Conquerors
   sometimes blinded their captives (2 Kings 25:7; 1 Sam. 11:2).
   Blindness denotes ignorance as to spiritual things (Isa. 6:10;
   42:18, 19; Matt. 15:14; Eph. 4:18). The opening of the eyes of
   the blind is peculiar to the Messiah (Isa. 29:18). Elymas was
   smitten with blindness at Paul's word (Acts 13:11).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blind \Blind\, a. [AS.; akin to D., G., OS., Sw., &amp; Dan. blind,
   Icel. blindr, Goth. blinds; of uncertain origin.]
   1. Destitute of the sense of seeing, either by natural defect
      or by deprivation; without sight.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that is strucken blind can not forget
            The precious treasure of his eyesight lost. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not having the faculty of discernment; destitute of
      intellectual light; unable or unwilling to understand or
      judge; as, authors are blind to their own defects.
      [1913 Webster]

            But hard be hardened, blind be blinded more,
            That they may stumble on, and deeper fall. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Undiscerning; undiscriminating; inconsiderate.
      [1913 Webster]

            This plan is recommended neither to blind
            approbation nor to blind reprobation. --Jay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Having such a state or condition as a thing would have to
      a person who is blind; not well marked or easily
      discernible; hidden; unseen; concealed; as, a blind path;
      a blind ditch.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Involved; intricate; not easily followed or traced.
      [1913 Webster]

            The blind mazes of this tangled wood. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Having no openings for light or passage; as, a blind wall;
      open only at one end; as, a blind alley; a blind gut.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Unintelligible, or not easily intelligible; as, a blind
      passage in a book; illegible; as, blind writing.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Hort.) Abortive; failing to produce flowers or fruit; as,
      blind buds; blind flowers.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Blind alley}, an alley closed at one end; a cul-de-sac.

   {Blind axle}, an axle which turns but does not communicate
      motion. --Knight.

   {Blind beetle}, one of the insects apt to fly against people,
      esp. at night.

   {Blind cat} (Zo["o]l.), a species of catfish ({Gronias
      nigrolabris}), nearly destitute of eyes, living in caverns
      in Pennsylvania.

   {Blind coal}, coal that burns without flame; anthracite coal.
      --Simmonds.

   {Blind door}, {Blind window}, an imitation of a door or
      window, without an opening for passage or light. See
      {Blank door} or {Blank window}, under {Blank}, a.

   {Blind level} (Mining), a level or drainage gallery which has
      a vertical shaft at each end, and acts as an inverted
      siphon. --Knight.

   {Blind nettle} (Bot.), dead nettle. See {Dead nettle}, under
      {Dead}.

   {Blind shell} (Gunnery), a shell containing no charge, or one
      that does not explode.

   {Blind side}, the side which is most easily assailed; a weak
      or unguarded side; the side on which one is least able or
      disposed to see danger. --Swift.

   {Blind snake} (Zo["o]l.), a small, harmless, burrowing snake,
      of the family {Typhlopid[ae]}, with rudimentary eyes.

   {Blind spot} (Anat.), the point in the retina of the eye
      where the optic nerve enters, and which is insensible to
      light.

   {Blind tooling}, in bookbinding and leather work, the
      indented impression of heated tools, without gilding; --
      called also {blank tooling}, and {blind blocking}.

   {Blind wall}, a wall without an opening; a blank wall.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blind \Blind\, n.
   1. Something to hinder sight or keep out light; a screen; a
      cover; esp. a hinged screen or shutter for a window; a
      blinder for a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Something to mislead the eye or the understanding, or to
      conceal some covert deed or design; a subterfuge.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. [Cf. F. blindes, p?., fr. G. blende, fr. blenden to blind,
      fr. blind blind.] (Mil.) A blindage. See {Blindage}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A halting place. [Obs.] --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blind \Blind\, Blinde \Blinde\, n.
   See {Blende}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blind \Blind\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Blinded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Blinding}.]
   1. To make blind; to deprive of sight or discernment. ``To
      blind the truth and me.'' --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            A blind guide is certainly a great mischief; but a
            guide that blinds those whom he should lead is . . .
            a much greater.                       --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To deprive partially of vision; to make vision difficult
      for and painful to; to dazzle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her beauty all the rest did blind.    --P. Fletcher.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To darken; to obscure to the eye or understanding; to
      conceal; to deceive.
      [1913 Webster]

            Such darkness blinds the sky.         --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The state of the controversy between us he
            endeavored, with all his art, to blind and confound.
                                                  --Stillingfleet.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cover with a thin coating of sand and fine gravel; as a
      road newly paved, in order that the joints between the
      stones may be filled.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>closed \closed\ adj.
   1. having an opening obstructed. [Narrower terms: {blind}]
      Also See: {obstructed}, {sealed}, {shut}, {unopen},
      {closed}. Antonym: {open}.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   2. (Math.) of a curve or surface: having no end points or
      boundary curves; of a set: having members that can be
      produced by a specific operation on other members of the
      same set; of an interval: containing both its endpoints.
      {open}
      [WordNet 1.5]

   3. Being in a position to obstruct an opening; -- especially
      of doors. [Narrower terms: {fastened, latched}] Also See:
      {closed}. Antonym: {open}.

   Syn: shut, unopen.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   4. having skin drawn so as to obstruct the opening; -- used
      of mouth or eyes. Opposite of {open}. he sat quietly with
      closed eyes [Narrower terms: {blinking, winking};
      {compressed, tight}; {squinched, squinting}]

   Syn: shut.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   5. requiring union membership; -- of a workplace; as, a
      closed shop. [prenominal]
      [WordNet 1.5]

   6. closed with shutters.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   7. hidden from the public; as, a closed ballot.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   8. not open to the general public; as, a closed meeting.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   9. unsympathetic; -- of a person's attitude. a closed mind
      unreceptive to new ideas
      [WordNet 1.5]

   10. surrounded by walls. a closed porch

   Syn: closed in(predicate).
        [WordNet 1.5]

   11. made compact by bending or doubling over; as, a closed
       map.

   Syn: folded.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   12. closed or fastened with or as if with buttons. [Narrower
       terms: {buttoned (vs. unbuttoned)}]
       [WordNet 1.5]

   13. not engaged in activity; -- of an organization or
       business establishment. the airport is closed because of
       the weather; the many closed shops and factories made the
       town look deserted

   Syn: shut down.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>blind
     adj 1: unable to see [syn: {unsighted}] [ant: {sighted}]
     2: unable or unwilling to perceive or understand; "blind to a
        lover's faults"; "blind to the consequences of their
        actions"
     3: not based on reason or evidence; "blind hatred"; "blind
        faith"; "unreasoning panic" [syn: {unreasoning}]
     n 1: people who have severe visual impairments; "he spent hours
          reading to the blind"
     2: a hiding place sometimes used by hunters (especially duck
        hunters); "he waited impatiently in the blind"
     3: something that keeps things out or hinders sight; "they had
        just moved in and had not put up blinds yet" [syn: {screen}]
     4: something intended to misrepresent the true nature of an
        activity; "he wasn't sick--it was just a subterfuge"; "the
        holding company was just a blind" [syn: {subterfuge}]
     v 1: render unable to see
     2: make blind by putting the eyes out; "The criminals were
        punished and blinded"
     3: make dim by comparison or conceal [syn: {dim}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
