<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>blow</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blow \Blow\ (bl[=o]), v. i. [imp. {Blew} (bl[=u]); p. p. {Blown}
   (bl[=o]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Blowing}.] [OE. blowen, AS.
   bl[=o]wan to blossom; akin to OS. bl[=o]jan, D. bloeijen,
   OHG. pluojan, MHG. bl["u]ejen, G. bl["u]hen, L. florere to
   flourish, OIr. blath blossom. Cf. {Blow} to puff,
   {Flourish}.]
   To flower; to blossom; to bloom.
   [1913 Webster]

         How blows the citron grove.              --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blow \Blow\, v. i. [imp. {Blew} (bl[=u]); p. p. {Blown}
   (bl[=o]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Blowing}.] [OE. blawen, blowen,
   AS. bl[=a]wan to blow, as wind; akin to OHG. pl[=a]jan, G.
   bl["a]hen, to blow up, swell, L. flare to blow, Gr.
   'ekflai`nein to spout out, and to E. bladder, blast, inflate,
   etc., and perh. blow to bloom.]
   1. To produce a current of air; to move, as air, esp. to move
      rapidly or with power; as, the wind blows.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hark how it rains and blows !         --Walton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To send forth a forcible current of air, as from the mouth
      or from a pair of bellows.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To breathe hard or quick; to pant; to puff.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here is Mistress Page at the door, sweating and
            blowing.                              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To sound on being blown into, as a trumpet.
      [1913 Webster]

            There let the pealing organ blow.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To spout water, etc., from the blowholes, as a whale.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To be carried or moved by the wind; as, the dust blows in
      from the street.
      [1913 Webster]

            The grass blows from their graves to thy own. --M.
                                                  Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To talk loudly; to boast; to storm. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            You blow behind my back, but dare not say anything
            to my face.                           --Bartlett.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To stop functioning due to a failure in an electrical
      circuit, especially on which breaks the circuit; sometimes
      used with out; -- used of light bulbs, electronic
      components, fuses; as, the dome light in the car blew out.
      [PJC]

   9. To deflate by sudden loss of air; usually used with out;
      -- of inflatable tires.
      [PJC]

   {To blow hot and cold} (a saying derived from a fable of
      [AE]sop's), to favor a thing at one time and treat it
      coldly at another; or to appear both to favor and to
      oppose.

   {To blow off}, to let steam escape through a passage provided
      for the purpose; as, the engine or steamer is blowing off.
      

   {To blow out}.
      (a) To be driven out by the expansive force of a gas or
          vapor; as, a steam cock or valve sometimes blows out.
      (b) To talk violently or abusively. [Low]

   {To blow over}, to pass away without effect; to cease, or be
      dissipated; as, the storm and the clouds have blown over.
      

   {To blow up}, to be torn to pieces and thrown into the air as
      by an explosion of powder or gas or the expansive force of
      steam; to burst; to explode; as, a powder mill or steam
      boiler blows up. ``The enemy's magazines blew up.''
      --Tatler.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blow \Blow\, v. t.
   To cause to blossom; to put forth (blossoms or flowers).
   [1913 Webster]

         The odorous banks, that blow
         Flowers of more mingled hue.             --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blow \Blow\, n. (Bot.)
   A blossom; a flower; also, a state of blossoming; a mass of
   blossoms. ``Such a blow of tulips.'' --Tatler.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blow \Blow\, n. [OE. blaw, blowe; cf. OHG. bliuwan, pliuwan, to
   beat, G. bl["a]uen, Goth. bliggwan.]
   1. A forcible stroke with the hand, fist, or some instrument,
      as a rod, a club, an ax, or a sword.
      [1913 Webster]

            Well struck ! there was blow for blow. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A sudden or forcible act or effort; an assault.
      [1913 Webster]

            A vigorous blow might win [Hanno's camp]. --T.
                                                  Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The infliction of evil; a sudden calamity; something which
      produces mental, physical, or financial suffering or loss
      (esp. when sudden); a buffet.
      [1913 Webster]

            A most poor man, made tame to fortune's blows.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At a blow}, suddenly; at one effort; by a single vigorous
      act. ``They lose a province at a blow.'' --Dryden.

   {To come to blows}, to engage in combat; to fight; -- said of
      individuals, armies, and nations.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Stroke; knock; shock; misfortune.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blow \Blow\, v. t.
   1. To force a current of air upon with the mouth, or by other
      means; as, to blow the fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To drive by a current air; to impel; as, the tempest blew
      the ship ashore.
      [1913 Webster]

            Off at sea northeast winds blow
            Sabean odors from the spicy shore.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause air to pass through by the action of the mouth,
      or otherwise; to cause to sound, as a wind instrument; as,
      to blow a trumpet; to blow an organ; to blow a horn.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hath she no husband
            That will take pains to blow a horn before her?
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Boy, blow the pipe until the bubble rise,
            Then cast it off to float upon the skies. --Parnell.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To clear of contents by forcing air through; as, to blow
      an egg; to blow one's nose.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To burst, shatter, or destroy by an explosion; -- usually
      with up, down, open, or similar adverb; as, to blow up a
      building.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To spread by report; to publish; to disclose; to reveal,
      intentionally or inadvertently; as, to blow an agent's
      cover.
      [1913 Webster]

            Through the court his courtesy was blown. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            His language does his knowledge blow. --Whiting.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To form by inflation; to swell by injecting air; as, to
      blow bubbles; to blow glass.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To inflate, as with pride; to puff up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Look how imagination blows him.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To put out of breath; to cause to blow from fatigue; as,
      to blow a horse. --Sir W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To deposit eggs or larv[ae] upon, or in (meat, etc.).
       [1913 Webster]

             To suffer
             The flesh fly blow my mouth.         --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To perform an act of fellatio on; to stimulate another's
       penis with one's mouth; -- usually considered vulgar.
       [slang]
       [PJC]

   12. to smoke (e. g. marijuana); to blow pot. [colloq.]
       [PJC]

   13. to botch; to bungle; as, he blew his chance at a good job
       by showing up late for the interview. [colloq.]
       [PJC]

   14. to leave; to depart from; as, to blow town. [slang]
       [PJC]

   15. to squander; as, he blew his inheritance gambling.
       [colloq.]
       [PJC]

   {To blow great guns}, to blow furiously and with roaring
      blasts; -- said of the wind at sea or along the coast.

   {To blow off}, to empty (a boiler) of water through the
      blow-off pipe, while under steam pressure; also, to eject
      (steam, water, sediment, etc.) from a boiler.

   {To blow one's own trumpet}, to vaunt one's own exploits, or
      sound one's own praises.

   {To blow out}, to extinguish by a current of air, as a
      candle.

   {To blow up}.
       (a) To fill with air; to swell; as, to blow up a bladder
           or bubble.
       (b) To inflate, as with pride, self-conceit, etc.; to
           puff up; as, to blow one up with flattery. ``Blown up
           with high conceits engendering pride.'' --Milton.
       (c) To excite; as, to blow up a contention.
       (d) To burst, to raise into the air, or to scatter, by an
           explosion; as, to blow up a fort.
       (e) To scold violently; as, to blow up a person for some
           offense. [Colloq.]
           [1913 Webster]

                 I have blown him up well -- nobody can say I
                 wink at what he does.            --G. Eliot.
           [1913 Webster]

   {To blow upon}.
       (a) To blast; to taint; to bring into discredit; to
           render stale, unsavory, or worthless.
       (b) To inform against. [Colloq.]
           [1913 Webster]

                 How far the very custom of hearing anything
                 spouted withers and blows upon a fine passage,
                 may be seen in those speeches from
                 [Shakespeare's] Henry V. which are current in
                 the mouths of schoolboys.        --C. Lamb.
           [1913 Webster]

                 A lady's maid whose character had been blown
                 upon.                            --Macaulay.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Blow \Blow\, n.
   1. A blowing, esp., a violent blowing of the wind; a gale;
      as, a heavy blow came on, and the ship put back to port.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of forcing air from the mouth, or through or from
      some instrument; as, to give a hard blow on a whistle or
      horn; to give the fire a blow with the bellows.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The spouting of a whale.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Metal.) A single heat or operation of the Bessemer
      converter. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An egg, or a larva, deposited by a fly on or in flesh, or
      the act of depositing it. --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>blow</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>blow
     n 1: a powerful stroke with the fist or a weapon; "a blow on the
          head"
     2: an impact (as from a collision); "the bump threw him off the
        bicycle" [syn: {bump}]
     3: an unfortunate happening that hinders of impedes; something
        that is thwarting or frustrating [syn: {reverse}, {reversal},
         {setback}, {black eye}]
     4: an unpleasant or disappointing surprise; "it came as a shock
        to learn that he was injured" [syn: {shock}]
     5: a strong current of air; "the tree was bent almost double by
        the gust" [syn: {gust}, {blast}]
     6: street names for cocaine [syn: {coke}, {nose candy}, {snow},
         {C}]
     7: forceful exhalation through the nose or mouth; "he gave his
        nose a loud blow"; "he blew out all the candles with a
        single puff" [syn: {puff}]
     v 1: exhale hard; "blow on the soup to cool it down"
     2: be blowing or storming; "The wind blew from the West"
     3: free of obstruction by blowing air through; "blow one's
        nose"
     4: be in motion due to some air or water current; "The leaves
        were blowing in the wind"; "the boat drifted on the lake";
        "The sailboat was adrift on the open sea"; "the
        shipwrecked boat drifted away from the shore" [syn: {float},
         {drift}, {be adrift}]
     5: make a sound as if blown; "The whistle blew"
     6: shape by blowing; "Blow a glass vase"
     7: make a mess of, destroy or ruin; "I botched the dinner and
        we had to eat out"; "the pianist screwed up the difficult
        passage in the second movement" [syn: {botch}, {bumble}, {fumble},
         {botch up}, {muff}, {flub}, {screw up}, {ball up}, {spoil},
         {muck up}, {bungle}, {fluff}, {bollix}, {bollix up}, {bollocks},
         {bollocks up}, {bobble}, {mishandle}, {louse up}, {foul
        up}, {mess up}, {fuck up}]
     8: spend thoughtlessly; throw away; "He wasted his inheritance
        on his insincere friends"; "You squandered the opportunity
        to get and advanced degree" [syn: {waste}, {squander}]
        [ant: {conserve}]
     9: spend lavishly or wastefully on; "He blew a lot of money on
        his new home theater"
     10: sound by having air expelled through a tube; "The trumpets
         blew"
     11: play or sound a wind instrument; "She blew the horn"
     12: provide sexual gratification through oral stimulation [syn:
         {fellate}, {go down on}]
     13: cause air to go in, on, or through; "Blow my hair dry"
     14: cause to move by means of an air current; "The wind blew the
         leaves around in the yard"
     15: spout moist air from the blowhole; "The whales blew"
     16: leave; informal or rude; "shove off!"; "The children shoved
         along"; "Blow now!" [syn: {shove off}, {shove along}]
     17: lay eggs; "certain insects are said to blow"
     18: cause to be revealed and jeopardized; "The story blew their
         cover"; "The double agent was blown by the other side"
     19: show off [syn: {boast}, {tout}, {swash}, {shoot a line}, {brag},
          {gas}, {bluster}, {vaunt}, {gasconade}]
     20: allow to regain its breath; "blow a horse"
     21: melt, break, or become otherwise unusable; "The lightbulbs
         blew out"; "The fuse blew" [syn: {blow out}, {burn out}]
     22: burst suddenly; "The tire blew"; "We blew a tire"
     [also: {blown}, {blew}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
