<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bluff</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bluff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bluff \Bluff\, a. [Cf. OD. blaf flat, broad, blaffaert one with
   a broad face, also, a boaster; or G. verbl["u]ffen to
   confuse, LG. bluffen to frighten; to unknown origin.]
   1. Having a broad, flattened front; as, the bluff bows of a
      ship. ``Bluff visages.'' --Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Rising steeply with a flat or rounded front. ``A bluff or
      bold shore.'' --Falconer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Its banks, if not really steep, had a bluff and
            precipitous aspect.                   --Judd.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Surly; churlish; gruff; rough.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Abrupt; roughly frank; unceremonious; blunt; brusque; as,
      a bluff answer; a bluff manner of talking; a bluff sea
      captain. ``Bluff King Hal.'' --Sir W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is indeed a bluff pertinacity which is a
            proper defense in a moment of surprise. --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bluff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bluff \Bluff\, v. i.
   To act as in the game of bluff.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bluff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bluff \Bluff\, n.
   1. A high, steep bank, as by a river or the sea, or beside a
      ravine or plain; a cliff with a broad face.
      [1913 Webster]

            Beach, bluff, and wave, adieu.        --Whittier.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An act of bluffing; an expression of self-confidence for
      the purpose of intimidation; braggadocio; as, that is only
      bluff, or a bluff.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A game at cards; poker. [U.S.] --Bartlett.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bluff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bluff \Bluff\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bluffed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bluffing}.]
   1. (Poker) To deter (an opponent) from taking the risk of
      betting on his hand of cards, as the bluffer does by
      betting heavily on his own hand although it may be of less
      value. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To frighten or deter from accomplishing a purpose by
      making a show of confidence in one's strength or
      resources; as, he bluffed me off. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bluff</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bluff
     adj 1: very steep; having a prominent and almost vertical front; "a
            bluff headland"; "where the bold chalk cliffs of
            England rise"; "a sheer descent of rock" [syn: {bold},
             {sheer}]
     2: bluntly direct and outspoken but good-natured; "a bluff but
        pleasant manner"; "a bluff and rugged natural leader"
     n 1: a high steep bank (usually formed by river erosion)
     2: pretense that your position is stronger than it really is;
        "his bluff succeeded in getting him accepted"
     3: the act of bluffing in poker; deception by a false show of
        confidence in the strength of your cards [syn: {four flush}]
     v 1: deceive an opponent by a bold bet on an inferior hand with
          the result that the opponent withdraws a winning hand
          [syn: {bluff out}]
     2: frighten someone by pretending to be stronger than one
        really is
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
