<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>boa</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boa</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>boa
     
        [IBM] Any one of the fat cables that lurk under the floor in a
        {dinosaur pen}.  Possibly so called because they display a
        ferocious life of their own when you try to lay them straight
        and flat after they have been coiled for some time.  It is
        rumored within IBM that channel cables for the 370 are limited
        to 200 feet because beyond that length the boas get dangerous
        --- and it is worth noting that one of the major cable makers
        uses the trademark "Anaconda".
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boa</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boa \Bo"a\ (b[=o]"[.a]), n.; pl. {Boas}. [L. boa a kind of water
   serpent. Perh. fr. bos an ox.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) A genus of large American serpents, including
      the boa constrictor, the emperor boa of Mexico ({Boa
      imperator}), and the chevalier boa of Peru ({Boa eques}).
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The name is also applied to related genera; as, the
         {dog-headed boa} ({Xiphosoma caninum}).
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A long, round fur tippet; -- so called from its
      resemblance in shape to the boa constrictor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boa</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>boa [IBM] n. Any one of the fat cables that lurk under the floor in a
   {dinosaur pen}. Possibly so called because they display a ferocious life
   of their own when you try to lay them straight and flat after they have
   been coiled for some time. It is rumored within IBM that channel cables
   for the 370 are limited to 200 feet because beyond that length the boas
   get dangerous -- and it is worth noting that one of the major cable
   makers uses the trademark `Anaconda'.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boa</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BOA
     Basic Object Adapter
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boa</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>boa
     n 1: a long thin fluffy scarf of feathers or fur [syn: {feather
          boa}]
     2: any of several chiefly tropical constrictors with vestigial
        hind limbs
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
