<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bob</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bob</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bob
     
        David Betz.  A tiny object-oriented language.
     
        {(ftp://ftp.mv.com/pub/ddj/packages/bob15.arc)}.
     
        [Dr Dobbs J, Sep 1991, p.26].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bob</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bob \Bob\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bobbed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bobbing}.] [OE. bobben. See {Bob}, n.]
   1. To cause to move in a short, jerking manner; to move (a
      thing) with a bob. ``He bobbed his head.'' --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To strike with a quick, light blow; to tap.
      [1913 Webster]

            If any man happened by long sitting to sleep . . .
            he was suddenly bobbed on the face by the servants.
                                                  --Elyot.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cheat; to gain by fraud or cheating; to filch.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gold and jewels that I bobbed from him. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To mock or delude; to cheat.
      [1913 Webster]

            To play her pranks, and bob the fool,
            The shrewish wife began.              --Turbervile.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cut short; as, to bob the hair, or a horse's tail.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bob</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bob \Bob\ (b[o^]b), n. [An onomatopoetic word, expressing quick,
   jerky motion; OE. bob bunch, bobben to strike, mock, deceive.
   Cf. Prov. Eng. bob, n., a ball, an engine beam, bunch, blast,
   trick, taunt, scoff; as, a v., to dance, to courtesy, to
   disappoint, OF. bober to mock.]
   1. Anything that hangs so as to play loosely, or with a short
      abrupt motion, as at the end of a string; a pendant; as,
      the bob at the end of a kite's tail.
      [1913 Webster]

            In jewels dressed and at each ear a bob. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A knot of worms, or of rags, on a string, used in angling,
      as for eels; formerly, a worm suitable for bait.
      [1913 Webster]

            Or yellow bobs, turned up before the plow,
            Are chiefest baits, with cork and lead enow.
                                                  --Lauson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A small piece of cork or light wood attached to a fishing
      line to show when a fish is biting; a float.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The ball or heavy part of a pendulum; also, the ball or
      weight at the end of a plumb line.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A small wheel, made of leather, with rounded edges, used
      in polishing spoons, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A short, jerking motion; act of bobbing; as, a bob of the
      head.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Steam Engine) A working beam.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A knot or short curl of hair; also, a bob wig.
      [1913 Webster]

            A plain brown bob he wore.            --Shenstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A peculiar mode of ringing changes on bells.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The refrain of a song.
       [1913 Webster]

             To bed, to bed, will be the bob of the song.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A blow; a shake or jog; a rap, as with the fist.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A jeer or flout; a sharp jest or taunt; a trick.
       [1913 Webster]

             He that a fool doth very wisely hit,
             Doth very foolishly, although he smart,
             Not to seem senseless of the bob.    --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. A shilling. [Slang, Eng.] --Dickens.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bob</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bob \Bob\, v. i.
   1. To have a short, jerking motion; to play to and fro, or up
      and down; to play loosely against anything. ``Bobbing and
      courtesying.'' --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To angle with a bob. See {Bob}, n., 2 &amp; 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            He ne'er had learned the art to bob
            For anything but eels.                --Saxe.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To bob at an apple}, {cherry}, etc. to attempt to bite or
      seize with the mouth an apple, cherry, or other round
      fruit, while it is swinging from a string or floating in a
      tug of water.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bob</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bob n. At Demon Internet (http://www.demon.net/), all tech support
   personnel are called "Bob". (Female support personnel have an option on
   "Bobette"). This has nothing to do with Bob the divine
   drilling-equipment salesman of the {Church of the SubGenius}. Nor is it
   acronymized from "Brother Of {BOFH}", though all parties agree it could
   have been. Rather, it was triggered by an unusually large draft of new
   tech-support people in 1995. It was observed that there would be much
   duplication of names. To ease the confusion, it was decided that all
   support techs would henceforth be known as "Bob", and identity badges
   were created labelled "Bob 1" and "Bob 2". ("No, we never got any
   further" reports a witness).

   The reason for "Bob" rather than anything else is due to a {luser}
   calling and asking to speak to "Bob", despite the fact that no "Bob" was
   currently working for Tech Support. Since we all know "the customer is
   always right", it was decided that there had to be at least one "Bob" on
   duty at all times, just in case.

   This sillyness inexorably snowballed. Shift leaders and managers began
   to refer to their groups of "bobs". Whole ranks of support machines were
   set up (and still exist in the DNS as of 1999) as bob1 through bobN.
   Then came alt.tech-support.recovery, and it was filled with Demon
   support personnel. They all referred to themselves, and to others, as
   `bob', and after a while it caught on.There is now a Bob Code
   (http://bob.bob.bofh.org/~giolla/bobcode.html) describing the Bob
   nature.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bob</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bob
     n 1: a former monetary unit in Great Britain [syn: {British
          shilling}, {shilling}]
     2: a hair style for women and children; a short haircut all
        around
     3: a long racing sled (for 2 or more people) with a steering
        mechanism [syn: {bobsled}, {bobsleigh}]
     4: a hanging weight, especially a metal ball on a string
     5: a small float usually made of cork; attached to a fishing
        line [syn: {bobber}, {cork}, {bobfloat}]
     6: a short or shortened tail of certain animals [syn: {bobtail},
         {dock}]
     7: a short abrupt inclination (as of the head); "he gave me a
        short bob of acknowledgement"
     v 1: move up and down repeatedly; "her rucksack bobbed gently on
          her back"
     2: ride a bobsled; "The boys bobbed down the hill screaming
        with pleasure" [syn: {bobsled}]
     3: remove or shorten the tail of an animal [syn: {dock}, {tail}]
     4: make a curtsy; usually done only by girls and women; as a
        sign of respect; "She curtsied when she shook the Queen's
        hand" [syn: {curtsy}]
     5: cut hair in the style of a bob; "Bernice bobs her hair these
        days!"
     [also: {bobbing}, {bobbed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
