<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>boiled</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boiled</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boil \Boil\ (boil), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Boiled} (boild); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Boiling}.] [OE. boilen, OF. boilir, builir, F.
   bouillir, fr. L. bullire to be in a bubbling motion, from
   bulla bubble; akin to Gr. ?, Lith. bumbuls. Cf. {Bull} an
   edict, {Budge}, v., and {Ebullition}.]
   1. To be agitated, or tumultuously moved, as a liquid by the
      generation and rising of bubbles of steam (or vapor), or
      of currents produced by heating it to the boiling point;
      to be in a state of ebullition; as, the water boils.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be agitated like boiling water, by any other cause than
      heat; to bubble; to effervesce; as, the boiling waves.
      [1913 Webster]

            He maketh the deep to boil like a pot. --Job xii.
                                                  31.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass from a liquid to an a["e]riform state or vapor
      when heated; as, the water boils away.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be moved or excited with passion; to be hot or fervid;
      as, his blood boils with anger.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then boiled my breast with flame and burning wrath.
                                                  --Surrey.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be in boiling water, as in cooking; as, the potatoes
      are boiling.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To boil away}, to vaporize; to evaporate or be evaporated by
      the action of heat.

   {To boil over}, to run over the top of a vessel, as liquid
      when thrown into violent agitation by heat or other cause
      of effervescence; to be excited with ardor or passion so
      as to lose self-control.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boiled</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boiled \Boiled\, a.
   Dressed or cooked by boiling; subjected to the action of a
   boiling liquid; as, boiled meat; a boiled dinner; boiled
   clothes.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boiled</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>boiled
     adj : cooked in hot water [syn: {poached}, {stewed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
