<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bond</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bond
   an obligation of any kind (Num. 30:2, 4, 12). The word means
   also oppression or affliction (Ps. 116:16; Phil. 1:7). Christian
   love is the "bond of perfectness" (Col. 3:14), and the
   influences of the Spirit are the "bond of peace" (Eph. 4:3).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bond, CO
  Zip code(s): 80423
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bond \Bond\ (b[o^]nd), n. [The same word as band. Cf. {Band},
   {Bend}.]
   1. That which binds, ties, fastens, or confines, or by which
      anything is fastened or bound, as a cord, chain, etc.; a
      band; a ligament; a shackle or a manacle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gnawing with my teeth my bonds in sunder,
            I gained my freedom.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. The state of being bound; imprisonment; captivity,
      restraint. ``This man doeth nothing worthy of death or of
      bonds.'' --Acts xxvi.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A binding force or influence; a cause of union; a uniting
      tie; as, the bonds of fellowship.
      [1913 Webster]

            A people with whom I have no tie but the common bond
            of mankind.                           --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Moral or political duty or obligation.
      [1913 Webster]

            I love your majesty
            According to my bond, nor more nor less. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) A writing under seal, by which a person binds
      himself, his heirs, executors, and administrators, to pay
      a certain sum on or before a future day appointed. This is
      a {single bond}. But usually a condition is added, that,
      if the obligor shall do a certain act, appear at a certain
      place, conform to certain rules, faithfully perform
      certain duties, or pay a certain sum of money, on or
      before a time specified, the obligation shall be void;
      otherwise it shall remain in full force. If the condition
      is not performed, the bond becomes forfeited, and the
      obligor and his heirs are liable to the payment of the
      whole sum. --Bouvier. --Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A financial instrument (of the nature of the ordinary
      legal bond) made by a government or a corporation for
      purpose of borrowing money; a written promise to pay a
      specific sum of money on or before a specified day, given
      in return for a sum of money; as, a government, city, or
      railway bond.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The state of goods placed in a bonded warehouse till the
      duties are paid; as, merchandise in bond.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Arch.) The union or tie of the several stones or bricks
      forming a wall. The bricks may be arranged for this
      purpose in several different ways, as in {English bond} or
      {block bond} (Fig. 1), where one course consists of bricks
      with their ends toward the face of the wall, called
      headers, and the next course of bricks with their lengths
      parallel to the face of the wall, called stretchers;
      Flemish bond (Fig.2), where each course consists of
      headers and stretchers alternately, so laid as always to
      break joints; Cross bond, which differs from the English
      by the change of the second stretcher line so that its
      joints come in the middle of the first, and the same
      position of stretchers comes back every fifth line;
      Combined cross and English bond, where the inner part of
      the wall is laid in the one method, the outer in the
      other.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Chem.) A unit of chemical attraction between atoms; as,
      oxygen has two bonds of affinity. Also called {chemical
      bond}. It is often represented in graphic formul[ae] by a
      short line or dash. See Diagram of {Benzene nucleus}, and
      {Valence}. Several types of bond are distinguished by
      chemists, as {double bond}, {triple bond}, {covalent
      bond}, {hydrogen bond}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   10. (Elec.) A heavy copper wire or rod connecting adjacent
       rails of an electric railway track when used as a part of
       the electric circuit.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. League; association; confederacy. [South Africa]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

             The Africander Bond, a league or association
             appealing to African, but practically to Boer,
             patriotism.                          --James Bryce.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Arbitration bond}. See under {Arbitration}.

   {Bond creditor} (Law), a creditor whose debt is secured by a
      bond. --Blackstone.

   {covalent bond}, an attractive force between two atoms of a
      molecule generated by the merging of an electron orbital
      of each atom into a combined orbital in the molecule. Such
      bonds vary in strength, but in molecules of substances
      typically encountered in human experience (as, water or
      alcohol) they are sufficiently strong to persist and
      maintain the identity and integrity of the molecule over
      appreciable periods of time. Each such bond satisfies one
      unit of {valence} for each of the atoms thus bonded.
      Contrasted with {hydrogen bond}, which is weaker and does
      not satisfy the valence of either atom involved.

   {double bond}, {triple bond}, a {covalent bond} which
      involves the merging of orbitals of two (or three)
      electrons on each of the two connected atoms, thus
      satisfying two (or three) units of valence on each of the
      bonded atoms. When two carbon atoms are thus bonded, the
      bond (and the compound) are said to be unsaturated.

   {Bond debt} (Law), a debt contracted under the obligation of
      a bond. --Burrows.

   {hydrogen bond}, a non-covalent bond between hydrogen and
      another atom, usually oxygen or nitrogen. It does not
      involve the sharing of electrons between the bonded atoms,
      and therefore does not satisfy the valence of either atom.
      Hydrogen bonds are weak (ca. 5 kcal/mol) and may be
      frequently broken and reformed in solution at room
      temperature.

   {Bond of a slate} or {lap of a slate}, the distance between
      the top of one slate and the bottom or drip of the second
      slate above, i. e., the space which is covered with three
      thicknesses; also, the distance between the nail of the
      under slate and the lower edge of the upper slate.

   {Bond timber}, timber worked into a wall to tie or strengthen
      it longitudinally.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Syn: Chains; fetters; captivity; imprisonment.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bond \Bond\ (b[o^]nd), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bonded}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Bonding}.]
   1. To place under the conditions of a bond; to mortgage; to
      secure the payment of the duties on (goods or merchandise)
      by giving a bond.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) To dispose in building, as the materials of a
      wall, so as to secure solidity.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bond \Bond\, n. [OE. bond, bonde, peasant, serf, AS. bonda,
   bunda, husband, bouseholder, from Icel. b[=o]ndi husbandman,
   for b[=u]andi, fr. b[=u]a to dwell. See {Boor}, {Husband}.]
   A vassal or serf; a slave. [Obs. or Archaic]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bond \Bond\, a.
   In a state of servitude or slavery; captive.
   [1913 Webster]

         By one Spirit are we all baptized . . . whether we be
         Jews or Gentiles, whether we be bond or free. --1 Cor.
                                                  xii. 13.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bond
     adj : held in slavery; "born of enslaved parents" [syn: {enslaved},
            {enthralled}, {in bondage}]
     n 1: an electrical force linking atoms [syn: {chemical bond}]
     2: a certificate of debt (usually interest-bearing or
        discounted) that is issued by a government or corporation
        in order to raise money; the issuer is required to pay a
        fixed sum annually until maturity and then a fixed sum to
        repay the principal [syn: {bond certificate}]
     3: a connection based on kinship or marriage or common
        interest; "the shifting alliances within a large family";
        "their friendship constitutes a powerful bond between
        them" [syn: {alliance}]
     4: (criminal law) money that must be forfeited by the bondsman
        if an accused person fails to appear in court for trial;
        "the judge set bail at $10,000"; "a $10,000 bond was
        furnished by an alderman" [syn: {bail}, {bail bond}]
     5: a restraint that confines or restricts freedom (especially
        something used to tie down or restrain a prisoner) [syn: {shackle},
         {hamper}, {trammel}, {trammels}]
     6: a connection that fastens things together [syn: {attachment}]
     7: a superior quality of strong durable white writing paper;
        originally made for printing documents [syn: {bond paper}]
     8: United States civil rights leader who was elected to the
        legislature in Georgia but was barred from taking his seat
        because he opposed the Vietnam War (born 1940) [syn: {Julian
        Bond}]
     9: British secret operative 007 in novels by Ian Fleming [syn:
        {James Bond}]
     10: the property of sticking together (as of glue and wood) or
         the joining of surfaces of different composition [syn: {adhesiveness},
          {adhesion}, {adherence}]
     v 1: stick to firmly; "Will this wallpaper adhere to the wall?"
          [syn: {adhere}, {hold fast}, {bind}, {stick}, {stick to}]
     2: create social or emotional ties; "The grandparents want to
        bond with the child" [syn: {bind}, {tie}, {attach}]
     3: issue bonds on
     4: bring together in a common cause or emotion; "The death of
        their child had drawn them together" [syn: {bring together},
         {draw together}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
