<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>book</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>book</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Book
   This word has a comprehensive meaning in Scripture. In the Old
   Testament it is the rendering of the Hebrew word _sepher_, which
   properly means a "writing," and then a "volume" (Ex. 17:14;
   Deut. 28:58; 29:20; Job 19:23) or "roll of a book" (Jer. 36:2,
   4).
   
     Books were originally written on skins, on linen or cotton
   cloth, and on Egyptian papyrus, whence our word "paper." The
   leaves of the book were generally written in columns, designated
   by a Hebrew word properly meaning "doors" and "valves" (Jer.
   36:23, R.V., marg. "columns").
   
     Among the Hebrews books were generally rolled up like our
   maps, or if very long they were rolled from both ends, forming
   two rolls (Luke 4:17-20). Thus they were arranged when the
   writing was on flexible materials; but if the writing was on
   tablets of wood or brass or lead, then the several tablets were
   bound together by rings through which a rod was passed.
   
     A sealed book is one whose contents are secret (Isa. 29:11;
   Rev. 5:1-3). To "eat" a book (Jer. 15:16; Ezek. 2:8-10; 3:1-3;
   Rev. 10:9) is to study its contents carefully.
   
     The book of judgment (Dan. 7:10) refers to the method of human
   courts of justice as illustrating the proceedings which will
   take place at the day of God's final judgment.
   The book of the wars of the Lord (Num. 21:14), the book of
   Jasher (Josh. 10:13), and the book of the chronicles of the
   kings of Judah and Israel (2 Chr. 25:26), were probably ancient
   documents known to the Hebrews, but not forming a part of the
   canon.
   
     The book of life (Ps. 69:28) suggests the idea that as the
   redeemed form a community or citizenship (Phil. 3:20; 4:3), a
   catalogue of the citizens' names is preserved (Luke 10:20; Rev.
   20:15). Their names are registered in heaven (Luke 10:20; Rev.
   3:5).
   
     The book of the covenant (Ex. 24:7), containing Ex.
   20:22-23:33, is the first book actually mentioned as a part of
   the written word. It contains a series of laws, civil, social,
   and religious, given to Moses at Sinai immediately after the
   delivery of the decalogue. These were written in this "book."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>book</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rhapsody \Rhap"so*dy\, n.; pl. {Rhapsodies}. [F. rhapsodie, L.
   rhapsodia, Gr. "rapsw,di`a, fr. "rapsw,do`s a rhapsodist;
   "ra`ptein to sew, stitch together, unite + 'w,dh` a song. See
   {Ode}.]
   1. A recitation or song of a rhapsodist; a portion of an epic
      poem adapted for recitation, or usually recited, at one
      time; hence, a division of the Iliad or the Odyssey; --
      called also a {book}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A disconnected series of sentences or statements composed
      under excitement, and without dependence or natural
      connection; rambling composition. ``A rhapsody of words.''
      --Shak. ``A rhapsody of tales.'' --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.) A composition irregular in form, like an
      improvisation; as, Liszt's ``Hungarian Rhapsodies.''
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>book</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bell \Bell\, n. [AS. belle, fr. bellan to bellow. See {Bellow}.]
   1. A hollow metallic vessel, usually shaped somewhat like a
      cup with a flaring mouth, containing a clapper or tongue,
      and giving forth a ringing sound on being struck.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Bells have been made of various metals, but the best
         have always been, as now, of an alloy of copper and
         tin.
         [1913 Webster]

   {The Liberty Bell}, the famous bell of the Philadelphia State
      House, which rang when the Continental Congress declared
      the Independence of the United States, in 1776. It had
      been cast in 1753, and upon it were the words ``Proclaim
      liberty throughout all the land, to all the inhabitants
      thereof.''
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A hollow perforated sphere of metal containing a loose
      ball which causes it to sound when moved.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything in the form of a bell, as the cup or corol of a
      flower. ``In a cowslip's bell I lie.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Arch.) That part of the capital of a column included
      between the abacus and neck molding; also used for the
      naked core of nearly cylindrical shape, assumed to exist
      within the leafage of a capital.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. (Naut.) The strikes of the bell which mark the time;
      or the time so designated.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: On shipboard, time is marked by a bell, which is struck
         eight times at 4, 8, and 12 o'clock. Half an hour after
         it has struck ``eight bells'' it is struck once, and at
         every succeeding half hour the number of strokes is
         increased by one, till at the end of the four hours,
         which constitute a watch, it is struck eight times.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To bear away the bell}, to win the prize at a race where the
      prize was a bell; hence, to be superior in something.
      --Fuller.

   {To bear the bell}, to be the first or leader; -- in allusion
      to the bellwether or a flock, or the leading animal of a
      team or drove, when wearing a bell.

   {To curse by bell}, {book}, {and candle}, a solemn form of
      excommunication used in the Roman Catholic church, the
      bell being tolled, the book of offices for the purpose
      being used, and three candles being extinguished with
      certain ceremonies. --Nares.

   {To lose the bell}, to be worsted in a contest. ``In single
      fight he lost the bell.'' --Fairfax.

   {To shake the bells}, to move, give notice, or alarm. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Bell is much used adjectively or in combinations; as,
         bell clapper; bell foundry; bell hanger; bell-mouthed;
         bell tower, etc., which, for the most part, are
         self-explaining.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Bell arch} (Arch.), an arch of unusual form, following the
      curve of an ogee.

   {Bell cage}, or {Bell carriage} (Arch.), a timber frame
      constructed to carry one or more large bells.

   {Bell cot} (Arch.), a small or subsidiary construction,
      frequently corbeled out from the walls of a structure, and
      used to contain and support one or more bells.

   {Bell deck} (Arch.), the floor of a belfry made to serve as a
      roof to the rooms below.

   {Bell founder}, one whose occupation it is to found or cast
      bells.

   {Bell foundry}, or {Bell foundery}, a place where bells are
      founded or cast.

   {Bell gable} (Arch.), a small gable-shaped construction,
      pierced with one or more openings, and used to contain
      bells.

   {Bell glass}. See {Bell jar}.

   {Bell hanger}, a man who hangs or puts up bells.

   {Bell pull}, a cord, handle, or knob, connecting with a bell
      or bell wire, and which will ring the bell when pulled.
      --Aytoun.

   {Bell punch}, a kind of conductor's punch which rings a bell
      when used.

   {Bell ringer}, one who rings a bell or bells, esp. one whose
      business it is to ring a church bell or chime, or a set of
      musical bells for public entertainment.

   {Bell roof} (Arch.), a roof shaped according to the general
      lines of a bell.

   {Bell rope}, a rope by which a church or other bell is rung.
      

   {Bell tent}, a circular conical-topped tent.

   {Bell trap}, a kind of bell shaped stench trap.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>book</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Book \Book\ (b[oo^]k), n. [OE. book, bok, AS. b[=o]c; akin to
   Goth. b[=o]ka a letter, in pl. book, writing, Icel. b[=o]k,
   Sw. bok, Dan. bog, OS. b[=o]k, D. boek, OHG. puoh, G. buch;
   and fr. AS. b[=o]c, b[=e]ce, beech; because the ancient
   Saxons and Germans in general wrote runes on pieces of
   beechen board. Cf. {Beech}.]
   1. A collection of sheets of paper, or similar material,
      blank, written, or printed, bound together; commonly, many
      folded and bound sheets containing continuous printing or
      writing.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When blank, it is called a blank book. When printed,
         the term often distinguishes a bound volume, or a
         volume of some size, from a pamphlet.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: It has been held that, under the copyright law, a book
         is not necessarily a volume made of many sheets bound
         together; it may be printed on a single sheet, as music
         or a diagram of patterns. --Abbott.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A composition, written or printed; a treatise.
      [1913 Webster]

            A good book is the precious life blood of a master
            spirit, embalmed and treasured up on purpose to a
            life beyond life.                     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A part or subdivision of a treatise or literary work; as,
      the tenth book of ``Paradise Lost.''
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A volume or collection of sheets in which accounts are
      kept; a register of debts and credits, receipts and
      expenditures, etc.; -- often used in the plural; as, they
      got a subpoena to examine our books.

   Syn: ledger, leger, account book, book of account. [1913
        Webster + WordNet 1.5]

   5. Six tricks taken by one side, in the game of bridge or
      whist, being the minimum number of tricks that must be
      taken before any additional tricks are counted as part of
      the score for that hand; in certain other games, two or
      more corresponding cards, forming a set.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   6. (Drama) a written version of a play or other dramatic
      composition; -- used in preparing for a performance.

   Syn: script, playscript.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   7. a set of paper objects (tickets, stamps, matches, checks
      etc.) bound together by one edge, like a book; as, he
      bought a book of stamps.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   8. a book or list, actual or hypothetical, containing records
      of the best performances in some endeavor; a recordbook;
      -- used in the phrase

   {one for the book} or

   {one for the books}.

   Syn: record, recordbook.
        [PJC]

   9. (Sport) the set of facts about an athlete's performance,
      such as typical performance or playing habits or methods,
      that are accumulated by potential opponents as an aid in
      deciding how best to compete against that athlete; as, the
      book on Ted Williams suggests pitching to him low and
      outside.
      [PJC]

   10. (Finance) same as {book value}.
       [PJC]

   11. (Stock market) the list of current buy and sell orders
       maintained by a stock market specialist.
       [PJC]

   12. (Commerce) the purchase orders still outstanding and
       unfilled on a company's ledger; as, book to bill ratio.
       [PJC]

   Note: Book is used adjectively or as a part of many
         compounds; as, book buyer, bookrack, book club, book
         lore, book sale, book trade, memorandum book, cashbook.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Book account}, an account or register of debt or credit in a
      book.

   {Book debt}, a debt for items charged to the debtor by the
      creditor in his book of accounts.

   {Book learning}, learning acquired from books, as
      distinguished from practical knowledge. ``Neither does it
      so much require book learning and scholarship, as good
      natural sense, to distinguish true and false.'' --Burnet.

   {Book louse} (Zo["o]l.), one of several species of minute,
      wingless insects injurious to books and papers. They
      belong to the {Pseudoneuroptera}.

   {Book moth} (Zo["o]l.), the name of several species of moths,
      the larv[ae] of which eat books.

   {Book oath}, an oath made on {The Book}, or Bible.

   {The Book of Books}, the Bible.

   {Book post}, a system under which books, bulky manuscripts,
      etc., may be transmitted by mail.

   {Book scorpion} (Zo["o]l.), one of the false scorpions
      ({Chelifer cancroides}) found among books and papers. It
      can run sidewise and backward, and feeds on small insects.
      

   {Book stall}, a stand or stall, often in the open air, for
      retailing books.

   {Canonical books}. See {Canonical}.

   {In one's books}, in one's favor. ``I was so much in his
      books, that at his decease he left me his lamp.''
      --Addison.

   {To bring to book}.
       (a) To compel to give an account.
       (b) To compare with an admitted authority. ``To bring it
           manifestly to book is impossible.'' --M. Arnold.

   {by the book}, according to standard procedures; using the
      correct or usual methods.

   {cook the books}, make fallacious entries in or otherwise
      manipulate a financial record book for fraudulent
      purposes.

   {To curse by bell, book, and candle}. See under {Bell}.

   {To make book} (Horse Racing), to conduct a business of
      accepting or placing bets from others on horse races.

   {To make a book} (Horse Racing), to lay bets (recorded in a
      pocket book) against the success of every horse, so that
      the bookmaker wins on all the unsuccessful horses and
      loses only on the winning horse or horses.

   {off the books}, not recorded in the official financial
      records of a business; -- usually used of payments made in
      cash to fraudulently avoid payment of taxes or of
      employment benefits.

   {one for the book}, {one for the books}, something
      extraordinary, such as a record-breaking performance or a
      remarkable accomplishment.

   {To speak by the book}, to speak with minute exactness.

   {to throw the book at}, to impose the maximum fine or penalty
      for an offense; -- usually used of judges imposing
      penalties for criminal acts.

   {Without book}.
       (a) By memory.
       (b) Without authority.

   {to write the book}, to be the leading authority in a field;
      -- usually used in the past tense; as, he's not just an
      average expert, he wrote the book.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>book</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Book \Book\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Booked} (b[oo^]kt); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Booking}.]
   1. To enter, write, or register in a book or list.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let it be booked with the rest of this day's deeds.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To enter the name of (any one) in a book for the purpose
      of securing a passage, conveyance, or seat; to reserve[2];
      also, to make an arrangement for a reservation; as, to be
      booked for Southampton; to book a seat in a theater; to
      book a reservation at a restaurant.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. To mark out for; to destine or assign for; as, he is
      booked for the valedictory. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Here I am booked for three days more in Paris.
                                                  --Charles
                                                  Reade.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. to make an official record of a charge against (a suspect
      in a crime); -- performed by police.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>book</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>book
     n 1: a written work or composition that has been published
          (printed on pages bound together); "I am reading a good
          book on economics"
     2: physical objects consisting of a number of pages bound
        together; "he used a large book as a doorstop" [syn: {volume}]
     3: a record in which commercial accounts are recorded; "they
        got a subpoena to examine our books" [syn: {ledger}, {leger},
         {account book}, {book of account}]
     4: a number of sheets (ticket or stamps etc.) bound together on
        one edge; "he bought a book of stamps"
     5: a compilation of the known facts regarding something or
        someone; "Al Smith used to say, `Let's look at the
        record'"; "his name is in all the recordbooks" [syn: {record},
         {record book}]
     6: a major division of a long written composition; "the book of
        Isaiah"
     7: a written version of a play or other dramatic composition;
        used in preparing for a performance [syn: {script}, {playscript}]
     8: a collection of rules or prescribed standards on the basis
        of which decisions are made; "they run things by the book
        around here" [syn: {rule book}]
     9: the sacred writings of Islam revealed by God to the prophet
        Muhammad during his life at Mecca and Medina [syn: {Koran},
         {Quran}, {al-Qur'an}]
     10: the sacred writings of the Christian religions; "he went to
         carry the Word to the heathen" [syn: {Bible}, {Christian
         Bible}, {Good Book}, {Holy Scripture}, {Holy Writ}, {Scripture},
          {Word of God}, {Word}]
     v 1: record a charge in a police register; "The policeman booked
          her when she tried to solicit a man"
     2: arrange for and reserve (something for someone else) in
        advance; "reserve me a seat on a flight"; "The agent
        booked tickets to the show for the whole family"; "please
        hold a table at Maxim's" [syn: {reserve}, {hold}]
     3: engage for a performance; "Her agent had booked her for
        several concerts in Tokyo"
     4: register in a hotel booker
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
