<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>booster</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>booster</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Booster
     
        A {data-parallel} language.
     
        "The Booster Language", E. Paalvast, TR PL 89-ITI-B-18, Inst
        voor Toegepaste Informatica TNO, Delft, 1989.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>booster</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Booster \Boost"er\ (b[=oo]st"[~e]r), n.
   1. (Elec.) An instrument for regulating the electro-motive
      force in an alternating-current circuit; -- so called
      because used to ``boost'', or raise, the pressure in the
      circuit.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. an enthusiastic supporter.
      [PJC]

   3. the first stage of a multistage rocket, providing all or
      part of the driving force at lift-off and until the second
      stage ignites, whether or not the booster stage is
      detached after the fuel is spent. Also called {booster
      rocket}. In some cases, a booster has been used to assist
      the takeoff of airplanes.
      [PJC]

   4. (Med.) an immunizing medication given after an initial
      immunizing treatment, to provide increased or extended
      immunity. Also called {booster dose}. When in the form of
      an injection, it may be called a {booster shot}.
      [PJC]

   5. any auxiliary device or part of a device to provide
      increased power, force, or effectiveness, as with a
      pumping device.
      [PJC]

   6. (Mil.) an explosive charge which is more powerful than a
      primer, used in conjunction with a primer to assure
      detonation of the main charge. Integrated blasting caps
      containing separate compartments for primer and booster
      are used as detonators for certain explosives.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>booster</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>booster
     n 1: a person who backs a politician or a team etc.; "all their
          supporters came out for the game"; "they are friends of
          the library" [syn: {supporter}, {protagonist}, {champion},
           {admirer}, {friend}]
     2: someone who is an active supporter and advocate [syn: {promoter},
         {plugger}]
     3: a thief who steals goods that are in a store [syn: {shoplifter},
         {lifter}]
     4: the first stage of a multistage rocket [syn: {booster rocket},
         {booster unit}, {multistage rocket}, {takeoff booster}, {takeoff
        rocket}]
     5: an additional dose that makes sure the first dose was
        effective [syn: {booster dose}, {booster shot}, {recall
        dose}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
