<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>boot</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>boot
     
        &lt;operating system&gt; (from "{bootstrap}" or "to pull oneself up
        by one's bootstraps") To load and initialise the {operating
        system} on a computer.
     
        See {reboot}, {cold boot}, {warm boot}, {soft boot}, {hard
        boot}, {bootstrap}, {bootstrap loader}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-11-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boot \Boot\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Booted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Booting}.]
   1. To profit; to advantage; to avail; -- generally followed
      by it; as, what boots it?
      [1913 Webster]

            What booteth it to others that we wish them well,
            and do nothing for them?              --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            What subdued
            To change like this a mind so far imbued
            With scorn of man, it little boots to know. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

            What boots to us your victories?      --Southey.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To enrich; to benefit; to give in addition. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            And I will boot thee with what gift beside
            Thy modesty can beg.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boot \Boot\ (b[=oo]t), n. [OE. bot, bote, advantage, amends,
   cure, AS. b[=o]t; akin to Icel. b[=o]t, Sw. bot, Dan. bod,
   Goth. b[=o]ta, D. boete, G. busse; prop., a making good or
   better, from the root of E. better, adj. [root]255.]
   1. Remedy; relief; amends; reparation; hence, one who brings
      relief.
      [1913 Webster]

            He gaf the sike man his boote.        --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou art boot for many a bruise
            And healest many a wound.             --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Next her Son, our soul's best boot.   --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is given to make an exchange equal, or to make
      up for the deficiency of value in one of the things
      exchanged.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll give you boot, I'll give you three for one.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Profit; gain; advantage; use. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Then talk no more of flight, it is no boot. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To boot}, in addition; over and above; besides; as a
      compensation for the difference of value between things
      bartered.
      [1913 Webster]

            Helen, to change, would give an eye to boot. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man's heaviness is refreshed long before he comes
            to drunkenness, for when he arrives thither he hath
            but changed his heaviness, and taken a crime to
            boot.                                 --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boot \Boot\, n. [OE. bote, OF. bote, F. botte, LL. botta; of
   uncertain origin.]
   1. A covering for the foot and lower part of the leg,
      ordinarily made of leather.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An instrument of torture for the leg, formerly used to
      extort confessions, particularly in Scotland.
      [1913 Webster]

            So he was put to the torture, which in Scotland they
            call the boots; for they put a pair of iron boots
            close on the leg, and drive wedges between them and
            the leg.                              --Bp. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A place at the side of a coach, where attendants rode;
      also, a low outside place before and behind the body of
      the coach. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A place for baggage at either end of an old-fashioned
      stagecoach.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An apron or cover (of leather or rubber cloth) for the
      driving seat of a vehicle, to protect from rain and mud.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Plumbing) The metal casing and flange fitted about a pipe
      where it passes through a roof.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Boot catcher}, the person at an inn whose business it was to
      pull off boots and clean them. [Obs.] --Swift.

   {Boot closer}, one who, or that which, sews the uppers of
      boots.

   {Boot crimp}, a frame or device used by bootmakers for
      drawing and shaping the body of a boot.

   {Boot hook}, a hook with a handle, used for pulling on boots.
      

   {Boots and saddles} (Cavalry Tactics), the trumpet call which
      is the first signal for mounted drill.

   {Sly boots}. See {Slyboots}, in the Vocabulary.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boot \Boot\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Booted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Booting}.]
   1. To put boots on, esp. for riding.
      [1913 Webster]

            Coated and booted for it.             --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To punish by kicking with a booted foot. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boot \Boot\, v. i.
   To boot one's self; to put on one's boots.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Boot \Boot\, n.
   Booty; spoil. [Obs. or R.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>boot v.,n. [techspeak; from `by one's bootstraps'] To load and
   initialize the operating system on a machine. This usage is no longer
   jargon (having passed into techspeak) but has given rise to some
   derivatives that are still jargon.

   The derivative `reboot' implies that the machine hasn't been down for
   long, or that the boot is a {bounce} (sense 4) intended to clear some
   state of {wedgitude}. This is sometimes used of human thought processes,
   as in the following exchange: "You've lost me." "OK, reboot. Here's the
   theory...."

   This term is also found in the variants `cold boot' (from power-off
   condition) and `warm boot' (with the CPU and all devices already powered
   up, as after a hardware reset or software crash).

   Another variant: `soft boot', reinitialization of only part of a
   system, under control of other software still running: "If you're
   running the {mess-dos} emulator, control-alt-insert will cause a
   soft-boot of the emulator, while leaving the rest of the system
   running."

   Opposed to this there is `hard boot', which connotes hostility towards
   or frustration with the machine being booted: "I'll have to hard-boot
   this losing Sun." "I recommend booting it hard." One often hard-boots by
   performing a {power cycle}.

   Historical note: this term derives from `bootstrap loader', a short
   program that was read in from cards or paper tape, or toggled in from
   the front panel switches. This program was always very short (great
   efforts were expended on making it short in order to minimize the labor
   and chance of error involved in toggling it in), but was just smart
   enough to read in a slightly more complex program (usually from a card
   or paper tape reader), to which it handed control; this program in turn
   was smart enough to read the application or operating system from a
   magnetic tape drive or disk drive. Thus, in successive steps, the
   computer `pulled itself up by its bootstraps' to a useful operating
   state. Nowadays the bootstrap is usually found in ROM or EPROM, and
   reads the first stage in from a fixed location on the disk, called the
   `boot block'. When this program gains control, it is powerful enough to
   load the actual OS and hand control over to it.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>boot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>boot
     n 1: footwear that covers the whole foot and lower leg
     2: British term for the luggage compartment in a car
     3: the swift release of a store of affective force; "they got a
        great bang out of it"; "what a boot!"; "he got a quick
        rush from injecting heroin"; "he does it for kicks" [syn:
        {bang}, {charge}, {rush}, {flush}, {thrill}, {kick}]
     4: protective casing for something that resembles a leg
     5: an instrument of torture that is used to crush the foot and
        leg [syn: {iron boot}, {iron heel}]
     6: the act of delivering a blow with the foot; "he gave the
        ball a powerful kick"; "the team's kicking was excellent"
        [syn: {kick}, {kicking}]
     v 1: kick; give a boot to
     2: cause to load (an operating system) and start the initial
        processes; "boot your computer" [syn: {reboot}, {bring up}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
