<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>booth</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>booth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Booth
   a hut made of the branches of a tree. In such tabernacles Jacob
   sojourned for a season at a place named from this circumstance
   Succoth (Gen. 33:17). Booths were erected also at the feast of
   Tabernacles (q.v.), Lev. 23:42, 43, which commemorated the abode
   of the Israelites in the wilderness.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>booth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Booth \Booth\ (b[=oo][th]), n. [OE. bothe; cf. Icel. b[=u][eth],
   Dan. &amp; Sw. bod, MHG. buode, G. bude, baude; from the same
   root as AS. b[=u]an to dwell, E. boor, bower, be; cf. Bohem.
   bauda, Pol. buda, Russ. budka, Lith. buda, W. bwth, pl.
   bythod, Gael. buth, Ir. both.]
   1. A house or shed built of boards, boughs, or other slight
      materials, for temporary occupation. --Camden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A covered stall or other temporary structure in a fair, or
      market, or at a polling place.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. a partly enclosed area within a room for use of one or a
      small number of people, such as one in a restaurant having
      a table and seats, or one at an exhibition containing a
      display of products from one organization.
      [PJC]

   4. a small structure designed for the use of one person
      performing a special activity; as, a telephone booth; a
      highway toll booth; a projection booth; a guard booth.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>booth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>booth
     n 1: a table (in a restaurant or bar) surrounded by two
          high-backed benches
     2: small area set off by walls for special use [syn: {cubicle},
         {stall}, {kiosk}]
     3: United States actor and assassin of President Lincoln
        (1838-1865) [syn: {John Wilkes Booth}]
     4: a small shop at a fair; for selling goods or entertainment
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
