<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bounty</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bounty</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>BOUNTY, n.  The liberality of one who has much, in permitting one who
has nothing to get all that he can.

        A single swallow, it is said, devours ten millions of insects
    every year.  The supplying of these insects I take to be a signal
    instance of the Creator's bounty in providing for the lives of His
    creatures.
                                                    Henry Ward Beecher


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bounty</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bounty \Boun"ty\, n.; pl. {Bounties}. [OE. bounte goodness,
   kindness, F. bont['e], fr. L. bonitas, fr. bonus good, for
   older duonus; cf. Skr. duvas honor, respect.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Goodness, kindness; virtue; worth. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Nature set in her at once beauty with bounty.
                                                  --Gower.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Liberality in bestowing gifts or favors; gracious or
      liberal giving; generosity; munificence.
      [1913 Webster]

            My bounty is as boundless as the sea. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is given generously or liberally. ``Thy morning
      bounties.'' --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A premium offered or given to induce men to enlist into
      the public service; or to encourage any branch of
      industry, as husbandry or manufactures.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bounty jumper}, one who, during the latter part of the Civil
      War, enlisted in the United States service, and deserted
      as soon as possible after receiving the bounty. [Collog.]
      

   {Queen Anne's bounty} (Eng. Hist.), a provision made in Queen
      Anne's reign for augmenting poor clerical livings.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Munificence; generosity; beneficence.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bounty</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bounty
     n 1: payment or reward (especially from a government) for acts
          such as catching criminals or killing predatory animals
          or enlisting in the military [syn: {premium}]
     2: the property of copious abundance [syn: {amplitude}, {bountifulness}]
     3: generosity evidenced by a willingness to give freely [syn: {bounteousness}]
     4: a ship of the British navy; in 1789 part of the crew
        mutineed against their commander William Bligh and set him
        afloat in an open boat [syn: {H.M.S. Bounty}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
