<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bowl</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bowl</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bowl
   The sockets of the lamps of the golden candlestick of the
   tabernacle are called bowls (Ex. 25:31, 33, 34; 37:17, 19, 20);
   the same word so rendered being elsewhere rendered "cup" (Gen.
   44:2, 12, 16), and wine "pot" (Jer. 35:5). The reservoir for
   oil, from which pipes led to each lamp in Zechariah's vision of
   the candlestick, is called also by this name (Zech. 4:2, 3); so
   also are the vessels used for libations (Ex. 25:29; 37:16).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bowl</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bowl \Bowl\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bowled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bowling}.]
   1. To roll, as a bowl or cricket ball.
      [1913 Webster]

            Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel,
            And bowl the round nave down the hill of heaven.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To roll or carry smoothly on, or as on, wheels; as, we
      were bowled rapidly along the road.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pelt or strike with anything rolled.
      [1913 Webster]

            Alas, I had rather be set quick i' the earth,
            And bowled to death with turnips?     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To bowl} (a player) {out}, in cricket, to put out a striker
      by knocking down a bail or a stump in bowling.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bowl</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bowl \Bowl\ (b[=o]l), n. [OE. bolle, AS. bolla; akin to Icel.
   bolli, Dan. bolle, G. bolle, and perh. to E. boil a tumor.
   Cf. {Boll}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A concave vessel of various forms (often approximately
      hemispherical), to hold liquids, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Brought them food in bowls of basswood.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically, a drinking vessel for wine or other
      spirituous liquors; hence, convivial drinking.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The contents of a full bowl; what a bowl will hold.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The hollow part of a thing; as, the bowl of a spoon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bowl</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bowl \Bowl\ (b[=o]l), n. [F. boule, fr. L. bulla bubble, stud.
   Cf. {Bull} an edict, {Bill} a writing.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A ball of wood or other material used for rolling on a
      level surface in play; a ball of hard wood having one side
      heavier than the other, so as to give it a bias when
      rolled.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. An ancient game, popular in Great Britain, played with
      biased balls on a level plat of greensward.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like an uninstructed bowler, . . . who thinks to
            attain the jack by delivering his bowl
            straightforward upon it.              --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. The game of tenpins or bowling. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bowl</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bowl \Bowl\, v. i.
   1. To play with bowls.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To roll a ball on a plane, as at cricket, bowls, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To move rapidly, smoothly, and like a ball; as, the
      carriage bowled along.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bowl</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bowl
     n 1: a round vessel that is open at the top; used for holding
          fruit or liquids or for serving food
     2: a concave shape with an open top [syn: {trough}]
     3: a dish that is round and open at the top for serving foods
     4: the quantity contained in a bowl [syn: {bowlful}]
     5: a large structure for open-air sports or entertainments
        [syn: {stadium}, {arena}, {sports stadium}]
     6: a wooden ball (with flattened sides) used in the game of
        bowls
     7: a small round container that is open at the top for holding
        tobacco [syn: {pipe bowl}]
     v 1: roll (a ball)
     2: engage in the sport of bowling; "My parents like to bowl on
        Friday nights"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
