<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>brake</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brake \Brake\ (br[=a]k),
   imp. of {Break}. [Arhaic] --Tennyson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brake \Brake\, n. [OE. brake fern; cf. AS. bracce fern, LG.
   brake willow bush, Da. bregne fern, G. brach fallow; prob.
   orig. the growth on rough, broken ground, fr. the root of E.
   break. See {Break}, v. t., cf. {Bracken}, and 2d {Brake}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Bot.) A fern of the genus {Pteris}, esp. the {Pteris
      aquilina}, common in almost all countries. It has solitary
      stems dividing into three principal branches. Less
      properly: Any fern.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A thicket; a place overgrown with shrubs and brambles,
      with undergrowth and ferns, or with canes.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rounds rising hillocks, brakes obscure and rough,
            To shelter thee from tempest and from rain. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He stayed not for brake, and he stopped not for
            stone.                                --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cane brake}, a thicket of canes. See {Canebrake}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brake \Brake\ (br[=a]k), n. [OE. brake; cf. LG. brake an
   instrument for breaking flax, G. breche, fr. the root of E.
   break. See Break, v. t., and cf. {Breach}.]
   1. An instrument or machine to break or bruise the woody part
      of flax or hemp so that it may be separated from the
      fiber.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An extended handle by means of which a number of men can
      unite in working a pump, as in a fire engine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A baker's kneading though. --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A sharp bit or snaffle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pampered jades . . . which need nor break nor bit.
                                                  --Gascoigne.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A frame for confining a refractory horse while the smith
      is shoeing him; also, an inclosure to restrain cattle,
      horses, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            A horse . . . which Philip had bought . . . and
            because of his fierceness kept him within a brake of
            iron bars.                            --J. Brende.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That part of a carriage, as of a movable battery, or
      engine, which enables it to turn.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mil.) An ancient engine of war analogous to the crossbow
      and ballista.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Agric.) A large, heavy harrow for breaking clods after
      plowing; a drag.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A piece of mechanism for retarding or stopping motion by
      friction, as of a carriage or railway car, by the pressure
      of rubbers against the wheels, or of clogs or ratchets
      against the track or roadway, or of a pivoted lever
      against a wheel or drum in a machine.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Engin.) An apparatus for testing the power of a steam
       engine, or other motor, by weighing the amount of
       friction that the motor will overcome; a friction brake.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A cart or carriage without a body, used in breaking in
       horses.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. An ancient instrument of torture. --Holinshed.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Air brake}. See {Air brake}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Brake beam} or {Brake bar}, the beam that connects the brake
      blocks of opposite wheels.

   {Brake block}.
       (a) The part of a brake holding the brake shoe.
       (b) A brake shoe.

   {Brake shoe} or {Brake rubber}, the part of a brake against
      which the wheel rubs.

   {Brake wheel}, a wheel on the platform or top of a car by
      which brakes are operated.

   {Continuous brake} . See under {Continuous}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Break \Break\ (br[=a]k), v. t. [imp. {broke} (br[=o]k), (Obs.
   {Brake}); p. p. {Broken} (br[=o]"k'n), (Obs. {Broke}); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Breaking}.] [OE. breken, AS. brecan; akin to OS.
   brekan, D. breken, OHG. brehhan, G. brechen, Icel. braka to
   creak, Sw. braka, br["a]kka to crack, Dan. br[ae]kke to
   break, Goth. brikan to break, L. frangere. Cf. {Bray} to
   pound, {Breach}, {Fragile}.]
   1. To strain apart; to sever by fracture; to divide with
      violence; as, to break a rope or chain; to break a seal;
      to break an axle; to break rocks or coal; to break a lock.
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay open as by breaking; to divide; as, to break a
      package of goods.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To lay open, as a purpose; to disclose, divulge, or
      communicate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Katharine, break thy mind to me.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To infringe or violate, as an obligation, law, or promise.
      [1913 Webster]

            Out, out, hyena! these are thy wonted arts . . .
            To break all faith, all vows, deceive, betray.
                                                  --Milton
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To interrupt; to destroy the continuity of; to dissolve or
      terminate; as, to break silence; to break one's sleep; to
      break one's journey.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go, release them, Ariel;
            My charms I'll break, their senses I'll restore.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To destroy the completeness of; to remove a part from; as,
      to break a set.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To destroy the arrangement of; to throw into disorder; to
      pierce; as, the cavalry were not able to break the British
      squares.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To shatter to pieces; to reduce to fragments.
      [1913 Webster]

            The victim broke in pieces the musical instruments
            with which he had solaced the hours of captivity.
                                                  --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To exchange for other money or currency of smaller
      denomination; as, to break a five dollar bill.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To destroy the strength, firmness, or consistency of; as,
       to break flax.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To weaken or impair, as health, spirit, or mind.
       [1913 Webster]

             An old man, broken with the storms of state.
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To diminish the force of; to lessen the shock of, as a
       fall or blow.
       [1913 Webster]

             I'll rather leap down first, and break your fall.
                                                  --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To impart, as news or information; to broach; -- with to,
       and often with a modified word implying some reserve; as,
       to break the news gently to the widow; to break a purpose
       cautiously to a friend.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. To tame; to reduce to subjection; to make tractable; to
       discipline; as, to break a horse to the harness or
       saddle. ``To break a colt.'' --Spenser.
       [1913 Webster]

             Why, then thou canst not break her to the lute?
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. To destroy the financial credit of; to make bankrupt; to
       ruin.
       [1913 Webster]

             With arts like these rich Matho, when he speaks,
             Attracts all fees, and little lawyers breaks.
                                                  --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. To destroy the official character and standing of; to
       cashier; to dismiss.
       [1913 Webster]

             I see a great officer broken.        --Swift.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: With prepositions or adverbs: 
         [1913 Webster]

   {To break down}.
       (a) To crush; to overwhelm; as, to break down one's
           strength; to break down opposition.
       (b) To remove, or open a way through, by breaking; as, to
           break down a door or wall.

   {To break in}.
       (a) To force in; as, to break in a door.
       (b) To train; to discipline; as, a horse well broken in.
           

   {To break of}, to rid of; to cause to abandon; as, to break
      one of a habit.

   {To break off}.
       (a) To separate by breaking; as, to break off a twig.
       (b) To stop suddenly; to abandon. ``Break off thy sins by
           righteousness.'' --Dan. iv. 27.

   {To break open}, to open by breaking. ``Open the door, or I
      will break it open.'' --Shak.

   {To break out}, to take or force out by breaking; as, to
      break out a pane of glass.

   {To break out a cargo}, to unstow a cargo, so as to unload it
      easily.

   {To break through}.
       (a) To make an opening through, as, as by violence or the
           force of gravity; to pass violently through; as, to
           break through the enemy's lines; to break through the
           ice.
       (b) To disregard; as, to break through the ceremony.

   {To break up}.
       (a) To separate into parts; to plow (new or fallow
           ground). ``Break up this capon.'' --Shak. ``Break up
           your fallow ground.'' --Jer. iv. 3.
       (b) To dissolve; to put an end to. ``Break up the
           court.'' --Shak.

   {To break} (one) {all up}, to unsettle or disconcert
      completely; to upset. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: With an immediate object: 
         [1913 Webster]

   {To break the back}.
       (a) To dislocate the backbone; hence, to disable totally.
       (b) To get through the worst part of; as, to break the
           back of a difficult undertaking.

   {To break bulk}, to destroy the entirety of a load by
      removing a portion of it; to begin to unload; also, to
      transfer in detail, as from boats to cars.

   {To break a code} to discover a method to convert coded
      messages into the original understandable text.

   {To break cover}, to burst forth from a protecting
      concealment, as game when hunted.

   {To break a deer} or {To break a stag}, to cut it up and
      apportion the parts among those entitled to a share.

   {To break fast}, to partake of food after abstinence. See
      {Breakfast}.

   {To break ground}.
       (a) To open the earth as for planting; to commence
           excavation, as for building, siege operations, and
           the like; as, to break ground for a foundation, a
           canal, or a railroad.
       (b) Fig.: To begin to execute any plan.
       (c) (Naut.) To release the anchor from the bottom.

   {To break the heart}, to crush or overwhelm (one) with grief.
      

   {To break a house} (Law), to remove or set aside with
      violence and a felonious intent any part of a house or of
      the fastenings provided to secure it.

   {To break the ice}, to get through first difficulties; to
      overcome obstacles and make a beginning; to introduce a
      subject.

   {To break jail}, to escape from confinement in jail, usually
      by forcible means.

   {To break a jest}, to utter a jest. ``Patroclus . . . the
      livelong day breaks scurril jests.'' --Shak.

   {To break joints}, to lay or arrange bricks, shingles, etc.,
      so that the joints in one course shall not coincide with
      those in the preceding course.

   {To break a lance}, to engage in a tilt or contest.

   {To break the neck}, to dislocate the joints of the neck.

   {To break no squares}, to create no trouble. [Obs.]

   {To break a path}, {road}, etc., to open a way through
      obstacles by force or labor.

   {To break upon a wheel}, to execute or torture, as a criminal
      by stretching him upon a wheel, and breaking his limbs
      with an iron bar; -- a mode of punishment formerly
      employed in some countries.

   {To break wind}, to give vent to wind from the anus.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To dispart; rend; tear; shatter; batter; violate;
        infringe; demolish; destroy; burst; dislocate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>brake
     n 1: a restraint used to slow or stop a vehicle
     2: any of various ferns of the genus Pteris having pinnately
        compound leaves and including several popular houseplants
     3: large coarse fern often several feet high; essentially weed
        ferns; cosmopolitan [syn: {bracken}, {pasture brake}, {Pteridium
        aquilinum}]
     4: an area thickly overgrown usually with one kind of plant
     v 1: stop travelling by applying a brake; "We had to brake
          suddenly when a chicken crossed the road"
     2: cause to stop by applying the brakes; "brake the car before
        you go into a curve"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
