<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>branches</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>branches</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Branch \Branch\, n.; pl. {Branches}. [OE. braunche, F. branche,
   fr. LL. branca claw of a bird or beast of prey; cf. Armor.
   brank branch, bough.]
   1. (Bot.) A shoot or secondary stem growing from the main
      stem, or from a principal limb or bough of a tree or other
      plant.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any division extending like a branch; any arm or part
      connected with the main body of thing; ramification; as,
      the branch of an antler; the branch of a chandelier; a
      branch of a river; a branch of a railway.
      [1913 Webster]

            Most of the branches, or streams, were dried up.
                                                  --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any member or part of a body or system; a distinct
      article; a section or subdivision; a department.
      ``Branches of knowledge.'' --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is a branch and parcel of mine oath. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Geom.) One of the portions of a curve that extends
      outwards to an indefinitely great distance; as, the
      branches of an hyperbola.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A line of family descent, in distinction from some other
      line or lines from the same stock; any descendant in such
      a line; as, the English branch of a family.
      [1913 Webster]

            His father, a younger branch of the ancient stock.
                                                  --Carew.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) A warrant or commission given to a pilot,
      authorizing him to pilot vessels in certain waters.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Branches of a bridle}, two pieces of bent iron, which bear
      the bit, the cross chains, and the curb.

   {Branch herring}. See {Alewife}.

   {Root and branch}, totally, wholly.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Bough; limb; shoot; offshoot; twig; sprig.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
