<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>brass</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brass
   which is an alloy of copper and zinc, was not known till the
   thirteenth century. What is designated by this word in Scripture
   is properly copper (Deut. 8:9). It was used for fetters (Judg.
   16:21; 2 Kings 25:7), for pieces of armour (1 Sam. 17:5, 6), for
   musical instruments (1 Chr. 15:19; 1 Cor. 13:1), and for money
   (Matt. 10:9).
   
     It is a symbol of insensibility and obstinacy in sin (Isa.
   48:4; Jer. 6:28; Ezek. 22:18), and of strength (Ps. 107:16;
   Micah 4:13).
   
     The Macedonian empire is described as a kingdom of brass (Dan.
   2:39). The "mountains of brass" Zechariah (6:1) speaks of have
   been supposed to represent the immutable decrees of God.
   
     The serpent of brass was made by Moses at the command of God
   (Num. 21:4-9), and elevated on a pole, so that it might be seen
   by all the people when wounded by the bite of the serpents that
   were sent to them as a punishment for their murmurings against
   God and against Moses. It was afterwards carried by the Jews
   into Canaan, and preserved by them till the time of Hezekiah,
   who caused it to be at length destroyed because it began to be
   viewed by the people with superstitious reverence (2 Kings
   18:4). (See {NEHUSHTAN}.)
   
     The brazen serpent is alluded to by our Lord in John 3:14, 15.
   (See {SERPENT}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brass \Brass\, n.; pl. {Brasses}. [OE. bras, bres, AS. br[ae]s;
   akin to Icel. bras cement, solder, brasa to harden by fire,
   and to E. braze, brazen. Cf. 1st &amp; 2d {Braze}.]
   1. An alloy (usually yellow) of copper and zinc, in variable
      proportion, but often containing two parts of copper to
      one part of zinc. It sometimes contains tin, and rarely
      other metals.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mach.) A journal bearing, so called because frequently
      made of brass. A brass is often lined with a softer metal,
      when the latter is generally called a white metal lining.
      See {Axle box}, {Journal Box}, and {Bearing}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Coin made of copper, brass, or bronze. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Provide neither gold, nor silver, nor brass in your
            purses, nor scrip for your journey.   --Matt. x. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Impudence; a brazen face. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. Utensils, ornaments, or other articles of brass.
      [1913 Webster]

            The very scullion who cleans the brasses.
                                                  --Hopkinson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A brass plate engraved with a figure or device.
      Specifically, one used as a memorial to the dead, and
      generally having the portrait, coat of arms, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. (Mining) Lumps of pyrites or sulphuret of iron, the
      color of which is near to that of brass.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The word brass as used in Sculpture language is a
         translation for copper or some kind of bronze.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: Brass is often used adjectively or in self-explaining
         compounds; as, brass button, brass kettle, brass
         founder, brass foundry or brassfoundry.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Brass band} (Mus.), a band of musicians who play upon wind
      instruments made of brass, as trumpets, cornets, etc.

   {Brass foil}, {Brass leaf}, brass made into very thin sheets;
      -- called also {Dutch gold}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>brass
     n 1: an alloy of copper and zinc
     2: a wind instrument that consists of a brass tube (usually of
        variable length) blown by means of a cup-shaped or
        funnel-shaped mouthpiece
     3: the persons (or committees or departments etc.) who make up
        a body for the purpose of administering something; "he
        claims that the present administration is corrupt"; "the
        governance of an association is responsible to its
        members"; "he quickly became recognized as a member of the
        establishment" [syn: {administration}, {governance}, {governing
        body}, {establishment}, {organization}, {organisation}]
     4: impudent aggressiveness; "I couldn't believe her boldness";
        "he had the effrontery to question my honesty" [syn: {boldness},
         {nerve}, {face}, {cheek}]
     5: an ornament or utensil made of brass
     6: the section of a band or orchestra that plays brass
        instruments [syn: {brass section}]
     7: a memorial made of brass [syn: {memorial tablet}, {plaque}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
