<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>breathe</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>breathe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Breathe \Breathe\, v. t.
   1. To inhale and exhale in the process of respiration; to
      respire.
      [1913 Webster]

            To view the light of heaven, and breathe the vital
            air.                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To inject by breathing; to infuse; -- with into.
      [1913 Webster]

            Able to breathe life into a stone.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the Lord God formed man of the dust of the
            ground, and breathed into his nostrils the breath of
            life.                                 --Gen. ii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To emit or utter by the breath; to utter softly; to
      whisper; as, to breathe a vow.
      [1913 Webster]

            He softly breathed thy name.          --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Or let the church, our mother, breathe her curse,
            A mother's curse, on her revolting son. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To exhale; to emit, as breath; as, the flowers breathe
      odors or perfumes.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To express; to manifest; to give forth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Others articles breathe the same severe spirit.
                                                  --Milner.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To act upon by the breath; to cause to sound by breathing.
      ``They breathe the flute.'' --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To promote free respiration in; to exercise.
      [1913 Webster]

            And every man should beat thee. I think thou wast
            created for men to breathe themselves upon thee.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To suffer to take breath, or recover the natural
      breathing; to rest; as, to breathe a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            A moment breathed his panting steed.  --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To put out of breath; to exhaust.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mr. Tulkinghorn arrives in his turret room, a little
            breathed by the journey up.           --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Phonetics) To utter without vocality, as the nonvocal
       consonants.
       [1913 Webster]

             The same sound may be pronounces either breathed,
             voiced, or whispered.                --H. Sweet.
       [1913 Webster]

             Breathed elements, being already voiceless, remain
             unchanged

   Note: [in whispering].                         --H. Sweet.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To breathe again}, to take breath; to feel a sense of
      relief, as from danger, responsibility, or press of
      business.

   {To breathe one's last}, to die; to expire.

   {To breathe a vein}, to open a vein; to let blood. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>breathe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Breathe \Breathe\ (br[=e][th]), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Breathed}
   (br[=e][th]d); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Breathing}.] [From {Breath}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To respire; to inhale and exhale air; hence;, to live. ``I
      am in health, I breathe.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Breathes there a man with soul so dead
            Who never to himself hath said,
            This is my own, my native land!       --Sir W. Scott
                                                  [The Lay of
                                                  the Last
                                                  Minstrel].
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. To take breath; to rest from action.
      [1913 Webster]

            Well! breathe awhile, and then to it again! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass like breath; noiselessly or gently; to exhale; to
      emanate; to blow gently.
      [1913 Webster]

            The air breathes upon us here most sweetly. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            There breathes a living fragrance from the shore.
                                                  --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>breathe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>breathe
     v 1: draw air into, and expel out of, the lungs; "I can breathe
          better when the air is clean"; "The patient is
          respiring" [syn: {take a breath}, {respire}, {suspire}]
     2: be alive; "Every creature that breathes"
     3: impart as if by breathing; "He breathed new life into the
        old house"
     4: allow the passage of air through; "Our new synthetic fabric
        breathes and is perfect for summer wear"
     5: utter or tell; "not breathe a word"
     6: manifest or evince; "She breathes the Christian spirit"
     7: take a short break from one's activities in order to relax
        [syn: {rest}, {catch one's breath}, {take a breather}]
     8: reach full flavor by absorbing air and being let to stand
        after having been uncorked; "This rare Bordeaux must be
        allowed to breathe for at least 2 hours"
     9: expel (gases or odors) [syn: {emit}, {pass off}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
