<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>breed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>breed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Breed \Breed\, n.
   1. A race or variety of men or other animals (or of plants),
      perpetuating its special or distinctive characteristics by
      inheritance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Twice fifteen thousand hearts of England's breed.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Greyhounds of the best breed.         --Carpenter.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Class; sort; kind; -- of men, things, or qualities.
      [1913 Webster]

            Are these the breed of wits so wondered at? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            This courtesy is not of the right breed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A number produced at once; a brood. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Breed is usually applied to domestic animals; species
         or variety to wild animals and to plants; and race to
         men.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>breed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Breed \Breed\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bred}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Breeding}.] [OE. breden, AS. br[=e]dan to nourish, cherish,
   keep warm, from br[=o]d brood; akin to D. broeden to brood,
   OHG. bruoten, G. br["u]ten. See {Brood}.]
   1. To produce as offspring; to bring forth; to bear; to
      procreate; to generate; to beget; to hatch.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet every mother breeds not sons alike. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If the sun breed maggots in a dead dog. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take care of in infancy, and through the age of youth;
      to bring up; to nurse and foster.
      [1913 Webster]

            To bring thee forth with pain, with care to breed.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Born and bred on the verge of the wilderness.
                                                  --Everett.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To educate; to instruct; to form by education; to train;
      -- sometimes followed by up.
      [1913 Webster]

            But no care was taken to breed him a Protestant.
                                                  --Bp. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

            His farm may not remove his children too far from
            him, or the trade he breeds them up in. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To engender; to cause; to occasion; to originate; to
      produce; as, to breed a storm; to breed disease.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lest the place
            And my quaint habits breed astonishment. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To give birth to; to be the native place of; as, a pond
      breeds fish; a northern country breeds stout men.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To raise, as any kind of stock.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To produce or obtain by any natural process. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Children would breed their teeth with less danger.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To engender; generate; beget; produce; hatch; originate;
        bring up; nourish; train; instruct.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>breed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Breed \Breed\, v. i.
   1. To bear and nourish young; to reproduce or multiply
      itself; to be pregnant.
      [1913 Webster]

            That they breed abundantly in the earth. --Gen.
                                                  viii. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mother had never bred before.     --Carpenter.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ant. Is your gold and silver ewes and rams?
            Shy. I can not tell. I make it breed as fast.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be formed in the parent or dam; to be generated, or to
      grow, as young before birth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To have birth; to be produced or multiplied.
      [1913 Webster]

            Heavens rain grace
            On that which breeds between them.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To raise a breed; to get progeny.
      [1913 Webster]

            The kind of animal which you wish to breed from.
                                                  --Gardner.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To breed in and in}, to breed from animals of the same stock
      that are closely related.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>breed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>breed
     n 1: a special lineage; "a breed of Americans"
     2: a special variety of domesticated animals within a species;
        "he experimented on a particular breed of white rats"; "he
        created a new strain of sheep" [syn: {strain}, {stock}]
     3: half-caste offspring of parents of different races
        (especially of white and Indian parents) [syn: {half-breed}]
     4: a lineage or race of people [syn: {strain}]
     v 1: call forth [syn: {engender}, {spawn}]
     2: copulate with a female, used especially of horses; "The
        horse covers the mare" [syn: {cover}]
     3: of plants or animals; "She breeds dogs"
     4: have young (animals); "pandas rarely breed in captivity"
        [syn: {multiply}]
     [also: {bred}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
