<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bridle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bridle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bridle
   Three Hebrew words are thus rendered in the Authorized Version.
   (1.) Heb. _mahsom'_ signifies a muzzle or halter or bridle, by
   which the rider governs his horse (Ps.39:1).
   
     (2.) _Me'theg_, rendered also "bit" in Ps. 32:9, which is its
   proper meaning. Found in 2 Kings 19:28, where the restraints of
   God's providence are metaphorically styled his "bridle" and
   "hook." God's placing a "bridle in the jaws of the people" (Isa.
   30:28; 37:29) signifies his preventing the Assyrians from
   carrying out their purpose against Jerusalem.
   
     (3.) Another word, _re'sen_, was employed to represent a
   halter or bridle-rein, as used Ps. 32:9; Isa. 30:28. In Job
   30:11 the restraints of law and humanity are called a bridle.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bridle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bridle \Bri"dle\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bridled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bridling}.]
   1. To put a bridle upon; to equip with a bridle; as, to
      bridle a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            He bridled her mouth with a silkweed twist. --Drake.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To restrain, guide, or govern, with, or as with, a bridle;
      to check, curb, or control; as, to bridle the passions; to
      bridle a muse. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Savoy and Nice, the keys of Italy, and the citadel
            in her hands to bridle Switzerland, are in that
            consolidation.                        --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To check; restrain; curb; govern; control; repress;
        master; subdue.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bridle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bridle \Bri"dle\, n. [OE. bridel, AS. bridel; akin to OHG.
   britil, brittil, D. breidel, and possibly to E. braid. Cf.
   {Bridoon}.]
   1. The head gear with which a horse is governed and
      restrained, consisting of a headstall, a bit, and reins,
      with other appendages.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A restraint; a curb; a check. --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Gun.) The piece in the interior of a gun lock, which
      holds in place the tumbler, sear, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Naut.)
      (a) A span of rope, line, or chain made fast as both ends,
          so that another rope, line, or chain may be attached
          to its middle.
      (b) A mooring hawser.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Bowline bridle}. See under {Bowline}.

   {Branches of a bridle}. See under {Branch}.

   {Bridle cable} (Naut.), a cable which is bent to a bridle.
      See 4, above.

   {Bridle hand}, the hand which holds the bridle in riding; the
      left hand.

   {Bridle path}, {Bridle way}, a path or way for saddle horses
      and pack horses, as distinguished from a road for
      vehicles.

   {Bridle port} (Naut.), a porthole or opening in the bow
      through which hawsers, mooring or bridle cables, etc., are
      passed.

   {Bridle rein}, a rein attached to the bit.

   {Bridle road}.
      (a) Same as {Bridle path}. --Lowell.
      (b) A road in a pleasure park reserved for horseback
          exercise.

   {Bridle track}, a bridle path.

   {Scolding bridle}. See {Branks}, 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: A check; restrain.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bridle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bridle \Bri"dle\, v. i.
   To hold up the head, and draw in the chin, as an expression
   of pride, scorn, or resentment; to assume a lofty manner; --
   usually with up. ``His bridling neck.'' --Wordsworth.
   [1913 Webster]

         By her bridling up I perceived she expected to be
         treated hereafter not as Jenny Distaff, but Mrs.
         Tranquillus.                             --Tatler.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bridle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bridle
     n 1: headgear for a horse; includes a headstall and bit and reins
          to give the rider or driver control
     2: the act of restraining power or action or limiting excess;
        "his common sense is a bridle to his quick temper" [syn: {check},
         {curb}]
     v 1: put a bridle on; "bridle horses"
     2: respond to the reins, as of horses
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
