<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>brush</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brush</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brush, CO (city, FIPS 9555)
  Location: 40.25675 N, 103.63230 W
  Population (1990): 4165 (1720 housing units)
  Area: 6.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 80723
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brush</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brush \Brush\ (br[u^]sh), n. [OE. brusche, OF. broche, broce,
   brosse, brushwood, F. brosse brush, LL. brustia, bruscia, fr.
   OHG. brusta, brust, bristle, G. borste bristle, b["u]rste
   brush. See {Bristle}, n., and cf. {Browse}.]
   1. An instrument composed of bristles, or other like
      material, set in a suitable back or handle, as of wood,
      bone, or ivory, and used for various purposes, as in
      removing dust from clothes, laying on colors, etc. Brushes
      have different shapes and names according to their use;
      as, clothes brush, paint brush, tooth brush, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The bushy tail of a fox.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) A tuft of hair on the mandibles.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Branches of trees lopped off; brushwood.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A thicket of shrubs or small trees; the shrubs and small
      trees in a wood; underbrush.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. land covered with brush[5]; in Australia, a dense growth
      of vegetation in good soil, including shrubs and trees,
      mostly small.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   7. (Elec.) A bundle of flexible wires or thin plates of
      metal, used to conduct an electrical current to or from
      the commutator of a dynamo, electric motor, or similar
      apparatus.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. The act of brushing; as, to give one's clothes a brush; a
      rubbing or grazing with a quick motion; a light touch; as,
      we got a brush from the wheel as it passed.
      [1913 Webster]

            [As leaves] have with one winter's brush
            Fell from their boughts.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A skirmish; a slight encounter; a shock or collision; as,
      to have a brush with an enemy; a brush with the law.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let grow thy sinews till their knots be strong,
            And tempt not yet the brushes of the war. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A short contest, or trial, of speed.
       [1913 Webster]

             Let us enjoy a brush across the country. --Cornhill
                                                  Mag.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Electrical brush}, a form of the electric discharge
      characterized by a brushlike appearance of luminous rays
      diverging from an electrified body.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brush</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brush \Brush\, v. i.
   To move nimbly in haste; to move so lightly as scarcely to be
   perceived; as, to brush by.
   [1913 Webster]

         Snatching his hat, he brushed off like the wind.
                                                  --Goldsmith.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brush</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Brush \Brush\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Brushed} (br[u^]sht); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Brushing}.] [OE. bruschen; cf. F. brosser. See
   {Brush}, n.]
   1. To apply a brush to, according to its particular use; to
      rub, smooth, clean, paint, etc., with a brush. ``A'
      brushes his hat o' mornings.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To touch in passing, or to pass lightly over, as with a
      brush.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some spread their sailes, some with strong oars
            sweep
            The waters smooth, and brush the buxom wave.
                                                  --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

            Brushed with the kiss of rustling wings. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To remove or gather by brushing, or by an act like that of
      brushing, or by passing lightly over, as wind; -- commonly
      with off.
      [1913 Webster]

            As wicked dew as e'er my mother brushed
            With raven's feather from unwholesome fen. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And from the boughts brush off the evil dew.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To brush aside}, to remove from one's way, as with a brush.
      

   {To brush away}, to remove, as with a brush or brushing
      motion.

   {To brush up}, to paint, or make clean or bright with a
      brush; to cleanse or improve; to renew.
      [1913 Webster]

            You have commissioned me to paint your shop, and I
            have done my best to brush you up like your
            neighbors.                            --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>brush</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>brush
     n 1: a dense growth of bushes [syn: {brushwood}, {coppice}, {copse},
           {thicket}]
     2: an implement that has hairs or bristles firmly set into a
        handle
     3: momentary contact [syn: {light touch}]
     4: conducts current between rotating and stationary parts of a
        generator or motor
     5: a minor short-term fight [syn: {clash}, {encounter}, {skirmish}]
     6: the act of brushing your teeth; "the dentist recommended two
        brushes a day" [syn: {brushing}]
     7: the act of brushing your hair; "he gave his hair a quick
        brush" [syn: {brushing}]
     8: contact with something dangerous or undesirable; "I had a
        brush with danger on my way to work"; "he tried to avoid
        any brushes with the police"
     v 1: rub with a brush, or as if with a brush; "Johnson brushed
          the hairs from his jacket"
     2: touch lightly and briefly; "He brushed the wall lightly"
     3: clean with a brush; "She brushed the suit before hanging it
        back into the closet"
     4: sweep across or over; "Her long skirt brushed the floor"; "A
        gasp swept cross the audience" [syn: {sweep}]
     5: remove with or as if with a brush; "brush away the crumbs";
        "brush the dust from the jacket"; "brush aside the
        objections"
     6: cover by brushing; "brush the bread with melted butter"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
