<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>buckle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>buckle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Buckle \Buc"kle\ (b[u^]k"k'l), v. i.
   1. To bend permanently; to become distorted; to bow; to curl;
      to kink.
      [1913 Webster]

            Buckled with the heat of the fire like parchment.
                                                  --Pepys.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bend out of a true vertical plane, as a wall.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To yield; to give way; to cease opposing. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The Dutch, as high as they seem, do begin to buckle.
                                                  --Pepys.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To enter upon some labor or contest; to join in close
      fight; to struggle; to contend.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bishop was as able and ready to buckle with the
            Lord Protector as he was with him.    --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

            In single combat thou shalt buckle with me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To buckle to}, to bend to; to engage with zeal.
      [1913 Webster]

            To make our sturdy humor buckle thereto. --Barrow.
      [1913 Webster]

            Before buckling to my winter's work.  --J. D.
                                                  Forbes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>buckle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Buckle \Buc"kle\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Buckled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Buckling}.] [OE. boclen, F. boucler. See {Buckle}, n.]
   1. To fasten or confine with a buckle or buckles; as, to
      buckle a harness.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bend; to cause to kink, or to become distorted.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To prepare for action; to apply with vigor and
      earnestness; -- formerly, generally used reflexively, but
      by mid 20th century, usually used with down; -- as, the
      programmers buckled down and worked late hours to finish
      the project in time for the promised delivery date.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Cartwright buckled himself to the employment.
                                                  --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To join in marriage. [Scot.] --Sir W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>buckle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Buckle \Buc"kle\, n. [OE. bocle buckle, boss of a shield, OF.
   bocle, F. boucle, boss of a shield, ring, fr. L. buccula a
   little cheek or mouth, dim. of bucca cheek; this boss or knob
   resembling a cheek.]
   1. A device, usually of metal, consisting of a frame with one
      more movable tongues or catches, used for fastening things
      together, as parts of dress or harness, by means of a
      strap passing through the frame and pierced by the tongue.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A distortion bulge, bend, or kink, as in a saw blade or a
      plate of sheet metal. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A curl of hair, esp. a kind of crisp curl formerly worn;
      also, the state of being curled.
      [1913 Webster]

            Earlocks in tight buckles on each side of a lantern
            face.                                 --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lets his wig lie in buckle for a whole half year.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A contorted expression, as of the face. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            'Gainst nature armed by gravity,
            His features too in buckle see.       --Churchill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>buckle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>buckle
     n 1: fastener that fastens together two ends of a belt or strap;
          often has loose prong
     2: a shape distorted by twisting or folding [syn: {warp}]
     v 1: fasten with a buckle or buckles [syn: {clasp}] [ant: {unbuckle}]
     2: fold or collapse; "His knees buckled" [syn: {crumple}]
     3: bend out of shape, as under pressure or from heat; "The
        highway buckled during the heatwave" [syn: {heave}, {warp}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
