<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bud</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bud \Bud\, v. t.
   To graft, as a plant with another or into another, by
   inserting a bud from the one into an opening in the bark of
   the other, in order to raise, upon the budded stock, fruit
   different from that which it would naturally bear.
   [1913 Webster]

         The apricot and the nectarine may be, and usually are,
         budded upon the peach; the plum and the peach are
         budded on each other.                    --Farm. Dict.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bud \Bud\ (b[u^]d), n. [OE. budde; cf. D. bot, G. butze, butz,
   the core of a fruit, bud, LG. butte in hagebutte, hainbutte,
   a hip of the dog-rose, or OF. boton, F. bouton, bud, button,
   OF. boter to bud, push; all akin to E. beat. See {Button}.]
   1. (Bot.) A small protuberance on the stem or branches of a
      plant, containing the rudiments of future leaves, flowers,
      or stems; an undeveloped branch or flower.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Biol.) A small protuberance on certain low forms of
      animals and vegetables which develops into a new organism,
      either free or attached. See {Hydra}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bud moth} (Zo["o]l.), a lepidopterous insect of several
      species, which destroys the buds of fruit trees; esp.
      {Tmetocera ocellana} and {Eccopsis malana} on the apple
      tree.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bud \Bud\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Budded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Budding}.]
   1. To put forth or produce buds, as a plant; to grow, as a
      bud does, into a flower or shoot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To begin to grow, or to issue from a stock in the manner
      of a bud, as a horn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be like a bud in respect to youth and freshness, or
      growth and promise; as, a budding virgin. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To sprout; germinate; blossom.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bud</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bud
     n 1: a partially opened flower
     2: a swelling on a plant stem consisting of overlapping
        immature leaves or petals
     v 1: develop buds; "The hibiscus is budding!"
     2: start to grow or develop; "a budding friendship"
     [also: {budding}, {budded}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
