<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bulb</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bulb \Bulb\ (b[u^]lb), n. [L. bulbus, Gr. bolbo`s: cf. F.
   bulbe.]
   1. (Bot.) A spheroidal body growing from a plant either above
      or below the ground (usually below), which is strictly a
      bud, consisting of a cluster of partially developed
      leaves, and producing, as it grows, a stem above, and
      roots below, as in the onion, tulip, etc. It differs from
      a corm in not being solid.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Anat.) A name given to some parts that resemble in shape
      certain bulbous roots; as, the bulb of the aorta.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bulb of the eye}, the eyeball.

   {Bulb of a hair}, the ``root,'' or part whence the hair
      originates.

   {Bulb of the spinal cord}, the medulla oblongata, often
      called simply bulb.

   {Bulb of a tooth}, the vascular and nervous papilla contained
      in the cavity of the tooth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An expansion or protuberance on a stem or tube, as the
      bulb of a thermometer, which may be of any form, as
      spherical, cylindrical, curved, etc. --Tomlinson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. a {light bulb}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bulb \Bulb\, v. i.
   To take the shape of a bulb; to swell.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bulb
     n 1: a modified bud consisting of a thickened globular
          underground stem serving as a reproductive structure
     2: electric lamp consisting of a glass bulb containing a wire
        filament (usually tungsten) that emits light when heated
        [syn: {light bulb}, {lightbulb}, {incandescent lamp}, {electric
        light}, {electric-light bulb}]
     3: a rounded part of a cylindrical instrument (usually at one
        end); "the bulb of a syringe"
     4: lower or hindmost part of the brain; continuous with spinal
        cord; (`bulb' is an old term for medulla oblongata); "the
        medulla oblongata is the most vital part of the brain
        because it contains centers controlling breathing and
        heart functioning" [syn: {medulla oblongata}, {medulla}]
     5: a rounded dilation or expansion in a canal or vessel or
        organ
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
