<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bulk</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bulk \Bulk\, n. [Icel. b[=a]lkr a beam, partition. Cf. {Balk},
   n. &amp; v.]
   A projecting part of a building. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Here, stand behind this bulk.            --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bulk \Bulk\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Bulked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bulking}.]
   To appear or seem to be, as to bulk or extent; to swell.
   [1913 Webster]

         The fame of Warburton possibly bulked larger for the
         moment.                                  --Leslie
                                                  Stephen.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bulk \Bulk\ (b[u^]lk), n. [OE. bulke, bolke, heap; cf. Dan. bulk
   lump, clod, OSw. bolk crowd, mass, Icel. b?lkast to be bulky.
   Cf. {Boll}, n., {Bile} a boil, {Bulge}, n.]
   1. Magnitude of material substance; dimensions; mass; size;
      as, an ox or ship of great bulk.
      [1913 Webster]

            Against these forces there were prepared near one
            hundred ships; not so great of bulk indeed, but of a
            more nimble motion, and more serviceable. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The main mass or body; the largest or principal portion;
      the majority; as, the bulk of a debt.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bulk of the people must labor, Burke told them,
            ``to obtain what by labor can be obtained.'' --J.
                                                  Morley.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) The cargo of a vessel when stowed.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The body. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            My liver leaped within my bulk.       --Turbervile.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Barrel bulk}. See under {Barrel}.

   {To break bulk} (Naut.), to begin to unload or more the
      cargo.

   {In bulk}, in a mass; loose; not inclosed in separate
      packages or divided into separate parts; in such shape
      that any desired quantity may be taken or sold.

   {Laden in bulk}, {Stowed in bulk}, having the cargo loose in
      the hold or not inclosed in boxes, bales, or casks.

   {Sale by bulk}, a sale of goods as they are, without weight
      or measure.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Size; magnitude; dimension; volume; bigness; largeness;
        massiveness.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fiber \Fi"ber\, Fibre \Fi"bre\,, n. [F. fibre, L. fibra.]
   1. One of the delicate, threadlike portions of which the
      tissues of plants and animals are in part constituted; as,
      the fiber of flax or of muscle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any fine, slender thread, or threadlike substance; as, a
      fiber of spun glass; especially, one of the slender
      rootlets of a plant. [WordNet sense 1]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. the inherent complex of attributes that determine a
      person's moral and ethical actions and reactions; sinew;
      strength; toughness; as, a man of real fiber. [WordNet
      sense 2]

   Syn: character, fibre.
        [1913 Webster + WordNet 1.5]

              Yet had no fibers in him, nor no force. --Chapman.
        [1913 Webster]

   4. A general name for the raw material, such as cotton, flax,
      hemp, etc., used in textile manufactures.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Nutrition) that portion of food composed of carbohydrates
      which are completely or partly indigestible, such as
      cellulose or pectin; it may be in an insoluble or a
      soluble form. It provides bulk to the solid waste and
      stimulates peristalsis in the intestine. It is found
      especially in grains, fruits, and vegetables. There is
      some medical evidence which indicates that diets high in
      fiber reduce the risk of colon cancer and reduce
      cholesterol levels in the blood. It is also called
      {dietary fiber}, {roughage}, or {bulk}.
      [PJC]

   6. a leatherlike material made by compressing layers of paper
      or cloth. [WordNet sense 3]

   Syn: fibre, vulcanized fiber.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   {Fiber gun}, a kind of steam gun for converting, wood, straw,
      etc., into fiber. The material is shut up in the gun with
      steam, air, or gas at a very high pressure which is
      afterward relieved suddenly by letting a lid at the muzzle
      fly open, when the rapid expansion separates the fibers.
      

   {Fiber plants} (Bot.), plants capable of yielding fiber
      useful in the arts, as hemp, flax, ramie, agave, etc.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bulk
     n 1: the property resulting from being or relating to the greater
          in number of two parts; the main part; "the majority of
          his customers prefer it"; "the bulk of the work is
          finished" [syn: {majority}] [ant: {minority}]
     2: the property of something that is great in magnitude; "it is
        cheaper to buy it in bulk"; "he received a mass of
        correspondence"; "the volume of exports" [syn: {mass}, {volume}]
     3: the property possessed by a large mass
     v 1: stick out or up; "The parcel bulked in the sack"
     2: cause to bulge or swell outwards [syn: {bulge}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
