<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bulletin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulletin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bulletin \Bul"le*tin\, n. [F. bulletin, fr. It. bullettino, dim.
   of bulletta, dim. of bulla, bolla, an edict of the pope, from
   L. bulla bubble. See {Bull} an edict.]
   1. A brief statement of facts respecting some passing event,
      as military operations or the health of some distinguished
      personage, issued by authority for the information of the
      public.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any public notice or announcement, especially of news
      recently received.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A periodical publication, especially one containing the
      proceeding of a society.
      [1913 Webster]

   {bulletin board}, a board on which announcements are put,
      particularly at newsrooms, newspaper offices, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulletin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flash \Flash\, n.; pl. {Flashes}.
   1. A sudden burst of light; a flood of light instantaneously
      appearing and disappearing; a momentary blaze; as, a flash
      of lightning.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A sudden and brilliant burst, as of wit or genius; a
      momentary brightness or show.
      [1913 Webster]

            The flash and outbreak of a fiery mind. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            No striking sentiment, no flash of fancy. --Wirt.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The time during which a flash is visible; an instant; a
      very brief period.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Persians and Macedonians had it for a flash.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A preparation of capsicum, burnt sugar, etc., for coloring
      and giving a fictitious strength to liquors.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. a lamp for providing intense momentary light to take a
      photograph; as, to take a picture without a flash.

   Syn: flashbulb, photoflash, flash lamp, flashgun.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   6. Same as {flashlight}. [informal]
      [PJC]

   7. (Journalism) A short news item providing recently received
      and usually preliminary information about an event that is
      considered important enough to interrupt normal
      broadcasting or other news delivery services; also called
      a {news flash} or {bulletin}.
      [PJC]

   {Flash light}, or {Flashing light}, a kind of light shown by
      lighthouses, produced by the revolution of reflectors, so
      as to show a flash of light every few seconds, alternating
      with periods of dimness. --Knight.

   {Flash in the pan}, the flashing of the priming in the pan of
      a flintlock musket without discharging the piece; hence,
      sudden, spasmodic effort that accomplishes nothing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bulletin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bulletin
     n : a brief report especially an official statement issued for
         immediate publication or broadcast
     v : make public by bulletin
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
