<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>burning</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>burning</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Burn \Burn\ (b[^u]rn), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Burned} (b[^u]rnd)
   or {Burnt} (b[^u]rnt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Burning}.] [OE.
   bernen, brennen, v. t., early confused with beornen, birnen,
   v. i., AS. b[ae]rnan, bernan, v. t., birnan, v. i.; akin to
   OS. brinnan, OFries. barna, berna, OHG. brinnan, brennan, G.
   brennen, OD. bernen, D. branden, Dan. br[ae]nde, Sw.
   br["a]nna, brinna, Icel. brenna, Goth. brinnan, brannjan (in
   comp.), and possibly to E. fervent.]
   1. To consume with fire; to reduce to ashes by the action of
      heat or fire; -- frequently intensified by up: as, to burn
      up wood. ``We'll burn his body in the holy place.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To injure by fire or heat; to change destructively some
      property or properties of, by undue exposure to fire or
      heat; to scorch; to scald; to blister; to singe; to char;
      to sear; as, to burn steel in forging; to burn one's face
      in the sun; the sun burns the grass.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To perfect or improve by fire or heat; to submit to the
      action of fire or heat for some economic purpose; to
      destroy or change some property or properties of, by
      exposure to fire or heat in due degree for obtaining a
      desired residuum, product, or effect; to bake; as, to burn
      clay in making bricks or pottery; to burn wood so as to
      produce charcoal; to burn limestone for the lime.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make or produce, as an effect or result, by the
      application of fire or heat; as, to burn a hole; to burn
      charcoal; to burn letters into a block.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To consume, injure, or change the condition of, as if by
      action of fire or heat; to affect as fire or heat does;
      as, to burn the mouth with pepper.
      [1913 Webster]

            This tyrant fever burns me up.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            This dry sorrow burns up all my tears. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the cold north wind bloweth, . . . it devoureth
            the mountains, and burneth the wilderness, and
            consumeth the ??ass as fire.          --Ecclus.
                                                  xliii. 20, 21.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Surg.) To apply a cautery to; to cauterize.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Chem.) To cause to combine with oxygen or other active
      agent, with evolution of heat; to consume; to oxidize; as,
      a man burns a certain amount of carbon at each
      respiration; to burn iron in oxygen.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To burn}, {To burn together}, as two surfaces of metal
      (Engin.), to fuse and unite them by pouring over them a
      quantity of the same metal in a liquid state.

   {To burn a bowl} (Game of Bowls), to displace it
      accidentally, the bowl so displaced being said to be
      burned.

   {To burn daylight}, to light candles before it is dark; to
      waste time; to perform superfluous actions. --Shak.

   {To burn one's fingers}, to get one's self into unexpected
      trouble, as by interfering the concerns of others,
      speculation, etc.

   {To burn out},
      (a) to destroy or obliterate by burning. ``Must you with
          hot irons burn out mine eyes?'' --Shak.
      (b) to force (people) to flee by burning their homes or
          places of business; as, the rioters burned out the
          Chinese businessmen.

   {To be burned out}, to suffer loss by fire, as the burning of
      one's house, store, or shop, with the contents.

   {To burn up}, {To burn down}, to burn entirely.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>burning</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Burning \Burn"ing\, n.
   The act of consuming by fire or heat, or of subjecting to the
   effect of fire or heat; the state of being on fire or
   excessively heated.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Burning fluid}, any volatile illuminating oil, as the
      lighter petroleums (naphtha, benzine), or oil of
      turpentine (camphine), but esp. a mixture of the latter
      with alcohol.

   {Burning glass}, a convex lens of considerable size, used for
      producing an intense heat by converging the sun's rays to
      a focus.

   {Burning house} (Metal.), the furnace in which tin ores are
      calcined, to sublime the sulphur and arsenic from the
      pyrites. --Weale.

   {Burning mirror}, a concave mirror, or a combination of plane
      mirrors, used for the same purpose as a burning glass.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Combustion; fire; conflagration; flame; blaze.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>burning</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Burning \Burn"ing\, a.
   1. That burns; being on fire; excessively hot; fiery.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Consuming; intense; inflaming; exciting; vehement;
      powerful; as, burning zeal.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like a young hound upon a burning scent. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Burning bush} (Bot.), an ornamental shrub ({Euonymus
      atropurpureus}), bearing a crimson berry.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>burning</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>burning
     adj 1: producing or having a painfully hot sensation; "begged for
            water to soothe his burning throat"
     2: intensely hot; "a burning fever"; "the burning sand" [syn: {burning(a)}]
     3: characterized by intense emotion; "ardent love"; "an ardent
        lover"; "a burning enthusiasm"; "a fervent desire to
        change society"; "a fervent admirer"; "fiery oratory"; "an
        impassioned appeal"; "a torrid love affair" [syn: {ardent},
         {burning(a)}, {fervent}, {fervid}, {fiery}, {impassioned},
         {perfervid}, {torrid}]
     4: lighted up by or as by fire or flame; "forests set ablaze
        (or afire) by lightning"; "even the car's tires were
        aflame"; "a night aflare with fireworks"; "candles alight
        on the tables"; "blazing logs in the fireplace"; "a
        burning cigarette"; "a flaming crackling fire"; "houses on
        fire" [syn: {ablaze(p)}, {afire(p)}, {aflame(p)}, {aflare(p)},
         {alight(p)}, {blazing}, {flaming}, {on fire(p)}]
     5: of immediate import; "burning issues of the day" [syn: {burning(a)}]
     6: consuming fuel; used in combination; "coal-burning (or
        wood-burning) stoves"
     n 1: the act of burning something; "the burning of leaves was
          prohibited by a town ordinance" [syn: {combustion}]
     2: pain that feels hot as if it were on fire [syn: {burn}]
     3: a process in which a substance reacts with oxygen to give
        heat and light [syn: {combustion}]
     4: execution by electricity [syn: {electrocution}]
     5: execution by fire [syn: {burning at the stake}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
