<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bursting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bursting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Burst \Burst\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Burst}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Bursting}. The past participle bursten is obsolete.] [OE.
   bersten, bresten, AS. berstan (pers. sing. berste, imp. sing.
   b[ae]rst, imp. pl. burston, p. p. borsten); akin to D.
   bersten, G. bersten, OHG. brestan, OS. brestan, Icel. bresta,
   Sw. brista, Dan. briste. Cf. {Brast}, {Break}.]
   1. To fly apart or in pieces; of break open; to yield to
      force or pressure, especially to a sudden and violent
      exertion of force, or to pressure from within; to explode;
      as, the boiler had burst; the buds will burst in spring.
      [1913 Webster]

            From the egg that soon
            Bursting with kindly rupture, forth disclosed
            Their callow young.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Often used figuratively, as of the heart, in reference
         to a surcharge of passion, grief, desire, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

               No, no, my heart will burst, an if I speak:
               And I will speak, that so my heart may burst.
                                                  --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To exert force or pressure by which something is made
      suddenly to give way; to break through obstacles or
      limitations; hence, to appear suddenly and unexpectedly or
      unaccountably, or to depart in such manner; -- usually
      with some qualifying adverb or preposition, as forth, out,
      away, into, upon, through, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tears, such as angels weep, burst forth. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            And now you burst (ah cruel!) from my arms. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            A resolved villain
            Whose bowels suddenly burst out.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            We were the first that ever burst
            Into that silent sea.                 --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            To burst upon him like an earthquake. --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bursting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bursting
     adj : (of munitions) going off; "bursting bombs"; "an exploding
           nuclear device"; "a spectacular display of detonating
           anti-tank mines" [syn: {detonating}, {exploding}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
