<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>bury</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bury</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bury \Bur"y\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Buried}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Burying}.] [OE. burien, birien, berien, AS. byrgan; akin to
   beorgan to protect, OHG. bergan, G. bergen, Icel. bjarga, Sw.
   berga, Dan. bierge, Goth. ba['i]rgan. [root]95. Cf.
   {Burrow}.]
   1. To cover out of sight, either by heaping something over,
      or by placing within something, as earth, etc.; to conceal
      by covering; to hide; as, to bury coals in ashes; to bury
      the face in the hands.
      [1913 Webster]

            And all their confidence
            Under the weight of mountains buried deep. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically: To cover out of sight, as the body of a
      deceased person, in a grave, a tomb, or the ocean; to
      deposit (a corpse) in its resting place, with funeral
      ceremonies; to inter; to inhume.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lord, suffer me first to go and bury my father.
                                                  --Matt. viii.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll bury thee in a triumphant grave. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To hide in oblivion; to put away finally; to abandon; as,
      to bury strife.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give me a bowl of wine
            In this I bury all unkindness, Cassius. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Burying beetle} (Zo["o]l.), the general name of many species
      of beetles, of the tribe {Necrophaga}; the sexton beetle;
      -- so called from their habit of burying small dead
      animals by digging away the earth beneath them. The
      larv[ae] feed upon decaying flesh, and are useful
      scavengers.

   {To bury the hatchet}, to lay aside the instruments of war,
      and make peace; -- a phrase used in allusion to the custom
      observed by the North American Indians, of burying a
      tomahawk when they conclude a peace.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To intomb; inter; inhume; inurn; hide; cover; conceal;
        overwhelm; repress.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bury</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bury \Bur"y\ (b[e^]r"r[y^]), n. [See 1st {Borough}.]
   1. A borough; a manor; as, the Bury of St. Edmond's;

   Note: used as a termination of names of places; as,
         Canterbury, Shrewsbury.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A manor house; a castle. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To this very day, the chief house of a manor, or the
            lord's seat, is called bury, in some parts of
            England.                              --Miege.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>bury</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>bury
     v 1: cover from sight; "Afghani women buried under their burkas"
     2: place in a grave or tomb; "Stalin was buried behind the
        Kremlin wall on Red Square"; "The pharaos were entombed in
        the pyramids"; "My grandfather was laid to rest last
        Sunday" [syn: {entomb}, {inhume}, {inter}, {lay to rest}]
     3: place in the earth and cover with soil; "They buried the
        stolen goods"
     4: enclose or envelop completely, as if by swallowing; "The
        huge waves swallowed the small boat and it sank shortly
        thereafter" [syn: {immerse}, {swallow}, {swallow up}, {eat
        up}]
     5: embed deeply; "She sank her fingers into the soft sand"; "He
        buried his head in her lap" [syn: {sink}]
     6: dismiss from the mind; stop remembering; "i tried to bury
        these unpleasant memories" [syn: {forget}] [ant: {remember}]
     [also: {buried}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
