<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>icon</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>icon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>icon
     
        &lt;graphics&gt; A small picture intended to represent something (a
        file, directory, or action) in a {graphical user interface}.
        When an icon is clicked on, some action is performed such as
        opening a directory or aborting a file transfer.
     
        Icons are usually stored as {bitmap} images.  {Microsoft
        Windows} uses a special bitmap format with file name extension
        ".ico" as well as embedding icons in executable (".exe") and
        {Dynamically Linked Library} (DLL) files.
     
        The term originates from {Alan Kay}'s theory for designing
        interfaces which was primarily based on the work of Jerome
        Bruner.  Bruner's second developmental stage, iconic, uses a
        system of representation that depends on visual or other
        sensory organization and upon the use of summarising images.
     
        {IEEE publication
       
     (http://www.ieee.org/organizations/history_center/cht_papers/Barnes.pdf)}.
     
        [What MS tool can create .ico files?]
     
        (2003-08-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>icon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Icon
     
        &lt;language&gt; A descendant of {SNOBOL4} with {Pascal}-like
        syntax, produced by Griswold in the 1970's.  Icon is a
        general-purpose language with special features for string
        scanning.  It has dynamic types: records, sets, lists,
        strings, tables.  If has some {object oriented} features but
        no {modules} or {exception}s.  It has a primitive {Unix}
        interface.
     
        The central theme of Icon is the generator: when an expression
        is evaluated it may be suspended and later resumed, producing
        a result sequence of values until it fails.  Resumption takes
        place implicitly in two contexts: iteration which is
        syntactically loop-like ('every-do'), and goal-directed
        evaluation in which a conditional expression automatically
        attempts to produce at least one result.  Expressions that
        fail are used in lieu of Booleans.  Data {backtracking} is
        supported by a reversible {assignment}.  Icon also has
        {co-expression}s, which can be explicitly resumed at any time.
     
        Version 8.8 by Ralph Griswold &lt;ralph@cs.arizona.edu&gt; includes
        an {interpreter}, a compiler (for some {platform}s) and a
        library (v8.8).  Icon has been ported to {Amiga}, {Atari},
        {CMS}, {Macintosh}, {Macintosh/MPW}, {MS-DOS}, {MVS}, {OS/2},
        {Unix}, {VMS}, {Acorn}.
     
        See also {Ibpag2}.
     
        {(ftp://cs.arizona.edu/icon/)}, {MS-DOS FTP
        (ftp://bellcore.com norman/iconexe.zip)}.
     
        {Usenet} newsgroup: {news:comp.lang.icon}.
     
        E-mail: &lt;icon-project@cs.arizona.edu&gt;, &lt;mengarini@delphi.com&gt;.
     
        Mailing list: icon-group@arizona.edu.
     
        ["The Icon Programmming Language", Ralph E. Griswold and Madge
        T. Griswold, Prentice Hall, seond edition, 1990].
     
        ["The Implementation of the Icon Programmming Language", Ralph
        E. Griswold and Madge T. Griswold, Princeton University Press
        1986].
     
        (1992-08-21)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>icon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>icon \i"con\ ([imac]"k[o^]n), n. [Also spelled {ikon}.] [L., fr.
   Gr. e'ikw`n.]
   1. An image or representation; a portrait or pretended
      portrait.
      [1913 Webster]

            Netherlands whose names and icons are published.
                                                  --Hakewill.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Gr. Ch.) A sacred picture representing the Virgin Mary,
      Christ, a saint, or a martyr, and having the same function
      as an image of such a person in the Latin Church. The term
      is used especially for a highly stylized and
      conventionalized representation of a holy person, rich in
      symbolism and used in devotional services in many of the
      eastern Orthodox churches, especially the Greek and
      Russian Orthodox Churches.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   3. a symbol, especially a symbol whose form suggests its
      meaning or the object it represents.
      [PJC]

   4. (Computers) a graphical symbol for a data object whose
      form suggests the nature or function of the object;
      especially, such a symbol as viewed on the computer
      screen.

   Note: In a graphical user interface, pointing to and clicking
         on an icon may cause any of several types of actions,
         such as opening a file or executing a program,
         depending on how the icon properties are defined.
         [PJC]

   5. any object of uncritical devotion.
      [PJC]

            The former congresswoman and Vice-Presidential
            candidate Geraldine Ferraro is still an icon to many
            party members.                        --The New York
                                                  Times, April
                                                  16, 1998
      [PJC]

   6. an outstanding example of something which has come to
      represent the class of things to which it belongs; a
      paragon; used of persons as well as objects.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>icon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>icon
     n 1: (computer science) a graphic symbol (usually a simple
          picture) that denotes a program or a command or a data
          file or a concept in a graphical user interface
     2: a visual representation (of an object or scene or person or
        abstraction) produced on a surface; "they showed us the
        pictures of their wedding"; "a movie is a series of images
        projected so rapidly that the eye integrates them" [syn: {picture},
         {image}, {ikon}]
     3: a conventional religious painting in oil on a small wooden
        panel; venerated in the Eastern Church [syn: {ikon}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
