<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>if</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>if</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Condition \Con*di"tion\, n. [F., fr. L. conditio (better
   condicio) agreement, compact, condition; con- + a root
   signifying to show, point out, akin to dicere to say, dicare
   to proclaim, dedicate. See {Teach}, {Token}.]
   1. Mode or state of being; state or situation with regard to
      external circumstances or influences, or to physical or
      mental integrity, health, strength, etc.; predicament;
      rank; position, estate.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am in my condition
            A prince, Miranda; I do think, a king. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And O, what man's condition can be worse
            Than his whom plenty starves and blessings curse?
                                                  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

            The new conditions of life.           --Darwin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Essential quality; property; attribute.
      [1913 Webster]

            It seemed to us a condition and property of divine
            powers and beings to be hidden and unseen to others.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Temperament; disposition; character. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The condition of a saint and the complexion of a
            devil.                                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which must exist as the occasion or concomitant of
      something else; that which is requisite in order that
      something else should take effect; an essential
      qualification; stipulation; terms specified.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had as lief take her dowry with this condition, to
            be whipped at the high cross every morning. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many are apt to believe remission of sins, but they
            believe it without the condition of repentance.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) A clause in a contract, or agreement, which has for
      its object to suspend, to defeat, or in some way to
      modify, the principal obligation; or, in case of a will,
      to suspend, revoke, or modify a devise or bequest. It is
      also the case of a future uncertain event, which may or
      may not happen, and on the occurrence or non-occurrence of
      which, the accomplishment, recission, or modification of
      an obligation or testamentary disposition is made to
      depend. --Blount. Tomlins. Bouvier. Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Equation of condition}. (Math.) See under {Equation}.

   {On condition} or {Upon condition} (that), used for {if} in
      introducing conditional sentences. ``Upon condition thou
      wilt swear to pay him tribute . . . thou shalt be placed
      as viceroy under him.'' --Shak.

   {Conditions of sale}, the terms on which it is proposed to
      sell property by auction; also, the instrument containing
      or expressing these terms.

   Syn: State; situation; circumstances; station; case; mode;
        plight; predicament; stipulation; qualification;
        requisite; article; provision; arrangement. See {State}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>if</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>If \If\, conj. [OE. if, gif, AS. gif; akin to OFries. ief, gef,
   ef, OS. ef, of, D. of, or, whether, if, G. ob whether, if,
   OHG. oba, ibu, Icel. ef, Goth. iba, ibai, an interrogative
   particle; properly a case form of a noun meaning, doubt (cf.
   OHG. iba doubt, condition, Icel. if, ef, ifi, efi), and
   therefore orig. meaning, on condition that.]
   1. In case that; granting, allowing, or supposing that; --
      introducing a condition or supposition.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tisiphone, that oft hast heard my prayer,
            Assist, if [OE]dipus deserve thy care. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            If thou be the Son of God, command that these stones
            be made bread.                        --Matt. iv. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Whether; -- in dependent questions.
      [1913 Webster]

            Uncertain if by augury or chance.     --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            She doubts if two and two make four.  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   {As if}, {But if}. See under {As}, {But}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>if</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>IF
     Information Flow (IN)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
