<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>illusion</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>illusion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Illusion \Il*lu"sion\, n. [F. illusion, L. illusio, fr.
   illudere, illusum, to illude. See {Illude}.]
   1. An unreal image presented to the bodily or mental vision;
      a deceptive appearance; a false show; mockery;
      hallucination.
      [1913 Webster]

            To cheat the eye with blear illusions. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: Anything agreeably fascinating and charming;
      enchantment; witchery; glamour.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye soft illusions, dear deceits, arise! --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Physiol.) A sensation originated by some external object,
      but so modified as in any way to lead to an erroneous
      perception; as when the rolling of a wagon is mistaken for
      thunder.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Some modern writers distinguish between an illusion and
         hallucination, regarding the former as originating with
         some external object, and the latter as having no
         objective occasion whatever.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. A plain, delicate lace, usually of silk, used for veils,
      scarfs, dresses, etc.

   Syn: Delusion; mockery; deception; chimera; fallacy. See
        {Delusion}. {Illusion}, {Delusion}. Illusion refers
        particularly to errors of the sense; delusion to false
        hopes or deceptions of the mind. An optical deception is
        an illusion; a false opinion is a delusion. --E.
        Edwards.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>illusion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>illusion
     n 1: an erroneous mental representation [syn: {semblance}]
     2: something many people believe that is false; "they have the
        illusion that I am very wealthy" [syn: {fantasy}, {phantasy},
         {fancy}]
     3: the act of deluding; deception by creating illusory ideas
        [syn: {delusion}, {head game}]
     4: an illusory feat; considered magical by naive observers
        [syn: {magic trick}, {conjuring trick}, {trick}, {magic},
        {legerdemain}, {conjuration}, {deception}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
