<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>in</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>IN':ARDS:, n.  The stomach, heart, soul and other bowels.  Many eminent
investigators do not class the soul as an in'ard, but that acute
observer and renowned authority, Dr. Gunsaulus, is persuaded that the
mysterious organ known as the spleen is nothing less than our
important part.  To the contrary, Professor Garrett P. Servis holds
that man's soul is that prolongation of his spinal marrow which forms
the pith of his no tail; and for demonstration of his faith points
confidently to the fact that no tailed animals have no souls. 
Concerning these two theories, it is best to suspend judgment by
believing both.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>in
     
        &lt;networking&gt; The {country code} for India.
     
        (1999-01-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>In- \In-\ ([i^]n-). [L. in-; akin to E. un-. See {Un-}.]
   An inseparable prefix, or particle, meaning not, non-, un-
   as, inactive, incapable, inapt. In- regularly becomes il-
   before l, ir- before r, and im- before a labial.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-in \-in\
   A suffix. See the Note under {-ine}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>In \In\, prep. [AS. in; akin to D. &amp; G. in, Icel. [=i], Sw. &amp;
   Dan. i, OIr. &amp; L. in, Gr. 'en. [root]197. Cf. 1st {In-},
   {Inn}.]
   The specific signification of in is situation or place with
   respect to surrounding, environment, encompassment, etc. It
   is used with verbs signifying being, resting, or moving
   within limits, or within circumstances or conditions of any
   kind conceived of as limiting, confining, or investing,
   either wholly or in part. In its different applications, it
   approaches some of the meanings of, and sometimes is
   interchangeable with, within, into, on, at, of, and among. It
   is used: 
   [1913 Webster]

   1. With reference to space or place; as, he lives in Boston;
      he traveled in Italy; castles in the air.
      [1913 Webster]

            The babe lying in a manger.           --Luke ii. 16.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy sun sets weeping in the lowly west. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Situated in the forty-first degree of latitude.
                                                  --Gibbon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Matter for censure in every page.     --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. With reference to circumstances or conditions; as, he is
      in difficulties; she stood in a blaze of light. ``Fettered
      in amorous chains.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wrapt in sweet sounds, as in bright veils.
                                                  --Shelley.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. With reference to a whole which includes or comprises the
      part spoken of; as, the first in his family; the first
      regiment in the army.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nine in ten of those who enter the ministry.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. With reference to physical surrounding, personal states,
      etc., abstractly denoted; as, I am in doubt; the room is
      in darkness; to live in fear.
      [1913 Webster]

            When shall we three meet again,
            In thunder, lightning, or in rain?    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. With reference to character, reach, scope, or influence
      considered as establishing a limitation; as, to be in
      one's favor. ``In sight of God's high throne.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sounds inharmonious in themselves, and harsh.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. With reference to movement or tendency toward a certain
      limit or environment; -- sometimes equivalent to into; as,
      to put seed in the ground; to fall in love; to end in
      death; to put our trust in God.
      [1913 Webster]

            He would not plunge his brother in despair.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            She had no jewels to deposit in their caskets.
                                                  --Fielding.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. With reference to a limit of time; as, in an hour; it
      happened in the last century; in all my life.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In as much as}, or {Inasmuch as}, in the degree that; in
      like manner as; in consideration that; because that;
      since. See {Synonym} of {Because}, and cf. {For as much
      as}, under {For}, prep.

   {In that}, because; for the reason that. ``Some things they
      do in that they are men . . .; some things in that they
      are men misled and blinded with error.'' --Hooker.

   {In the name of}, in behalf of; on the part of; by authority;
      as, it was done in the name of the people; -- often used
      in invocation, swearing, praying, and the like.

   {To be in for it}.
      (a) To be in favor of a thing; to be committed to a
          course.
      (b) To be unable to escape from a danger, penalty, etc.
          [Colloq.]

   {To be in with} or {To keep in with}.
      (a) To be close or near; as, to keep a ship in with the
          land.
      (b) To be on terms of friendship, familiarity, or intimacy
          with; to secure and retain the favor of. [Colloq.]

   Syn: Into; within; on; at. See {At}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>In- \In-\ ([i^]n-). [See {In}, prep. Cf. {Em-}, {En-}.]
   A prefix from Eng. prep. in, also from Lat. prep. in, meaning
   in, into, on, among; as, inbred, inborn, inroad; incline,
   inject, intrude. In words from the Latin, in- regularly
   becomes il- before l, ir- before r, and im- before a labial;
   as, illusion, irruption, imblue, immigrate, impart. In- is
   sometimes used with an simple intensive force.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>In \In\, adv.
   1. Not out; within; inside. In, the preposition, becomes an
      adverb by omission of its object, leaving it as the
      representative of an adverbial phrase, the context
      indicating what the omitted object is; as, he takes in the
      situation (i. e., he comprehends it in his mind); the
      Republicans were in (i. e., in office); in at one ear and
      out at the other (i. e., in or into the head); his side
      was in (i. e., in the turn at the bat); he came in (i. e.,
      into the house).
      [1913 Webster]

            Their vacation . . . falls in so pat with ours.
                                                  --Lamb.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The sails of a vessel are said, in nautical language,
         to be in when they are furled, or when stowed. In
         certain cases in has an adjectival sense; as, the in
         train (i. e., the incoming train); compare up grade,
         down grade, undertow, afterthought, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) With privilege or possession; -- used to denote a
      holding, possession, or seisin; as, in by descent; in by
      purchase; in of the seisin of her husband. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In and in breeding}. See under {Breeding}.

   {In and out} (Naut.), through and through; -- said of a
      through bolt in a ship's side. --Knight.

   {To be in}, to be at home; as, Mrs. A. is in.

   {To come in}. See under {Come}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>In \In\ ([i^]n), v. t.
   To inclose; to take in; to harvest. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         He that ears my land spares my team and gives me leave
         to in the crop.                          --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>In \In\, n.

   Note: [Usually in the plural.]
   1. One who is in office; -- the opposite of {out}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A re["e]ntrant angle; a nook or corner.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ins and outs},
      (a) nooks and corners; twists and turns.
      (b) the peculiarities or technicalities (of a subject);
          intricacies; details; -- used with of; as, he knew the
          ins and outs of the Washington power scene.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

                All the ins and outs of this neighborhood. --D.
                                                  Jerrold.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tetrazine \Tet*raz"ine\, n. Also -in \-in\ . [Tetrazo- + -ine.]
   (Chem.)
   A hypothetical compound, {C2H2N4} which may be regarded as
   benzene with four {CH} groups replaced by nitrogen atoms;
   also, any of various derivatives of the same. There are three
   isomeric varieties.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cadaverine \Ca*dav"er*ine\, n. Also -in \-in\ . [From {Cadaver}
   and amine.] (Chem.)
   A sirupy, nontoxic ptomaine, {H2N.(CH2)5.NH2} (chemically
   {pentamethylene diamine}), formed in putrefaction of flesh,
   etc.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>IN
     Individual Network [e.v.] (org., ISP)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>IN
     Intelligent Network (ITU-T, Q.1200)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>in</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>in
     adj 1: holding office; "the in party" [syn: {in(p)}]
     2: directed or bound inward; "took the in bus"; "the in basket"
        [syn: {in(a)}]
     3: currently fashionable; "the in thing to do"; "large shoulder
        pads are in"
     n 1: a unit of length equal to one twelfth of a foot [syn: {inch}]
     2: a rare soft silvery metallic element; occurs in small
        quantities in sphalerite [syn: {indium}, {atomic number 49}]
     3: a state in midwestern United States [syn: {Indiana}, {Hoosier
        State}]
     adv 1: to or toward the inside of; "come in"; "smash in the door"
            [syn: {inwards}, {inward}]
     2: inside an enclosed space [ant: {out}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
