<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>inclined</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inclined</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Incline \In*cline"\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Inclined}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Inclining}.] [OE. inclinen, enclinen, OF. encliner,
   incliner, F. incliner, L. inclinare; pref. in- in + clinare
   to bend, incline; akin to E. lean. See {Lean} to incline.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To deviate from a line, direction, or course, toward an
      object; to lean; to tend; as, converging lines incline
      toward each other; a road inclines to the north or south.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: To lean or tend, in an intellectual or moral sense;
      to favor an opinion, a course of conduct, or a person; to
      have a propensity or inclination; to be disposed.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their hearts inclined to follow Abimelech. --Judges
                                                  ix. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            Power finds its balance, giddy motions cease
            In both the scales, and each inclines to peace.
                                                  --Parnell.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bow; to incline the head. --Chaucer.

   Syn: To lean; slope; slant; tend; bend.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inclined</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inclined \In*clined"\, p. p. &amp; a.
   1. Having a leaning or tendency towards, or away from, a
      thing; disposed or moved by wish, desire, or judgment; as,
      a man inclined to virtue. ``Each pensively inclined.''
      --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Math.) Making an angle with some line or plane; -- said
      of a line or plane.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) Bent out of a perpendicular position, or into a
      curve with the convex side uppermost.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Inclined plane}. (Mech.)
      (a) A plane that makes an oblique angle with the plane of
          the horizon; a sloping plane. When used to produce
          pressure, or as a means of moving bodies, it is one of
          the mechanical powers, so called.
      (b) (Railroad &amp; Canal) An inclined portion of track, on
          which trains or boats are raised or lowered from one
          level to another.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inclined</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>inclined
     adj 1: (often followed by `to') having a preference, disposition,
            or tendency; "wasn't inclined to believe the excuse";
            "inclined to be moody" [syn: {inclined(p)}] [ant: {disinclined}]
     2: at an angle to the horizontal or vertical position; "an
        inclined plane" [ant: {horizontal}, {vertical}]
     3: having made preparations; "prepared to take risks" [syn: {disposed(p)},
         {fain}, {inclined(p)}, {prepared}]
     4: used especially of the head or upper back; "a bent head and
        sloping shoulders" [syn: {bent}, {bowed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
