<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>indicator</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>indicator</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Honey \Hon"ey\ (h[u^]n"[y^]), n. [OE. honi, huni, AS. hunig;
   akin to OS. honeg, D. &amp; G. honig, OHG. honag, honang, Icel.
   hunang, Sw. h[*a]ning, Dan. honning, cf. Gr. ko`nis dust,
   Skr. ka[.n]a grain.]
   1. A sweet viscid fluid, esp. that collected by bees from
      flowers of plants, and deposited in the cells of the
      honeycomb.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is sweet or pleasant, like honey.
      [1913 Webster]

            The honey of his language.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Sweet one; -- a term of endearment. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Honey, you shall be well desired in Cyprus. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Honey is often used adjectively or as the first part of
         compound; as, honeydew or honey dew; honey guide or
         honeyguide; honey locust or honey-locust.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Honey ant} (Zo["o]l.), a small ant ({Myrmecocystus
      melliger}), found in the Southwestern United States, and
      in Mexico, living in subterranean formicares. There are
      larger and smaller ordinary workers, and others, which
      serve as receptacles or cells for the storage of honey,
      their abdomens becoming distended to the size of a
      currant. These, in times of scarcity, regurgitate the
      honey and feed the rest.

   {Honey badger} (Zo["o]l.), the ratel.

   {Honey bear}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Kinkajou}.

   {Honey buzzard} (Zo["o]l.), a bird related to the kites, of
      the genus {Pernis}. The European species is {Pernis
      apivorus}; the Indian or crested honey buzzard is {Pernis
      ptilorhyncha}. They feed upon honey and the larv[ae] of
      bees. Called also {bee hawk}, {bee kite}.

   {Honey guide} (Zo["o]l.), one of several species of small
      birds of the family {Indicatorid[ae]}, inhabiting Africa
      and the East Indies. They have the habit of leading
      persons to the nests to wild bees. Called also
      {honeybird}, and {indicator}.

   {Honey harvest}, the gathering of honey from hives, or the
      honey which is gathered. --Dryden.

   {Honey kite}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Honey buzzard} (above).

   {Honey locust} (Bot.), a North American tree ({Gleditschia
      triacanthos}), armed with thorns, and having long pods
      with a sweet pulp between the seeds.

   {Honey month}. Same as {Honeymoon}.

   {Honey weasel} (Zo["o]l.), the ratel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>indicator</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Indicator \In"di*ca`tor\ ([i^]n"d[i^]*k[=a]`t[~e]r), n. [L.: cf.
   F. indicateur.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. One who, or that which, shows or points out; as, a fare
      indicator in a street car.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mach.) A pressure gauge; a water gauge, as for a steam
      boiler; an apparatus or instrument for showing the working
      of a machine or moving part; as:
      (a) (Steam Engine) An instrument which draws a diagram
          showing the varying pressure in the cylinder of an
          engine or pump at every point of the stroke. It
          consists of a small cylinder communicating with the
          engine cylinder and fitted with a piston which the
          varying pressure drives upward more or less against
          the resistance of a spring. A lever imparts motion to
          a pencil which traces the diagram on a card wrapped
          around a vertical drum which is turned back and forth
          by a string connected with the piston rod of the
          engine. See {Indicator card} (below).
      (b) A telltale connected with a hoisting machine, to show,
          at the surface, the position of the cage in the shaft
          of a mine, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mech.) The part of an instrument by which an effect is
      indicated, as an index or pointer.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) Any bird of the genus {Indicator} and allied
      genera. See {Honey guide}, under {Honey}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Chem.) That which indicates the condition of acidity,
      alkalinity, or the deficiency, excess, or sufficiency of a
      standard reagent, by causing an appearance, disappearance,
      or change of color, as in titration or volumetric
      analysis.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The common indicators are litmus, trop[ae]olin, phenol
         phthalein, potassic permanganate, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Indicator card}, the figure drawn by an engine indicator, by
      means of which the working of the engine can be
      investigated and its power calculated. The Illustration
      shows one form of indicator card, from a steam engine,
      together with scales by which the pressure of the steam
      above or below that of the atmosphere, corresponding to
      any position of the engine piston in its stroke, can be
      measured. Called also {indicator diagram}.

   {Indicator telegraph}, a telegraph in which the signals are
      the deflections of a magnetic needle, as in the
      trans-Atlantic system.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>indicator</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>indicator
     n 1: a number or ratio (a value on a scale of measurement)
          derived from a series of observed facts; can reveal
          relative changes as a function of time [syn: {index}, {index
          number}, {indicant}]
     2: a signal for attracting attention
     3: a device for showing the operating condition of some system
     4: (chemistry) a substance that changes color to indicate the
        presence of some ion or substance; can be used to indicate
        the completion of a chemical reaction or (in medicine) to
        test for a particular reaction
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
