<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>induce</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>induce</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Induce \In*duce"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Induced}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Inducing}.] [L. inducere, inductum; pref. in- in + ducere
   to lead. See {Duke}, and cf. {Induct}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To lead in; to introduce. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The poet may be seen inducing his personages in the
            first Iliad.                          --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw on; to overspread. [A Latinism] --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To lead on; to influence; to prevail on; to incite; to
      persuade; to move by persuasion or influence. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is not obliged by your offer to do it, . . .
            though he may be induced, persuaded, prevailed upon,
            tempted.                              --Paley.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let not the covetous desire of growing rich induce
            you to ruin your reputation.          --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To bring on; to effect; to cause; as, a fever induced by
      fatigue or exposure; anaphylactic shock induced by
      exposure to a allergen.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Sour things induces a contraction in the nerves.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Physics) To produce, or cause, by proximity without
      contact or transmission, as a particular electric or
      magnetic condition in a body, by the approach of another
      body in an opposite electric or magnetic state.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Logic) To generalize or conclude as an inference from all
      the particulars; -- the opposite of {deduce}.

   7. (Genetics, Biochemistry) To cause the expression of (a
      gene or gene product) by affecting a transcription control
      element on the genome, either by inhibiting a negative
      control or by activating a positive control; to derepress;
      as, lactose induces the production of beta-galactosidase
      in {Eschericia coli}..
      [PJC]

   Syn: To move; instigate; urge; impel; incite; press;
        influence; actuate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>induce</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>induce
     v 1: cause to arise; "induce a crisis" [syn: {bring on}]
     2: cause to do; cause to act in a specified manner; "The ads
        induced me to buy a VCR"; "My children finally got me to
        buy a computer"; "My wife made me buy a new sofa" [syn: {stimulate},
         {cause}, {have}, {get}, {make}]
     3: cause to occur rapidly; "the infection precipitated a high
        fever and allergic reactions" [syn: {stimulate}, {rush}, {hasten}]
     4: reason or establish by induction
     5:  produce electric current by electrostatic or magnetic
        processes [syn: {induct}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
