<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>indulge</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>indulge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Indulge \In*dulge"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Indulged}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Indulging}.] [L. indulgere to be kind or tender to
   one; cf. OIr. dilgud, equiv. to L. remissio, OIr. dligeth,
   equiv. to L. lex, Goth. dulgs debt.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To be complacent toward; to give way to; not to oppose or
      restrain;
      (a) when said of a habit, desire, etc.: to give free
          course to; to give one's self up to; as, to indulge
          sloth, pride, selfishness, or inclinations;
      (b) when said of a person: to yield to the desire of; to
          gratify by compliance; to humor; to withhold restraint
          from; as, to indulge children in their caprices or
          willfulness; to indulge one's self with a rest or in
          pleasure.
          [1913 Webster]

                Hope in another life implies that we indulge
                ourselves in the gratifications of this very
                sparingly.                        --Atterbury.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. To grant as by favor; to bestow in concession, or in
      compliance with a wish or request.
      [1913 Webster]

            Persuading us that something must be indulged to
            public manners.                       --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet, yet a moment, one dim ray of light
            Indulge, dread Chaos, and eternal Night! --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: It is remarked by Johnson, that if the matter of
         indulgence is a single thing, it has with before it; if
         it is a habit, it has in; as, he indulged himself with
         a glass of wine or a new book; he indulges himself in
         idleness or intemperance. See {Gratify}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>indulge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Indulge \In*dulge"\, v. i.
   To indulge one's self; to gratify one's tastes or desires;
   esp., to give one's self up (to); to practice a forbidden or
   questionable act without restraint; -- followed by in, but
   formerly, also, by to. ``Willing to indulge in easy vices.''
   --Johnson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>indulge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>indulge
     v 1: give free rein to; "The writer indulged in metaphorical
          language"
     2: yield (to); give satisfaction to [syn: {gratify}, {pander}]
     3: enjoy to excess [syn: {luxuriate}]
     4: treat with excessive indulgence; "grandparents often pamper
        the children"; "Let's not mollycoddle our students!" [syn:
         {pamper}, {featherbed}, {cosset}, {cocker}, {baby}, {coddle},
         {mollycoddle}, {spoil}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
