<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>information</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>information</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Information \In`for*ma"tion\, n. [F., fr. L. informatio
   representation, conception. See {Inform}, v. t.]
   1. The act of informing, or communicating knowledge or
      intelligence.
      [1913 Webster]

            The active informations of the intellect. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any fact or set of facts, knowledge, news, or advice,
      whether communicated by others or obtained by personal
      study and investigation; any datum that reduces
      uncertainty about the state of any part of the world;
      intelligence; knowledge derived from reading, observation,
      or instruction.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Larger opportunities of information.  --Rogers.
      [1913 Webster]

            He should get some information in the subject he
            intends to handle.                    --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) A proceeding in the nature of a prosecution for some
      offense against the government, instituted and prosecuted,
      really or nominally, by some authorized public officer on
      behalf of the government. It differs from an indictment in
      criminal cases chiefly in not being based on the finding
      of a grand jury. See {Indictment}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Information Theory) A measure of the number of possible
      choices of messages contained in a symbol, signal,
      transmitted message, or other information-bearing object;
      it is usually quantified as the negative logarithm of the
      number of allowed symbols that could be contained in the
      message; for logarithms to the base 2, the measure
      corresponds to the unit of information, the hartley, which
      is log210, or 3.323 bits; called also {information
      content}. The smallest unit of information that can be
      contained or transmitted is the bit, corresponding to a
      yes-or-no decision.
      [PJC]

   5. (Computers) Useful facts, as contrasted with raw data; as,
      among all this data, there must be some interesting
      information.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>information</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>information
     n 1: a message received and understood [syn: {info}]
     2: a collection of facts from which conclusions may be drawn;
        "statistical data" [syn: {data}]
     3: knowledge acquired through study or experience or
        instruction
     4: (communication theory) a numerical measure of the
        uncertainty of an outcome; "the signal contained thousands
        of bits of information" [syn: {selective information}, {entropy}]
     5: formal accusation of a crime
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
