<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ink</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>INK, n.  A villainous compound of tannogallate of iron, gum-arabic and
water, chiefly used to facilitate the infection of idiocy and promote
intellectual crime.  The properties of ink are peculiar and
contradictory:  it may be used to make reputations and unmake them; to
blacken them and to make them white; but it is most generally and
acceptably employed as a mortar to bind together the stones of an
edifice of fame, and as a whitewash to conceal afterward the rascal
quality of the material.  There are men called journalists who have
established ink baths which some persons pay money to get into, others
to get out of.  Not infrequently it occurs that a person who has paid
to get in pays twice as much to get out.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inc \Inc\, n.
   A Japanese measure of length equal to about two and one
   twelfth yards. [Written also {ink}.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ink \Ink\ ([i^][ng]k), n. (Mach.)
   The step, or socket, in which the lower end of a millstone
   spindle runs.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ink \Ink\, n. [OE. enke, inke, OF. enque, F. encre, L. encaustum
   the purple red ink with which the Roman emperors signed their
   edicts, Gr. ?, fr. ? burnt in, encaustic, fr. ? to burn in.
   See {Encaustic}, {Caustic}.]
   1. A fluid, or a viscous material or preparation of various
      kinds (commonly black or colored), used in writing or
      printing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Make there a prick with ink.          --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Deformed monsters, foul and black as ink. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A pigment. See {India ink}, under {India}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Ordinarily, black ink is made from nutgalls and a
         solution of some salt of iron, and consists essentially
         of a tannate or gallate of iron; sometimes indigo
         sulphate, or other coloring matter, is added. Other
         black inks contain potassium chromate, and extract of
         logwood, salts of vanadium, etc. Blue ink is usually a
         solution of Prussian blue. Red ink was formerly made
         from carmine (cochineal), Brazil wood, etc., but
         potassium eosin is now used. Also red, blue, violet,
         and yellow inks are largely made from aniline dyes.
         Indelible ink is usually a weak solution of silver
         nitrate, but carbon in the form of lampblack or India
         ink, salts of molybdenum, vanadium, etc., are also
         used. Sympathetic inks may be made of milk, salts of
         cobalt, etc. See {Sympathetic ink} (below).
         [1913 Webster]

   {Copying ink}, a peculiar ink used for writings of which
      copies by impression are to be taken.

   {Ink bag} (Zo["o]l.), an ink sac.

   {Ink berry}. (Bot.)
      (a) A shrub of the Holly family ({Ilex glabra}), found in
          sandy grounds along the coast from New England to
          Florida, and producing a small black berry.
      (b) The West Indian indigo berry. See {Indigo}.

   {Ink plant} (Bot.), a New Zealand shrub ({Coriaria
      thymifolia}), the berries of which yield a juice which
      forms an ink.

   {Ink powder}, a powder from which ink is made by solution.

   {Ink sac} (Zo["o]l.), an organ, found in most cephalopods,
      containing an inky fluid which can be ejected from a duct
      opening at the base of the siphon. The fluid serves to
      cloud the water, and enable these animals to escape from
      their enemies. See Illust. of {Dibranchiata}.

   {Printer's ink}, or {Printing ink}. See under {Printing}.

   {Sympathetic ink}, a writing fluid of such a nature that what
      is written remains invisible till the action of a reagent
      on the characters makes it visible.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ink \Ink\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Inked} ([i^][ng]kt); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Inking}.]
   To put ink upon; to supply with ink; to blacken, color, or
   daub with ink.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ink</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ink
     n 1: a liquid used for printing or writing or drawing
     2: dark protective fluid ejected into the water by cuttlefish
        and other cephalopods
     v 1: append one's signature to; "They inked the contract"
     2: fill with ink; "ink a pen"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
