<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>innuendo</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>innuendo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Innuendo \In`nu*en"do\, n.; pl. {Innuedoes}(?). [L., by
   intimation, by hinting, gerund of innuere, innutum, to give a
   nod, to intimate; pref. in- in, to + -nuere (in comp.) to
   nod. See {Nutation}.]
   1. An oblique hint; a remote allusion or reference, usually
      derogatory to a person or thing not named; an insinuation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mercury . . . owns it a marriage by an innuendo.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pursue your trade of scandal picking;
            Your innuendoes, when you tell us,
            That Stella loves to talk with fellows. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) An averment employed in pleading, to point the
      application of matter otherwise unintelligible; an
      interpretative parenthesis thrown into quoted matter to
      explain an obscure word or words; -- as, the plaintiff
      avers that the defendant said that he (innuendo the
      plaintiff) was a thief. --Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The term is so applied from having been the
         introductory word of this averment or parenthetic
         explanation when pleadings were in Latin. The word
         ``meaning'' is used as its equivalent in modern forms.

   Syn: Insinuation; suggestion; hint; intimation; reference;
        allusion; implication; representation; -- {Innuendo},
        {Insinuation}.

   Usage: An innuendo is an equivocal allusion so framed as to
          point distinctly at something which is injurious to
          the character or reputation of the person referred to.
          An insinuation turns on no such double use of
          language, but consists in artfully winding into the
          mind imputations of an injurious nature without making
          any direct charge.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>innuendo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>innuendo
     n : an indirect (and usually malicious) implication [syn: {insinuation}]
     [also: {innuendoes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
