<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>inscribed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inscribed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inscribe \In*scribe"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Inscribed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Inscribing}.] [L. inscribere. See 1st {In-}, and
   {Scribe}.]
   1. To write or engrave; to mark down as something to be read;
      to imprint.
      [1913 Webster]

            Inscribe a verse on this relenting stone. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mark with letters, characters, or words.
      [1913 Webster]

            O let thy once lov'd friend inscribe thy stone.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To assign or address to; to commend to by a short address;
      to dedicate informally; as, to inscribe an ode to a
      friend. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To imprint deeply; to impress; to stamp; as, to inscribe a
      sentence on the memory.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Geom.) To draw within so as to meet yet not cut the
      boundaries.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A line is inscribed in a circle, or in a sphere, when
         its two ends are in the circumference of the circle, or
         in the surface of the sphere. A triangle is inscribed
         in another triangle, when the three angles of the
         former are severally on the three sides of the latter.
         A circle is inscribed in a polygon, when it touches
         each side of the polygon. A sphere is inscribed in a
         polyhedron, when the sphere touches each boundary plane
         of the polyhedron. The latter figure in each case is
         circumscribed about the former.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inscribed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>inscribed
     adj 1: written (by handwriting, printing, engraving, or carving) on
            or in a surface
     2: cut or impressed into a surface; "an incised design";
        "engraved invitations" [syn: {engraved}, {etched}, {graven},
         {incised}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
