<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>inspiration</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inspiration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inspiration
   that extraordinary or supernatural divine influence vouchsafed
   to those who wrote the Holy Scriptures, rendering their writings
   infallible. "All scripture is given by inspiration of God"
   (R.V., "Every scripture inspired of God"), 2 Tim. 3:16. This is
   true of all the "sacred writings," not in the sense of their
   being works of genius or of supernatural insight, but as
   "theopneustic," i.e., "breathed into by God" in such a sense
   that the writers were supernaturally guided to express exactly
   what God intended them to express as a revelation of his mind
   and will. The testimony of the sacred writers themselves
   abundantly demonstrates this truth; and if they are infallible
   as teachers of doctrine, then the doctrine of plenary
   inspiration must be accepted. There are no errors in the Bible
   as it came from God, none have been proved to exist.
   Difficulties and phenomena we cannot explain are not errors. All
   these books of the Old and New Testaments are inspired. We do
   not say that they contain, but that they are, the Word of God.
   The gift of inspiration rendered the writers the organs of God,
   for the infallible communication of his mind and will, in the
   very manner and words in which it was originally given.
   
     As to the nature of inspiration we have no information. This
   only we know, it rendered the writers infallible. They were all
   equally inspired, and are all equally infallible. The
   inspiration of the sacred writers did not change their
   characters. They retained all their individual peculiarities as
   thinkers or writers. (See {BIBLE}; WORD OF {GOD}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inspiration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inspiration \In`spi*ra"tion\, n. [F. inspiration, L. inspiratio.
   See {Inspire}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of inspiring or breathing in; breath; specif.
      (Physiol.), the drawing of air into the lungs,
      accomplished in mammals by elevation of the chest walls
      and flattening of the diaphragm; -- the opposite of
      expiration.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act or power of exercising an elevating or stimulating
      influence upon the intellect or emotions; the result of
      such influence which quickens or stimulates; as, the
      inspiration of occasion, of art, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your father was ever virtuous, and holy men at their
            death have good inspirations.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Theol.) A supernatural divine influence on the prophets,
      apostles, or sacred writers, by which they were qualified
      to communicate moral or religious truth with authority; a
      supernatural influence which qualifies men to receive and
      communicate divine truth; also, the truth communicated.
      [1913 Webster]

            All Scripture is given by inspiration of God. --2
                                                  Tim. iii. 16.
      [1913 Webster]

            The age which we now live in is not an age of
            inspiration and impulses.             --Sharp.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Plenary inspiration} (Theol.), that kind of inspiration
      which excludes all defect in the utterance of the inspired
      message.

   {Verbal inspiration} (Theol.), that kind of inspiration which
      extends to the very words and forms of expression of the
      divine message.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inspiration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>inspiration
     n 1: arousal of the mind to special unusual activity or
          creativity
     2: a product of your creative thinking and work; "he had little
        respect for the inspirations of other artists"; "after
        years of work his brainchild was a tangible reality" [syn:
         {brainchild}]
     3: a sudden intuition as part of solving a problem
     4: (theology) a special influence of a divinity on the minds of
        human beings; "they believe that the books of Scripture
        were written under divine guidance" [syn: {divine guidance}]
     5: arousing to a particular emotion or action [syn: {stirring}]
     6: the act of inhaling; the drawing in of air (or other gases)
        as in breathing [syn: {inhalation}, {aspiration}, {breathing
        in}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
