<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>institute</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>institute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Institute \In"sti*tute\, n. [L. institutum: cf. F. institut. See
   {Institute}, v. t. &amp; a.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of instituting; institution. [Obs.] ``Water
      sanctified by Christ's institute.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is instituted, established, or fixed, as a law,
      habit, or custom. --Glover.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: An elementary and necessary principle; a precept,
      maxim, or rule, recognized as established and
      authoritative; usually in the plural, a collection of such
      principles and precepts; esp., a comprehensive summary of
      legal principles and decisions; as, the Institutes of
      Justinian; Coke's Institutes of the Laws of England. Cf.
      {Digest}, n.
      [1913 Webster]

            They made a sort of institute and digest of anarchy.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

            To make the Stoics' institutes thy own. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An institution; a society established for the promotion of
      learning, art, science, etc.; a college; as, the Institute
      of Technology; The Massachusetts Institute of Technology;
      also, a building owned or occupied by such an institute;
      as, the Cooper Institute.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Scots Law) The person to whom an estate is first given by
      destination or limitation. --Tomlins.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Institutes of medicine}, theoretical medicine; that
      department of medical science which attempts to account
      philosophically for the various phenomena of health as
      well as of disease; physiology applied to the practice of
      medicine. --Dunglison.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>institute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Institute \In"sti*tute\ ([i^]n"st[i^]*t[=u]t), v. t. [imp. &amp; p.
   p. {Instituted} ([i^]n"st[i^]*t[=u]`t[e^]d); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Instituting}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To set up; to establish; to ordain; as, to institute laws,
      rules, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To originate and establish; to found; to organize; as, to
      institute a court, or a society.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whenever any from of government becomes destructive
            of these ends it is the right of the people to alter
            or to abolish it, and to institute a new government.
                                                  --Jefferson
                                                  (Decl. of
                                                  Indep. ).
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To nominate; to appoint. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We institute your Grace
            To be our regent in these parts of France. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To begin; to commence; to set on foot; as, to institute an
      inquiry; to institute a suit.
      [1913 Webster]

            And haply institute
            A course of learning and ingenious studies. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To ground or establish in principles and rudiments; to
      educate; to instruct. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            If children were early instituted, knowledge would
            insensibly insinuate itself.          --Dr. H. More.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Eccl. Law) To invest with the spiritual charge of a
      benefice, or the care of souls. --Blackstone.

   Syn: To originate; begin; commence; establish; found; erect;
        organize; appoint; ordain.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>institute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Institute \In"sti*tute\ ([i^]n"st[i^]*t[=u]t), p. a. [L.
   institutus, p. p. of instituere to place in, to institute, to
   instruct; pref. in- in + statuere to cause to stand, to set.
   See {Statute}.]
   Established; organized; founded. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         They have but few laws. For to a people so instruct and
         institute, very few to suffice.          --Robynson
                                                  (More's
                                                  Utopia).
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>institute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>institute
     n : an association organized to promote art or science or
         education
     v 1: set up or lay the groundwork for; "establish a new
          department" [syn: {establish}, {found}, {plant}, {constitute}]
     2: avance or set forth in court; "bring charges", "institute
        proceedings" [syn: {bring}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
