<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>instrument</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>instrument</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>instrument
     
        &lt;programming&gt; To install devices or instructions into hardware
        or software to monitor the operation of a system or component.
     
        (1996-05-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>instrument</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Instrument \In"stru*ment\, v. t.
   1. To perform upon an instrument; to prepare for an
      instrument; as, a sonata instrumented for orchestra.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To furnish or equip with instruments; to attach
      instruments to; as, the fighter planes were heavily
      instrumented; the patient was instrumented to monitor him
      remotely.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>instrument</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Instrument \In"stru*ment\, n. [F. instrument, L. instrumentum.
   See {Instruct}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. That by means of which any work is performed, or result is
      effected; a tool; a utensil; an implement; a device; as,
      the instruments of a mechanic; astronomical instruments.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the lofty instruments of war.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A contrivance or implement, by which musical sounds are
      produced; as, a musical instrument.
      [1913 Webster]

            Praise him with stringed instruments and organs.
                                                  --Ps. cl. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

            But signs when songs and instruments he hears.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) A writing, as the means of giving formal expression
      to some act; a writing expressive of some act, contract,
      process, as a deed, contract, writ, etc. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. One who, or that which, is made a means, or is caused to
      serve a purpose; a medium, means, or agent; as, their army
      was primarily an instrument of oppression.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Or useful serving man and instrument,
            To any sovereign state.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bold are but the instruments of the wise.
                                                  --Dryden.

   Syn: Tool; implement; utensil; machine; apparatus; channel;
        agent.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>instrument</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>instrument
     n 1: a device that requires skill for proper use
     2: the means whereby some act is accomplished; "my greed was
        the instrument of my destruction"; "science has given us
        new tools to fight disease" [syn: {tool}]
     3: a person used by another to gain an end [syn: {pawn}, {cat's-paw}]
     4: (law) a document that states some contractual relationship
        or grants some right [syn: {legal document}, {legal
        instrument}, {official document}]
     5: the semantic role of the entity (usually inanimate) that the
        agent uses to perform an action or start a process [syn: {instrumental
        role}]
     6: any of various devices or contrivances that can be used to
        produce musical tones or sounds [syn: {musical instrument}]
     v 1: equip with instruments for measuring, recording, or
          controlling
     2: write an instrumental score for [syn: {instrumentate}]
     3: address a legal document to
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
