<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>intention</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>intention</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>INTENTION, n.  The mind's sense of the prevalence of one set of
influences over another set; an effect whose cause is the imminence,
immediate or remote, of the performance of an involuntary act.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>intention</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Intention \In*ten"tion\, n. [F. intention, L. intentio. See
   {Intend}, and cf. {Intension}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A stretching or bending of the mind toward an object;
      closeness of application; fixedness of attention;
      earnestness.
      [1913 Webster]

            Intention is when the mind, with great earnestness,
            and of choice, fixes its view on any idea. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A determination to act in a certain way or to do a certain
      thing; purpose; design; as, an intention to go to New
      York.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hell is paved with good intentions.   --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The object toward which the thoughts are directed; end;
      aim.
      [1913 Webster]

            In [chronical distempers], the principal intention
            is to restore the tone of the solid parts.
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The state of being strained. See {Intension}. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Logic) Any mental apprehension of an object.
      [1913 Webster]

   {First intention} (Logic), a conception of a thing formed by
      the first or direct application of the mind to the
      individual object; an idea or image; as, man, stone.

   {Second intention} (Logic), a conception generalized from
      first intuition or apprehension already formed by the
      mind; an abstract notion; especially, a classified notion,
      as species, genus, whiteness.

   {To heal by the first intention} (Surg.), to cicatrize, as a
      wound, without suppuration.

   {To heal by the second intention} (Surg.), to unite after
      suppuration.

   Syn: Design; purpose; object; aim; intent; drift; purport;
        meaning. See {Design}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>intention</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>intention
     n 1: an anticipated outcome that is intended or that guides your
          planned actions; "his intent was to provide a new
          translation"; "good intentions are not enough"; "it was
          created with the conscious aim of answering immediate
          needs"; "he made no secret of his designs" [syn: {purpose},
           {intent}, {aim}, {design}]
     2: (usually plural) the goal with respect to a marriage
        proposal; "his intentions are entirely honorable"
     3: an act of intending; a volition that you intend to carry
        out; "my intention changed once I saw her"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
