<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>interface</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>interface</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>interface
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; A boundary across which two systems communicate.  An
        interface might be a hardware connector used to link to other
        devices, or it might be a convention used to allow
        communication between two software systems.  Often there is
        some intermediate component between the two systems which
        connects their interfaces together.  For example, two {EIA-232}
        interfaces connected via a serial cable.
     
        See also {graphical user interface}, {Application Program
        Interface}.
     
        (1996-05-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>interface</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>interface \interface\ n.
   1. a surface forming a common boundary between two things,
      especially between two fluids. [WordNet sense 1]
      [WordNet 1.5]

   2. (Computers) hardware that links one device with another
      (especially a computer). [WordNet sense 2]
      [WordNet 1.5]

   3. (Computers) That part of a computer program which controls
      the way a program interacts with a user; the manner of
      inputting and outputting of data, and the way information
      is presented on a computer monitor; also called {user
      interface}; as, a graphical user interface; a
      character-based interface.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>interface</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>interface
     n 1: (chemistry) a surface forming a common boundary between two
          things (two objects or liquids or chemical phases)
     2: (computer science) a program that controls a display for the
        user (usually on a computer monitor) and that allows the
        user to interact with the system [syn: {user interface}]
     3: the overlap where two theories or phenomena affect each
        other or have links with each other; "the interface
        between chemistry and biology"
     4: (computer science) computer circuit consisting of the
        hardware and associated circuitry that links one device
        with another (especially a computer and a hard disk drive
        or other peripherals) [syn: {port}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
