<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>into</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>into</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Into \In"to\, prep. [In + to.]
   To the inside of; within. It is used in a variety of
   applications.
   [1913 Webster]

   1. Expressing entrance, or a passing from the outside of a
      thing to its interior parts; -- following verbs expressing
      motion; as, come into the house; go into the church; one
      stream falls or runs into another; water enters into the
      fine vessels of plants.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Expressing penetration beyond the outside or surface, or
      access to the inside, or contents; as, to look into a
      letter or book; to look into an apartment.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Indicating insertion; as, to infuse more spirit or
      animation into a composition.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Denoting inclusion; as, put these ideas into other words.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Indicating the passing of a thing from one form,
      condition, or state to another; as, compound substances
      may be resolved into others which are more simple; ice is
      convertible into water, and water into vapor; men are more
      easily drawn than forced into compliance; we may reduce
      many distinct substances into one mass; men are led by
      evidence into belief of truth, and are often enticed into
      the commission of crimes; she burst into tears; children
      are sometimes frightened into fits; all persons are liable
      to be seduced into error and folly.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Compare {In}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
