<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>inventory</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inventory</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inventory \In"ven*to*ry\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Inventoried}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Inventorying}.] [Cf. F. inventorier.]
   To make an inventory of; to make a list, catalogue, or
   schedule of; to insert or register in an account of goods;
   as, a merchant inventories his stock.
   [1913 Webster]

         I will give out divers schedules of my beauty; it shall
         be inventoried, and every particle and utensil labeled.
                                                  --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inventory</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inventory \In"ven*to*ry\, n.; pl. {Inventories}. [L.
   inventarium: cf. LL. inventorium, F. inventaire, OF. also
   inventoire. See {Invent}.]
   1. An account, catalogue, or schedule, made by an executor or
      administrator, of all the goods and chattels, and
      sometimes of the real estate, of a deceased person; a list
      of the property of which a person or estate is found to be
      possessed; hence, an itemized list of goods or valuables,
      with their estimated worth. Hence: Any listing, as in a
      catalogue, of objects or resources on hand and available
      for use or for sale. Specifically, the annual account
      listing the stock on hand, taken in any business.
      [1913 Webster]

            There take an inventory of all I have. --Shak.

   2. The objects contained on an inventory[1]; especially: the
      stock of items on hand in any business, either for sale
      and not yet sold, or kept as raw materials to be converted
      into finished products.
      [PJC]

   3. The total value of all goods in an inventory[2].
      [PJC]

   4. The act of making an inventory[1].
      [PJC]

   Syn: List; register; schedule; catalogue. See {List}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>inventory</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>inventory
     n 1: a detailed list of all the items in stock [syn: {stock list}]
     2: the merchandise that a shop has on hand; "they carried a
        vast inventory of hardware" [syn: {stock}]
     3: (accounting) the value of a firm's current assets including
        raw materials and work in progress and finished goods
     4: a collection of resources; "he dipped into his intellectual
        armory to find an answer" [syn: {armory}, {armoury}]
     5: making an itemized list of merchandise or supplies on hand;
        "the inventory took two days" [syn: {inventorying}, {stocktaking}]
     v : make or include in an itemized record or report; "Inventory
         all books before the end of the year"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
