<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>it</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>it</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>IT
     
        1. &lt;business, jargon&gt; {Information Technology}.
     
        2. &lt;language, mathematics, history&gt; {Internal Translator}.
     
        (2000-10-02)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>it</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>it
     
        &lt;networking&gt; The {country code} for Italy.
     
        (1999-01-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>it</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Personal \Per"son*al\ (p[~e]r"s[u^]n*al), a. [L. personalis: cf.
   F. personnel.]
   1. Pertaining to human beings as distinct from things.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every man so termed by way of personal difference.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of or pertaining to a particular person; relating to, or
      affecting, an individual, or each of many individuals;
      peculiar or proper to private concerns; not public or
      general; as, personal comfort; personal desire.
      [1913 Webster]

            The words are conditional, -- If thou doest well, --
            and so personal to Cain.              --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Pertaining to the external or bodily appearance;
      corporeal; as, personal charms. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Done in person; without the intervention of another.
      ``Personal communication.'' --Fabyan.
      [1913 Webster]

            The immediate and personal speaking of God. --White.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Relating to an individual, his character, conduct,
      motives, or private affairs, in an invidious and offensive
      manner; as, personal reflections or remarks.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Gram.) Denoting person; as, a personal pronoun.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Personal action} (Law), a suit or action by which a man
      claims a debt or personal duty, or damages in lieu of it;
      or wherein he claims satisfaction in damages for an injury
      to his person or property, or the specific recovery of
      goods or chattels; -- opposed to real action.

   {Personal equation}. (Astron.) See under {Equation}.

   {Personal estate} or {Personal property} (Law), movables;
      chattels; -- opposed to real estate or property. It
      usually consists of things temporary and movable,
      including all subjects of property not of a freehold
      nature.

   {Personal identity} (Metaph.), the persistent and continuous
      unity of the individual person, which is attested by
      consciousness.

   {Personal pronoun} (Gram.), one of the pronouns {I}, {thou},
      {he}, {she}, {it}, and their plurals.

   {Personal representatives} (Law), the executors or
      administrators of a person deceased.

   {Personal rights}, rights appertaining to the person; as, the
      rights of a personal security, personal liberty, and
      private property.

   {Personal tithes}. See under {Tithe}.

   {Personal verb} (Gram.), a verb which is modified or
      inflected to correspond with the three persons.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>it</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>It \It\ ([i^]t), pron. [OE. it, hit, AS. hit; cf. D. het.
   [root]181. See {He}.]
   The neuter pronoun of the third person, corresponding to the
   masculine pronoun he and the feminine she, and having the
   same plural (they, their or theirs, them).
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The possessive form its is modern, being rarely found
         in the writings of Shakespeare and Milton, and not at
         all in the original King James's version of the Bible.
         During the transition from the regular his to the
         anomalous its, it was to some extent employed in the
         possessive without the case ending. See {His}, and
         {He}. In Dryden's time its had become quite established
         as the regular form.
         [1913 Webster]

               The day present hath ever inough to do with it
               owne grief.                        --Genevan
                                                  Test.
         [1913 Webster]

               Do, child, go to it grandam, child. --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

               It knighthood shall do worse. It shall fright all
               it friends with borrowing letters. --B. Jonson.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the course of time, the nature of the neuter sign t
         in it, the form being found in but a few words, became
         misunderstood. Instead of being looked upon as an
         affix, it passed for part of the original word. Hence
         was formed from it the anomalous genitive its,
         superseding the Saxon his. --Latham.
         [1913 Webster]

               The fruit tree yielding fruit after his (its)
               kind.                              --Gen. i. 11.

   Usage: It is used,

   1. As a substance for any noun of the neuter gender; as, here
      is the book, take it home.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. As a demonstrative, especially at the beginning of a
      sentence, pointing to that which is about to be stated,
      named, or mentioned, or referring to that which apparent
      or well known; as, I saw it was John.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is I; be not afraid.               --Matt. xiv.
                                                  27.
      [1913 Webster]

            Peter heard that it was the Lord.     --John xxi. 7.
      Often, in such cases, as a substitute for a sentence or
      clause; as, it is thought he will come; it is wrong to do
      this.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. As an indefinite nominative for a impersonal verb; as, it
      snows; it rains.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. As a substitute for such general terms as, the state of
      affairs, the condition of things, and the like; as, how is
      it with the sick man?
      [1913 Webster]

            Think on me when it shall be well with thee. --Gen.
                                                  xl. 14.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. As an indefinite object after some intransitive verbs, or
      after a substantive used humorously as a verb; as, to foot
      it (i. e., to walk).
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lacedemonians, at the Straits of Thermopyl[ae],
            when their arms failed them, fought it out with
            nails and teeth.                      --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether the charmer sinner it, or saint it,
            If folly grows romantic, I must paint it. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Its self}. See {Itself}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>it</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>IT
     Information Technology
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>it</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>IT
     Iran Time [+0300] (TZ)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
