<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>aberration</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>aberration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Aberration \Ab`er*ra"tion\, n. [L. aberratio: cf. F. aberration.
   See {Aberrate}.]
   1. The act of wandering; deviation, especially from truth or
      moral rectitude, from the natural state, or from a type.
      ``The aberration of youth.'' --Hall. ``Aberrations from
      theory.'' --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A partial alienation of reason. ``Occasional aberrations
      of intellect.'' --Lingard.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whims, which at first are the aberrations of a
            single brain, pass with heat into epidemic form.
                                                  --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Astron.) A small periodical change of position in the
      stars and other heavenly bodies, due to the combined
      effect of the motion of light and the motion of the
      observer; called {annual aberration}, when the observer's
      motion is that of the earth in its orbit, and daily or
      {diurnal aberration}, when of the earth on its axis;
      amounting when greatest, in the former case, to 20.4'',
      and in the latter, to 0.3''. {Planetary aberration} is
      that due to the motion of light and the motion of the
      planet relative to the earth.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Opt.) The convergence to different foci, by a lens or
      mirror, of rays of light emanating from one and the same
      point, or the deviation of such rays from a single focus;
      called {spherical aberration}, when due to the spherical
      form of the lens or mirror, such form giving different
      foci for central and marginal rays; and {chromatic
      aberration}, when due to different refrangibilities of the
      colored rays of the spectrum, those of each color having a
      distinct focus.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Physiol.) The passage of blood or other fluid into parts
      not appropriate for it.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law) The producing of an unintended effect by the
      glancing of an instrument, as when a shot intended for A
      glances and strikes B.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Insanity; lunacy; madness; derangement; alienation;
        mania; dementia; hallucination; illusion; delusion. See
        {Insanity}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>aberration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>aberration
     n 1: a state or condition markedly different from the norm [syn:
          {aberrance}, {aberrancy}, {deviance}]
     2: a disorder in one's mental state
     3: an optical phenomenon resulting from the failure of a lens
        or mirror to produce a good image [syn: {distortion}, {optical
        aberration}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
