<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>absurd</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>absurd</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Absurd \Ab*surd"\ ([a^]b*s[^u]rd"), a. [L. absurdus
   harsh-sounding; ab + (prob) a derivative fr. a root svar to
   sound; not connected with surd: cf. F. absurde. See
   {Syringe}.]
   Contrary to reason or propriety; obviously and flatly opposed
   to manifest truth; inconsistent with the plain dictates of
   common sense; logically contradictory; nonsensical;
   ridiculous; as, an absurd person, an absurd opinion; an
   absurd dream.
   [1913 Webster]

         This proffer is absurd and reasonless.   --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         'This phrase absurd to call a villain great. --Pope.
                                                  --p. 9
   [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Foolish; irrational; ridiculous; preposterous;
        inconsistent; incongruous.

   Usage: {Absurd}, {Irrational}, {Foolish}, {Preposterous}. Of
          these terms, irrational is the weakest, denoting that
          which is plainly inconsistent with the dictates of
          sound reason; as, an irrational course of life.
          Foolish rises higher, and implies either a perversion
          of that faculty, or an absolute weakness or fatuity of
          mind; as, foolish enterprises. Absurd rises still
          higher, denoting that which is plainly opposed to
          received notions of propriety and truth; as, an absurd
          man, project, opinion, story, argument, etc.
          Preposterous rises still higher, and supposes an
          absolute inversion in the order of things; or, in
          plain terms, a ``putting of the cart before the
          horse;'' as, a preposterous suggestion, preposterous
          conduct, a preposterous regulation or law.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>absurd</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Absurd \Ab*surd"\ ([a^]b*s[^u]rd"), n.
   An absurdity. [Obs.] --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>absurd</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>absurd
     adj 1: inconsistent with reason or logic or common sense; "the
            absurd predicament of seeming to argue that virtue is
            highly desirable but intensely unpleasant"- Walter
            Lippman [syn: {unreasonable}]
     2: completely devoid of wisdom or good sense; "the absurd
        excuse that the dog ate his homework"; "that's a cockeyed
        idea"; "ask a nonsensical question and get a nonsensical
        answer"; "a contribution so small as to be laughable"; "it
        is ludicrous to call a cottage a mansion"; "a preposterous
        attempt to turn back the pages of history"; "her conceited
        assumption of universal interest in her rather dull
        children was ridiculous" [syn: {cockeyed}, {derisory}, {idiotic},
         {laughable}, {ludicrous}, {nonsensical}, {preposterous},
        {ridiculous}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
