<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>acceptance</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acceptance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Acceptance \Ac*cept"ance\, n.
   1. The act of accepting; a receiving what is offered, with
      approbation, satisfaction, or acquiescence; esp.,
      favorable reception; approval; as, the acceptance of a
      gift, office, doctrine, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shall come up with acceptance on mine altar.
                                                  --Isa. lx. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. State of being accepted; acceptableness. ``Makes it
      assured of acceptance.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Com.)
      (a) An assent and engagement by the person on whom a bill
          of exchange is drawn, to pay it when due according to
          the terms of the acceptance.
      (b) The bill itself when accepted.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. An agreeing to terms or proposals by which a bargain is
      concluded and the parties are bound; the reception or
      taking of a thing bought as that for which it was bought,
      or as that agreed to be delivered, or the taking
      possession as owner.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) An agreeing to the action of another, by some act
      which binds the person in law.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: What acts shall amount to such an acceptance is often a
         question of great nicety and difficulty. --Mozley &amp; W.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: In modern law, proposal and acceptance are the
         constituent elements into which all contracts are
         resolved.
         [1913 Webster]

   {acceptance of a bill of exchange}, {acceptance of a check},
   {acceptance of a draft}, or {acceptance of an order}, is an
      engagement to pay it according to the terms. This
      engagement is usually made by writing the word
      ``accepted'' across the face of the bill.

   {Acceptance of goods}, under the statute of frauds, is an
      intelligent acceptance by a party knowing the nature of
      the transaction.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Meaning; acceptation. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Acceptance of persons}, partiality, favoritism. See under
      {Accept}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acceptance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>acceptance
     n 1: the mental attitude that something is believable and should
          be accepted as true; "he gave credence to the gossip";
          "acceptance of Newtonian mechanics was unquestioned for
          200 years" [syn: {credence}]
     2: the act of accepting with approval; favorable reception;
        "its adoption by society"; "the proposal found wide
        acceptance" [syn: {adoption}, {acceptation}, {espousal}]
     3: the state of being acceptable and accepted; "torn jeans
        received no acceptance at the country club" [ant: {rejection}]
     4: (contract law) words signifying consent to the terms of an
        offer (thereby creating a contract)
     5: banking: a time draft drawn on and accepted by a bank [syn:
        {banker's acceptance}]
     6: a disposition to tolerate or accept people or situations;
        "all people should practice toleration and live together
        in peace" [syn: {toleration}, {sufferance}]
     7: the act of taking something that is offered; "her acceptance
        of the gift encouraged him"; "he anticipated their
        acceptance of his offer"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
