<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>accident</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accident</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ACCIDENT, n.  An inevitable occurrence due to the action of immutable
natural laws.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accident</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Accident, MD (town, FIPS 225)
  Location: 39.62694 N, 79.32088 W
  Population (1990): 349 (155 housing units)
  Area: 1.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 21520
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accident</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Accident \Ac"ci*dent\, n. [F. accident, fr. L. accidens,
   -dentis, p. pr. of accidere to happen; ad + cadere to fall.
   See {Cadence}, {Case}.]
   1. Literally, a befalling; an event that takes place without
      one's foresight or expectation; an undesigned, sudden, and
      unexpected event; chance; contingency; often, an
      undesigned and unforeseen occurrence of an afflictive or
      unfortunate character; a casualty; a mishap; as, to die by
      an accident.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of moving accidents by flood and field. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou cam'st not to thy place by accident:
            It is the very place God meant for thee. --Trench.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Gram.) A property attached to a word, but not essential
      to it, as gender, number, case.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Her.) A point or mark which may be retained or omitted in
      a coat of arms.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Log.)
      (a) A property or quality of a thing which is not
          essential to it, as whiteness in paper; an attribute.
      (b) A quality or attribute in distinction from the
          substance, as sweetness, softness.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. Any accidental property, fact, or relation; an accidental
      or nonessential; as, beauty is an accident.
      [1913 Webster]

            This accident, as I call it, of Athens being
            situated some miles from the sea.     --J. P.
                                                  Mahaffy.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Unusual appearance or effect. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Accident, in Law, is equivalent to casus, or such
         unforeseen, extraordinary, extraneous interference as
         is out of the range of ordinary calculation.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accident</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>accident
     n 1: a mishap; especially one causing injury or death
     2: anything that happens by chance without an apparent cause
        [syn: {fortuity}, {chance event}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
