<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>accusing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accusing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Accuse \Ac*cuse"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Accused}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Accusing}.] [OF. acuser, F. accuser, L. accusare, to call
   to account, accuse; ad + causa cause, lawsuit. Cf. {Cause}.]
   1. To charge with, or declare to have committed, a crime or
      offense; (Law) to charge with an offense, judicially or by
      a public process; -- with of; as, to accuse one of a high
      crime or misdemeanor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Neither can they prove the things whereof they now
            accuse me.                            --Acts xxiv.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are accused of having persuaded Austria and
            Sardinia to lay down their arms.      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To charge with a fault; to blame; to censure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their thoughts the meanwhile accusing or else
            excusing one another.                 --Rom. ii. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To betray; to show. [R.]                    --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To charge; blame; censure; reproach; criminate; indict;
        impeach; arraign.

   Usage: To {Accuse}, {Charge}, {Impeach}, {Arraign}. These
          words agree in bringing home to a person the
          imputation of wrongdoing. To accuse is a somewhat
          formal act, and is applied usually (though not
          exclusively) to crimes; as, to accuse of treason.
          Charge is the most generic. It may refer to a crime, a
          dereliction of duty, a fault, etc.; more commonly it
          refers to moral delinquencies; as, to charge with
          dishonesty or falsehood. To arraign is to bring (a
          person) before a tribunal for trial; as, to arraign
          one before a court or at the bar public opinion. To
          impeach is officially to charge with misbehavior in
          office; as, to impeach a minister of high crimes. Both
          impeach and arraign convey the idea of peculiar
          dignity or impressiveness.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accusing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>accusing \accusing\ adj.
   1. serving to accuse; expressing accusation

   Syn: accusatorial, accusatory
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accusing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>accusing
     adj : containing or expressing accusation; "an accusitive
           forefinger"; "black accusatory looks"; "accusive shoes
           and telltale trousers"- O.Henry; "his accusing glare"
           [syn: {accusative}, {accusatory}, {accusive}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
