<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>accurate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accurate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Accurate \Ac"cu*rate\, a. [L. accuratus, p. p. and a., fr.
   accurare to take care of; ad + curare to take care, cura
   care. See {Cure}.]
   1. In exact or careful conformity to truth, or to some
      standard of requirement, the result of care or pains; free
      from failure, error, or defect; exact; as, an accurate
      calculator; an accurate measure; accurate expression,
      knowledge, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Precisely fixed; executed with care; careful. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Those conceive the celestial bodies have more
            accurate influences upon these things below.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Correct; exact; just; nice; particular.

   Usage: {Accurate}, {Correct}, {Exact}, {Precise}. We speak of
          a thing as correct with reference to some rule or
          standard of comparison; as, a correct account, a
          correct likeness, a man of correct deportment. We
          speak of a thing as accurate with reference to the
          care bestowed upon its execution, and the increased
          correctness to be expected therefrom; as, an accurate
          statement, an accurate detail of particulars. We speak
          of a thing as exact with reference to that perfected
          state of a thing in which there is no defect and no
          redundance; as, an exact coincidence, the exact truth,
          an exact likeness. We speak of a thing as precise when
          we think of it as strictly conformed to some rule or
          model, as if cut down thereto; as a precise conformity
          instructions; precisely right; he was very precise in
          giving his directions.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>accurate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>accurate
     adj 1: conforming exactly or almost exactly to fact or to a
            standard or performing with total accuracy; "an
            accurate reproduction"; "the accounting was accurate";
            "accurate measurements"; "an accurate scale" [ant: {inaccurate}]
     2: (of ideas, images, representations, expressions)
        characterized by perfect conformity to fact or truth ;
        strictly correct; "a precise image"; "a precise
        measurement" [syn: {exact}, {precise}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
