<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>acknowledgement</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acknowledgement</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Acknowledgment \Ac*knowl"edg*ment\, Acknowledgement
\Ac*knowl"edge*ment\ ([a^]k*n[o^]l"[e^]j*ment), n.
   1. The act of acknowledging; admission; avowal; owning;
      confession. ``An acknowledgment of fault.'' --Froude.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of owning or recognizing in a particular character
      or relationship; recognition as regards the existence,
      authority, truth, or genuineness; a statement
      acknowledging something or someone.
      [1913 Webster +WordNet 1.5]

            Immediately upon the acknowledgment of the Christian
            faith, the eunuch was baptized by Philip. --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The owning of a benefit received; courteous recognition;
      the state or quality of being recognized or acknowledged;
      an expression of thanks. --Shak.

   Syn: recognition
        [1913 Webster +WordNet 1.5]

   4. Something given or done in return for a favor, message,
      etc. --Smollett.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A declaration or avowal of one's own act, to give it legal
      validity; as, the acknowledgment of a deed before a proper
      officer. Also, the certificate of the officer attesting
      such declaration.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Acknowledgment money}, in some parts of England, a sum paid
      by copyhold tenants, on the death of their landlords, as
      an acknowledgment of their new lords. --Cowell.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Confession; concession; recognition; admission; avowal;
        recognizance.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acknowledgement</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>acknowledgement
     n 1: the state or quality of being recognized or acknowledged;
          "the partners were delighted with the recognition of
          their work"; "she seems to avoid much in the way of
          recognition or acknowledgement of feminist work prior to
          her own" [syn: {recognition}, {acknowledgment}]
     2: a statement acknowledging something or someone; "she must
        have seen him but she gave no sign of acknowledgment";
        "the preface contained an acknowledgment of those who had
        helped her" [syn: {acknowledgment}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
