<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>acknowledge</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acknowledge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ACKNOWLEDGE, v.t.  To confess.  Acknowledgement of one another's
faults is the highest duty imposed by our love of truth.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acknowledge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>acknowledge \ac*knowl"edge\ ([a^]k*n[o^]l"[e^]j), v. t. [imp. &amp;
   p. p. {acknowledged} ([a^]k*n[o^]l"[e^]jd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {acknowledging} ([a^]k*n[o^]l"[e^]j*[i^]ng).] [Prob. fr.
   pref. a- + the verb knowledge. See {Knowledge}, and cf.
   {Acknow}.]
   1. To own or admit the knowledge of; to recognize as a fact
      or truth; to declare one's belief in; as, to acknowledge
      the being of a God.
      [1913 Webster]

            I acknowledge my transgressions.      --Ps. li. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            For ends generally acknowledged to be good.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To own or recognize in a particular character or
      relationship; to admit the claims or authority of; to give
      recognition to.
      [1913 Webster]

            In all thy ways acknowledge Him.      --Prov. iii.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

            By my soul, I'll ne'er acknowledge thee. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To own with gratitude or as a benefit or an obligation;
      as, to acknowledge a favor, the receipt of a letter.
      [1913 Webster]

            They his gifts acknowledged none.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To own as genuine; to assent to, as a legal instrument, to
      give it validity; to avow or admit in legal form; as, to
      acknowledge a deed.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To avow; proclaim; recognize; own; admit; allow;
        concede; confess.

   Usage: {Acknowledge}, {Recognize}. Acknowledge is opposed to
          keep back, or conceal, and supposes that something had
          been previously known to us (though perhaps not to
          others) which we now feel bound to lay open or make
          public. Thus, a man acknowledges a secret marriage;
          one who has done wrong acknowledges his fault; and
          author acknowledges his obligation to those who have
          aided him; we acknowledge our ignorance. Recognize
          supposes that we have either forgotten or not had the
          evidence of a thing distinctly before our minds, but
          that now we know it (as it were) anew, or receive and
          admit in on the ground of the evidence it brings.
          Thus, we recognize a friend after a long absence. We
          recognize facts, principles, truths, etc., when their
          evidence is brought up fresh to the mind; as, bad men
          usually recognize the providence of God in seasons of
          danger. A foreign minister, consul, or agent, of any
          kind, is recognized on the ground of his producing
          satisfactory credentials. See also {Confess}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acknowledge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>acknowledge
     v 1: declare to be true or admit the existence or reality or
          truth of; "He admitted his errors"; "She acknowledged
          that she might have forgotten" [syn: {admit}] [ant: {deny}]
     2: report the receipt of; "The program committee acknowledged
        the submission of the authors of the paper" [syn: {receipt}]
     3: express recognition of the presence or existence of, or
        acquaintance with; "He never acknowledges his colleagues
        when they run into him in the hallway"; "She acknowledged
        his complement with a smile"; "it is important to
        acknowledge the work of others in one's own writing" [syn:
         {notice}]
     4: express obligation, thanks, or gratitude for; "We must
        acknowledge the kindness she showed towards us" [syn: {recognize},
         {recognise}]
     5: accept as legally binding and valid; "acknowledge the deed"
     6: accept (someone) to be what is claimed or accept his power
        and authority; "The Crown Prince was acknowledged as the
        true heir to the throne"; "We do not recognize your gods"
        [syn: {recognize}, {recognise}, {know}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
