<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>acquaintance</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acquaintance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ACQUAINTANCE, n.  A person whom we know well enough to borrow from,
but not well enough to lend to.  A degree of friendship called slight
when its object is poor or obscure, and intimate when he is rich or
famous.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acquaintance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Acquaintance \Ac*quaint"ance\, n. [OE. aqueintance, OF.
   acointance, fr. acointier. See {Acquaint}.]
   1. A state of being acquainted, or of having intimate, or
      more than slight or superficial, knowledge; personal
      knowledge gained by intercourse short of that of
      friendship or intimacy; as, I know the man; but have no
      acquaintance with him.
      [1913 Webster]

            Contract no friendship, or even acquaintance, with a
            guileful man.                         --Sir W.
                                                  Jones.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A person or persons with whom one is acquainted.
      [1913 Webster]

            Montgomery was an old acquaintance of Ferguson.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense the collective term acquaintance was
         formerly both singular and plural, but it is now
         commonly singular, and has the regular plural
         acquaintances.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To be of acquaintance}, to be intimate.

   {To take acquaintance of} or {with}, to make the acquaintance
      of. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Familiarity; intimacy; fellowship; knowledge.

   Usage: {Acquaintance}, {Familiarity}, {Intimacy}. These words
          mark different degrees of closeness in social
          intercourse. Acquaintance arises from occasional
          intercourse; as, our acquaintance has been a brief
          one. We can speak of a slight or an intimate
          acquaintance. Familiarity is the result of continued
          acquaintance. It springs from persons being frequently
          together, so as to wear off all restraint and reserve;
          as, the familiarity of old companions. Intimacy is the
          result of close connection, and the freest interchange
          of thought; as, the intimacy of established
          friendship.
          [1913 Webster]

                Our admiration of a famous man lessens upon our
                nearer acquaintance with him.     --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

                We contract at last such a familiarity with them
                as makes it difficult and irksome for us to call
                off our minds.                    --Atterbury.
          [1913 Webster]

                It is in our power to confine our friendships
                and intimacies to men of virtue.  --Rogers.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>acquaintance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>acquaintance
     n 1: personal knowledge or information about someone or something
          [syn: {familiarity}, {conversance}, {conversancy}]
     2: a relationship less intimate than friendship [syn: {acquaintanceship}]
     3: a person with whom you are acquainted; "I have trouble
        remembering the names of all my acquaintances"; "we are
        friends of the family" [syn: {friend}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
