<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>adam</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>adam</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Adam
   red, a Babylonian word, the generic name for man, having the
   same meaning in the Hebrew and the Assyrian languages. It was
   the name given to the first man, whose creation, fall, and
   subsequent history and that of his descendants are detailed in
   the first book of Moses (Gen. 1:27-ch. 5). "God created man
   [Heb., Adam] in his own image, in the image of God created he
   him; male and female created he them."
   
     Adam was absolutely the first man whom God created. He was
   formed out of the dust of the earth (and hence his name), and
   God breathed into his nostrils the breath of life, and gave him
   dominion over all the lower creatures (Gen. 1:26; 2:7). He was
   placed after his creation in the Garden of Eden, to cultivate
   it, and to enjoy its fruits under this one prohibition: "Of the
   tree of the knowledge of good and evil thou shalt not eat of it;
   for in the day that thou eatest thereof thou shalt surely die."
   
     The first recorded act of Adam was his giving names to the
   beasts of the field and the fowls of the air, which God brought
   to him for this end. Thereafter the Lord caused a deep sleep to
   fall upon him, and while in an unconscious state took one of his
   ribs, and closed up his flesh again; and of this rib he made a
   woman, whom he presented to him when he awoke. Adam received her
   as his wife, and said, "This is now bone of my bones, and flesh
   of my flesh: she shall be called Woman, because she was taken
   out of Man." He called her Eve, because she was the mother of
   all living.
   
     Being induced by the tempter in the form of a serpent to eat
   the forbidden fruit, Eve persuaded Adam, and he also did eat.
   Thus man fell, and brought upon himself and his posterity all
   the sad consequences of his transgression. The narrative of the
   Fall comprehends in it the great promise of a Deliverer (Gen.
   3:15), the "first gospel" message to man. They were expelled
   from Eden, and at the east of the garden God placed a flame,
   which turned every way, to prevent access to the tree of life
   (Gen. 3). How long they were in Paradise is matter of mere
   conjecture.
   
     Shortly after their expulsion Eve brought forth her
   first-born, and called him Cain. Although we have the names of
   only three of Adam's sons, viz., Cain, Abel, and Seth, yet it is
   obvious that he had several sons and daughters (Gen. 5:4). He
   died aged 930 years.
   
     Adam and Eve were the progenitors of the whole human race.
   Evidences of varied kinds are abundant in proving the unity of
   the human race. The investigations of science, altogether
   independent of historical evidence, lead to the conclusion that
   God "hath made of one blood all nations of men for to dwell on
   all the face of the earth" (Acts 17:26. Comp. Rom. 5:12-12; 1
   Cor. 15:22-49).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>adam</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ADAM
     
        {A Data Management system}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>adam</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Adam \Ad"am\, n.
   1. The name given in the Bible to the first man, the
      progenitor of the human race.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (As a symbol) ``Original sin;'' human frailty.
      [1913 Webster]

            And whipped the offending Adam out of him. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Adam's ale}, water. [Coll.]

   {Adam's apple}.

   1. (Bot.)
      (a) A species of banana ({Musa paradisiaca}). It attains a
          height of twenty feet or more. --Paxton.
      (b) A species of lime ({Citris limetta}).

   2. The projection formed by the thyroid cartilage in the
      neck. It is particularly prominent in males, and is so
      called from a notion that it was caused by the forbidden
      fruit (an apple) sticking in the throat of our first
      parent.

   {Adam's flannel} (Bot.), the mullein ({Verbascum thapsus}).
      

   {Adam's needle} (Bot.), the popular name of a genus ({Yucca})
      of liliaceous plants.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>adam</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Adam, earthy; red

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>adam</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Adam
     n 1: (Old Testament) in Judeo-Christian mythology; the first man
          and the husband of Eve and the progenitor of the human
          race
     2: Scottish architect who designed many public buildings in
        England and Scotland (1728-1792) [syn: {Robert Adam}]
     3: street names for methylenedioxymethamphetamine [syn: {ecstasy},
         {XTC}, {go}, {disco biscuit}, {cristal}, {X}, {hug drug}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
