<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>adjourned</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>adjourned</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Adjourn \Ad*journ\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Adjourned}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Adjourning}.] [OE. ajornen, OF. ajoiner, ajurner, F.
   ajourner; OF. a (L. ad) + jor, jur, jorn, F. jour, day, fr.
   L. diurnus belonging to the day, fr. dies day. Cf. {Journal},
   {Journey}.]
   To put off or defer to another day, or indefinitely; to
   postpone; to close or suspend for the day; -- commonly said
   of the meeting, or the action, of convened body; as, to
   adjourn the meeting; to adjourn a debate.
   [1913 Webster]

         It is a common practice to adjourn the reformation of
         their lives to a further time.           --Barrow.
   [1913 Webster]

         'Tis a needful fitness
         That we adjourn this court till further day. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To delay; defer; postpone; put off; suspend.

   Usage: To {Adjourn}, {Prorogue}, {Dissolve}. These words are
          used in respect to public bodies when they lay aside
          business and separate. Adjourn, both in Great Britain
          and this country, is applied to all cases in which
          such bodies separate for a brief period, with a view
          to meet again. Prorogue is applied in Great Britain to
          that act of the executive government, as the
          sovereign, which brings a session of Parliament to a
          close. The word is not used in this country, but a
          legislative body is said, in such a case, to adjourn
          sine die. To dissolve is to annul the corporate
          existence of a body. In order to exist again the body
          must be reconstituted.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
