<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>administration</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>administration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ADMINISTRATION, n.  An ingenious abstraction in politics, designed to
receive the kicks and cuffs due to the premier or president.  A man of
straw, proof against bad-egging and dead-catting.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>administration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Administration \Ad*min`is*tra"tion\ (?; 277), n. [OE.
   administracioun, L. administratio: cf. F. administration.]
   1. The act of administering; government of public affairs;
      the service rendered, or duties assumed, in conducting
      affairs; the conducting of any office or employment;
      direction; management.
      [1913 Webster]

            His financial administration was of a piece with his
            military administration.              --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The executive part of government; the persons collectively
      who are intrusted with the execution of laws and the
      superintendence of public affairs; the chief magistrate
      and his cabinet or council; or the council, or ministry,
      alone, as in Great Britain.
      [1913 Webster]

            A mild and popular administration.    --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            The administration has been opposed in parliament.
                                                  --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The act of administering, or tendering something to
      another; dispensation; as, the administration of a
      medicine, of an oath, of justice, or of the sacrament.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law)
      (a) The management and disposal, under legal authority, of
          the estate of an intestate, or of a testator having no
          competent executor.
      (b) The management of an estate of a deceased person by an
          executor, the strictly corresponding term execution
          not being in use.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Administration with the will annexed}, administration
      granted where the testator has appointed no executor, or
      where his appointment of an executor for any cause has
      failed, as by death, incompetency, refusal to act, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Conduct; management; direction; regulation; execution;
        dispensation; distribution.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>administration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>administration
     n 1: a method of tending to (especially business) matters [syn: {disposal}]
     2: the persons (or committees or departments etc.) who make up
        a body for the purpose of administering something; "he
        claims that the present administration is corrupt"; "the
        governance of an association is responsible to its
        members"; "he quickly became recognized as a member of the
        establishment" [syn: {governance}, {governing body}, {establishment},
         {brass}, {organization}, {organisation}]
     3: the act of administering medication [syn: {giving medication}]
     4: the tenure of a president; "things were quiet during the
        Eisenhower administration" [syn: {presidency}, {presidential
        term}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
