<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>advantage</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>advantage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Turn \Turn\, v. i.
   1. To move round; to have a circular motion; to revolve
      entirely, repeatedly, or partially; to change position, so
      as to face differently; to whirl or wheel round; as, a
      wheel turns on its axis; a spindle turns on a pivot; a man
      turns on his heel.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gate . . . on golden hinges turning. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to revolve as if upon a point of support; to hinge;
      to depend; as, the decision turns on a single fact.
      [1913 Webster]

            Conditions of peace certainly turn upon events of
            war.                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To result or terminate; to come about; to eventuate; to
      issue.
      [1913 Webster]

            If we repent seriously, submit contentedly, and
            serve him faithfully, afflictions shall turn to our
            advantage.                            --Wake.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be deflected; to take a different direction or
      tendency; to be directed otherwise; to be differently
      applied; to be transferred; as, to turn from the road.
      [1913 Webster]

            Turn from thy fierce wrath.           --Ex. xxxii.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Turn ye, turn ye from your evil ways. --Ezek.
                                                  xxxiii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

            The understanding turns inward on itself, and
            reflects on its own operations.       --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be changed, altered, or transformed; to become
      transmuted; also, to become by a change or changes; to
      grow; as, wood turns to stone; water turns to ice; one
      color turns to another; to turn Mohammedan.
      [1913 Webster]

            I hope you have no intent to turn husband. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cygnets from gray turn white.         --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To undergo the process of turning on a lathe; as, ivory
      turns well.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To become acid; to sour; -- said of milk, ale, etc.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To become giddy; -- said of the head or brain.
          [1913 Webster]

                I'll look no more;
                Lest my brain turn.               --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To be nauseated; -- said of the stomach.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To become inclined in the other direction; -- said of
          scales.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To change from ebb to flow, or from flow to ebb; --
          said of the tide.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) (Obstetrics) To bring down the feet of a child in the
          womb, in order to facilitate delivery.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Print.) To invert a type of the same thickness, as
      temporary substitute for any sort which is exhausted.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To turn about}, to face to another quarter; to turn around.
      

   {To turn again}, to come back after going; to return. --Shak.

   {To turn against}, to become unfriendly or hostile to.

   {To turn aside} or {To turn away}.
      (a) To turn from the direct course; to withdraw from a
          company; to deviate.
      (b) To depart; to remove.
      (c) To avert one's face.

   {To turn back}, to turn so as to go in an opposite direction;
      to retrace one's steps.

   {To turn in}.
      (a) To bend inward.
      (b) To enter for lodgings or entertainment.
      (c) To go to bed. [Colloq.]

   {To turn into}, to enter by making a turn; as, to turn into a
      side street.

   {To turn off}, to be diverted; to deviate from a course; as,
      the road turns off to the left.

   {To turn on} or {To turn upon}.
      (a) To turn against; to confront in hostility or anger.
      (b) To reply to or retort.
      (c) To depend on; as, the result turns on one condition.
          

   {To turn out}.
      (a) To move from its place, as a bone.
      (b) To bend or point outward; as, his toes turn out.
      (c) To rise from bed. [Colloq.]
      (d) To come abroad; to appear; as, not many turned out to
          the fire.
      (e) To prove in the result; to issue; to result; as, the
          crops turned out poorly.

   {To turn over}, to turn from side to side; to roll; to
      tumble.

   {To turn round}.
      (a) To change position so as to face in another direction.
      (b) To change one's opinion; to change from one view or
          party to another.

   {To turn to}, to apply one's self to; have recourse to; to
      refer to. ``Helvicus's tables may be turned to on all
      occasions.'' --Locke.

   {To turn to account}, {profit}, {advantage}, or the like, to
      be made profitable or advantageous; to become worth the
      while.

   {To turn under}, to bend, or be folded, downward or under.

   {To turn up}.
      (a) To bend, or be doubled, upward.
      (b) To appear; to come to light; to transpire; to occur;
          to happen.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>advantage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Advantage \Ad*van"tage\ (?; 61, 48), n. [OE. avantage,
   avauntage, F. avantage, fr. avant before. See {Advance}, and
   cf. {Vantage}.]
   1. Any condition, circumstance, opportunity, or means,
      particularly favorable to success, or to any desired end;
      benefit; as, the enemy had the advantage of a more
      elevated position.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give me advantage of some brief discourse. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The advantages of a close alliance.   --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Superiority; mastery; -- with of or over.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lest Satan should get an advantage of us. --2 Cor.
                                                  ii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Superiority of state, or that which gives it; benefit;
      gain; profit; as, the advantage of a good constitution.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Interest of money; increase; overplus (as the thirteenth
      in the baker's dozen). [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            And with advantage means to pay thy love. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Advantage ground}, vantage ground. [R.] --Clarendon.

   {To have the advantage of} (any one), to have a personal
      knowledge of one who does not have a reciprocal knowledge.
      ``You have the advantage of me; I don't remember ever to
      have had the honor.'' --Sheridan.

   {To take advantage of}, to profit by; (often used in a bad
      sense) to overreach, to outwit.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: {Advantage}, {Advantageous}, {Benefit}, {Beneficial}.

   Usage: We speak of a thing as a benefit, or as beneficial,
          when it is simply productive of good; as, the benefits
          of early discipline; the beneficial effects of
          adversity. We speak of a thing as an advantage, or as
          advantageous, when it affords us the means of getting
          forward, and places us on a ``vantage ground'' for
          further effort. Hence, there is a difference between
          the benefits and the advantages of early education;
          between a beneficial and an advantageous investment of
          money.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>advantage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Advantage \Ad*van"tage\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Advantaged}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Advantaging}.] [F. avantager, fr. avantage. See
   {Advance}.]
   To give an advantage to; to further; to promote; to benefit;
   to profit.
   [1913 Webster]

         The truth is, the archbishop's own stiffness and
         averseness to comply with the court designs, advantaged
         his adversaries against him.             --Fuller.
   [1913 Webster]

         What is a man advantaged, if he gain the whole world,
         and lose himself, or be cast away?       --Luke ix. 25.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To advantage one's self of}, to avail one's self of. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>advantage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>advantage
     n 1: the quality of having a superior or more favorable position;
          "the experience gave him the advantage over me" [syn: {vantage}]
          [ant: {disadvantage}]
     2: first point scored after deuce
     3: benefit resulting from some event or action; "it turned out
        to my advantage"; "reaping the rewards of generosity"
        [syn: {reward}] [ant: {penalty}]
     v : give an advantage to; "This system advantages the rich"
         [ant: {disadvantage}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
