<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>age</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>age</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>AGE, n.  That period of life in which we compound for the vices that
we still cherish by reviling those that we have no longer the
enterprise to commit.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>age</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Age
   used to denote the period of a man's life (Gen. 47:28), the
   maturity of life (John 9:21), the latter end of life (Job
   11:17), a generation of the human race (Job 8:8), and an
   indefinite period (Eph. 2:7; 3:5, 21; Col. 1:26). Respect to be
   shown to the aged (Lev. 19:32). It is a blessing to communities
   when they have old men among them (Isa. 65:20; Zech. 8:4). The
   aged supposed to excel in understanding (Job 12:20; 15:10; 32:4,
   9; 1 Kings 12:6, 8). A full age the reward of piety (Job 5:26;
   Gen. 15:15).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>age</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Age \Age\ ([=a]j), n. [OF. aage, eage, F. [^a]ge, fr. L. aetas
   through a supposed LL. aetaticum. L. aetas is contracted fr.
   aevitas, fr. aevum lifetime, age; akin to E. aye ever. Cf.
   {Each}.]
   1. The whole duration of a being, whether animal, vegetable,
      or other kind; lifetime.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mine age is as nothing before thee.   --Ps. xxxix.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That part of the duration of a being or a thing which is
      between its beginning and any given time; as, what is the
      present age of a man, or of the earth?
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The latter part of life; an advanced period of life;
      seniority; state of being old.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor wrong mine age with this indignity. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. One of the stages of life; as, the age of infancy, of
      youth, etc. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Mature age; especially, the time of life at which one
      attains full personal rights and capacities; as, to come
      of age; he (or she) is of age. --Abbott.

   Note: In the United States, both males and females are of age
         when twenty-one years old. Some rights, such as that of
         voting in elections, are conferred earlier.
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   6. The time of life at which some particular power or
      capacity is understood to become vested; as, the age of
      consent; the age of discretion. --Abbott.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A particular period of time in history, as distinguished
      from others; as, the golden age, the age of Pericles.
      ``The spirit of the age.'' --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Truth, in some age or other, will find her witness.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Archeological ages are designated as three: The Stone
         age (the early and the later stone age, called
         paleolithic and neolithic), the Bronze age, and the
         Iron age. During the Age of Stone man is supposed to
         have employed stone for weapons and implements.
         [1913 Webster] See {Augustan}, {Brazen}, {Golden},
         {Heroic}, {Middle}.
         [1913 Webster]

   8. A great period in the history of the Earth.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The geologic ages are as follows: 1. The Arch[ae]an,
         including the time when was no life and the time of the
         earliest and simplest forms of life. 2. The age of
         Invertebrates, or the Silurian, when the life on the
         globe consisted distinctively of invertebrates. 3. The
         age of Fishes, or the Devonian, when fishes were the
         dominant race. 4. The age of Coal Plants, or Acrogens,
         or the Carboniferous age. 5. The Mesozoic or Secondary
         age, or age of Reptiles, when reptiles prevailed in
         great numbers and of vast size. 6. The Tertiary age, or
         age of Mammals, when the mammalia, or quadrupeds,
         abounded, and were the dominant race. 7. The Quaternary
         age, or age of Man, or the modern era. --Dana.
         [1913 Webster]

   9. A century; the period of one hundred years.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fleury . . . apologizes for these five ages.
                                                  --Hallam.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The people who live at a particular period; hence, a
       generation. ``Ages yet unborn.'' --Pope.
       [1913 Webster]

             The way which the age follows.       --J. H.
                                                  Newman.
       [1913 Webster]

             Lo! where the stage, the poor, degraded stage,
             Holds its warped mirror to a gaping age. --C.
                                                  Sprague.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A long time. [Colloq.] ``He made minutes an age.''
       --Tennyson.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (poker) the right belonging to the player to the left of
       the dealer to pass the first round in betting, and then
       to come in last or stay out; also, the player holding
       this position; the eldest hand.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Age of a tide}, the time from the origin of a tide in the
      South Pacific Ocean to its arrival at a given place.

   {Moon's age}, the time that has elapsed since the last
      preceding conjunction of the sun and moon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Age is used to form the first part of many compounds;
         as, agelasting, age-adorning, age-worn, age-enfeebled,
         agelong.
         [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Time; period; generation; date; era; epoch.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>age</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Age \Age\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Aged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Aging}.]
   To grow aged; to become old; to show marks of age; as, he
   grew fat as he aged.
   [1913 Webster]

         They live one hundred and thirty years, and never age
         for all that.                            --Holland.
   [1913 Webster]

         I am aging; that is, I have a whitish, or rather a
         light-colored, hair here and there.      --Landor.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>age</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Age \Age\, v. t.
   To cause to grow old; to impart the characteristics of age
   to; as, grief ages us.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>age</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>age
     n 1: how long something has existed; "it was replaced because of
          its age"
     2: an era of history having some distinctive feature; "we live
        in a litigious age" [syn: {historic period}]
     3: a time in life (usually defined in years) at which some
        particular qualification or power arises; "she was now of
        school age"; "tall for his eld" [syn: {eld}]
     4: a late time of life; "old age is not for sissies"; "he's
        showing his years"; "age hasn't slowed him down at all";
        "a beard white with eld"; "on the brink of geezerhood"
        [syn: {old age}, {years}, {eld}, {geezerhood}]
     5: a prolonged period of time; "we've known each other for
        ages"; "I haven't been there for years and years" [syn: {long
        time}, {years}]
     v 1: begin to seem older; get older; "The death of his wife
          caused him to age fast"
     2: grow old or older; "She aged gracefully"; "we age every
        day--what a depressing thought!"; "Young men senesce"
        [syn: {senesce}, {get on}, {mature}, {maturate}]
     3: make older; "The death of his child aged him tremendously"
        [ant: {rejuvenate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
