<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>airplane</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>airplane</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>aeroplane \aer"*o*plane`\ aeroplane \a"["e]r*o*plane`\, n.
   [a["e]ro- + plane.] (A["e]ronautics)
   1. A light rigid plane used in a["e]rial navigation to oppose
      sudden upward or downward movement in the air, as in
      gliding machines; specif., such a plane slightly inclined
      and driven forward as a lifting device in some flying
      machines. Also called {airfoil}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. hence, a heavier-than-air flying machine using such a
      device to provide lift. In a modern aeroplane, the
      airfoils are called the {wings}, and most of the lift is
      derived from these surfaces. In contrast to helicopters,
      the wings are fixed to the passenger compartment
      (airframe) and do not move relative to the frame; thus
      such a machine is called a {fixed-wing aircraft}. These
      machines are called monoplanes, biplanes, triplanes, or
      quadruplanes, according to the number of main supporting
      planes (wings) used in their construction. After 1940 few
      planes with more than one airfoil were constructed, and
      these are used by hobbyists or for special purposes. Being
      heavier than air they depend for their levitation on
      motion imparted by the thrust from either propellers
      driven by an engine, or, in a jet plane, by the reaction
      from a high-velocity stream of gases expelled rearward
      from a jet engine. They start from the ground by a run on
      small wheels or runners, and are guided by a steering
      apparatus consisting of horizontal and vertical movable
      planes, which usually form part of the wings or tail.
      There are many varieties of form and construction, which
      in some cases are known by the names of their inventors.
      In U.S., an aeroplane is usually called an {airplane} or
      {plane}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>airplane</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>airplane \air"plane\ n.
   a heavier-than-air aircraft. Same as {{aeroplane[2]}}.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>airplane</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>airplane
     n : an aircraft that has a fixed wing and is powered by
         propellers or jets; "the flight was delayed due to
         trouble with the airplane" [syn: {aeroplane}, {plane}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
