<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>airport</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>airport</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Airport, FL
  Zip code(s): 34622
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>airport</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Port \Port\, n. [F. porte, L. porta, akin to portus; cf. AS.
   porte, fr. L. porta. See {Port} a harbor, and cf. {Porte}.]
   1. A passageway; an opening or entrance to an inclosed place;
      a gate; a door; a portal. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Him I accuse
            The city ports by this hath entered.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Form their ivory port the cherubim
            Forth issuing.                        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) An opening in the side of a vessel; an embrasure
      through which cannon may be discharged; a porthole; also,
      the shutters which close such an opening.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her ports being within sixteen inches of the water.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Raleigh.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.) A passageway in a machine, through which a fluid,
      as steam, water, etc., may pass, as from a valve to the
      interior of the cylinder of a steam engine; an opening in
      a valve seat, or valve face.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Air port}, {Bridle port}, etc. See under {Air}, {Bridle},
      etc.

   {Port bar} (Naut.), a bar to secure the ports of a ship in a
      gale.

   {Port lid} (Naut.), a lid or hanging for closing the
      portholes of a vessel.

   {Steam port}, &amp; {Exhaust port} (Steam Engine), the ports of
      the cylinder communicating with the valve or valves, for
      the entrance or exit of the steam, respectively.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>airport</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Air \Air\ ([^a]r), n. [OE. air, eir, F. air, L. a["e]r, fr. Gr.
   'ah`r, air, mist, for 'a[digamma]hr, fr. root 'a[digamma] to
   blow, breathe, probably akin to E. wind. In sense 10 the
   French has taking a meaning fr. It. aria atmosphere, air, fr.
   the same Latin word; and in senses 11, 12, 13 the French
   meaning is either fr. L. aria, or due to confusion with F.
   aire, in an older sense of origin, descent. Cf. {A["e]ry},
   {Debonair}, {Malaria}, {Wind}.]
   1. The fluid which we breathe, and which surrounds the earth;
      the atmosphere. It is invisible, inodorous, insipid,
      transparent, compressible, elastic, and ponderable.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: By the ancient philosophers, air was regarded as an
         element; but modern science has shown that it is
         essentially a mixture of oxygen and nitrogen, with a
         small amount of carbon dioxide, the average proportions
         being, by volume: oxygen, 20.96 per cent.; nitrogen,
         79.00 per cent.; carbon dioxide, 0.04 per cent. These
         proportions are subject to a very slight variability.
         Air also always contains some vapor of water.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Symbolically: Something unsubstantial, light, or volatile.
      ``Charm ache with air.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was still all air and fire. [Air and fire being
      the finer and quicker elements as opposed to earth and
      water.]                                     --Macaulay
      .
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A particular state of the atmosphere, as respects heat,
      cold, moisture, etc., or as affecting the sensations; as,
      a smoky air, a damp air, the morning air, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any a["e]riform body; a gas; as, oxygen was formerly
      called vital air. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Air in motion; a light breeze; a gentle wind.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let vernal airs through trembling osiers play.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Odoriferous or contaminated air.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. That which surrounds and influences.
      [1913 Webster]

            The keen, the wholesome air of poverty.
                                                  --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Utterance abroad; publicity; vent.
      [1913 Webster]

            You gave it air before me.            --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Intelligence; information. [Obs.] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mus.)
       (a) A musical idea, or motive, rhythmically developed in
           consecutive single tones, so as to form a symmetrical
           and balanced whole, which may be sung by a single
           voice to the stanzas of a hymn or song, or even to
           plain prose, or played upon an instrument; a melody;
           a tune; an aria.
       (b) In harmonized chorals, psalmody, part songs, etc.,
           the part which bears the tune or melody -- in modern
           harmony usually the upper part -- is sometimes called
           the air.
           [1913 Webster]

   11. The peculiar look, appearance, and bearing of a person;
       mien; demeanor; as, the air of a youth; a heavy air; a
       lofty air. ``His very air.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Peculiar appearance; apparent character; semblance;
       manner; style.
       [1913 Webster]

             It was communicated with the air of a secret.
                                                  --Pope.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. pl. An artificial or affected manner; show of pride or
       vanity; haughtiness; as, it is said of a person, he puts
       on airs. --Thackeray.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Paint.)
       (a) The representation or reproduction of the effect of
           the atmospheric medium through which every object in
           nature is viewed. --New Am. Cyc.
       (b) Carriage; attitude; action; movement; as, the head of
           that portrait has a good air. --Fairholt.
           [1913 Webster]

   15. (Man.) The artificial motion or carriage of a horse.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Air is much used adjectively or as the first part of a
         compound term. In most cases it might be written
         indifferently, as a separate limiting word, or as the
         first element of the compound term, with or without the
         hyphen; as, air bladder, air-bladder, or airbladder;
         air cell, air-cell, or aircell; air-pump, or airpump.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Air balloon}. See {Balloon}.

   {Air bath}.
       (a) An apparatus for the application of air to the body.
       (b) An arrangement for drying substances in air of any
           desired temperature.

   {Air castle}. See {Castle in the air}, under {Castle}.

   {Air compressor}, a machine for compressing air to be used as
      a motive power.

   {Air crossing}, a passage for air in a mine.

   {Air cushion}, an air-tight cushion which can be inflated;
      also, a device for arresting motion without shock by
      confined air.

   {Air fountain}, a contrivance for producing a jet of water by
      the force of compressed air.

   {Air furnace}, a furnace which depends on a natural draft and
      not on blast.

   {Air line}, a straight line; a bee line. Hence

   {Air-line}, adj.; as, air-line road.

   {Air lock} (Hydr. Engin.), an intermediate chamber between
      the outer air and the compressed-air chamber of a
      pneumatic caisson. --Knight.

   {Air port} (Nav.), a scuttle or porthole in a ship to admit
      air.

   {Air spring}, a spring in which the elasticity of air is
      utilized.

   {Air thermometer}, a form of thermometer in which the
      contraction and expansion of air is made to measure
      changes of temperature.

   {Air threads}, gossamer.

   {Air trap}, a contrivance for shutting off foul air or gas
      from drains, sewers, etc.; a stench trap.

   {Air trunk}, a pipe or shaft for conducting foul or heated
      air from a room.

   {Air valve}, a valve to regulate the admission or egress of
      air; esp. a valve which opens inwardly in a steam boiler
      and allows air to enter.

   {Air way}, a passage for a current of air; as the air way of
      an air pump; an air way in a mine.

   {In the air}.
       (a) Prevalent without traceable origin or authority, as
           rumors.
       (b) Not in a fixed or stable position; unsettled.
       (c) (Mil.) Unsupported and liable to be turned or taken
           in flank; as, the army had its wing in the air.

   {on the air}, currently transmitting; live; -- used of radio
      and television broadcasts, to indicate that the images and
      sounds being picked up by cameras and microphones are
      being broadcast at the present moment.

   Note: In call-in programs where individuals outside a radio
         or television studio have telephoned into the station,
         when their voice is being directly broadcast, the host
         of the program commonly states ``You're on the air.''
         as a warning that the conversation is not private.

   {To take air}, to be divulged; to be made public.

   {To take the air}, to go abroad; to walk or ride out.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>airport</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>airport
     n : an airfield equipped with control tower and hangers as well
         as accommodations for passengers and cargo [syn: {airdrome},
          {aerodrome}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
