<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>alcohol</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>alcohol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Alcohol \Al"co*hol\ ([a^]l"k[-o]*h[o^]l), n. [Cf. F. alcool,
   formerly written alcohol, Sp. alcohol alcohol, antimony,
   galena, OSp. alcofol; all fr. Ar. al-kohl a powder of
   antimony or galena, to paint the eyebrows with. The name was
   afterwards applied, on account of the fineness of this
   powder, to highly rectified spirits, a signification unknown
   in Arabia. The Sp. word has both meanings. Cf. {Alquifou}.]
   1. An impalpable powder. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The fluid essence or pure spirit obtained by distillation.
      [Obs.] --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Pure spirit of wine; pure or highly rectified spirit
      (called also {ethyl alcohol} or {ethanol}, {CH3.CH2.OH});
      the spirituous or intoxicating element of fermented or
      distilled liquors, or more loosely a liquid containing it
      in considerable quantity. It is extracted by simple
      distillation from various vegetable juices and infusions
      of a saccharine nature, which have undergone vinous
      fermentation.

   Note: [The ferementation is usually carried out by addition
         of brewer's yeast, {Saccharomyces cerevisiae} to an
         aqueous solution containing carbohydrates.]
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: As used in the U. S. ``Pharmacop[oe]ia,'' alcohol
         contains 91 per cent by weight of ethyl alcohol and 9
         per cent of water; and diluted alcohol (proof spirit)
         contains 45.5 per cent by weight of ethyl alcohol and
         54.5 per cent of water.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. (Organic Chem.) A class of compounds analogous to vinic
      alcohol in constitution. Chemically speaking, they are
      hydroxides of certain organic radicals; as, the radical
      ethyl forms common or {ethyl alcohol} ({C2H5.OH}); methyl
      forms {methyl alcohol} ({CH3.OH}) or {wood spirit}; amyl
      forms {amyl alcohol} ({C5H11.OH}) or {fusel oil}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>alcohol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ethanol \eth"an*ol\ ([e^]th"[a^]n*[add]l), n. (Chem.)
   The organic compound {C2H5.OH}, the common {alcohol} which is
   the intoxicating agent in beer, wine, and other fermented and
   distilled liquors; called also {ethyl alcohol}. It is used
   pure or denatured as a solvent or in medicines and colognes
   and cleaning solutions, or mixed in gasoline as a fuel for
   automobiles, and as a rocket fuel (as in the V-2 rocket).

   Syn: ethyl alcohol, fermentation alcohol, grain alcohol.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>alcohol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>alcohol
     n 1: a liquor or brew containing alcohol as the active agent;
          "alcohol (or drink) ruined him" [syn: {alcoholic
          beverage}, {intoxicant}, {inebriant}]
     2: any of a series of volatile hydroxyl compounds that are made
        from hydrocarbons by distillation
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
