<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>allegiance</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>allegiance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ALLEGIANCE, n.

    This thing Allegiance, as I suppose,
    Is a ring fitted in the subject's nose,
    Whereby that organ is kept rightly pointed
    To smell the sweetness of the Lord's anointed.
                                                                  G.J.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>allegiance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Allegiance \Al*le"giance\, n. [OE. alegeaunce; pref. a- + OF.
   lige, liege. The meaning was influenced by L. ligare to bind,
   and even by lex, legis, law. See {Liege}, {Ligeance}.]
   1. The tie or obligation, implied or expressed, which a
      subject owes to his sovereign or government; the duty of
      fidelity to one's king, government, or state.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Devotion; loyalty; as, allegiance to science.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Loyalty; fealty.

   Usage: {Allegiance}, {Loyalty}. These words agree in
          expressing the general idea of fidelity and attachment
          to the ``powers that be.'' Allegiance is an obligation
          to a ruling power. Loyalty is a feeling or sentiment
          towards such power. Allegiance may exist under any
          form of government, and, in a republic, we generally
          speak of allegiance to the government, to the state,
          etc. In well conducted monarchies, loyalty is a
          warm-hearted feeling of fidelity and obedience to the
          sovereign. It is personal in its nature; and hence we
          speak of the loyalty of a wife to her husband, not of
          her allegiance. In cases where we personify, loyalty
          is more commonly the word used; as, loyalty to the
          constitution; loyalty to the cause of virtue; loyalty
          to truth and religion, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

                Hear me, recreant, on thine allegiance hear me!
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                So spake the Seraph Abdiel, faithful found, . .
                .
                Unshaken, unseduced, unterrified,
                His loyalty he kept, his love, his zeal.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>allegiance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>allegiance
     n 1: the act of binding yourself (intellectually or emotionally)
          to a course of action; "his long commitment to public
          service"; "they felt no loyalty to a losing team" [syn:
          {commitment}, {loyalty}, {dedication}]
     2: the loyalty that citizens owe to their country (or subjects
        to their sovereign) [syn: {fealty}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
