<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>almond</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>almond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Almond
   a native of Syria and Palestine. In form, blossoms, and fruit it
   resembles the peach tree. Its blossoms are of a very pale pink
   colour, and appear before its leaves. Its Hebrew name, _shaked_,
   signifying "wakeful, hastening," is given to it on account of
   its putting forth its blossoms so early, generally in February,
   and sometimes even in January. In Eccl. 12:5, it is referred to
   as illustrative, probably, of the haste with which old age
   comes. There are others, however, who still contend for the old
   interpretation here. "The almond tree bears its blossoms in the
   midst of winter, on a naked, leafless stem, and these blossoms
   (reddish or flesh-coloured in the beginning) seem at the time of
   their fall exactly like white snow-flakes. In this way the
   almond blossom is a very fitting symbol of old age, with its
   silvery hair and its wintry, dry, barren, unfruitful condition."
   In Jer. 1:11 "I see a rod of an almond tree [shaked]...for I
   will hasten [shaked] my word to perform it" the word is used as
   an emblem of promptitude. Jacob desired his sons (Gen. 43:11) to
   take with them into Egypt of the best fruits of the land,
   almonds, etc., as a present to Joseph, probably because this
   tree was not a native of Egypt. Aaron's rod yielded almonds
   (Num. 17:8; Heb. 9:4). Moses was directed to make certain parts
   of the candlestick for the ark of carved work "like unto
   almonds" (Ex. 25:33, 34). The Hebrew word _luz_, translated
   "hazel" in the Authorized Version (Gen. 30:37), is rendered in
   the Revised Version "almond." It is probable that _luz_ denotes
   the wild almond, while _shaked_ denotes the cultivated variety.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>almond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Almond, NC
  Zip code(s): 28702
Almond, NY (village, FIPS 1440)
  Location: 42.31898 N, 77.73954 W
  Population (1990): 458 (202 housing units)
  Area: 1.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 14804
Almond, WI (village, FIPS 1400)
  Location: 44.26131 N, 89.40874 W
  Population (1990): 455 (201 housing units)
  Area: 2.7 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 54909
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>almond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Almond \Alm"ond\ ([aum]"m[u^]nd), n. [OE. almande, almaunde,
   alemaunde, F. amande, L. amygdala, fr. Gr. 'amygda`lh: cf.
   Sp. almendra. Cf. {Amygdalate}.]
   1. The fruit of the almond tree.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The different kinds, as bitter, sweet, thin-shelled,
         thick-shelled almonds, and Jordan almonds, are the
         products of different varieties of the one species,
         {Amygdalus communis}, a native of the Mediterranean
         region and western Asia.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The tree that bears the fruit; almond tree.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything shaped like an almond. Specifically: (Anat.) One
      of the tonsils.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Almond oil}, fixed oil expressed from sweet or bitter
      almonds.

   {Oil of bitter almonds}, a poisonous volatile oil obtained
      from bitter almonds by maceration and distillation;
      benzoic aldehyde.

   {Imitation oil of bitter almonds}, nitrobenzene.

   {Almond tree} (Bot.), the tree bearing the almond.

   {Almond willow} (Bot.), a willow which has leaves that are of
      a light green on both sides; almond-leaved willow ({Salix
      amygdalina}). --Shenstone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>almond</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>almond
     n 1: small bushy deciduous tree native to Asia and North Africa
          having pretty pink blossoms and highly prized edible
          nuts enclosed in a hard green hull; cultivated in
          southern Australia and California [syn: {sweet almond},
          {Prunus dulcis}, {Prunus amygdalus}, {Amygdalus communis}]
     2: oval-shaped edible seed of the almond tree
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
