<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>and</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>and</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>AND
     
        &lt;logic&gt; (Or "conjunction") The {Boolean} function which is
        true only if all its arguments are true.  The {truth table}
        for the two argument AND function is:
     
         A | B | A AND B
         --+---+---------
         F | F |    F
         F | T |    F
         T | F |    F
         T | T |    T
     
        AND is often written as an inverted "V" in texts on logic.  In
        the {C} programming language it is represented by the &amp;&amp;
        (logical and) {operator}.
     
        (1997-11-15)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>and</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>And \And\, conj. [AS. and; akin to OS. endi, Icel. enda, OHG.
   anti, enti, inti, unti, G. und, D. en, OD. ende. Cf, {An} if,
   {Ante-}.]
   1. A particle which expresses the relation of connection or
      addition. It is used to conjoin a word with a word, a
      clause with a clause, or a sentence with a sentence.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: (a) It is sometimes used emphatically; as, ``there are
         women and women,'' that is, two very different sorts of
         women. (b) By a rhetorical figure, notions, one of
         which is modificatory of the other, are connected by
         and; as, ``the tediousness and process of my travel,''
         that is, the tedious process, etc.; ``thy fair and
         outward character,'' that is, thy outwardly fair
         character, --Schmidt's Shak. Lex.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. In order to; -- used instead of the infinitival to,
      especially after try, come, go.
      [1913 Webster]

            At least to try and teach the erring soul. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. It is sometimes, in old songs, a mere expletive.
      [1913 Webster]

            When that I was and a little tiny boy. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. If; though. See {An}, conj. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            As they will set an house on fire, and it were but
            to roast their eggs.                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   {And so forth}, and others; and the rest; and similar things;
      and other things or ingredients. The abbreviation, etc.
      (et cetera), or &amp;c., is usually read and so forth.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
