<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>angel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>angel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Angel
   a word signifying, both in the Hebrew and Greek, a "messenger,"
   and hence employed to denote any agent God sends forth to
   execute his purposes. It is used of an ordinary messenger (Job
   1:14: 1 Sam. 11:3; Luke 7:24; 9:52), of prophets (Isa. 42:19;
   Hag. 1:13), of priests (Mal. 2:7), and ministers of the New
   Testament (Rev. 1:20).
   
     It is also applied to such impersonal agents as the pestilence
   (2 Sam. 24:16, 17; 2 Kings 19:35), the wind (Ps. 104:4).
   
     But its distinctive application is to certain heavenly
   intelligences whom God employs in carrying on his government of
   the world. The name does not denote their nature but their
   office as messengers. The appearances to Abraham at Mamre (Gen.
   18:2, 22. Comp. 19:1), to Jacob at Peniel (Gen. 32:24, 30), to
   Joshua at Gilgal (Josh. 5:13, 15), of the Angel of the Lord,
   were doubtless manifestations of the Divine presence,
   "foreshadowings of the incarnation," revelations before the
   "fulness of the time" of the Son of God.
   
     (1.) The existence and orders of angelic beings can only be
   discovered from the Scriptures. Although the Bible does not
   treat of this subject specially, yet there are numerous
   incidental details that furnish us with ample information. Their
   personal existence is plainly implied in such passages as Gen.
   16:7, 10, 11; Judg. 13:1-21; Matt. 28:2-5; Heb. 1:4, etc.
   
     These superior beings are very numerous. "Thousand thousands,"
   etc. (Dan. 7:10; Matt. 26:53; Luke 2:13; Heb. 12:22, 23). They
   are also spoken of as of different ranks in dignity and power
   (Zech. 1:9, 11; Dan. 10:13; 12:1; 1 Thess. 4:16; Jude 1:9; Eph.
   1:21; Col. 1:16).
   
     (2.) As to their nature, they are spirits (Heb. 1:14), like
   the soul of man, but not incorporeal. Such expressions as "like
   the angels" (Luke 20:36), and the fact that whenever angels
   appeared to man it was always in a human form (Gen. 18:2; 19:1,
   10; Luke 24:4; Acts 1:10), and the titles that are applied to
   them ("sons of God," Job 1:6; 38:7; Dan. 3:25; comp. 28) and to
   men (Luke 3:38), seem all to indicate some resemblance between
   them and the human race. Imperfection is ascribed to them as
   creatures (Job 4:18; Matt. 24:36; 1 Pet. 1:12). As finite
   creatures they may fall under temptation; and accordingly we
   read of "fallen angels." Of the cause and manner of their "fall"
   we are wholly ignorant. We know only that "they left their first
   estate" (Matt. 25:41; Rev. 12:7,9), and that they are "reserved
   unto judgement" (2 Pet. 2:4). When the manna is called "angels'
   food," this is merely to denote its excellence (Ps. 78:25).
   Angels never die (Luke 20:36). They are possessed of superhuman
   intelligence and power (Mark 13:32; 2 Thess. 1:7; Ps. 103:20).
   They are called "holy" (Luke 9:26), "elect" (1 Tim. 5:21). The
   redeemed in glory are "like unto the angels" (Luke 20:36). They
   are not to be worshipped (Col. 2:18; Rev. 19:10).
   
     (3.) Their functions are manifold. (a) In the widest sense
   they are agents of God's providence (Ex. 12:23; Ps. 104:4; Heb.
   11:28; 1 Cor. 10:10; 2 Sam. 24:16; 1 Chr. 21:16; 2 Kings 19:35;
   Acts 12:23). (b) They are specially God's agents in carrying on
   his great work of redemption. There is no notice of angelic
   appearances to man till after the call of Abraham. From that
   time onward there are frequent references to their ministry on
   earth (Gen. 18; 19; 24:7, 40; 28:12; 32:1). They appear to
   rebuke idolatry (Judg. 2:1-4), to call Gideon (Judg. 6:11, 12),
   and to consecrate Samson (13:3). In the days of the prophets,
   from Samuel downward, the angels appear only in their behalf (1
   Kings 19:5; 2 Kings 6:17; Zech. 1-6; Dan. 4:13, 23; 10:10, 13,
   20, 21).
   
     The Incarnation introduces a new era in the ministrations of
   angels. They come with their Lord to earth to do him service
   while here. They predict his advent (Matt. 1:20; Luke 1:26-38),
   minister to him after his temptation and agony (Matt. 4:11; Luke
   22:43), and declare his resurrection and ascension (Matt.
   28:2-8; John 20:12, 13; Acts 1:10, 11). They are now ministering
   spirits to the people of God (Heb. 1:14; Ps. 34:7; 91:11; Matt.
   18:10; Acts 5:19; 8:26; 10:3; 12:7; 27:23). They rejoice over a
   penitent sinner (Luke 15:10). They bear the souls of the
   redeemed to paradise (Luke 16:22); and they will be the
   ministers of judgement hereafter on the great day (Matt. 13:39,
   41, 49; 16:27; 24:31). The passages (Ps. 34:7, Matt. 18:10)
   usually referred to in support of the idea that every individual
   has a particular guardian angel have no such meaning. They
   merely indicate that God employs the ministry of angels to
   deliver his people from affliction and danger, and that the
   angels do not think it below their dignity to minister even to
   children and to the least among Christ's disciples.
   
     The "angel of his presence" (Isa. 63:9. Comp. Ex. 23:20, 21;
   32:34; 33:2; Num. 20:16) is probably rightly interpreted of the
   Messiah as the guide of his people. Others have supposed the
   expression to refer to Gabriel (Luke 1:19).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>angel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Angel
     
        &lt;operating system&gt; A single {address space}, {micro-kernel}
        {operating system} for {multiprocessor} computers, developed
        at {Imperial College} and {City University}, London, UK.
     
        [Ariel Burton]
     
        (1995-11-24)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>angel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Angel \An"gel\, n. [AS. [ae]ngel, engel, influenced by OF.
   angele, angle, F. ange. Both the AS. and the OF. words are
   from L. angelus, Gr. 'a`ggelos messenger, a messenger of God,
   an angel.]
   1. A messenger. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The dear good angel of the Spring,
            The nightingale.                      --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A spiritual, celestial being, superior to man in power and
      intelligence. In the Scriptures the angels appear as God's
      messengers.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, welcome, pure-eyed Faith, white-handed Hope,
            Thou hovering angel, girt with golden wings.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One of a class of ``fallen angels;'' an evil spirit; as,
      the devil and his angels.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A minister or pastor of a church, as in the Seven Asiatic
      churches. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Unto the angel of the church of Ephesus write.
                                                  --Rev. ii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Attendant spirit; genius; demon. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An appellation given to a person supposed to be of angelic
      goodness or loveliness; a darling.
      [1913 Webster]

            When pain and anguish wring the brow,
            A ministering angel thou.             --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Numis.) An ancient gold coin of England, bearing the
      figure of the archangel Michael. It varied in value from
      6s. 8d. to 10s. --Amer. Cyc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Angel is sometimes used adjectively; as, angel grace;
         angel whiteness.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Angel bed}, a bed without posts.

   {Angel fish}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A species of shark ({Squatina angelus}) from six to
          eight feet long, found on the coasts of Europe and
          North America. It takes its name from its pectoral
          fins, which are very large and extend horizontally
          like wings when spread.
      (b) One of several species of compressed, bright colored
          fishes warm seas, belonging to the family
          {Ch[ae]todontid[ae]}.

   {Angel gold}, standard gold. [Obs.] --Fuller.

   {Angel shark}. See {Angel fish}.

   {Angel shot} (Mil.), a kind of chain shot.

   {Angel water}, a perfumed liquid made at first chiefly from
      angelica; afterwards containing rose, myrtle, and
      orange-flower waters, with ambergris, etc. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>angel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>angel
     n 1: spiritual being attendant upon God
     2: person of exceptional holiness [syn: {saint}, {holy man}, {holy
        person}]
     3: invests in a theatrical production [syn: {backer}]
     4: the highest waterfall; has more than one leap; flow varies
        seasonally [syn: {Angel Falls}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
