<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>anger</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>anger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Anger
   the emotion of instant displeasure on account of something evil
   that presents itself to our view. In itself it is an original
   susceptibility of our nature, just as love is, and is not
   necessarily sinful. It may, however, become sinful when
   causeless, or excessive, or protracted (Matt. 5:22; Eph. 4:26;
   Col. 3:8). As ascribed to God, it merely denotes his displeasure
   with sin and with sinners (Ps. 7:11).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>anger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Anger \An"ger\ (a[ng]"g[~e]r), n. [OE. anger, angre, affliction,
   anger, fr. Icel. angr affliction, sorrow; akin to Dan. anger
   regret, Swed. [*a]nger regret, AS. ange oppressed, sad, L.
   angor a strangling, anguish, angere to strangle, Gr.
   'a`gchein to strangle, Skr. a[mdot]has pain, and to E.
   anguish, anxious, quinsy, and perh. awe, ugly. The word seems
   to have orig. meant to choke, squeeze. [root]3.]
   1. Trouble; vexation; also, physical pain or smart of a sore,
      etc. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I made the experiment, setting the moxa where . . .
            the greatest anger and soreness still continued.
                                                  --Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A strong passion or emotion of displeasure or antagonism,
      excited by a real or supposed injury or insult to one's
      self or others, or by the intent to do such injury.
      [1913 Webster]

            Anger is like
            A full hot horse, who being allowed his way,
            Self-mettle tires him.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Resentment; wrath; rage; fury; passion; ire gall;
        choler; indignation; displeasure; vexation; grudge;
        spleen.

   Usage: {Anger}, {Indignation}, {Resentment}, {Wrath}, {Ire},
          {Rage}, {Fury}. Anger is a feeling of keen displeasure
          (usually with a desire to punish) for what we regard
          as wrong toward ourselves or others. It may be
          excessive or misplaced, but is not necessarily
          criminal. Indignation is a generous outburst of anger
          in view of things which are indigna, or unworthy to be
          done, involving what is mean, cruel, flagitious, etc.,
          in character or conduct. Resentment is often a moody
          feeling, leading one to brood over his supposed
          personal wrongs with a deep and lasting anger. See
          {Resentment}. Wrath and ire (the last poetical)
          express the feelings of one who is bitterly provoked.
          Rage is a vehement ebullition of anger; and fury is an
          excess of rage, amounting almost to madness. Warmth of
          constitution often gives rise to anger; a high sense
          of honor creates indignation at crime; a man of quick
          sensibilities is apt to cherish resentment; the wrath
          and ire of men are often connected with a haughty and
          vindictive spirit; rage and fury are distempers of the
          soul to be regarded only with abhorrence.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>anger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Anger \An"ger\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Angered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Angering}.] [Cf. Icel. angra.]
   1. To make painful; to cause to smart; to inflame. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . angereth malign ulcers.      --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To excite to anger; to enrage; to provoke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Taxes and impositions . . . which rather angered
            than grieved the people.              --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>anger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>anger
     n 1: a strong emotion; a feeling that is oriented toward some
          real or supposed grievance [syn: {choler}, {ire}]
     2: the state of being angry [syn: {angriness}]
     3: belligerence aroused by a real or supposed wrong
        (personified as one of the deadly sins) [syn: {wrath}, {ire},
         {ira}]
     v 1: make angry; "The news angered him"
     2: become angry; "He angers easily" [syn: {see red}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
