<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>answering</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>answering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Answer \An"swer\ ([a^]n"s[~e]r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Answered}
   ([a^]n"s[~e]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Answering}.] [OE.
   andswerien, AS. andswerian, andswarian, to answer, fr.
   andswaru, n., answer. See {Answer}, n.]
   1. To speak in defense against; to reply to in defense; as,
      to answer a charge; to answer an accusation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To speak or write in return to, as in return to a call or
      question, or to a speech, declaration, argument, or the
      like; to reply to (a question, remark, etc.); to respond
      to.
      [1913 Webster]

            She answers him as if she knew his mind. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            So spake the apostate angel, though in pain: . . .
            And him thus answered soon his bold compeer.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To respond to satisfactorily; to meet successfully by way
      of explanation, argument, or justification, and the like;
      to refute.
      [1913 Webster]

            No man was able to answer him a word. --Matt. xxii.
                                                  46.
      [1913 Webster]

            These shifts refuted, answer thine appellant.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The reasoning was not and could not be answered.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be or act in return or response to. Hence:
      (a) To be or act in compliance with, in fulfillment or
          satisfaction of, as an order, obligation, demand; as,
          he answered my claim upon him; the servant answered
          the bell.
          [1913 Webster]

                This proud king . . . studies day and night
                To answer all the debts he owes unto you.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To render account to or for.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will . . . send him to answer thee. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To atone; to be punished for.
          [1913 Webster]

                And grievously hath C[ae]zar answered it.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To be opposite to; to face.
          [1913 Webster]

                The windows answering each other, we could just
                discern the glowing horizon them. --Gilpin.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To be or act an equivalent to, or as adequate or
          sufficient for; to serve for; to repay. [R.]
          [1913 Webster]

                Money answereth all things.       --Eccles. x.
                                                  19.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) To be or act in accommodation, conformity, relation,
          or proportion to; to correspond to; to suit.
          [1913 Webster]

                Weapons must needs be dangerous things, if they
                answered the bulk of so prodigious a person.
                                                  --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>answering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>answering
     adj : replying; "an answering glance"; "an answering smile" [syn:
           {respondent}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
