<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>answer</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>answer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Answer \An"swer\ ([a^]n"s[~e]r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Answered}
   ([a^]n"s[~e]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Answering}.] [OE.
   andswerien, AS. andswerian, andswarian, to answer, fr.
   andswaru, n., answer. See {Answer}, n.]
   1. To speak in defense against; to reply to in defense; as,
      to answer a charge; to answer an accusation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To speak or write in return to, as in return to a call or
      question, or to a speech, declaration, argument, or the
      like; to reply to (a question, remark, etc.); to respond
      to.
      [1913 Webster]

            She answers him as if she knew his mind. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            So spake the apostate angel, though in pain: . . .
            And him thus answered soon his bold compeer.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To respond to satisfactorily; to meet successfully by way
      of explanation, argument, or justification, and the like;
      to refute.
      [1913 Webster]

            No man was able to answer him a word. --Matt. xxii.
                                                  46.
      [1913 Webster]

            These shifts refuted, answer thine appellant.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The reasoning was not and could not be answered.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be or act in return or response to. Hence:
      (a) To be or act in compliance with, in fulfillment or
          satisfaction of, as an order, obligation, demand; as,
          he answered my claim upon him; the servant answered
          the bell.
          [1913 Webster]

                This proud king . . . studies day and night
                To answer all the debts he owes unto you.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To render account to or for.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will . . . send him to answer thee. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To atone; to be punished for.
          [1913 Webster]

                And grievously hath C[ae]zar answered it.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To be opposite to; to face.
          [1913 Webster]

                The windows answering each other, we could just
                discern the glowing horizon them. --Gilpin.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To be or act an equivalent to, or as adequate or
          sufficient for; to serve for; to repay. [R.]
          [1913 Webster]

                Money answereth all things.       --Eccles. x.
                                                  19.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) To be or act in accommodation, conformity, relation,
          or proportion to; to correspond to; to suit.
          [1913 Webster]

                Weapons must needs be dangerous things, if they
                answered the bulk of so prodigious a person.
                                                  --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>answer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Answer \An"swer\, v. i.
   1. To speak or write by way of return (originally, to a
      charge), or in reply; to make response.
      [1913 Webster]

            There was no voice, nor any that answered. --1 Kings
                                                  xviii. 26.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make a satisfactory response or return. Hence: To
      render account, or to be responsible; to be accountable;
      to make amends; as, the man must answer to his employer
      for the money intrusted to his care.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let his neck answer for it, if there is any martial
            law.                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be or act in return. Hence:
      (a) To be or act by way of compliance, fulfillment,
          reciprocation, or satisfaction; to serve the purpose;
          as, gypsum answers as a manure on some soils.
          [1913 Webster]

                Do the strings answer to thy noble hand?
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To be opposite, or to act in opposition.
      (c) To be or act as an equivalent, or as adequate or
          sufficient; as, a very few will answer.
      (d) To be or act in conformity, or by way of
          accommodation, correspondence, relation, or
          proportion; to conform; to correspond; to suit; --
          usually with to.
          [1913 Webster]

                That the time may have all shadow and silence in
                it, and the place answer to convenience. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                If this but answer to my just belief,
                I 'll remember you.               --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                As in water face answereth to face, so the heart
                of man to man.                    --Prov. xxvii.
                                                  19.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>answer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Answer \An"swer\, n. [OE. andsware, AS. andswaru; and against +
   swerian to swear. [root]177, 196. See {Anti-}, and {Swear},
   and cf. 1st {un-}.]
   1. A reply to a charge; a defense.
      [1913 Webster]

            At my first answer no man stood with me. --2 Tim.
                                                  iv. 16.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Something said or written in reply to a question, a call,
      an argument, an address, or the like; a reply.
      [1913 Webster]

            A soft answer turneth away wrath.     --Prov. xv. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            I called him, but he gave me no answer. --Cant. v.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Something done in return for, or in consequence of,
      something else; a responsive action.
      [1913 Webster]

            Great the slaughter is
            Here made by the Roman; great the answer be
            Britons must take.                    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A solution, the result of a mathematical operation; as,
      the answer to a problem.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) A counter-statement of facts in a course of
      pleadings; a confutation of what the other party has
      alleged; a responsive declaration by a witness in reply to
      a question. In Equity, it is the usual form of defense to
      the complainant's charges in his bill. --Bouvier.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Reply; rejoinder; response. See {Reply}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>answer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>answer
     n 1: a statement (either spoken or written) that is made in reply
          to a question or request or criticism or accusation; "I
          waited several days for his answer"; "he wrote replies
          to several of his critics" [syn: {reply}, {response}]
     2: a statement that solves a problem or explains how to solve
        the problem; "they were trying to find a peaceful
        solution"; "the answers were in the back of the book"; "he
        computed the result to four decimal places" [syn: {solution},
         {result}, {resolution}, {solvent}]
     3: the speech act of replying to a question [ant: {question}]
     4: the principle pleading by the defendant in response to
        plaintiff's complaint; in criminal law it consists of the
        defendant's plea of `guilty' or `not guilty' (or nolo
        contendere); in civil law it must contain denials of all
        allegations in the plaintiff's complaint that the
        defendant hopes to controvert and it can contain
        affirmative defenses or counterclaims
     5: a nonverbal reaction; "his answer to any problem was to get
        drunk"; "their answer was to sue me"
     v 1: reply or respond to; "She didn't want to answer"; "answer
          the question"; "We answered that we would accept the
          invitation" [syn: {reply}, {respond}]
     2: give the correct answer or solution to; "answer a question";
        "answer the riddle"
     3: respond to a signal; "answer the door"; "answer the
        telephone"
     4: understand the meaning of; "The question concerning the
        meaning of life cannot be answered" [syn: {resolve}]
     5: give a defence or refutation of (a charge) or in (an
        argument); "The defendant answered to all the charges of
        the prosecution"
     6: be liable or accountable; "She must answer for her actions"
     7: be sufficient; be adequate, either in quality or quantity;
        "A few words would answer"; "This car suits my purpose
        well"; "Will $100 do?"; "A 'B' grade doesn't suffice to
        get me into medical school"; "Nothing else will serve"
        [syn: {suffice}, {do}, {serve}]
     8: match or correspond; "The drawing of the suspect answers to
        the description the victim gave"
     9: be satisfactory for; meet the requirements of or serve the
        purpose of; "This may answer her needs"
     10: react to a stimulus or command; "The steering of my new car
         answers to the slightest touch"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
