<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>anticipate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>anticipate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Anticipate \An*tic"i*pate\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Anticipated};
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Anticipating}.] [L. anticipatus, p. p. of
   anticipare to anticipate; ante + capere to make. See
   {Capable}.]
   1. To be before in doing; to do or take before another; to
      preclude or prevent by prior action.
      [1913 Webster]

            To anticipate and prevent the duke's purpose. --R.
                                                  Hall.
      [1913 Webster]

            He would probably have died by the hand of the
            executioner, if indeed the executioner had not been
            anticipated by the populace.          --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take up or introduce beforehand, or before the proper
      or normal time; to cause to occur earlier or prematurely;
      as, the advocate has anticipated a part of his argument.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To foresee (a wish, command, etc.) and do beforehand that
      which will be desired.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To foretaste or foresee; to have a previous view or
      impression of; as, to anticipate the pleasures of a visit;
      to anticipate the evils of life.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To prevent; obviate; preclude; forestall; expect.

   Usage: To {Anticipate}, {Expect}. These words, as here
          compared, agree in regarding some future event as
          about to take place. Expect is the stringer. It
          supposes some ground or reason in the mind for
          considering the event as likely to happen. Anticipate
          is, literally, to take beforehand, and here denotes
          simply to take into the mind as conception of the
          future. Hence, to say, ``I did not anticipate a
          refusal,'' expresses something less definite and
          strong than to say, `` did not expect it.'' Still,
          anticipate is a convenient word to be interchanged
          with expect in cases where the thought will allow.
          [1913 Webster]

                Good with bad
                Expect to hear; supernal grace contending
                With sinfulness of men.           --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                I would not anticipate the relish of any
                happiness, nor feel the weight of any misery,
                before it actually arrives.       --Spectator.
          [1913 Webster]

                Timid men were anticipating another civil war.
                                                  --Macaulay.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>anticipate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>anticipate
     v 1: regard something as probable or likely; "The meteorologists
          are expecting rain for tomorrow" [syn: {expect}]
     2: act in advance of; deal with ahead of time [syn: {foresee},
        {forestall}, {counter}]
     3: realize beforehand [syn: {previse}, {foreknow}, {foresee}]
     4: make a prediction about; tell in advance; "Call the outcome
        of an election" [syn: {predict}, {foretell}, {prognosticate},
         {call}, {forebode}, {promise}]
     5: be excited or anxious about [syn: {look for}, {look to}]
     6: be a forerunner of or occur earlier than; "This composition
        anticipates Impressionism"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
