<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>antimony</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>antimony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>elements</Id>
        <Name>Elements database 20001107</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>antimony
Symbol: Sb
Atomic number: 51
Atomic weight: 121.75
Element of group 15. Multiple allotropic forms. The stable form of
antimony is a blue-white metal. Yellow and black antimony are unstable
non-metals. Used in flame-proofing, paints, ceramics, enamels, and rubber.
Attacked by oxidizing acids and halogens. First reported by Tholden in
1450.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>antimony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Antimony, UT (town, FIPS 1860)
  Location: 38.10089 N, 111.98358 W
  Population (1990): 83 (59 housing units)
  Area: 26.2 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 84712
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>antimony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Antimony \An"ti*mo*ny\ ([a^]n"t[i^]*m[-o]*n[y^]; 112), n. [LL.
   antimonium, of unknown origin.] (Chem.)
   An elementary substance, resembling a metal in its appearance
   and physical properties, but in its chemical relations
   belonging to the class of nonmetallic substances. Atomic
   weight, 120. Symbol, Sb.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: It is of tin-white color, brittle, laminated or
         crystalline, fusible, and vaporizable at a rather low
         temperature. It is used in some metallic alloys, as
         type metal and bell metal, and also for medical
         preparations, which are in general emetics or
         cathartics. By ancient writers, and some moderns, the
         term is applied to native gray ore of antimony, or
         stibnite (the stibium of the Romans, and the sti`mmi of
         the Greeks, a sulphide of antimony, from which most of
         the antimony of commerce is obtained. Cervantite,
         senarmontite, and valentinite are native oxides of
         antimony.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>antimony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>antimony
     n : a metallic element having four allotropic forms; used in a
         wide variety of alloys; found in stibnite [syn: {Sb}, {atomic
         number 51}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
