<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>appearance</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appearance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Appearance \Ap*pear"ance\, n. [F. apparence, L. apparentia, fr.
   apparere. See {Appear}.]
   1. The act of appearing or coming into sight; the act of
      becoming visible to the eye; as, his sudden appearance
      surprised me.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A thing seed; a phenomenon; a phase; an apparition; as, an
      appearance in the sky.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Personal presence; exhibition of the person; look; aspect;
      mien.
      [1913 Webster]

            And now am come to see . . .
            It thy appearance answer loud report. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Semblance, or apparent likeness; external show. pl.
      Outward signs, or circumstances, fitted to make a
      particular impression or to determine the judgment as to
      the character of a person or a thing, an act or a state;
      as, appearances are against him.
      [1913 Webster]

            There was upon the tabernacle, as it were, the
            appearance of fire.                   --Num. ix. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

            For man looketh on the outward appearance. --1 Sam.
                                                  xvi. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

            Judge not according to the appearance. --John. vii.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The act of appearing in a particular place, or in society,
      a company, or any proceedings; a coming before the public
      in a particular character; as, a person makes his
      appearance as an historian, an artist, or an orator.
      [1913 Webster]

            Will he now retire,
            After appearance, and again prolong
            Our expectation?                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Probability; likelihood. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            There is that which hath no appearance. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) The coming into court of either of the parties; the
      being present in court; the coming into court of a party
      summoned in an action, either by himself or by his
      attorney, expressed by a formal entry by the proper
      officer to that effect; the act or proceeding by which a
      party proceeded against places himself before the court,
      and submits to its jurisdiction. --Burrill. --Bouvier.
      --Daniell.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To put in an appearance}, to be present; to appear in
      person.

   {To save appearances}, to preserve a fair outward show.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Coming; arrival; presence; semblance; pretense; air;
        look; manner; mien; figure; aspect.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appearance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>appearance
     n 1: outward or visible aspect of a person or thing [syn: {visual
          aspect}]
     2: the event of coming into sight [ant: {disappearance}]
     3: formal attendance (in court or at a hearing) of a party in
        an action [syn: {appearing}, {coming into court}]
     4: a mental representation; "I tried to describe his appearance
        to the police"
     5: the act of appearing in public view; "the rookie made a
        brief appearance in the first period"; "it was Bernhardt's
        last appearance in America" [ant: {disappearance}]
     6: pretending that something is the case in order to make a
        good impression; "they try to keep up appearances"; "that
        ceremony is just for show" [syn: {show}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
