<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>appeal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appeal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>APPEAL, v.t.  In law, to put the dice into the box for another throw.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appeal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Appeal
   a reference of any case from an inferior to a superior court.
   Moses established in the wilderness a series of judicatories
   such that appeals could be made from a lower to a higher (Ex.
   18:13-26.)
   
     Under the Roman law the most remarkable case of appeal is that
   of Paul from the tribunal of Festus at Caesarea to that of the
   emperor at Rome (Acts 25:11, 12, 21, 25). Paul availed himself
   of the privilege of a Roman citizen in this matter.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appeal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Appeal \Ap*peal"\, n. [OE. appel, apel, OF. apel, F. appel, fr.
   appeler. See {Appeal}, v. t.]
   1. (Law)
      (a) An application for the removal of a cause or suit from
          an inferior to a superior judge or court for
          re["e]xamination or review.
      (b) The mode of proceeding by which such removal is
          effected.
      (c) The right of appeal.
      (d) An accusation; a process which formerly might be
          instituted by one private person against another for
          some heinous crime demanding punishment for the
          particular injury suffered, rather than for the
          offense against the public.
      (e) An accusation of a felon at common law by one of his
          accomplices, which accomplice was then called an
          approver. See {Approvement}. --Tomlins. --Bouvier.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A summons to answer to a charge. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A call upon a person or an authority for proof or
      decision, in one's favor; reference to another as witness;
      a call for help or a favor; entreaty.
      [1913 Webster]

            A kind of appeal to the Deity, the author of
            wonders.                              --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Resort to physical means; recourse.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every milder method is to be tried, before a nation
            makes an appeal to arms.              --Kent.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appeal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Appeal \Ap*peal"\, v. t.
   1. (Law) To apply for the removal of a cause from an inferior
      to a superior judge or court for the purpose of
      re["e]xamination of for decision. --Tomlins.
      [1913 Webster]

            I appeal unto C[ae]sar.               --Acts xxv.
                                                  11.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To call upon another to decide a question controverted, to
      corroborate a statement, to vindicate one's rights, etc.;
      as, I appeal to all mankind for the truth of what is
      alleged. Hence: To call on one for aid; to make earnest
      request.
      [1913 Webster]

            I appeal to the Scriptures in the original.
                                                  --Horsley.
      [1913 Webster]

            They appealed to the sword.           --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appeal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Appeal \Ap*peal"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Appealed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Appealing}.] [OE. appelen, apelen, to appeal, accuse, OF.
   appeler, fr. L. appellare to approach, address, invoke,
   summon, call, name; akin to appellere to drive to; ad +
   pellere to drive. See {Pulse}, and cf. {Peal}.]
   1. (Law)
      (a) To make application for the removal of (a cause) from
          an inferior to a superior judge or court for a
          rehearing or review on account of alleged injustice or
          illegality in the trial below. We say, the cause was
          appealed from an inferior court.
      (b) To charge with a crime; to accuse; to institute a
          private criminal prosecution against for some heinous
          crime; as, to appeal a person of felony.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. To summon; to challenge. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Man to man will I appeal the Norman to the lists.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To invoke. [Obs.] --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appeal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>appeal
     n 1: earnest or urgent request; "an entreaty to stop the
          fighting"; "an appeal for help"; "an appeal to the
          public to keep calm" [syn: {entreaty}, {prayer}]
     2: attractiveness that interests or pleases or stimulates; "his
        smile was part of his appeal to her" [syn: {appealingness},
         {charm}]
     3: (law) a legal proceeding in which the appellant resorts to a
        higher court for the purpose of obtaining a review of a
        lower court decision and a reversal of the lower court's
        judgment or the granting of a new trial; "their appeal was
        denied in the superior court"
     4: request for a sum of money; "an appeal to raise money for
        starving children" [syn: {solicitation}, {collection}, {ingathering}]
     v 1: take a court case to a higher court for review; "He was
          found guilty but appealed immediately"
     2: request earnestly (something from somebody); ask for aid or
        protection; "appeal to somebody for help"; "Invoke God in
        times of trouble" [syn: {invoke}]
     3: be attractive to; "The idea of a vacation appeals to me";
        "The beautiful garden attracted many people" [syn: {attract}]
        [ant: {repel}]
     4: challenge (a decision); "She appealed the verdict"
     5: cite as an authority; resort to; "He invoked the law that
        would save him"; "I appealed to the law of 1900"; "She
        invoked an ancient law" [syn: {invoke}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
