<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>appointment</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appointment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Appointment \Ap*point"ment\, n. [Cf. F. appointement.]
   1. The act of appointing; designation of a person to hold an
      office or discharge a trust; as, he erred by the
      appointment of unsuitable men.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being appointed to som? service or office; an
      office to which one is appointed; station; position; an,
      the appointment of treasurer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Stipulation; agreement; the act of fixing by mutual
      agreement. Hence:: Arrangement for a meeting; engagement;
      as, they made an appointment to meet at six.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Decree; direction; established order or constitution; as,
      to submit to the divine appointments.
      [1913 Webster]

            According to the appointment of the priests. --Ezra
                                                  vi. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) The exercise of the power of designating (under a
      ``power of appointment'') a person to enjoy an estate or
      other specific property; also, the instrument by which the
      designation is made.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Equipment, furniture, as for a ship or an army; whatever
      is appointed for use and management; outfit; (pl.) the
      accouterments of military officers or soldiers, as belts,
      sashes, swords.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cavaliers emulated their chief in the richness
            of their appointments.                --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll prove it in my shackles, with these hands
            Void of appointment, that thou liest. --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. An allowance to a person, esp. to a public officer; a
      perquisite; -- properly only in the plural. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            An expense proportioned to his appointments and
            fortune is necessary.                 --Chesterfield.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A honorary part or exercise, as an oration, etc., at a
      public exhibition of a college; as, to have an
      appointment. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Designation; command; order; direction; establishment;
        equipment.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>appointment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>appointment
     n 1: the act of putting a person into a non-elective position;
          "the appointment had to be approved by the whole
          committee" [syn: {assignment}, {designation}, {naming}]
     2: a meeting arranged in advance; "she asked how to avoid
        kissing at the end of a date" [syn: {date}, {engagement}]
     3: (usually plural) furnishings and equipment (especially for a
        ship or hotel) [syn: {fitting}]
     4: a person who is appointed to a job or position [syn: {appointee}]
     5: the job to which you are (or hope to be) appointed; "he
        applied for an appointment in the treasury"
     6: (law) the act of disposing of property by virtue of the
        power of appointment; "she allocated part of the trust to
        her church by appointment"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
