<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>apron</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>apron</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Apron
   found in the Authorized Version in Gen. 3:7, of the bands of
   fig-leaves made by our first parents. In Acts 19:12, it denotes
   the belt or half-girdle worn by artisans and servants round the
   waist for the purpose of preserving the clothing from injury. In
   marg. of Authorized Version, Ruth 3:15, correctly rendered
   instead of "vail." (R.V., "mantle.")
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>apron</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Apron \A"pron\ ([=a]"p[u^]rn or [=a]"pr[u^]n; 277), n. [OE.
   napron, OF. naperon, F. napperon, dim. of OF. nape, F. nappe,
   cloth, tablecloth, LL. napa, fr. L. mappa, napkin, table
   napkin. See {Map}.]
   1. An article of dress, of cloth, leather, or other stuff,
      worn on the fore part of the body, to keep the clothes
      clean, to defend them from injury, or as a covering. It is
      commonly tied at the waist by strings.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Something which by its shape or use suggests an apron; as,
      (a) The fat skin covering the belly of a goose or duck.
          [Prov. Eng.] --Halliwell.
      (b) A piece of leather, or other material, to be spread
          before a person riding on an outside seat of a
          vehicle, to defend him from the rain, snow, or dust; a
          boot. ``The weather being too hot for the apron.''
          --Hughes.
      (c) (Gun.) A leaden plate that covers the vent of a
          cannon.
      (d) (Shipbuilding) A piece of carved timber, just above
          the foremost end of the keel. --Totten.
      (e) A platform, or flooring of plank, at the entrance of a
          dock, against which the dock gates are shut.
      (f) A flooring of plank before a dam to cause the water to
          make a gradual descent.
      (g) (Mech.) The piece that holds the cutting tool of a
          planer.
      (h) (Plumbing) A strip of lead which leads the drip of a
          wall into a gutter; a flashing.
      (i) (Zo["o]l.) The infolded abdomen of a crab.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>apron</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>apron
     n 1: a garment of cloth or leather or plastic that is tied about
          the waist and worn to protect your clothing
     2: (golf) the part of the fairway leading onto the green
     3: the part of a modern theater stage between the curtain and
        the orchestra (i.e., in front of the curtain) [syn: {proscenium},
         {forestage}]
     4: a paved surface where aircraft stand while not being used
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
