<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>array</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>array</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>array
     
        1. &lt;programming&gt; A collection of identically typed data items
        distinguished by their indices (or "subscripts").  The number
        of dimensions an array can have depends on the language but is
        usually unlimited.
     
        An array is a kind of {aggregate} data type.  A single
        ordinary variable (a "{scalar}") could be considered as a
        zero-dimensional array.  A one-dimensional array is also known
        as a "{vector}".
     
        A reference to an array element is written something like
        A[i,j,k] where A is the array name and i, j and k are the
        indices.  The {C} language is peculiar in that each index is
        written in separate brackets, e.g. A[i][j][k].  This expresses
        the fact that, in C, an N-dimensional array is actually a
        vector, each of whose elements is an N-1 dimensional array.
     
        Elements of an array are usually stored contiguously.
        Languages differ as to whether the leftmost or rightmost index
        varies most rapidly, i.e. whether each row is stored
        contiguously or each column (for a 2D array).
     
        Arrays are appropriate for storing data which must be accessed
        in an unpredictable order, in contrast to {lists} which are
        best when accessed sequentially.
     
        See also {associative array}.
     
        2. &lt;architecture&gt; A {processor array}, not to be confused with
        an {array processor}.
     
        (1995-01-25)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>array</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Array \Ar*ray"\, n. [OE. arai, arrai, OF. arrai, arrei, arroi,
   order, arrangement, dress, F. arroi; a (L. ad) + OF. rai,
   rei, roi, order, arrangement, fr. G. or Scand.; cf. Goth.
   raidjan, garaidjan, to arrange, MHG. gereiten, Icel.
   rei[eth]i rigging, harness; akin to E. ready. Cf. {Ready},
   {Greith}, {Curry}.]
   1. Order; a regular and imposing arrangement; disposition in
      regular lines; hence, order of battle; as, drawn up in
      battle array.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wedged together in the closest array. --Gibbon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The whole body of persons thus placed in order; an orderly
      collection; hence, a body of soldiers.
      [1913 Webster]

            A gallant array of nobles and cavaliers. --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An imposing series of things.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their long array of sapphire and of gold. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Dress; garments disposed in order upon the person; rich or
      beautiful apparel. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law)
      (a) A ranking or setting forth in order, by the proper
          officer, of a jury as impaneled in a cause.
      (b) The panel itself.
      (c) The whole body of jurors summoned to attend the court.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To challenge the array} (Law), to except to the whole panel.
      --Cowell. --Tomlins. --Blount.

   {Commission of array} (Eng. Hist.), a commission given by the
      prince to officers in every county, to muster and array
      the inhabitants, or see them in a condition for war.
      --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>array</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Array \Ar*ray"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Arrayed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Arraying}.] [OE. araien, arraien, fr. OE. arraier, arreier,
   arreer, arroier, fr. arrai. See {Array}, n.]
   1. To place or dispose in order, as troops for battle; to
      marshal.
      [1913 Webster]

            By torch and trumpet fast arrayed,
            Each horseman drew his battle blade.  --Campbell.
      [1913 Webster]

            These doubts will be arrayed before their minds.
                                                  --Farrar.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To deck or dress; to adorn with dress; to cloth to
      envelop; -- applied esp. to dress of a splendid kind.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pharaoh . . . arrayed him in vestures of fine linen.
                                                  --Gen. xli.?.
      [1913 Webster]

            In gelid caves with horrid gloom arrayed.
                                                  --Trumbull.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) To set in order, as a jury, for the trial of a
      cause; that is, to call them man by man. --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To array a panel}, to set forth in order the men that are
      impaneled. --Cowell. --Tomlins.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To draw up; arrange; dispose; set in order.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>array</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>array
     n 1: an orderly arrangement; "an array of troops in battle order"
     2: an impressive display; "it was a bewildering array of
        books"; "his tools were in an orderly array on the
        basement wall"
     3: especially fine or decorative clothing [syn: {raiment}, {regalia}]
     4: an arrangement of aerials spaced to give desired directional
        characteristics
     v 1: lay out in a line [syn: {range}, {lay out}, {set out}]
     2: align oneself with a group or a way of thinking [syn: {align}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
