<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>arrangement</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>arrangement</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Arrangement \Ar*range"ment\, n. [Cf. F. arrangement.]
   1. The act of arranging or putting in an orderly condition;
      the state of being arranged or put in order; disposition
      in suitable form.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The manner or result of arranging; system of parts
      disposed in due order; regular and systematic
      classification; as, arrangement of one's dress; the
      Linn[ae]an arrangement of plants.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Preparatory proceeding or measure; preparation; as, we
      have made arrangement for receiving company.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Settlement; adjustment by agreement; as, the parties have
      made an arrangement between themselves concerning their
      disputes; a satisfactory arrangement.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.)
      (a) The adaptation of a composition to voices or
          instruments for which it was not originally written.
      (b) A piece so adapted; a transcription; as, a pianoforte
          arrangement of Beethoven's symphonies; an orchestral
          arrangement of a song, an opera, or the like.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>arrangement</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>arrangement
     n 1: the thing arranged or agreed to; "they made arrangements to
          meet in Chicago" [syn: {agreement}]
     2: an orderly grouping (of things or persons) considered as a
        unit; the result of arranging; "a flower arrangement"
     3: an organized structure for arranging or classifying; "he
        changed the arrangement of the topics"; "the facts were
        familiar but it was in the organization of them that he
        was original"; "he tried to understand their system of
        classification" [syn: {organization}, {organisation}, {system}]
     4: the spatial property of the way in which something is
        placed; "the arrangement of the furniture"; "the placement
        of the chairs" [syn: {placement}]
     5: a piece of music that has been adapted for performance by a
        particular set of voices or instruments [syn: {musical
        arrangement}]
     6: the act of arranging and adapting a piece of music [syn: {arranging},
         {transcription}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
