<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>art</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ART, n.  This word has no definition.  Its origin is related as
follows by the ingenious Father Gassalasca Jape, S.J.

    One day a wag -- what would the wretch be at? --
    Shifted a letter of the cipher RAT,
    And said it was a god's name!  Straight arose
    Fantastic priests and postulants (with shows,
    And mysteries, and mummeries, and hymns,
    And disputations dire that lamed their limbs)
    To serve his temple and maintain the fires,
    Expound the law, manipulate the wires.
    Amazed, the populace that rites attend,
    Believe whate'er they cannot comprehend,
    And, inly edified to learn that two
    Half-hairs joined so and so (as Art can do)
    Have sweeter values and a grace more fit
    Than Nature's hairs that never have been split,
    Bring cates and wines for sacrificial feasts,
    And sell their garments to support the priests.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ART
     
        &lt;language&gt; A {real-time} {functional language}.  It timestamps
        each data value when it was created.
     
        ["Applicative Real-Time Programming", M. Broy, PROC IFIP 1983,
        N-H].
     
        (1996-01-15)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Art, TX
  Zip code(s): 76820
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-ard \-ard\, -art \-art\
   The termination of many English words; as, coward, reynard,
   drunkard, mostly from the French, in which language this
   ending is of German origin, being orig. the same word as
   English hard. It usually has the sense of one who has to a
   high or excessive degree the quality expressed by the root;
   as, braggart, sluggard.
   [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Art \Art\ ([aum]rt).
   The second person singular, indicative mode, present tense,
   of the substantive verb {Be}; but formed after the analogy of
   the plural are, with the ending -t, as in thou shalt, wilt,
   orig. an ending of the second person sing. pret. Cf. {Be}.
   Now used only in solemn or poetical style.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Art \Art\ ([aum]rt), n. [F. art, L. ars, artis, orig., skill in
   joining or fitting; prob. akin to E. arm, aristocrat,
   article.]
   1. The employment of means to accomplish some desired end;
      the adaptation of things in the natural world to the uses
      of life; the application of knowledge or power to
      practical purposes.
      [1913 Webster]

            Blest with each grace of nature and of art. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A system of rules serving to facilitate the performance of
      certain actions; a system of principles and rules for
      attaining a desired end; method of doing well some special
      work; -- often contradistinguished from science or
      speculative principles; as, the art of building or
      engraving; the art of war; the art of navigation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Science is systematized knowledge . . . Art is
            knowledge made efficient by skill.    --J. F.
                                                  Genung.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The systematic application of knowledge or skill in
      effecting a desired result. Also, an occupation or
      business requiring such knowledge or skill.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fishermen can't employ their art with so much
            success in so troubled a sea.         --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The application of skill to the production of the
      beautiful by imitation or design, or an occupation in
      which skill is so employed, as in painting and sculpture;
      one of the fine arts; as, he prefers art to literature.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. Those branches of learning which are taught in the
      academical course of colleges; as, master of arts.
      [1913 Webster]

            In fearless youth we tempt the heights of arts.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Four years spent in the arts (as they are called in
            colleges) is, perhaps, laying too laborious a
            foundation.                           --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Learning; study; applied knowledge, science, or letters.
      [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            So vast is art, so narrow human wit.  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Skill, dexterity, or the power of performing certain
      actions, acquired by experience, study, or observation;
      knack; as, a man has the art of managing his business to
      advantage.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Skillful plan; device.
      [1913 Webster]

            They employed every art to soothe . . . the
            discontented warriors.                --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Cunning; artifice; craft.
      [1913 Webster]

            Madam, I swear I use no art at all.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Animals practice art when opposed to their superiors
            in strength.                          --Crabb.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The black art; magic. [Obs.] --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Art and part} (Scots Law), share or concern by aiding and
      abetting a criminal in the perpetration of a crime,
      whether by advice or by assistance in the execution;
      complicity.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The arts are divided into various classes.

   {The useful arts},

   {The mechanical arts}, or

   {The industrial arts} are those in which the hands and body
      are more concerned than the mind; as in making clothes and
      utensils. These are called trades.

   {The fine arts} are those which have primarily to do with
      imagination and taste, and are applied to the production
      of what is beautiful. They include poetry, music,
      painting, engraving, sculpture, and architecture; but the
      term is often confined to painting, sculpture, and
      architecture.

   {The liberal arts} (artes liberales, the higher arts, which,
      among the Romans, only freemen were permitted to pursue)
      were, in the Middle Ages, these seven branches of
      learning, -- grammar, logic, rhetoric, arithmetic,
      geometry, music, and astronomy. In modern times the
      liberal arts include the sciences, philosophy, history,
      etc., which compose the course of academical or collegiate
      education. Hence, degrees in the arts; master and bachelor
      of arts.
      [1913 Webster]

            In America, literature and the elegant arts must
            grow up side by side with the coarser plants of
            daily necessity.                      --Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Science; literature; aptitude; readiness; skill;
        dexterity; adroitness; contrivance; profession;
        business; trade; calling; cunning; artifice; duplicity.
        See {Science}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ART
     Adaptive Resonance Theory (NN)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ART
     Advanced Resolution Technology (Minolta)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>art</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>art
     n 1: the products of human creativity; works of art collectively;
          "an art exhibition"; "a fine collection of art" [syn: {fine
          art}]
     2: the creation of beautiful or significant things; "art does
        not need to be innovative to be good"; "I was never any
        good at art"; "he said that architecture is the art of
        wasting space beautifully" [syn: {artistic creation}, {artistic
        production}]
     3: a superior skill that you can learn by study and practice
        and observation; "the art of conversation"; "it's quite an
        art" [syn: {artistry}, {prowess}]
     4: photographs or other visual representations in a printed
        publication; "the publisher was responsible for all the
        artwork in the book" [syn: {artwork}, {graphics}, {nontextual
        matter}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
