<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ass</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ASS, n.  A public singer with a good voice but no ear.  In Virginia
City, Nevada, he is called the Washoe Canary, in Dakota, the Senator,
and everywhere the Donkey.  The animal is widely and variously
celebrated in the literature, art and religion of every age and
country; no other so engages and fires the human imagination as this
noble vertebrate.  Indeed, it is doubted by some (Ramasilus, _lib.

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ass
   frequently mentioned throughout Scripture. Of the domesticated
   species we read of, (1.) The she ass (Heb. 'athon), so named
   from its slowness (Gen. 12:16; 45:23; Num. 22:23; 1 Sam. 9:3).
   (2.) The male ass (Heb. hamor), the common working ass of
   Western Asia, so called from its red colour. Issachar is
   compared to a strong ass (Gen. 49:14). It was forbidden to yoke
   together an ass and an ox in the plough (Deut. 22:10). (3.) The
   ass's colt (Heb. 'air), mentioned Judg. 10:4; 12:14. It is
   rendered "foal" in Gen. 32:15; 49:11. (Comp. Job 11:12; Isa.
   30:6.) The ass is an unclean animal, because it does not chew
   the cud (Lev. 11:26. Comp. 2 Kings 6:25). Asses constituted a
   considerable portion of wealth in ancient times (Gen. 12:16;
   30:43; 1 Chr. 27:30; Job 1:3; 42:12). They were noted for their
   spirit and their attachment to their master (Isa. 1:3). They are
   frequently spoken of as having been ridden upon, as by Abraham
   (Gen. 22:3), Balaam (Num. 22:21), the disobedient prophet (1
   Kings 13:23), the family of Abdon the judge, seventy in number
   (Judg. 12:14), Zipporah (Ex. 4:20), the Shunammite (1 Sam.
   25:30), etc. Zechariah (9:9) predicted our Lord's triumphal
   entrance into Jerusalem, "riding upon an ass, and upon a colt,"
   etc. (Matt. 21:5, R.V.).
   
     Of wild asses two species are noticed, (1) that called in
   Hebrew _'arod_, mentioned Job 39:5 and Dan. 5:21, noted for its
   swiftness; and (2) that called _pe're_, the wild ass of Asia
   (Job 39:6-8; 6:5; 11:12; Isa. 32:14; Jer. 2:24; 14:6, etc.). The
   wild ass was distinguished for its fleetness and its extreme
   shyness. In allusion to his mode of life, Ishmael is likened to
   a wild ass (Gen. 16:12. Here the word is simply rendered "wild"
   in the Authorized Version, but in the Revised Version, "wild-ass
   among men").
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ass \Ass\, n. [OE. asse, AS. assa; akin to Icel. asni, W. asen,
   asyn, L. asinus, dim. aselus, Gr. ?; also to AS. esol, OHG.
   esil, G. esel, Goth. asilus, Dan. [ae]sel, Lith. asilas,
   Bohem. osel, Pol. osiel. The word is prob. of Semitic origin;
   cf. Heb. ath?n she ass. Cf. {Ease}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) A quadruped of the genus {Equus} ({Equus
      asinus}), smaller than the horse, and having a peculiarly
      harsh bray and long ears. The tame or domestic ass is
      patient, slow, and sure-footed, and has become the type of
      obstinacy and stupidity. There are several species of wild
      asses which are swift-footed.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A dull, heavy, stupid fellow; a dolt. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Asses' Bridge}. [L. pons asinorum.] The fifth proposition of
      the first book of Euclid, ``The angles at the base of an
      isosceles triangle are equal to one another.'' [Sportive]
      ``A schoolboy, stammering out his Asses' Bridge.'' --F.
      Harrison.

   {To make an ass of one's self}, to do or say something very
      foolish or absurd.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Butt \Butt\, But \But\, n. [F. but butt, aim (cf. butte knoll),
   or bout, OF. bot, end, extremity, fr. boter, buter, to push,
   butt, strike, F. bouter; of German origin; cf. OHG. b[=o]zan,
   akin to E. beat. See {Beat}, v. t.]
   1. A limit; a bound; a goal; the extreme bound; the end.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here is my journey's end, here my butt
            And very sea mark of my utmost sail.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: As applied to land, the word is nearly synonymous with
         mete, and signifies properly the end line or boundary;
         the abuttal.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The larger or thicker end of anything; the blunt end, in
      distinction from the sharp end; as, the butt of a rifle.
      Formerly also spelled {but}. See 2nd {but}, n. sense 2.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. A mark to be shot at; a target. --Sir W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            The groom his fellow groom at butts defies,
            And bends his bow, and levels with his eyes.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A person at whom ridicule, jest, or contempt is directed;
      as, the butt of the company.
      [1913 Webster]

            I played a sentence or two at my butt, which I
            thought very smart.                   --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A push, thrust, or sudden blow, given by the head of an
      animal; as, the butt of a ram.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A thrust in fencing.
      [1913 Webster]

            To prove who gave the fairer butt,
            John shows the chalk on Robert's coat. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A piece of land left unplowed at the end of a field.
      [1913 Webster]

            The hay was growing upon headlands and butts in
            cornfields.                           --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mech.)
      (a) A joint where the ends of two objects come squarely
          together without scarfing or chamfering; -- also
          called {butt joint}.
      (b) The end of a connecting rod or other like piece, to
          which the boxing is attached by the strap, cotter, and
          gib.
      (c) The portion of a half-coupling fastened to the end of
          a hose.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Shipbuilding) The joint where two planks in a strake
      meet.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Carp.) A kind of hinge used in hanging doors, etc.; --
       so named because fastened on the edge of the door, which
       butts against the casing, instead of on its face, like
       the strap hinge; also called {butt hinge}.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Leather Trade) The thickest and stoutest part of tanned
       oxhides, used for soles of boots, harness, trunks.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. The hut or shelter of the person who attends to the
       targets in rifle practice.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. The buttocks; as, get up off your butt and get to work;
       -- used as a euphemism, less objectionable than {ass}.
       [slang]

   Syn: ass, rear end, derriere, behind, rump, heinie.
        [PJC]

   {Butt chain} (Saddlery), a short chain attached to the end of
      a tug.

   {Butt end}. The thicker end of anything. See {But end}, under
      2d {But}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Amen; and make me die a good old man!
            That's the butt end of a mother's blessing. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {A butt's length}, the ordinary distance from the place of
      shooting to the butt, or mark.

   {Butts and bounds} (Conveyancing), abuttals and boundaries.
      In lands of the ordinary rectangular shape, butts are the
      lines at the ends (F. bouts), and bounds are those on the
      sides, or sidings, as they were formerly termed.
      --Burrill.

   {Bead and butt}. See under {Bead}.

   {Butt and butt}, joining end to end without overlapping, as
      planks.

   {Butt weld} (Mech.), a butt joint, made by welding together
      the flat ends, or edges, of a piece of iron or steel, or
      of separate pieces, without having them overlap. See
      {Weld}.

   {Full butt}, headfirst with full force. [Colloq.] ``The
      corporal . . . ran full butt at the lieutenant.''
      --Marryat.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ass</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ass
     n 1: the fleshy part of the human body that you sit on; "he
          deserves a good kick in the butt"; "are you going to sit
          on your fanny and do nothing?" [syn: {buttocks}, {nates},
           {arse}, {butt}, {backside}, {bum}, {buns}, {can}, {fundament},
           {hindquarters}, {hind end}, {keister}, {posterior}, {prat},
           {rear}, {rear end}, {rump}, {stern}, {seat}, {tail}, {tail
          end}, {tooshie}, {tush}, {bottom}, {behind}, {derriere},
           {fanny}]
     2: a pompous fool
     3: hardy and sure-footed animal smaller and with longer ears
        than the horse
     4: slang terms for sexual intercourse [syn: {fuck}, {fucking},
        {screw}, {screwing}, {nooky}, {nookie}, {piece of ass}, {piece
        of tail}, {roll in the hay}, {shag}, {shtup}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
