<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>assembly</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>assembly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ASSEMBLY
     
        &lt;language&gt; An early system on the {IBM 702}.
     
        [Listed in CACM 2(5):1959-05-16].
     
        (1996-06-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>assembly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Assembly \As*sem"bly\, n.; pl. {Assemblies}. [F. assembl['e]e,
   fr. assembler. See {Assemble}.]
   1. A company of persons collected together in one place, and
      usually for some common purpose, esp. for deliberation and
      legislation, for worship, or for social entertainment.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A collection of inanimate objects. [Obs.] --Howell.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil.) A beat of the drum or sound of the bugle as a
      signal to troops to assemble.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In some of the United States, the legislature, or the
         popular branch of it, is called the Assembly, or the
         General Assembly. In the Presbyterian Church, the
         General Assembly is the highest ecclesiastical
         tribunal, composed of ministers and ruling elders
         delegated from each presbytery; as, the General
         Assembly of the Presbyterian Church in the United
         States, or of Scotland.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Assembly room}, a room in which persons assemble, especially
      for dancing.

   {Unlawful assembly} (Law), a meeting of three or more persons
      on a common plan, in such a way as to cause a reasonable
      apprehension that they will disturb the peace
      tumultuously.

   {Westminster Assembly}, a convocation, consisting chiefly of
      divines, which, by act of Parliament, assembled July 1,
      1643, and remained in session some years. It framed the
      ``Confession of Faith,'' the ``Larger Catechism,'' and the
      ``Shorter Catechism,'' which are still received as
      authority by Presbyterians, and are substantially accepted
      by Congregationalists.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See {Assemblage}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>assembly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>assembly
     n 1: a group of machine parts that fit together to form a
          self-contained unit
     2: the act of constructing something (as a piece of machinery)
        [syn: {fabrication}] [ant: {dismantling}]
     3: a public facility to meet for open discussion [syn: {forum},
         {meeting place}]
     4: a group of persons gathered together for a common purpose
     5: the social act of assembling; "they demanded the right of
        assembly" [syn: {assemblage}, {gathering}] [ant: {dismantling}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
