<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>assignment</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>assignment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>assignment
     
        &lt;programming&gt; Storing the value of an expression in a
        {variable}.  This is commonly written in the form "v = e".  In
        {Algol} the assignment operator was ":=" (pronounced
        "becomes") to avoid mathematicians qualms about writing
        statements like x = x+1.
     
        Assignment is not allowed in {functional languages}, where an
        {identifier} always has the same value.
     
        See also {referential transparency}, {single assignment},
        {zero assignment}.
     
        (1996-08-19)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>assignment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Assignment \As*sign"ment\, n. [LL. assignamentum: cf. OF.
   assenement.]
   1. An allotting or an appointment to a particular person or
      use; or for a particular time, as of a cause or causes in
      court.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law)
      (a) A transfer of title or interest by writing, as of
          lease, bond, note, or bill of exchange; a transfer of
          the whole of some particular estate or interest in
          lands.
      (b) The writing by which an interest is transferred.
      (c) The transfer of the property of a bankrupt to certain
          persons called assignees, in whom it is vested for the
          benefit of creditors.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Assignment of dower}, the setting out by metes and bounds of
      the widow's thirds or portion in the deceased husband's
      estate, and allotting it to her.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Assignment is also used in law as convertible with
         specification; assignment of error in proceedings for
         review being specification of error; and assignment of
         perjury or fraud in indictment being specifications of
         perjury or fraud.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>assignment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>assignment
     n 1: a duty that you are assigned to perform (especially in the
          armed forces); "hazardous duty" [syn: {duty assignment}]
     2: the instrument by which a claim or right or interest or
        property is transferred from one person to another
     3: the act of distributing something to designated places or
        persons; "the first task is the assignment of an address
        to each datum" [syn: {assigning}]
     4: (law) a transfer of property by deed of conveyance [syn: {grant}]
     5: an undertaking that you have been assigned to do (as by an
        instructor)
     6: the act of putting a person into a non-elective position;
        "the appointment had to be approved by the whole
        committee" [syn: {appointment}, {designation}, {naming}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
