<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>at</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>at</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>at
     
        1. &lt;character&gt; {commercial at}.
     
        2. &lt;networking&gt; The {country code} for Austria.
     
        (1999-01-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>at</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>AT
     
        {IBM PC AT}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>at</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>At \At\, prep. [AS. [ae]t; akin to OHG. az, Goth., OS., &amp; Icel.
   at, Sw. [*a]t, Dan. &amp; L. ad.]
   Primarily, this word expresses the relations of presence,
   nearness in place or time, or direction toward; as, at the
   ninth hour; at the house; to aim at a mark. It is less
   definite than in or on; at the house may be in or near the
   house. From this original import are derived all the various
   uses of at. It expresses: 
   [1913 Webster]

   1. A relation of proximity to, or of presence in or on,
      something; as, at the door; at your shop; at home; at
      school; at hand; at sea and on land.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The relation of some state or condition; as, at war; at
      peace; at ease; at your service; at fault; at liberty; at
      risk; at disadvantage.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The relation of some employment or action; occupied with;
      as, at engraving; at husbandry; at play; at work; at meat
      (eating); except at puns.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The relation of a point or position in a series, or of
      degree, rate, or value; as, with the thermometer at
      80[deg]; goods sold at a cheap price; a country estimated
      at 10,000 square miles; life is short at the longest.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The relations of time, age, or order; as, at ten o'clock;
      at twenty-one; at once; at first.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The relations of source, occasion, reason, consequence, or
      effect; as, at the sight; at this news; merry at anything;
      at this declaration; at his command; to demand, require,
      receive, deserve, endure at your hands.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Relation of direction toward an object or end; as, look at
      it; to point at one; to aim at a mark; to throw, strike,
      shoot, wink, mock, laugh at any one.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At all}, {At home}, {At large}, {At last}, {At length}, {At
   once}, etc. See under {All}, {Home}, {Large}, {Last} (phrase
      and syn.), {Length}, {Once}, etc.

   {At it}, busily or actively engaged.

   {At least}. See {Least} and {However}.

   {At one}. See {At one}, in the Vocabulary.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: {In}, {At}.

   Usage: When reference to the interior of any place is made
          prominent in is used. It is used before the names of
          countries and cities (esp. large cities); as, we live
          in America, in New York, in the South. At is commonly
          employed before names of houses, institutions,
          villages, and small places; as, Milton was educated at
          Christ's College; money taken in at the Customhouse; I
          saw him at the jeweler's; we live at Beachville. At
          may be used before the name of a city when it is
          regarded as a mere point of locality. ``An English
          king was crowned at Paris.'' --Macaulay. ``Jean
          Jacques Rousseau was born at Geneva, June, 28, 1712.''
          --J. Morley. In regard to time, we say at the hour, on
          the day, in the year; as, at 9 o'clock, on the morning
          of July 5th, in the year 1775.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>at</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>AT
     Advanced Technology (IBM, PC)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>at</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>At
     n 1: a highly unstable radioactive element (the heaviest of the
          halogen series); a decay product of uranium and thorium
          [syn: {astatine}, {atomic number 85}]
     2: 100 at equal 1 kip
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
