<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>atomic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>atomic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>atomic
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; (From Greek "atomos", indivisible) Indivisible;
        cannot be split up.
     
        For example, an instruction may be said to do several things
        "atomically", i.e. all the things are done immediately, and
        there is no chance of the instruction being half-completed or
        of another being interspersed.  Used especially to convey that
        an operation cannot be interrupted.
     
        An atomic {data type} has no internal structure visible to the
        program.  It can be represented by a flat {domain} (all
        elements are equally defined).  Machine {integers} and
        {Booleans} are two examples.
     
        An atomic {database transaction} is one which is guaranteed to
        complete successfully or not at all.  If an error prevents a
        partially-performed transaction from proceeding to completion,
        it must be "backed out" to prevent the database being left in
        an inconsistent state.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2000-04-03)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>atomic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Atomic \A*tom"ic\, Atomical \A*tom"ic*al\, a. [Cf. F. atomique.]
   1. Of or pertaining to atoms.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Extremely minute; tiny.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Atomic bomb}, see {atom bomb} in the vocabulary.

   {Atomic philosophy}, or {Doctrine of atoms}, a system which,
      assuming that atoms are endued with gravity and motion,
      accounted thus for the origin and formation of all things.
      This philosophy was first broached by Leucippus, was
      developed by Democritus, and afterward improved by
      Epicurus, and hence is sometimes denominated the Epicurean
      philosophy.

   {Atomic theory}, or the {Doctrine of definite proportions}
      (Chem.), teaches that chemical combinations take place
      between the supposed ultimate particles or atoms of
      bodies, in some simple ratio, as of one to one, two to
      three, or some other, always expressible in whole numbers.
      

   {Atomic weight} (Chem.), the weight of the atom of an element
      as compared with the weight of the atom of hydrogen, taken
      as a standard.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>atomic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>atomic adj. [from Gk. `atomos', indivisible] 1. Indivisible; cannot be
   split up. For example, an instruction may be said to do several things
   `atomically', i.e., all the things are done immediately, and there is no
   chance of the instruction being half-completed or of another being
   interspersed. Used esp. to convey that an operation cannot be screwed up
   by interrupts. "This routine locks the file and increments the file's
   semaphore atomically." 2. [primarily techspeak] Guaranteed to complete
   successfully or not at all, usu. refers to database transactions. If an
   error prevents a partially-performed transaction from proceeding to
   completion, it must be "backed out," as the database must not be left in
   an inconsistent state.

   Computer usage, in either of the above senses, has none of the
   connotations that `atomic' has in mainstream English (i.e. of particles
   of matter, nuclear explosions etc.).


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>atomic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>atomic
     adj 1: of or relating to or comprising atoms; "atomic structure";
            "atomic hydrogen"
     2: (weapons) deriving destructive energy from  the release of
        atomic energy; "nuclear war"; "nuclear weapons"; "atomic
        bombs" [syn: {nuclear}] [ant: {conventional}]
     3: immeasurably small [syn: {atomlike}, {minute}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
