<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>attack</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Appel \Ap`pel"\, n. [F., prop., a call. See {Appeal}, n.]
   (Fencing)
   A tap or stamp of the foot as a warning of intent to attack;
   -- called also {attack}.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attack \At*tack"\, v. i.
   To make an onset or attack.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attack \At*tack"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Attacked}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Attacking}.] [F. attaquer, orig. another form of attacher
   to attack: cf. It. attacare to fasten, attack. See {Attach},
   {Tack} a small nail.]
   1. To fall upon with force; to assail, as with force and
      arms; to assault. ``Attack their lines.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To assail with unfriendly speech or writing; to begin a
      controversy with; to attempt to overthrow or bring into
      disrepute, by criticism or satire; to censure; as, to
      attack a man, or his opinions, in a pamphlet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To set to work upon, as upon a task or problem, or some
      object of labor or investigation.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To begin to affect; to begin to act upon, injuriously or
      destructively; to begin to decompose or waste.
      [1913 Webster]

            On the fourth of March he was attacked by fever.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hydrofluoric acid . . . attacks the glass. --B.
                                                  Stewart.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To {Attack}, {Assail}, {Assault}, {Invade}.

   Usage: These words all denote a violent onset; attack being
          the generic term, and the others specific forms of
          attack. To attack is to commence the onset; to assail
          is to make a sudden and violent attack, or to make
          repeated attacks; to assault (literally, to leap upon)
          is to attack physically by a had-to-hand approach or
          by unlawful and insulting violence; to invade is to
          enter by force on what belongs to another. Thus, a
          person may attack by offering violence of any kind; he
          may assail by means of missile weapons; he may assault
          by direct personal violence; a king may invade by
          marching an army into a country. Figuratively, we may
          say, men attack with argument or satire; they assail
          with abuse or reproaches; they may be assaulted by
          severe temptations; the rights of the people may be
          invaded by the encroachments of the crown.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attack \At*tack"\, n. [Cf. F. attaque.]
   1. The act of attacking, or falling on with force or
      violence; an onset; an assault; -- opposed to defense.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An assault upon one's feelings or reputation with
      unfriendly or bitter words.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A setting to work upon some task, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An access of disease; a fit of sickness.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The beginning of corrosive, decomposing, or destructive
      action, by a chemical agent.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>attack
     n 1: (military) an offensive against an enemy (using weapons);
          "the attack began at dawn" [syn: {onslaught}, {onset}, {onrush}]
     2: a sudden occurrence of an uncontrollable condition; "an
        attack of diarrhea"
     3: intense adverse criticism; "Clinton directed his fire at the
        Republican Party"; "the government has come under attack";
        "don't give me any flak" [syn: {fire}, {flak}, {flack}, {blast}]
     4: the act of attacking; "attacks on women increased last
        year"; "they made an attempt on his life" [syn: {attempt}]
     5: an offensive move in a sport or game; "they won the game
        with a 10-hit attack in the 9th inning"
     6: the onset of a corrosive or destructive process (as by a
        chemical agent); "the film was sensitive to attack by
        acids"; "open to attack by the elements"
     7: ideas or actions intended to deal with a problem or
        situation; "his approach to every problem is to draw up a
        list of pros and cons"; "an attack on inflation"; "his
        plan of attack was misguided" [syn: {approach}, {plan of
        attack}]
     8: a decisive manner of beginning a musical tone or phrase
        [syn: {tone-beginning}]
     9: strong criticism; "he published an unexpected attack on my
        work"
     v 1: launch an attack or assault on; begin hostilities or start
          warfare with; "Hitler attacked Poland on September 1,
          1939 and started World War II"; "Serbian forces assailed
          Bosnian towns all week" [syn: {assail}] [ant: {defend}]
     2: attack in speech or writing; "The editors of the
        left-leaning paper attacked the new House Speaker" [syn: {round},
         {assail}, {lash out}, {snipe}, {assault}]
     3: take the initiative and go on the offensive; "The Serbs
        attacked the village at night"; "The visiting team started
        to attack" [syn: {aggress}]
     4: attack someone physically or emotionally; "The mugger
        assaulted the woman"; "Nightmares assailed him regularly"
        [syn: {assail}, {assault}, {set on}]
     5: set to work upon; turn one's energies vigorously to a task;
        "I attacked the problem as soon as I got out of bed"
     6: begin to injure; "The cancer cells are attacking his liver";
        "Rust is attacking the metal"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
