<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>attention</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attention</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attention \At*ten"tion\, n. [L. attentio: cf. F. attention.]
   1. The act or state of attending or heeding; the application
      of the mind to any object of sense, representation, or
      thought; notice; exclusive or special consideration;
      earnest consideration, thought, or regard; obedient or
      affectionate heed; the supposed power or faculty of
      attending.
      [1913 Webster]

            They say the tongues of dying men
            Enforce attention like deep harmony.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Attention is consciousness and something more. It is
         consciousness voluntarily applied, under its law of
         limitations, to some determinate object; it is
         consciousness concentrated. --Sir W. Hamilton.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. An act of civility or courtesy; care for the comfort and
      pleasure of others; as, attentions paid to a stranger.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pay attention to}, {To pay one's attentions to}, to be
      courteous or attentive to; to wait upon as a lover; to
      court.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Care; heed; study; consideration; application;
        advertence; respect; regard.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attention</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>attention
     n 1: the process whereby a person concentrates on some features
          of the environment to the (relative) exclusion of others
          [syn: {attending}] [ant: {inattention}]
     2: the work of caring for or attending to someone or something;
        "no medical care was required"; "the old car needed
        constant attention" [syn: {care}, {aid}, {tending}]
     3: a general interest that leads people to want to know more;
        "She was the center of attention"
     4: a courteous act indicating affection; "she tried to win his
        heart with her many attentions"
     5: the faculty or power of mental concentration; "keeping track
        of all the details requires your complete attention"
     6: a motionless erect stance with arms at the sides and feet
        together; assumed by military personnel during drill or
        review; "the troops stood at attention"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
