<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>attending</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attending</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attend \At*tend"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Attended}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Attending}.] [OE. atenden, OF. atendre, F. attendre, to
   expect, to wait, fr. L. attendre to stretch, (sc. animum), to
   apply the mind to; ad + tendere to stretch. See {Tend}.]
   1. To direct the attention to; to fix the mind upon; to give
      heed to; to regard. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The diligent pilot in a dangerous tempest doth not
            attend the unskillful words of the passenger. --Sir
                                                  P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To care for; to look after; to take charge of; to watch
      over.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To go or stay with, as a companion, nurse, or servant; to
      visit professionally, as a physician; to accompany or
      follow in order to do service; to escort; to wait on; to
      serve.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fifth had charge sick persons to attend.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Attends the emperor in his royal court. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            With a sore heart and a gloomy brow, he prepared to
            attend William thither.               --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be present with; to accompany; to be united or
      consequent to; as, a measure attended with ill effects.
      [1913 Webster]

            What cares must then attend the toiling swain.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be present at; as, to attend church, school, a concert,
      a business meeting.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To wait for; to await; to remain, abide, or be in store
      for. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The state that attends all men after this. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Three days I promised to attend my doom. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To {Attend}, {Mind}, {Regard}, {Heed}, {Notice}.

   Usage: Attend is generic, the rest are specific terms. To
          mind is to attend so that it may not be forgotten; to
          regard is to look on a thing as of importance; to heed
          is to attend to a thing from a principle of caution;
          to notice is to think on that which strikes the
          senses. --Crabb. See {Accompany}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attending</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>attending
     adj 1: being present at meeting or event [syn: {in attendance(p)}]
     2: serving attendance on someone; "a ministering angel"; "the
        angels ministrant sang"; "the attending physician" [syn: {ministering},
         {ministrant}]
     n 1: the process whereby a person concentrates on some features
          of the environment to the (relative) exclusion of others
          [syn: {attention}] [ant: {inattention}]
     2: the act of being present (at a meeting or event etc.) [syn:
        {attendance}] [ant: {nonattendance}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
