<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>attend</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attend \At*tend"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Attended}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Attending}.] [OE. atenden, OF. atendre, F. attendre, to
   expect, to wait, fr. L. attendre to stretch, (sc. animum), to
   apply the mind to; ad + tendere to stretch. See {Tend}.]
   1. To direct the attention to; to fix the mind upon; to give
      heed to; to regard. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The diligent pilot in a dangerous tempest doth not
            attend the unskillful words of the passenger. --Sir
                                                  P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To care for; to look after; to take charge of; to watch
      over.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To go or stay with, as a companion, nurse, or servant; to
      visit professionally, as a physician; to accompany or
      follow in order to do service; to escort; to wait on; to
      serve.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fifth had charge sick persons to attend.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Attends the emperor in his royal court. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            With a sore heart and a gloomy brow, he prepared to
            attend William thither.               --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be present with; to accompany; to be united or
      consequent to; as, a measure attended with ill effects.
      [1913 Webster]

            What cares must then attend the toiling swain.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be present at; as, to attend church, school, a concert,
      a business meeting.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To wait for; to await; to remain, abide, or be in store
      for. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The state that attends all men after this. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Three days I promised to attend my doom. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To {Attend}, {Mind}, {Regard}, {Heed}, {Notice}.

   Usage: Attend is generic, the rest are specific terms. To
          mind is to attend so that it may not be forgotten; to
          regard is to look on a thing as of importance; to heed
          is to attend to a thing from a principle of caution;
          to notice is to think on that which strikes the
          senses. --Crabb. See {Accompany}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attend \At*tend"\, v. i.
   1. To apply the mind, or pay attention, with a view to
      perceive, understand, or comply; to pay regard; to heed;
      to listen; -- usually followed by to.
      [1913 Webster]

            Attend to the voice of my supplications. --Ps.
                                                  lxxxvi. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man can not at the same time attend to two objects.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To accompany or be present or near at hand, in pursuance
      of duty; to be ready for service; to wait or be in
      waiting; -- often followed by on or upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was required to attend upon the committee.
                                                  --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (with to) To take charge of; to look after; as, to attend
      to a matter of business.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To wait; to stay; to delay. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            For this perfection she must yet attend,
            Till to her Maker she espoused be.    --Sir J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To {Attend}, {Listen}, {Hearken}.

   Usage: We attend with a view to hear and learn; we listen
          with fixed attention, in order to hear correctly, or
          to consider what has been said; we hearken when we
          listen with a willing mind, and in reference to
          obeying.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>attend</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>attend
     v 1: be present at (meetings, church services, university), etc.;
          "She attends class regularly"; "I rarely attend services
          at my church"; "did you go to the meeting?" [syn: {go to}]
          [ant: {miss}]
     2: take charge of or deal with; "Could you see about lunch?";
        "I must attend to this matter"; "She took care of this
        business" [syn: {take care}, {look}, {see}]
     3: to accompany as a circumstance or follow as a result;
        "Menuhin's playing was attended by a 15-minute standing
        ovation"
     4: work for or be a servant to; "May I serve you?"; "She
        attends the old lady in the wheelchair"; "Can you wait on
        our table, please?"; "Is a salesperson assisting you?";
        "The minister served the King for many years" [syn: {serve},
         {attend to}, {wait on}, {assist}]
     5: give heed (to); "The children in the audience attended the
        recital quietly"; "She hung on his every word"; "They
        attended to everything he said" [syn: {hang}, {advert}, {pay
        heed}, {give ear}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
