<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>audience</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>audience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Court \Court\ (k[=o]rt), n. [OF. court, curt, cort, F. cour, LL.
   cortis, fr. L. cohors, cors, chors, gen. cohortis, cortis,
   chortis, an inclosure, court, thing inclosed, crowd, throng;
   co- + a root akin to Gr. chorto`s inclosure, feeding place,
   and to E. garden, yard, orchard. See {Yard}, and cf.
   {Cohort}, {Curtain}.]
   1. An inclosed space; a courtyard; an uncovered area shut in
      by the walls of a building, or by different building;
      also, a space opening from a street and nearly surrounded
      by houses; a blind alley.
      [1913 Webster]

            The courts of the house of our God.   --Ps. cxxxv.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

            And round the cool green courts there ran a row
            Of cloisters.                         --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            Goldsmith took a garret in a miserable court.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The residence of a sovereign, prince, nobleman, or other
      dignitary; a palace.
      [1913 Webster]

            Attends the emperor in his royal court. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            This our court, infected with their manners,
            Shows like a riotous inn.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The collective body of persons composing the retinue of a
      sovereign or person high in authority; all the
      surroundings of a sovereign in his regal state.
      [1913 Webster]

            My lord, there is a nobleman of the court at door
            would speak with you.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Love rules the court, the camp, the grove. --Sir. W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any formal assembling of the retinue of a sovereign; as,
      to hold a court.
      [1913 Webster]

            The princesses held their court within the fortress.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Attention directed to a person in power; conduct or
      address designed to gain favor; courtliness of manners;
      civility; compliment; flattery.
      [1913 Webster]

            No solace could her paramour intreat
            Her once to show, ne court, nor dalliance.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            I went to make my court to the Duke and Duchess of
            Newcastle.                            --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law)
      (a) The hall, chamber, or place, where justice is
          administered.
      (b) The persons officially assembled under authority of
          law, at the appropriate time and place, for the
          administration of justice; an official assembly,
          legally met together for the transaction of judicial
          business; a judge or judges sitting for the hearing or
          trial of causes.
      (c) A tribunal established for the administration of
          justice.
      (d) The judge or judges; as distinguished from the counsel
          or jury, or both.
          [1913 Webster]

                Most heartily I do beseech the court
                To give the judgment.             --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. The session of a judicial assembly.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Any jurisdiction, civil, military, or ecclesiastical.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A place arranged for playing the game of tennis; also, one
      of the divisions of a tennis court.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Christian court}, the English ecclesiastical courts in the
      aggregate, or any one of them.

   {Court breeding}, education acquired at court.

   {Court card}. Same as {Coat card}.

   {Court circular}, one or more paragraphs of news respecting
      the sovereign and the royal family, together with the
      proceedings or movements of the court generally, supplied
      to the newspapers by an officer specially charged with
      such duty. [Eng.] --Edwards.

   {Court of claims} (Law), a court for settling claims against
      a state or government; specif., a court of the United
      States, created by act of Congress, and holding its
      sessions at Washington. It is given jurisdiction over
      claims on contracts against the government, and sometimes
      may advise the government as to its liabilities. [Webster
      1913 Suppl.]

   {Court day}, a day on which a court sits to administer
      justice.

   {Court dress}, the dress prescribed for appearance at the
      court of a sovereign.

   {Court fool}, a buffoon or jester, formerly kept by princes
      and nobles for their amusement.

   {Court guide}, a directory of the names and adresses of the
      nobility and gentry in a town.

   {Court hand}, the hand or manner of writing used in records
      and judicial proceedings. --Shak.

   {Court lands} (Eng. Law), lands kept in demesne, -- that is,
      for the use of the lord and his family.

   {Court marshal}, one who acts as marshal for a court.

   {Court party}, a party attached to the court.

   {Court rolls}, the records of a court. See{Roll}.

   {Court in banc}, or {Court in bank}, The full court sitting
      at its regular terms for the hearing of arguments upon
      questions of law, as distinguished from a sitting at nisi
      prius.

   {Court of Arches}, {audience}, etc. See under {Arches},
      {Audience}, etc.

   {Court of Chancery}. See {Chancery}, n.

   {Court of Common pleas}. (Law) See {Common pleas}, under
      {Common}.

   {Court of Equity}. See under {Equity}, and {Chancery}.

   {Court of Inquiry} (Mil.), a court appointed to inquire into
      and report on some military matter, as the conduct of an
      officer.

   {Court of St. James}, the usual designation of the British
      Court; -- so called from the old palace of St. James,
      which is used for the royal receptions, levees, and
      drawing-rooms.

   {The court of the Lord}, the temple at Jerusalem; hence, a
      church, or Christian house of worship.

   {General Court}, the legislature of a State; -- so called
      from having had, in the colonial days, judicial power; as,
      the General Court of Massachusetts. [U.S.]

   {To pay one's court}, to seek to gain favor by attentions.
      ``Alcibiades was assiduous in paying his {court} to
      Tissaphernes.'' --Jowett.

   {To put out of court}, to refuse further judicial hearing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>audience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Audience \Au"di*ence\, n. [F. audience, L. audientia, fr. audire
   to hear. See {Audible}, a.]
   1. The act of hearing; attention to sounds.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou, therefore, give due audience, and attend.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Admittance to a hearing; a formal interview, esp. with a
      sovereign or the head of a government, for conference or
      the transaction of business.
      [1913 Webster]

            According to the fair play of the world,
            Let me have audience: I am sent to speak. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An auditory; an assembly of hearers. Also applied by
      authors to their readers.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fit audience find, though few.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            He drew his audience upward to the sky. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Court of audience}, or {Audience court} (Eng.), a court long
      since disused, belonging to the Archbishop of Canterbury;
      also, one belonging to the Archbishop of York. --Mozley &amp;
      W.

   {In general} (or {open}) {audience}, publicly.

   {To give audience}, to listen; to admit to an interview.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>audience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Audience \Au"di*ence\, n. [F. audience, L. audientia, fr. audire
   to hear. See {Audible}, a.]
   1. The act of hearing; attention to sounds.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou, therefore, give due audience, and attend.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Admittance to a hearing; a formal interview, esp. with a
      sovereign or the head of a government, for conference or
      the transaction of business.
      [1913 Webster]

            According to the fair play of the world,
            Let me have audience: I am sent to speak. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An auditory; an assembly of hearers. Also applied by
      authors to their readers.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fit audience find, though few.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            He drew his audience upward to the sky. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Court of audience}, or {Audience court} (Eng.), a court long
      since disused, belonging to the Archbishop of Canterbury;
      also, one belonging to the Archbishop of York. --Mozley &amp;
      W.

   {In general} (or {open}) {audience}, publicly.

   {To give audience}, to listen; to admit to an interview.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>audience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>audience
     n 1: a gathering of spectators or listeners at a (usually public)
          performance; "the audience applauded"; "someone in the
          audience began to cough"
     2: the part of the general public interested in a source of
        information or entertainment; "every artist needs an
        audience"; "the broadcast reached an audience of millions"
     3: an opportunity to state your case and be heard; "they
        condemned him without a hearing"; "he saw that he had lost
        his audience" [syn: {hearing}]
     4: a conference (usually with someone important); "he had a
        consultation with the judge"; "he requested an audience
        with the king" [syn: {consultation}, {interview}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
