<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>axe</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>axe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Axe
   used in the Authorized Version of Deut. 19:5; 20:19; 1 Kings
   6:7, as the translation of a Hebrew word which means "chopping."
   It was used for felling trees (Isa. 10:34) and hewing timber for
   building. It is the rendering of a different word in Judg. 9:48,
   1 Sam. 13:20, 21, Ps. 74:5, which refers to its sharpness. In 2
   Kings 6:5 it is the translation of a word used with reference to
   its being made of iron. In Isa. 44:12 the Revised Version
   renders by "axe" the Hebrew _maatsad_, which means a "hewing"
   instrument. In the Authorized Version it is rendered "tongs." It
   is also used in Jer. 10:3, and rendered "axe." The "battle-axe"
   (army of Medes and Persians) mentioned in Jer. 51:20 was
   probably, as noted in the margin of the Revised Version, a
   "maul" or heavy mace. In Ps. 74:6 the word so rendered means
   "feller." (See the figurative expression in Matt. 3:10; Luke
   3:9.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>axe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>aXe
     
        &lt;tool&gt; A {text editor} for the {X Window System}.  No longer
        maintained.
     
        (1998-03-13)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>axe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ax \Ax\, Axe \Axe\, ([a^]ks), n. [OE. ax, axe, AS. eax, [ae]x,
   acas; akin to D. akse, OS. accus, OHG. acchus, G. axt, Icel.
   ["o]x, ["o]xi, Sw. yxe, Dan. ["o]kse, Goth. aqizi, Gr.
   'axi`nh, L. ascia; not akin to E. acute.]
   A tool or instrument of steel, or of iron with a steel edge
   or blade, for felling trees, chopping and splitting wood,
   hewing timber, etc. It is wielded by a wooden helve or
   handle, so fixed in a socket or eye as to be in the same
   plane with the blade. The broadax, or carpenter's ax, is an
   ax for hewing timber, made heavier than the chopping ax, and
   with a broader and thinner blade and a shorter handle.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The ancient battle-ax had sometimes a double edge.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: The word is used adjectively or in combination; as,
         axhead or ax head; ax helve; ax handle; ax shaft;
         ax-shaped; axlike.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: This word was originally spelt with e, axe; and so also
         was nearly every corresponding word of one syllable:
         as, flaxe, taxe, waxe, sixe, mixe, pixe, oxe, fluxe,
         etc. This superfluous e is not dropped; so that, in
         more than a hundred words ending in x, no one thinks of
         retaining the e except in axe. Analogy requires its
         exclusion here.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: ``The spelling ax is better on every ground, of
         etymology, phonology, and analogy, than axe, which has
         of late become prevalent.'' --New English Dict.
         (Murray).
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>axe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Axe \Axe\, Axeman \Axe"man\, etc.
   See {Ax}, {Axman}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>axe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>AXE
     Application eXecution Environment
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>axe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>axe
     n : an edge tool with a heavy bladed head mounted across a
         handle [syn: {ax}]
     v 1: chop or split with an ax; "axe wood" [syn: {ax}]
     2: terminate; "The NSF axed the research program and stopped
        funding it" [syn: {ax}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
