<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>azimuth</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>azimuth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Azimuth \Az"i*muth\, n. [OE. azimut, F. azimut, fr. Ar.
   as-sum?t, pl. of as-samt a way, or perh., a point of the
   horizon and a circle extending to it from the zenith, as
   being the Arabic article: cf. It. azzimutto, Pg. azimuth, and
   Ar. samt-al-r[=a]'s the vertex of the heaven. Cf. {Zenith}.]
   (Astron. &amp; Geodesy)
      (a) The quadrant of an azimuth circle.
      (b) An arc of the horizon intercepted between the meridian
          of the place and a vertical circle passing through the
          center of any object; as, the azimuth of a star; the
          azimuth or bearing of a line surveying.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: In trigonometrical surveying, it is customary to reckon
         the azimuth of a line from the south point of the
         horizon around by the west from 0[deg] to 360[deg].
         [1913 Webster]

   {Azimuth circle}, or {Vertical circle}, one of the great
      circles of the sphere intersecting each other in the
      zenith and nadir, and cutting the horizon at right angles.
      --Hutton.

   {Azimuth compass}, a compass resembling the mariner's
      compass, but having the card divided into degrees instead
      of rhumbs, and having vertical sights; used for taking the
      magnetic azimuth of a heavenly body, in order to find, by
      comparison with the true azimuth, the variation of the
      needle.

   {Azimuth dial}, a dial whose stile or gnomon is at right
      angles to the plane of the horizon. --Hutton.

   {Magnetic azimuth}, an arc of the horizon, intercepted
      between the vertical circle passing through any object and
      the magnetic meridian. This is found by observing the
      object with an azimuth compass.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>azimuth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>azimuth
     n : the azimuth of a celestial body is the angle between the
         vertical plane containing it and the plane of the
         meridian [syn: {AZ}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
