<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>yankee</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yankee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>YANKEE, n.  In Europe, an American.  In the Northern States of our
Union, a New Englander.  In the Southern States the word is unknown. 
(See DAMNYANK.)


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yankee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Yankee \Yan"kee\, a.
   Of or pertaining to a Yankee; characteristic of the Yankees.
   [1913 Webster]

         The alertness of the Yankee aspect.      --Hawthorne.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Yankee clover}. (Bot.) See {Japan clover}, under {Japan}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yankee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Yankee \Yan"kee\, n. [Commonly considered to be a corrupt
   pronunciation of the word English, or of the French word
   Anglais, by the native Indians of America. According to
   Thierry, a corruption of Jankin, a diminutive of John, and a
   nickname given to the English colonists of Connecticut by the
   Dutch settlers of New York. Dr. W. Gordon (``Hist. of the
   Amer. War,'' ed, 1789, vol. i., pp. 324, 325) says it was a
   favorite cant word in Cambridge, Mass., as early as 1713, and
   that it meant excellent; as, a yankee good horse, yankee good
   cider, etc. Cf. Scot yankie a sharp, clever, and rather bold
   woman, and Prov. E. bow-yankees a kind of leggins worn by
   agricultural laborers.]
   A nickname for a native or citizen of New England, especially
   one descended from old New England stock; by extension, an
   inhabitant of the Northern States as distinguished from a
   Southerner; also, applied sometimes by foreigners to any
   inhabitant of the United States.
   [1913 Webster]

         From meanness first this Portsmouth Yankey rose,
         And still to meanness all his conduct flows.
                                                  --Oppression,
                                                  A poem by an
                                                  American
                                                  (Boston,
                                                  1765).
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yankee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Yankee
     adj : used by southerners for an inhabitant of a northern state in
           the United States (especially a Union soldier)
     n 1: an American who lives in the North (especially during the
          American Civil War) [syn: {Yank}, {Northerner}]
     2: an American who lives in New England [syn: {New Englander},
        {Yank}]
     3: an American [syn: {Yank}, {Yankee-Doodle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
