<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>yard</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Yard \Yard\, n. [OE. yerd, AS. gierd, gyrd, a rod, stick, a
   measure, a yard; akin to OFries. ierde, OS. gerda, D. garde,
   G. gerte, OHG. gartia, gerta, gart, Icel. gaddr a goad,
   sting, Goth. gazds, and probably to L. hasta a spear. Cf.
   {Gad}, n., {Gird}, n., {Gride}, v. i., {Hastate}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A rod; a stick; a staff. [Obs.] --P. Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            If men smote it with a yerde.         --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A branch; a twig. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The bitter frosts with the sleet and rain
            Destroyed hath the green in every yerd. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A long piece of timber, as a rafter, etc. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A measure of length, equaling three feet, or thirty-six
      inches, being the standard of English and American
      measure.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The penis.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) A long piece of timber, nearly cylindrical,
      tapering toward the ends, and designed to support and
      extend a square sail. A yard is usually hung by the center
      to the mast. See Illust. of {Ship}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Zo["o]l.) A place where moose or deer herd together in
      winter for pasture, protection, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Golden Yard}, or {Yard and Ell} (Astron.), a popular name of
      the three stars in the belt of Orion.

   {Under yard} [i. e., under the rod], under contract. [Obs.]
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Yard \Yard\, v. t.
   To confine (cattle) to the yard; to shut up, or keep, in a
   yard; as, to yard cows.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Yard \Yard\, n. [OE. yard, yerd, AS. geard; akin to OFries.
   garda garden, OS. gardo garden, gard yard, D. gaard garden,
   G. garten, OHG. garto garden, gari inclosure, Icel. gar[eth]r
   yard, house, Sw. g[*a]rd, Dan. gaard, Goth. gards a house,
   garda sheepfold, L. hortus garden, Gr. cho`rtos an inclosure.
   Cf. {Court}, {Garden}, {Garth}, {Horticulture}, {Orchard}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. An inclosure; usually, a small inclosed place in front of,
      or around, a house or barn; as, a courtyard; a cowyard; a
      barnyard.
      [1913 Webster]

            A yard . . . inclosed all about with sticks
            In which she had a cock, hight chanticleer.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An inclosure within which any work or business is carried
      on; as, a dockyard; a shipyard.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Liberty of the yard}, a liberty, granted to persons
      imprisoned for debt, of walking in the yard, or within any
      other limits prescribed by law, on their giving bond not
      to go beyond those limits.

   {Prison yard}, an inclosure about a prison, or attached to
      it.

   {Yard grass} (Bot.), a low-growing grass ({Eleusine Indica})
      having digitate spikes. It is common in dooryards, and
      like places, especially in the Southern United States.
      Called also {crab grass}.

   {Yard of land}. See {Yardland}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>yard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>yard
     n 1: a unit of length equal to 3 feet; defined as 91.44
          centimeters; originally taken to be the average length
          of a stride [syn: {pace}]
     2: the enclosed land around a house or other building; "it was
        a small house with almost no yard" [syn: {grounds}, {curtilage}]
     3: a tract of land enclosed for particular activities
        (sometimes paved and usually associated with buildings);
        "they opened a repair yard on the edge of town"
     4: an area having a network of railway tracks and sidings for
        storage and maintenance of cars and engines [syn: {railway
        yard}]
     5: an enclosure for animals (as chicken or livestock)
     6: a unit of volume (as for sand or gravel) [syn: {cubic yard}]
     7: a long horizontal spar tapered at the end and used to
        support and spread a square sail or lateen
     8: the cardinal number that is the product of 10 and 100 [syn:
        {thousand}, {one thousand}, {1000}, {M}, {K}, {chiliad}, {G},
         {grand}, {thou}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
