<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>year</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>year</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>YEAR, n.  A period of three hundred and sixty-five disappointments.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>year</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Year
   Heb. shanah, meaning "repetition" or "revolution" (Gen. 1:14;
   5:3). Among the ancient Egyptians the year consisted of twelve
   months of thirty days each, with five days added to make it a
   complete revolution of the earth round the sun. The Jews
   reckoned the year in two ways, (1) according to a sacred
   calendar, in which the year began about the time of the vernal
   equinox, with the month Abib; and (2) according to a civil
   calendar, in which the year began about the time of the autumnal
   equinox, with the month Nisan. The month Tisri is now the
   beginning of the Jewish year.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>year</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sidereal \Si*de"re*al\, a. [L. sidereus, from sidus, sideris, a
   constellation, a star. Cf. {Sideral}, {Consider}, {Desire}.]
   1. Relating to the stars; starry; astral; as, sidereal
      astronomy.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Astron.) Measuring by the apparent motion of the stars;
      designated, marked out, or accompanied, by a return to the
      same position in respect to the stars; as, the sidereal
      revolution of a planet; a sidereal day.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Sidereal clock}, {day}, {month}, {year}. See under {Clock},
      {Day}, etc.

   {Sideral time}, time as reckoned by sideral days, or, taking
      the sidereal day as the unit, the time elapsed since a
      transit of the vernal equinox, reckoned in parts of a
      sidereal day. This is, strictly, apparent sidereal time,
      mean sidereal time being reckoned from the transit, not of
      the true, but of the mean, equinoctial point.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>year</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Year \Year\, n. [OE. yer, yeer, [yogh]er, AS. ge['a]r; akin to
   OFries. i?r, g?r, D. jaar, OHG. j[=a]r, G. jahr, Icel. [=a]r,
   Dan. aar, Sw. [*a]r, Goth. j?r, Gr. ? a season of the year,
   springtime, a part of the day, an hour, ? a year, Zend
   y[=a]re year. [root]4, 279. Cf. {Hour}, {Yore}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The time of the apparent revolution of the sun trough the
      ecliptic; the period occupied by the earth in making its
      revolution around the sun, called the astronomical year;
      also, a period more or less nearly agreeing with this,
      adopted by various nations as a measure of time, and
      called the civil year; as, the common lunar year of 354
      days, still in use among the Mohammedans; the year of 360
      days, etc. In common usage, the year consists of 365 days,
      and every fourth year (called bissextile, or leap year) of
      366 days, a day being added to February on that year, on
      account of the excess above 365 days (see {Bissextile}).
      [1913 Webster]

            Of twenty year of age he was, I guess. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The civil, or legal, year, in England, formerly
         commenced on the 25th of March. This practice continued
         throughout the British dominions till the year 1752.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The time in which any planet completes a revolution about
      the sun; as, the year of Jupiter or of Saturn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. Age, or old age; as, a man in years. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Anomalistic year}, the time of the earth's revolution from
      perihelion to perihelion again, which is 365 days, 6
      hours, 13 minutes, and 48 seconds.

   {A year's mind} (Eccl.), a commemoration of a deceased
      person, as by a Mass, a year after his death. Cf. {A
      month's mind}, under {Month}.

   {Bissextile year}. See {Bissextile}.

   {Canicular year}. See under {Canicular}.

   {Civil year}, the year adopted by any nation for the
      computation of time.

   {Common lunar year}, the period of 12 lunar months, or 354
      days.

   {Common year}, each year of 365 days, as distinguished from
      leap year.

   {Embolismic year}, or {Intercalary lunar year}, the period of
      13 lunar months, or 384 days.

   {Fiscal year} (Com.), the year by which accounts are
      reckoned, or the year between one annual time of
      settlement, or balancing of accounts, and another.

   {Great year}. See {Platonic year}, under {Platonic}.

   {Gregorian year}, {Julian year}. See under {Gregorian}, and
      {Julian}.

   {Leap year}. See {Leap year}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Lunar astronomical year}, the period of 12 lunar synodical
      months, or 354 days, 8 hours, 48 minutes, 36 seconds.

   {Lunisolar year}. See under {Lunisolar}.

   {Periodical year}. See {Anomalistic year}, above.

   {Platonic year}, {Sabbatical year}. See under {Platonic}, and
      {Sabbatical}.

   {Sidereal year}, the time in which the sun, departing from
      any fixed star, returns to the same. This is 365 days, 6
      hours, 9 minutes, and 9.3 seconds.

   {Tropical year}. See under {Tropical}.

   {Year and a day} (O. Eng. Law), a time to be allowed for an
      act or an event, in order that an entire year might be
      secured beyond all question. --Abbott.

   {Year of grace}, any year of the Christian era; Anno Domini;
      A. D. or a. d.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>year</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>year
     n 1: a period of time containing 365 (or 366) days; "she is 4
          years old"; "in the year 1920" [syn: {twelvemonth}, {yr}]
     2: a period of time occupying a regular part of a calendar year
        that is used for some particular activity; "a school year"
     3: the period of time that it takes for a planet (as, e.g.,
        Earth or Mars) to make a complete revolution around the
        sun; "a Martian year takes 687 of our days"
     4: a body of students who graduate together; "the class of
        '97"; "she was in my year at Hoehandle High" [syn: {class}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
