<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>w</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>w</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Labial \La"bi*al\, n.
   1. (Phonetics) A letter or character representing an
      articulation or sound formed or uttered chiefly with the
      lips, as {b}, {p}, {w}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mus.) An organ pipe that is furnished with lips; a flue
      pipe.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) One of the scales which border the mouth of a
      fish or reptile.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>w</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>W \W\ (d[u^]b"'l [=u]),
   the twenty-third letter of the English alphabet, is usually a
   consonant, but sometimes it is a vowel, forming the second
   element of certain diphthongs, as in few, how. It takes its
   written form and its name from the repetition of a V, this
   being the original form of the Roman capital letter which we
   call U. Etymologically it is most related to v and u. See V,
   and U. Some of the uneducated classes in England, especially
   in London, confuse w and v, substituting the one for the
   other, as weal for veal, and veal for weal; wine for vine,
   and vine for wine, etc. See Guide to Pronunciation,
   [sect][sect] 266-268.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>w</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>W
     n 1: a heavy gray-white metallic element; the pure form is used
          mainly in electrical applications; it is found in
          several ores including wolframite and scheelite [syn: {tungsten},
           {wolfram}, {atomic number 74}]
     2: the cardinal compass point that is a 270 degrees [syn: {west},
         {due west}]
     3: a unit of power equal to 1 joule per second; the power
        dissipated by a current of 1 ampere flowing across a
        resistance of 1 ohm [syn: {watt}]
     4: the 23rd letter of the Roman alphabet [syn: {double-u}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
