<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wake</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wake, VA
  Zip code(s): 23176
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wake \Wake\, n. [Originally, an open space of water s?rrounded
   by ice, and then, the passage cut through ice for a vessel,
   probably of Scand. origin; cf. Icel. v["o]k a hole, opening
   in ice, Sw. vak, Dan. vaage, perhaps akin to E. humid.]
   The track left by a vessel in the water; by extension, any
   track; as, the wake of an army.
   [1913 Webster]

         This effect followed immediately in the wake of his
         earliest exertions.                      --De Quincey.
   [1913 Webster]

         Several humbler persons . . . formed quite a procession
         in the dusty wake of his chariot wheels. --Thackeray.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wake \Wake\, v. t.
   1. To rouse from sleep; to awake.
      [1913 Webster]

            The angel . . . came again and waked me. --Zech. iv.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put in motion or action; to arouse; to excite. ``I
      shall waken all this company.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lest fierce remembrance wake my sudden rage.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Even Richard's crusade woke little interest in his
            island realm.                         --J. R. Green.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bring to life again, as if from the sleep of death; to
      reanimate; to revive.
      [1913 Webster]

            To second life
            Waked in the renovation of the just.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To watch, or sit up with, at night, as a dead body.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wake \Wake\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Waked}or {Woke} (?); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Waking}.] [AS. wacan, wacian; akin to OFries. waka,
   OS. wak?n, D. waken, G. wachen, OHG. wahh?n, Icel. vaka, Sw.
   vaken, Dan. vaage, Goth. wakan, v. i., uswakjan, v. t., Skr.
   v[=a]jay to rouse, to impel. ????. Cf. {Vigil}, {Wait}, v.
   i., {Watch}, v. i.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To be or to continue awake; to watch; not to sleep.
      [1913 Webster]

            The father waketh for the daughter.   --Ecclus.
                                                  xlii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though wisdom wake, suspicion sleeps. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            I can not think any time, waking or sleeping,
            without being sensible of it.         --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To sit up late festive purposes; to hold a night revel.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king doth wake to-night, and takes his rouse,
            Keeps wassail, and the swaggering upspring reels.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be excited or roused from sleep; to awake; to be
      awakened; to cease to sleep; -- often with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            He infallibly woke up at the sound of the concluding
            doxology.                             --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be exited or roused up; to be stirred up from a
      dormant, torpid, or inactive state; to be active.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gentle airs due at their hour
            To fan the earth now waked.           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then wake, my soul, to high desires.  --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wake \Wake\, n.
   1. The act of waking, or being awaked; also, the state of
      being awake. [Obs. or Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Making such difference 'twixt wake and sleep.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Singing her flatteries to my morning wake. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of forbearing sleep, especially for solemn or
      festive purposes; a vigil.
      [1913 Webster]

            The warlike wakes continued all the night,
            And funeral games played at new returning light.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wood nymphs, decked with daises trim,
            Their merry wakes and pastimes keep.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically:
      (a) (Ch. of Eng.) An annual parish festival formerly held
          in commemoration of the dedication of a church.
          Originally, prayers were said on the evening
          preceding, and hymns were sung during the night, in
          the church; subsequently, these vigils were
          discontinued, and the day itself, often with
          succeeding days, was occupied in rural pastimes and
          exercises, attended by eating and drinking, often to
          excess.
          [1913 Webster]

                Great solemnities were made in all churches, and
                great fairs and wakes throughout all England.
                                                  --Ld. Berners.
          [1913 Webster]

                And every village smokes at wakes with lusty
                cheer.                            --Drayton.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) The sitting up of persons with a dead body, often
          attended with a degree of festivity, chiefly among the
          Irish. ``Blithe as shepherd at a wake.'' --Cowper.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Wake play}, the ceremonies and pastimes connected with a
      wake. See {Wake}, n., 3
      (b), above. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wake
     n 1: the consequences of an event (especially a catastrophic
          event); "the aftermath of war"; "in the wake of the
          accident no one knew how many had been injured" [syn: {aftermath},
           {backwash}]
     2: an island in the western Pacific between Guam and Hawaii
        [syn: {Wake Island}]
     3: the wave that spreads behind a boat as it moves forward;
        "the motorboat's wake capsized the canoe" [syn: {backwash}]
     4: a vigil held over a corpse the night before burial; "there's
        no weeping at an Irish wake" [syn: {viewing}]
     v 1: be awake, be alert, be there [ant: {sleep}]
     2: stop sleeping; "She woke up to the sound of the alarm clock"
        [syn: {wake up}, {awake}, {arouse}, {awaken}, {come alive},
         {waken}] [ant: {fall asleep}]
     3: arouse or excite feelings and passions; "The ostentatious
        way of living of the rich ignites the hatred of the poor";
        "The refugees' fate stirred up compassion around the
        world"; "Wake old feelings of hatred" [syn: {inflame}, {stir
        up}, {ignite}, {heat}, {fire up}]
     4: make aware of; "His words woke us to terrible facts of the
        situation"
     5: cause to become awake or conscious; "He was roused by the
        drunken men in the street"; "Please wake me at 6 AM."
        [syn: {awaken}, {waken}, {rouse}, {wake up}, {arouse}]
        [ant: {cause to sleep}]
     [also: {woken}, {woke}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
