<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>walking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Walk \Walk\ (w[add]k), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Walked}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Walking}.] [OE. walken, probably from AS. wealcan to
   roll, turn, revolve, akin to D. walken to felt hats, to work
   a hat, G. walken to full, OHG. walchan to beat, to full,
   Icel. v[=a]lka to roll, to stamp, Sw. valka to full, to roll,
   Dan. valke to full; cf. Skr. valg to spring; but cf. also AS.
   weallian to roam, ramble, G. wallen. [root]130.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To move along on foot; to advance by steps; to go on at a
      moderate pace; specifically, of two-legged creatures, to
      proceed at a slower or faster rate, but without running,
      or lifting one foot entirely before the other touches the
      ground.
      [1913 Webster]

            At the end of twelve months, he walked in the palace
            of the kingdom of Babylon.            --Dan. iv. 29.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Peter was come down out of the ship, he walked
            on the water, to go to Jesus.         --Matt. xiv.
                                                  29.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the walk of quadrupeds, there are always two, and
         for a brief space there are three, feet on the ground
         at once, but never four.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To move or go on the feet for exercise or amusement; to
      take one's exercise; to ramble.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be stirring; to be abroad; to go restlessly about; --
      said of things or persons expected to remain quiet, as a
      sleeping person, or the spirit of a dead person; to go
      about as a somnambulist or a specter.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have heard, but not believed, the spirits of the
            dead
            May walk again.                       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            When was it she last walked?          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be in motion; to act; to move; to wag. [Obs.] ``Her
      tongue did walk in foul reproach.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Do you think I'd walk in any plot?    --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

            I heard a pen walking in the chimney behind the
            cloth.                                --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To behave; to pursue a course of life; to conduct one's
      self.
      [1913 Webster]

            We walk perversely with God, and he will walk
            crookedly toward us.                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To move off; to depart. [Obs. or Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He will make their cows and garrans to walk.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To walk} in, to go in; to enter, as into a house.

   {To walk after the flesh} (Script.), to indulge sensual
      appetites, and to live in sin. --Rom. viii. 1.

   {To walk after the Spirit} (Script.), to be guided by the
      counsels and influences of the Spirit, and by the word of
      God. --Rom. viii. 1.

   {To walk by faith} (Script.), to live in the firm belief of
      the gospel and its promises, and to rely on Christ for
      salvation. --2 Cor. v. 7.

   {To walk in darkness} (Script.), to live in ignorance, error,
      and sin. --1 John i. 6.

   {To walk in the flesh} (Script.), to live this natural life,
      which is subject to infirmities and calamities. --2 Cor.
      x. 3.

   {To walk in the light} (Script.), to live in the practice of
      religion, and to enjoy its consolations. --1 John i. 7.

   {To walk over}, in racing, to go over a course at a walk; --
      said of a horse when there is no other entry; hence,
      colloquially, to gain an easy victory in any contest.

   {To walk through the fire} (Script.), to be exercised with
      severe afflictions. --Isa. xliii. 2.

   {To walk with God} (Script.), to live in obedience to his
      commands, and have communion with him.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Walking \Walk"ing\,
   a. &amp; n. from {Walk}, v.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Walking beam}. See {Beam}, 10.

   {Walking crane}, a kind of traveling crane. See under
      {Crane}.

   {Walking fern}. (Bot.) See {Walking leaf}, below.

   {Walking fish} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      Asiatic fishes of the genus {Ophiocephalus}, some of
      which, as {Ophiocephalus marulius}, become over four feet
      long. They have a special cavity over the gills lined with
      a membrane adapted to retain moisture to aid in
      respiration, and are thus able to travel considerable
      distances over the land at night, whence the name. They
      construct a curious nest for their young. Called also
      {langya}.

   {Walking gentleman} (Theater), an actor who usually fills
      subordinate parts which require a gentlemanly appearance
      but few words. [Cant]

   {Walking lady} (Theater), an actress who usually fills such
      parts as require only a ladylike appearance on the stage.
      [Cant]

   {Walking leaf}.
   (a) (Bot.) A little American fern ({Camptosorus
       rhizophyllus}); -- so called because the fronds taper
       into slender prolongations which often root at the apex,
       thus producing new plants.
   (b) (Zo["o]l.) A leaf insect. See under {Leaf}.

   {Walking papers}, or {Walking ticket}, an order to leave;
      dismissal, as from office; as, to get one's walking
      papers, i. e. to be dismissed or fired. [Colloq.]
      --Bartlett.

   {Walking stick}.
   (a) A stick or staff carried in the hand for hand for support
       or amusement when walking; a cane.
   (b) (Zo["o]l.) A stick insect; -- called also {walking
       straw}. See Illust. of {Stick insect}, under {Stick}.

   {Walking wheel} (Mach.), a prime mover consisting of a wheel
      driven by the weight of men or animals walking either in
      it or on it; a treadwheel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>walking
     adj : close enough to be walked to; "walking distance"; "the
           factory with the big parking lot...is more convenient
           than the walk-to factory" [syn: {walk-to(a)}, {walking(a)}]
     n : the act of traveling by foot; "walking is a healthy form of
         exercise" [syn: {walk}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
