<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>walk</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>walk
     
        &lt;programming&gt; To Traverse a data structure, especially an
        {array} or {linked-list} in {core}.
     
        See also {codewalker}, {silly walk}, {clobber}.
     
        (2001-04-12)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Walk \Walk\ (w[add]k), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Walked}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Walking}.] [OE. walken, probably from AS. wealcan to
   roll, turn, revolve, akin to D. walken to felt hats, to work
   a hat, G. walken to full, OHG. walchan to beat, to full,
   Icel. v[=a]lka to roll, to stamp, Sw. valka to full, to roll,
   Dan. valke to full; cf. Skr. valg to spring; but cf. also AS.
   weallian to roam, ramble, G. wallen. [root]130.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To move along on foot; to advance by steps; to go on at a
      moderate pace; specifically, of two-legged creatures, to
      proceed at a slower or faster rate, but without running,
      or lifting one foot entirely before the other touches the
      ground.
      [1913 Webster]

            At the end of twelve months, he walked in the palace
            of the kingdom of Babylon.            --Dan. iv. 29.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Peter was come down out of the ship, he walked
            on the water, to go to Jesus.         --Matt. xiv.
                                                  29.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the walk of quadrupeds, there are always two, and
         for a brief space there are three, feet on the ground
         at once, but never four.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To move or go on the feet for exercise or amusement; to
      take one's exercise; to ramble.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be stirring; to be abroad; to go restlessly about; --
      said of things or persons expected to remain quiet, as a
      sleeping person, or the spirit of a dead person; to go
      about as a somnambulist or a specter.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have heard, but not believed, the spirits of the
            dead
            May walk again.                       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            When was it she last walked?          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be in motion; to act; to move; to wag. [Obs.] ``Her
      tongue did walk in foul reproach.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Do you think I'd walk in any plot?    --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

            I heard a pen walking in the chimney behind the
            cloth.                                --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To behave; to pursue a course of life; to conduct one's
      self.
      [1913 Webster]

            We walk perversely with God, and he will walk
            crookedly toward us.                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To move off; to depart. [Obs. or Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He will make their cows and garrans to walk.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To walk} in, to go in; to enter, as into a house.

   {To walk after the flesh} (Script.), to indulge sensual
      appetites, and to live in sin. --Rom. viii. 1.

   {To walk after the Spirit} (Script.), to be guided by the
      counsels and influences of the Spirit, and by the word of
      God. --Rom. viii. 1.

   {To walk by faith} (Script.), to live in the firm belief of
      the gospel and its promises, and to rely on Christ for
      salvation. --2 Cor. v. 7.

   {To walk in darkness} (Script.), to live in ignorance, error,
      and sin. --1 John i. 6.

   {To walk in the flesh} (Script.), to live this natural life,
      which is subject to infirmities and calamities. --2 Cor.
      x. 3.

   {To walk in the light} (Script.), to live in the practice of
      religion, and to enjoy its consolations. --1 John i. 7.

   {To walk over}, in racing, to go over a course at a walk; --
      said of a horse when there is no other entry; hence,
      colloquially, to gain an easy victory in any contest.

   {To walk through the fire} (Script.), to be exercised with
      severe afflictions. --Isa. xliii. 2.

   {To walk with God} (Script.), to live in obedience to his
      commands, and have communion with him.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Walk \Walk\, v. t.
   1. To pass through, over, or upon; to traverse; to
      perambulate; as, to walk the streets.
      [1913 Webster]

            As we walk our earthly round.         --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to walk; to lead, drive, or ride with a slow
      pace; as, to walk one's horses; to walk the dog. `` I will
      rather trust . . . a thief to walk my ambling gelding.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. [AS. wealcan to roll. See {Walk} to move on foot.] To
      subject, as cloth or yarn, to the fulling process; to
      full. [Obs. or Scot.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Sporting) To put or keep (a puppy) in a walk; to train
      (puppies) in a walk. [Cant]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   5. To move in a manner likened to walking. [Colloq.]

            She walked a spinning wheel into the house, making
            it use first one and then the other of its own
            spindling legs to achieve progression rather than
            lifting it by main force.             --C. E.
                                                  Craddock.

   {To walk one's chalks}, to make off; take French leave.

   {To walk the plank}, to walk off the plank into the water and
      be drowned; -- an expression derived from the practice of
      pirates who extended a plank from the side of a ship, and
      compelled those whom they would drown to walk off into the
      water; figuratively, to vacate an office by compulsion.
      --Bartlett.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Walk \Walk\, n.
   1. The act of walking, or moving on the feet with a slow
      pace; advance without running or leaping.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of walking for recreation or exercise; as, a
      morning walk; an evening walk.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Manner of walking; gait; step; as, we often know a person
      at a distance by his walk.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That in or through which one walks; place or distance
      walked over; a place for walking; a path or avenue
      prepared for foot passengers, or for taking air and
      exercise; way; road; hence, a place or region in which
      animals may graze; place of wandering; range; as, a sheep
      walk.
      [1913 Webster]

            A woody mountain . . . with goodliest trees
            Planted, with walks and bowers.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had walk for a hundred sheep.      --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Amid the sound of steps that beat
            The murmuring walks like rain.        --Bryant.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A frequented track; habitual place of action; sphere; as,
      the walk of the historian.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mountains are his walks.          --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

            He opened a boundless walk for his imagination.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Conduct; course of action; behavior.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The route or district regularly served by a vender; as, a
      milkman's walk. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   8. In coffee, coconut, and other plantations, the space
      between them.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Sporting)
      (a) A place for keeping and training puppies.
      (b) An inclosed area of some extent to which a gamecock is
          confined to prepare him for fighting.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Arm \Arm\, n. [AS. arm, earm; akin to OHG. aram, G., D., Dan., &amp;
   Sw. arm, Icel. armr, Goth. arms, L. armus arm, shoulder, and
   prob. to Gr. ? joining, joint, shoulder, fr. the root ? to
   join, to fit together; cf. Slav. rame. ?. See {Art},
   {Article}.]
   1. The limb of the human body which extends from the shoulder
      to the hand; also, the corresponding limb of a monkey.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything resembling an arm; as,
      (a) The fore limb of an animal, as of a bear.
      (b) A limb, or locomotive or prehensile organ, of an
          invertebrate animal.
      (c) A branch of a tree.
      (d) A slender part of an instrument or machine, projecting
          from a trunk, axis, or fulcrum; as, the arm of a
          steelyard.
      (e) (Naut) The end of a yard; also, the part of an anchor
          which ends in the fluke.
      (f) An inlet of water from the sea.
      (g) A support for the elbow, at the side of a chair, the
          end of a sofa, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Fig.: Power; might; strength; support; as, the secular
      arm; the arm of the law.
      [1913 Webster]

            To whom is the arm of the Lord revealed? --Isa. lii.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Arm's end}, the end of the arm; a good distance off.
      --Dryden.

   {Arm's length}, the length of the arm.

   {Arm's reach}, reach of the arm; the distance the arm can
      reach.

   {To go} (or {walk}) {arm in arm}, to go with the arm or hand
      of one linked in the arm of another. ``When arm in armwe
      went along.'' --Tennyson.

   {To keep at arm's length}, to keep at a distance (literally
      or figuratively); not to allow to come into close contact
      or familiar intercourse.

   {To work at arm's length}, to work disadvantageously.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>walk n.,vt. Traversal of a data structure, especially an array or
   linked-list data structure in {core}. See also {codewalker}, {silly
   walk}, {clobber}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>walk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>walk
     n 1: the act of traveling by foot; "walking is a healthy form of
          exercise" [syn: {walking}]
     2: (baseball) an advance to first base by a batter who receives
        four balls; "he worked the pitcher for a base on balls"
        [syn: {base on balls}, {pass}]
     3: manner of walking; "he had a funny walk" [syn: {manner of
        walking}]
     4: the act of walking somewhere; "he took a walk after lunch"
     5: a path set aside for walking; "after the blizzard he
        shoveled the front walk" [syn: {walkway}, {paseo}]
     6: a slow gait of a horse in which two feet are always on the
        ground
     7: careers in general; "it happens in all walks of life" [syn:
        {walk of life}]
     v 1: use one's feet to advance; advance by steps; "Walk, don't
          run!"; "We walked instead of driving"; "She walks with a
          slight limp"; "The patient cannot walk yet"; "Walk over
          to the cabinet" [ant: {ride}]
     2: traverse or cover by walking; "Walk the tightrope"; "Paul
        walked the streets of Damascus"; "She walks 3 miles every
        day"
     3: accompany or escort; "I'll walk you to your car"
     4: obtain a base on balls
     5: live or behave in a specified manner; "walk in sadness"
     6: take a walk; go for a walk; walk for pleasure; "The lovers
        held hands while walking"; "We like to walk every Sunday"
        [syn: {take the air}]
     7: give a base on balls to
     8: be or act in association with; "We must walk with our
        dispossessed brothers and sisters"; "Walk with God"
     9: make walk; "He walks the horse up the mountain"; "Walk the
        dog twice a day"
     10: walk at a pace; "The horsese walked across the meadow"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
