<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wallpaper</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wallpaper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wallpaper
     
        1. A file containing a listing (e.g. assembly listing) or a
        transcript, especially a file containing a transcript of all
        or part of a login session.  (The idea was that the paper for
        such listings was essentially good only for wallpaper, as
        evidenced at {Stanford}, where it was used to cover windows).
     
        The term is now rare, especially since other systems have
        developed other terms for it (e.g. PHOTO on {TWENEX}).
        However, the {Unix} world doesn't have an equivalent term, so
        perhaps wallpaper will take hold there.  The term probably
        originated on {ITS}, where the commands to begin and end
        transcript files were ":WALBEG" and ":WALEND", with default
        file "WALL PAPER" (the space was a path delimiter).
     
        2. The background pattern used on graphical workstations under
        the {Microsoft Windows} {graphical user interface} to
        {MS-DOS}.
     
        (1994-12-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wallpaper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paper \Pa"per\ (p[=a]"p[~e]r), n. [F. papier, fr. L. papyrus
   papyrus, from which the Egyptians made a kind of paper, Gr.
   pa`pyros. Cf. {Papyrus}.]
   1. A substance in the form of thin sheets or leaves intended
      to be written or printed on, or to be used in wrapping. It
      is made of rags, straw, bark, wood, or other fibrous
      material, which is first reduced to pulp, then molded,
      pressed, and dried.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A sheet, leaf, or piece of such substance.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A printed or written instrument; a document, essay, or the
      like; a writing; as, a paper read before a scientific
      society.
      [1913 Webster]

            They brought a paper to me to be signed. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A printed sheet appearing periodically; a newspaper; a
      journal; as, a daily paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Negotiable evidences of indebtedness; notes; bills of
      exchange, and the like; as, the bank holds a large amount
      of his paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Decorated hangings or coverings for walls, made of paper.
      See {Paper hangings}, below.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A paper containing (usually) a definite quantity; as, a
      paper of pins, tacks, opium, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A medicinal preparation spread upon paper, intended for
      external application; as, cantharides paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. pl. Documents establishing a person's identity, or status,
      or attesting to some right, such as the right to drive a
      vehicle; as, the border guard asked for his papers.
      [PJC]

   Note: Paper is manufactured in sheets, the trade names of
         which, together with the regular sizes in inches, are
         shown in the following table. But paper makers vary the
         size somewhat.
         [1913 Webster]
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the manufacture of books, etc., a sheet, of whatever
         size originally, is termed, when folded once, a folio;
         folded twice, a quarto, or 4to; three times, an octavo,
         or 8vo; four times, a sextodecimo, or 16mo; five times,
         a 32mo; three times, with an offcut folded twice and
         set in, a duodecimo, or 12mo; four times, with an
         offcut folded three times and set in, a 24mo.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: Paper is often used adjectively or in combination,
         having commonly an obvious signification; as, paper
         cutter or paper-cutter; paper knife, paper-knife, or
         paperknife; paper maker, paper-maker, or papermaker;
         paper mill or paper-mill; paper weight, paper-weight,
         or paperweight, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Business paper}, checks, notes, drafts, etc., given in
      payment of actual indebtedness; -- opposed to
      accommodation paper.

   {Fly paper}, paper covered with a sticky preparation, -- used
      for catching flies.

   {Laid paper}. See under {Laid}.

   {Paper birch} (Bot.), the canoe birch tree ({Betula
      papyracea}).

   {Paper blockade}, an ineffective blockade, as by a weak naval
      force.

   {Paper boat} (Naut.), a boat made of water-proof paper.

   {Paper car wheel} (Railroad), a car wheel having a steel
      tire, and a center formed of compressed paper held between
      two plate-iron disks. --Forney.

   {Paper credit}, credit founded upon evidences of debt, such
      as promissory notes, duebills, etc.

   {Paper hanger}, one who covers walls with paper hangings.

   {Paper hangings}, paper printed with colored figures, or
      otherwise made ornamental, prepared to be pasted against
      the walls of apartments, etc.; wall paper.

   {Paper house}, an audience composed of people who have come
      in on free passes. [Cant]

   {Paper money}, notes or bills, usually issued by government
      or by a banking corporation, promising payment of money,
      and circulated as the representative of coin.

   {Paper mulberry}. (Bot.) See under Mulberry.

   {Paper muslin}, glazed muslin, used for linings, etc.

   {Paper nautilus}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Argonauta}.

   {Paper reed} (Bot.), the papyrus.

   {Paper sailor}. (Zo["o]l.) See Argonauta.

   {Paper stainer}, one who colors or stamps wall paper. --De
      Colange.

   {Paper wasp} (Zo["o]l.), any wasp which makes a nest of
      paperlike material, as the yellow jacket.

   {Paper weight}, any object used as a weight to prevent loose
      papers from being displaced by wind, or otherwise.

   {on paper}.
      (a) in writing; as, I would like to see that on paper.
      (b) in theory, though not necessarily in paractice.
      (c) in the design state; planned, but not yet put into
          practice.

   {Parchment paper}. See {Papyrine}.

   {Tissue paper}, thin, gauzelike paper, such as is used to
      protect engravings in books.

   {Wall paper}. Same as {Paper hangings}, above.

   {Waste paper}, paper thrown aside as worthless or useless,
      except for uses of little account.

   {Wove paper}, a writing paper with a uniform surface, not
      ribbed or watermarked.

   {paper tiger}, a person or group that appears to be powerful
      and dangerous but is in fact weak and ineffectual.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wallpaper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wall \Wall\, n. [AS. weall, from L. vallum a wall, vallus a
   stake, pale, palisade; akin to Gr. ? a nail. Cf. {Interval}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A work or structure of stone, brick, or other materials,
      raised to some height, and intended for defense or
      security, solid and permanent inclosing fence, as around a
      field, a park, a town, etc., also, one of the upright
      inclosing parts of a building or a room.
      [1913 Webster]

            The plaster of the wall of the King's palace. --Dan.
                                                  v. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A defense; a rampart; a means of protection; in the
      plural, fortifications, in general; works for defense.
      [1913 Webster]

            The waters were a wall unto them on their right
            hand, and on their left.              --Ex. xiv. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

            In such a night,
            Troilus, methinks, mounted the Troyan walls. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To rush undaunted to defend the walls. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An inclosing part of a receptacle or vessel; as, the walls
      of a steam-engine cylinder.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mining)
      (a) The side of a level or drift.
      (b) The country rock bounding a vein laterally. --Raymond.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Wall is often used adjectively, and also in the
         formation of compounds, usually of obvious
         signification; as in wall paper, or wall-paper; wall
         fruit, or wall-fruit; wallflower, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Blank wall}, Blind wall, etc. See under {Blank}, {Blind},
      etc.

   {To drive to the wall}, to bring to extremities; to push to
      extremes; to get the advantage of, or mastery over.

   {To go to the wall}, to be hard pressed or driven; to be the
      weaker party; to be pushed to extremes.

   {To take the wall}. to take the inner side of a walk, that
      is, the side next the wall; hence, to take the precedence.
      ``I will take the wall of any man or maid of Montague's.''
      --Shak.

   {Wall barley} (Bot.), a kind of grass ({Hordeum murinum})
      much resembling barley; squirrel grass. See under
      {Squirrel}.

   {Wall box}. (Mach.) See {Wall frame}, below.

   {Wall creeper} (Zo["o]l.), a small bright-colored bird
      ({Tichodroma muraria}) native of Asia and Southern Europe.
      It climbs about over old walls and cliffs in search of
      insects and spiders. Its body is ash-gray above, the wing
      coverts are carmine-red, the primary quills are mostly red
      at the base and black distally, some of them with white
      spots, and the tail is blackish. Called also {spider
      catcher}.

   {Wall cress} (Bot.), a name given to several low cruciferous
      herbs, especially to the mouse-ear cress. See under
      {Mouse-ear}.

   {Wall frame} (Mach.), a frame set in a wall to receive a
      pillow block or bearing for a shaft passing through the
      wall; -- called also {wall box}.

   {Wall fruit}, fruit borne by trees trained against a wall.

   {Wall gecko} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of Old
      World geckos which live in or about buildings and run over
      the vertical surfaces of walls, to which they cling by
      means of suckers on the feet.

   {Wall lizard} (Zo["o]l.), a common European lizard ({Lacerta
      muralis}) which frequents houses, and lives in the chinks
      and crevices of walls; -- called also {wall newt}.

   {Wall louse}, a wood louse.

   {Wall moss} (Bot.), any species of moss growing on walls.

   {Wall newt} (Zo["o]l.), the wall lizard. --Shak.

   {Wall paper}, paper for covering the walls of rooms; paper
      hangings.

   {Wall pellitory} (Bot.), a European plant ({Parictaria
      officinalis}) growing on old walls, and formerly esteemed
      medicinal.

   {Wall pennywort} (Bot.), a plant ({Cotyledon Umbilicus})
      having rounded fleshy leaves. It is found on walls in
      Western Europe.

   {Wall pepper} (Bot.), a low mosslike plant ({Sedum acre})
      with small fleshy leaves having a pungent taste and
      bearing yellow flowers. It is common on walls and rocks in
      Europe, and is sometimes seen in America.

   {Wall pie} (Bot.), a kind of fern; wall rue.

   {Wall piece}, a gun planted on a wall. --H. L. Scott.

   {Wall plate} (Arch.), a piece of timber placed horizontally
      upon a wall, and supporting posts, joists, and the like.
      See Illust. of {Roof}.

   {Wall rock}, granular limestone used in building walls. [U.
      S.] --Bartlett.

   {Wall rue} (Bot.), a species of small fern ({Asplenium
      Ruta-muraria}) growing on walls, rocks, and the like.

   {Wall spring}, a spring of water issuing from stratified
      rocks.

   {Wall tent}, a tent with upright cloth sides corresponding to
      the walls of a house.

   {Wall wasp} (Zo["o]l.), a common European solitary wasp
      ({Odynerus parietus}) which makes its nest in the crevices
      of walls.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wallpaper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wallpaper n. 1. A file containing a listing (e.g., assembly listing) or
   a transcript, esp. a file containing a transcript of all or part of a
   login session. (The idea was that the paper for such listings was
   essentially good only for wallpaper, as evidenced at Stanford, where it
   was used to cover windows.) Now rare, esp. since other systems have
   developed other terms for it (e.g., PHOTO on TWENEX). However, the Unix
   world doesn't have an equivalent term, so perhaps {wallpaper} will take
   hold there. The term probably originated on ITS, where the commands to
   begin and end transcript files were `:WALBEG' and `:WALEND', with
   default file `WALL PAPER' (the space was a path delimiter). 2. The
   background pattern used on graphical workstations (this is techspeak
   under the `Windows' graphical user interface to MS-DOS). 3. `wallpaper
   file' n. The file that contains the wallpaper information before it is
   actually printed on paper. (Even if you don't intend ever to produce a
   real paper copy of the file, it is still called a wallpaper file.)


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wallpaper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wallpaper
     n : a decorative paper for the walls of rooms
     v : cover with wallpaper [syn: {paper}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
