<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>war</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>WAR, n.  A by-product of the arts of peace.  The most menacing
political condition is a period of international amity.  The student
of history who has not been taught to expect the unexpected may justly
boast himself inaccessible to the light.  "In time of peace prepare
for war" has a deeper meaning than is commonly discerned; it means,
not merely that all things earthly have an end -- that change is the
one immutable and eternal law -- but that the soil of peace is thickly
sown with the seeds of war and singularly suited to their germination
and growth.  It was when Kubla Khan had decreed his "stately pleasure
dome" -- when, that is to say, there were peace and fat feasting in
Xanadu -- that he

                        heard from afar
    Ancestral voices prophesying war.

    One of the greatest of poets, Coleridge was one of the wisest of
men, and it was not for nothing that he read us this parable.  Let us
have a little less of "hands across the sea," and a little more of
that elemental distrust that is the security of nations.  War loves to
come like a thief in the night; professions of eternal amity provide
the night.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>War
   The Israelites had to take possession of the Promised Land by
   conquest. They had to engage in a long and bloody war before the
   Canaanitish tribes were finally subdued. Except in the case of
   Jericho and Ai, the war did not become aggressive till after the
   death of Joshua. Till then the attack was always first made by
   the Canaanites. Now the measure of the iniquity of the
   Canaanites was full, and Israel was employed by God to sweep
   them away from off the face of the earth. In entering on this
   new stage of the war, the tribe of Judah, according to divine
   direction, took the lead.
   
     In the days of Saul and David the people of Israel engaged in
   many wars with the nations around, and after the division of the
   kingdom into two they often warred with each other. They had to
   defend themselves also against the inroads of the Egyptians, the
   Assyrians, and the Babylonians. The whole history of Israel from
   first to last presents but few periods of peace.
   
     The Christian life is represented as a warfare, and the
   Christian graces are also represented under the figure of pieces
   of armour (Eph. 6:11-17; 1 Thess. 5:8; 2 Tim. 2:3, 4). The final
   blessedness of believers is attained as the fruit of victory
   (Rev. 3:21).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>War, WV (city, FIPS 84484)
  Location: 37.30277 N, 81.68008 W
  Population (1990): 1081 (525 housing units)
  Area: 2.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>War \War\, a.
   Ware; aware. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>War \War\, n. [OE. &amp; AS. werre; akin to OHG. werra scandal,
   quarrel, sedition, werran to confound, mix, D. warren, G.
   wirren, verwirren, to embroil, confound, disturb, and perhaps
   to E. worse; cf. OF. werre war, F. querre, of Teutonic
   origin. Cf. {Guerrilla}, {Warrior}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A contest between nations or states, carried on by force,
      whether for defence, for revenging insults and redressing
      wrongs, for the extension of commerce, for the acquisition
      of territory, for obtaining and establishing the
      superiority and dominion of one over the other, or for any
      other purpose; armed conflict of sovereign powers;
      declared and open hostilities.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men will ever distinguish war from mere bloodshed.
                                                  --F. W.
                                                  Robertson.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: As war is the contest of nations or states, it always
         implies that such contest is authorized by the monarch
         or the sovereign power of the nation. A war begun by
         attacking another nation, is called an offensive war,
         and such attack is aggressive. War undertaken to repel
         invasion, or the attacks of an enemy, is called
         defensive.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) A condition of belligerency to be maintained by
      physical force. In this sense, levying war against the
      sovereign authority is treason.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Instruments of war. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            His complement of stores, and total war. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Forces; army. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            On their embattled ranks the waves return,
            And overwhelm their war.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The profession of arms; the art of war.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou art but a youth, and he is a man of war from
            his youth.                            --1 Sam. xvii.
                                                  33.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. a state of opposition or contest; an act of opposition; an
      inimical contest, act, or action; enmity; hostility.
      ``Raised impious war in heaven.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The words of his mouth were smoother than butter,
            but war was in his heart.             --Ps. lv. 21.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Civil war}, a war between different sections or parties of
      the same country or nation.

   {Holy war}. See under {Holy}.

   {Man of war}. (Naut.) See in the Vocabulary.

   {Public war}, a war between independent sovereign states.

   {War cry}, a cry or signal used in war; as, the Indian war
      cry.

   {War dance}, a dance among savages preliminary to going to
      war. Among the North American Indians, it is begun by some
      distinguished chief, and whoever joins in it thereby
      enlists as one of the party engaged in a warlike
      excursion. --Schoolcraft.

   {War field}, a field of war or battle.

   {War horse}, a horse used in war; the horse of a cavalry
      soldier; especially, a strong, powerful, spirited horse
      for military service; a charger.

   {War paint}, paint put on the face and other parts of the
      body by savages, as a token of going to war. ``Wash the
      war paint from your faces.'' --Longfellow.

   {War song}, a song of or pertaining to war; especially, among
      the American Indians, a song at the war dance, full of
      incitements to military ardor.

   {War whoop}, a war cry, especially that uttered by the
      American Indians.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>War \War\, v. t.
   1. To make war upon; to fight. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To war the Scot, and borders to defend. --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To carry on, as a contest; to wage. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            That thou . . . mightest war a good warfare. --Tim.
                                                  i. 18.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>War \War\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Warred}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Warring}.]
   1. To make war; to invade or attack a state or nation with
      force of arms; to carry on hostilities; to be in a state
      by violence.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rezin the king of Syria, and Pekah the son of
            Remaliah, king of Israel, went up toward Jerusalem
            to war against it.                    --Isa. vii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Why should I war without the walls of Troy? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our countrymen were warring on that day! --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To contend; to strive violently; to fight. ``Lusts which
      war against the soul.'' --1 Pet. ii. 11.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>war</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>war
     n 1: the waging of armed conflict against an enemy; "thousands of
          people were killed in the war" [syn: {warfare}]
     2: a legal state created by a declaration of war and ended by
        official declaration during which the international rules
        of war apply; "war was declared in November but actual
        fighting did not begin until the following spring" [syn: {state
        of war}] [ant: {peace}]
     3: an active struggle between competing entities; "a price
        war"; "a war of wits"; "diplomatic warfare" [syn: {warfare}]
     4: a concerted campaign to end something that is injurious;
        "the war on poverty"; "the war against crime"
     v : make or wage war [ant: {make peace}]
     [also: {warring}, {warred}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
