<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ward</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ward</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ward
   a prison (Gen. 40:3, 4); a watch-station (Isa. 21:8); a guard
   (Neh. 13:30).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ward</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ward, AL
  Zip code(s): 36922
Ward, AR (city, FIPS 73130)
  Location: 35.01886 N, 91.95503 W
  Population (1990): 1269 (506 housing units)
  Area: 8.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 72176
Ward, CO (town, FIPS 82735)
  Location: 40.07250 N, 105.51128 W
  Population (1990): 159 (100 housing units)
  Area: 1.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 80481
Ward, SC (town, FIPS 74590)
  Location: 33.85719 N, 81.73232 W
  Population (1990): 132 (59 housing units)
  Area: 2.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 29166
Ward, SD (town, FIPS 68660)
  Location: 44.15536 N, 96.46079 W
  Population (1990): 35 (22 housing units)
  Area: 0.7 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 57074
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ward</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-ward \-ward\ (w[~e]rd), -wards \-wards\ (w[~e]rdz). [AS.
   -weard, -weardes; akin to OS. &amp; OFries. -ward. OHG. -wert, G.
   -w["a]rts, Icel. -ver[eth]r, Goth. -va['i]r[thorn]s, L.
   vertere to turn, versus toward, and E. worth to become.
   [root]143. See {Worth}. v. i., and cf. {Verse}. Adverbs
   ending in -wards (AS. -weardes) and some other adverbs, such
   as besides, betimes, since (OE. sithens). etc., were
   originally genitive forms used adverbially.]
   Suffixes denoting course or direction to; motion or tendency
   toward; as in backward, or backwards; toward, or towards,
   etc.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ward</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ward \Ward\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Warded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Warding}.] [OE. wardien, AS. weardian to keep, protect; akin
   to OS. ward?n to watch, take care, OFries. wardia, OHG.
   wart?n, G. warten to wait, wait on, attend to, Icel. var?a to
   guarantee defend, Sw. v[*a]rda to guard, to watch; cf. OF.
   warder, of German origin. See {Ward}, n., and cf. {Award},
   {Guard}, {Reward}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To keep in safety; to watch; to guard; formerly, in a
      specific sense, to guard during the day time.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whose gates he found fast shut, no living wight
            To ward the same.                     --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To defend; to protect.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tell him it was a hand that warded him
            From thousand dangers.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To defend by walls, fortifications, etc. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To fend off; to repel; to turn aside, as anything
      mischievous that approaches; -- usually followed by off.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now wards a felling blow, now strikes again.
                                                  --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

            The pointed javelin warded off his rage. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            It instructs the scholar in the various methods of
            warding off the force of objections.  --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ward</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ward \Ward\, n. [AS. weard, fem., guard, weard, masc., keeper,
   guard; akin to OS. ward a watcher, warden, G. wart, OHG.
   wart, Icel. v["o]r[eth]r a warden, a watch, Goth. -wards in
   da['u]rawards a doorkeeper, and E. wary; cf. OF. warde guard,
   from the German. See {Ware}, a., {Wary}, and cf. {Guard},
   {Wraith}.]
   1. The act of guarding; watch; guard; guardianship;
      specifically, a guarding during the day. See the Note
      under {Watch}, n., 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Still, when she slept, he kept both watch and ward.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who, or that which, guards; garrison; defender;
      protector; means of guarding; defense; protection.
      [1913 Webster]

            For the best ward of mine honor.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The assieged castle's ward
            Their steadfast stands did mightily maintain.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            For want of other ward,
            He lifted up his hand, his front to guard. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The state of being under guard or guardianship;
      confinement under guard; the condition of a child under a
      guardian; custody.
      [1913 Webster]

            And he put them in ward in the house of the captain
            of the guard.                         --Gen. xl. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            I must attend his majesty's command, to whom I am
            now in ward.                          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is also inconvenient, in Ireland, that the wards
            and marriages of gentlemen's children should be in
            the disposal of any of those lords.   --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A guarding or defensive motion or position, as in fencing;
      guard. ``Thou knowest my old ward; here I lay, and thus I
      bore my point.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. One who, or that which, is guarded. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) A minor or person under the care of a guardian; as, a
          ward in chancery. ``You know our father's ward, the
          fair Monimia.'' --Otway.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A division of a county. [Eng. &amp; Scot.]
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) A division, district, or quarter of a town or city.
          [1913 Webster]

                Throughout the trembling city placed a guard,
                Dealing an equal share to every ward. --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) A division of a forest. [Eng.]
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) A division of a hospital; as, a fever ward.
          [1913 Webster]

   6.
      (a) A projecting ridge of metal in the interior of a lock,
          to prevent the use of any key which has not a
          corresponding notch for passing it.
      (b) A notch or slit in a key corresponding to a ridge in
          the lock which it fits; a ward notch. --Knight.
          [1913 Webster]

                The lock is made . . . more secure by attaching
                wards to the front, as well as to the back,
                plate of the lock, in which case the key must be
                furnished with corresponding notches.
                                                  --Tomlinson.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Ward penny} (O. Eng. Law), money paid to the sheriff or
      castellan for watching and warding a castle.

   {Ward staff}, a constable's or watchman's staff. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ward</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ward \Ward\, v. i.
   1. To be vigilant; to keep guard.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To act on the defensive with a weapon.
      [1913 Webster]

            She redoubling her blows drove the stranger to no
            other shift than to ward and go back. --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ward</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ward
     n 1: a person who is under the protection or in the custody of
          another
     2: a district into which a city or town is divided for the
        purpose of administration and elections
     3: block forming a division of a hospital (or a suite of rooms)
        shared by patients who need a similar kind of care; "they
        put her in a 4-bed ward" [syn: {hospital ward}]
     4: English economist and conservationist (1914-1981) [syn: {Barbara
        Ward}, {Baroness Jackson of Lodsworth}]
     5: English writer of novels who was an active opponent of the
        women's suffrage movement (1851-1920) [syn: {Mrs. Humphrey
        Ward}, {Mary Augusta Arnold Ward}]
     6: United States businessman who in 1872 established a
        successful mail-order business (1843-1913) [syn: {Montgomery
        Ward}, {Asron Montgomery Ward}]
     7: a division of a prison (usually consisting of several cells)
        [syn: {cellblock}]
     v : watch over or shield from danger or harm; protect; "guard my
         possessions while I'm away" [syn: {guard}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
