<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>warp</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>warp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Warp
     
        {OS/2}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>warp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Warp \Warp\, v. i.
   1. To turn, twist, or be twisted out of shape; esp., to be
      twisted or bent out of a flat plane; as, a board warps in
      seasoning or shrinking.
      [1913 Webster]

            One of you will prove a shrunk panel, and, like
            green timber, warp, warp.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            They clamp one piece of wood to the end of another,
            to keep it from casting, or warping.  --Moxon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. to turn or incline from a straight, true, or proper
      course; to deviate; to swerve.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is our commission,
            From which we would not have you warp. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fly with a bending or waving motion; to turn and wave,
      like a flock of birds or insects.
      [1913 Webster]

            A pitchy cloud
            Of locusts, warping on the eastern wind. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cast the young prematurely; to slink; -- said of
      cattle, sheep, etc. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Weaving) To wind yarn off bobbins for forming the warp of
      a web; to wind a warp on a warp beam.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>warp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Warp \Warp\ (w[add]rp), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Warped}
   (w[add]rpt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Warping}.] [OE. warpen; fr.
   Icel. varpa to throw, cast, varp a casting, fr. verpa to
   throw; akin to Dan. varpe to warp a ship, Sw. varpa, AS.
   weorpan to cast, OS. werpan, OFries. werpa, D. &amp; LG. werpen,
   G. werfen, Goth. wa['i]rpan; cf. Skr. v[.r]j to twist.
   [root]144. Cf. {Wrap}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To throw; hence, to send forth, or throw out, as words; to
      utter. [Obs.] --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To turn or twist out of shape; esp., to twist or bend out
      of a flat plane by contraction or otherwise.
      [1913 Webster]

            The planks looked warped.             --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Walter warped his mouth at this
            To something so mock solemn, that I laughed.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To turn aside from the true direction; to cause to bend or
      incline; to pervert.
      [1913 Webster]

            This first avowed, nor folly warped my mind.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have no private considerations to warp me in this
            controversy.                          --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are divested of all those passions which cloud
            the intellects, and warp the understandings, of men.
                                                  --Southey.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To weave; to fabricate. [R. &amp; Poetic.] --Nares.
      [1913 Webster]

            While doth he mischief warp.          --Sternhold.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) To tow or move, as a vessel, with a line, or warp,
      attached to a buoy, anchor, or other fixed object.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cast prematurely, as young; -- said of cattle, sheep,
      etc. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Agric.) To let the tide or other water in upon (lowlying
      land), for the purpose of fertilization, by a deposit of
      warp, or slimy substance. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Rope Making) To run off the reel into hauls to be tarred,
      as yarns.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Weaving) To arrange (yarns) on a warp beam.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (A["e]ronautics) To twist the end surfaces of (an
       a["e]rocurve in an airfoil) in order to restore or
       maintain equilibrium.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Warped surface} (Geom.), a surface generated by a straight
      line moving so that no two of its consecutive positions
      shall be in the same plane. --Davies &amp; Peck.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>warp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Warp \Warp\, n. [AS. wearp; akin to Icel. varp a casting,
   throwing, Sw. varp the draught of a net, Dan. varp a towline,
   OHG. warf warp, G. werft. See {Warp}, v.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Weaving) The threads which are extended lengthwise in the
      loom, and crossed by the woof.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) A rope used in hauling or moving a vessel, usually
      with one end attached to an anchor, a post, or other fixed
      object; a towing line; a warping hawser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Agric.) A slimy substance deposited on land by tides,
      etc., by which a rich alluvial soil is formed. --Lyell.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A premature casting of young; -- said of cattle, sheep,
      etc. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Four; esp., four herrings; a cast. See {Cast}, n., 17.
      [Prov. Eng.] --Wright.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. [From {Warp}, v.] The state of being warped or twisted;
      as, the warp of a board.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Warp beam}, the roller on which the warp is wound in a loom.
      

   {Warp fabric}, fabric produced by warp knitting.

   {Warp frame}, or {Warp-net frame}, a machine for making warp
      lace having a number of needles and employing a thread for
      each needle.

   {Warp knitting}, a kind of knitting in which a number of
      threads are interchained each with one or more contiguous
      threads on either side; -- also called {warp weaving}.

   {Warp lace}, or {Warp net}, lace having a warp crossed by
      weft threads.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>warp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>warp
     n 1: a twist or aberration; especially a perverse or abnormal way
          of judging or acting [syn: {deflection}]
     2: a shape distorted by twisting or folding [syn: {buckle}]
     3: a moral or mental distortion [syn: {warping}]
     4: yarn arranged lengthways on a loom and crossed by the woof
     v 1: make false by mutilation or addition; as of a message or
          story [syn: {falsify}, {distort}, {garble}]
     2: bend out of shape, as under pressure or from heat; "The
        highway buckled during the heatwave" [syn: {heave}, {buckle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
