<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wash</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wash</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wash \Wash\ (w[o^]sh), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Washed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Washing}.] [OE. waschen, AS. wascan; akin to D.
   wasschen, G. waschen, OHG. wascan, Icel. &amp; Sw. vaska, Dan.
   vaske, and perhaps to E. water. [root]150.]
   1. To cleanse by ablution, or dipping or rubbing in water; to
      apply water or other liquid to for the purpose of
      cleansing; to scrub with water, etc., or as with water;
      as, to wash the hands or body; to wash garments; to wash
      sheep or wool; to wash the pavement or floor; to wash the
      bark of trees.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Pilate saw that he could prevail nothing, . . .
            he took water and washed his hands before the
            multitude, saying, I am innocent of the blood of
            this just person.                     --Matt. xxvii.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover with water or any liquid; to wet; to fall on and
      moisten; hence, to overflow or dash against; as, waves
      wash the shore.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fresh-blown roses washed with dew.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The landscape] washed with a cold, gray mist.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To waste or abrade by the force of water in motion; as,
      heavy rains wash a road or an embankment.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To remove by washing to take away by, or as by, the action
      of water; to drag or draw off as by the tide; -- often
      with away, off, out, etc.; as, to wash dirt from the
      hands.
      [1913 Webster]

            Arise, and be baptized, and wash away thy sins.
                                                  --Acts xxii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

            The tide will wash you off.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cover with a thin or watery coat of color; to tint
      lightly and thinly.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To overlay with a thin coat of metal; as, steel washed
      with silver.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cause dephosphorisation of (molten pig iron) by adding
      substances containing iron oxide, and sometimes manganese
      oxide.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. To pass (a gas or gaseous mixture) through or over a
      liquid for the purpose of purifying it, esp. by removing
      soluble constituents.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To wash gold}, etc., to treat earth or gravel, or crushed
      ore, with water, in order to separate the gold or other
      metal, or metallic ore, through their higher density.

   {To wash the hands of}. See under {Hand}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wash</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wash \Wash\, v. i.
   1. To perform the act of ablution.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wash in Jordan seven times.           --2 Kings v.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To clean anything by rubbing or dipping it in water; to
      perform the business of cleansing clothes, ore, etc., in
      water. ``She can wash and scour.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bear without injury the operation of being washed; as,
      some calicoes do not wash. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be wasted or worn away by the action of water, as by a
      running or overflowing stream, or by the dashing of the
      sea; -- said of road, a beach, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To use washes, as for the face or hair.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. To move with a lapping or swashing sound, or the like; to
      lap; splash; as, to hear the water washing.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. to be accepted as true or valid; to be proven true by
      subsequent evidence; -- usually used in the negative; as,
      his alibi won't wash. [informal]
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wash</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wash \Wash\, n.
   1. The act of washing; an ablution; a cleansing, wetting, or
      dashing with water; hence, a quantity, as of clothes,
      washed at once.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A piece of ground washed by the action of a sea or river,
      or sometimes covered and sometimes left dry; the
      shallowest part of a river, or arm of the sea; also, a
      bog; a marsh; a fen; as, the washes in Lincolnshire. ``The
      Wash of Edmonton so gay.'' --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

            These Lincoln washes have devoured them. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Substances collected and deposited by the action of water;
      as, the wash of a sewer, of a river, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wash of pastures, fields, commons, and roads,
            where rain water hath a long time settled.
                                                  --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Waste liquid, the refuse of food, the collection from
      washed dishes, etc., from a kitchen, often used as food
      for pigs. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Distilling)
      (a) The fermented wort before the spirit is extracted.
      (b) A mixture of dunder, molasses, water, and scummings,
          used in the West Indies for distillation. --B.
          Edwards.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. That with which anything is washed, or wetted, smeared,
      tinted, etc., upon the surface. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) A liquid cosmetic for the complexion.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A liquid dentifrice.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) A liquid preparation for the hair; as, a hair wash.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) A medical preparation in a liquid form for external
          application; a lotion.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) (Painting) A thin coat of color, esp. water color.
          [1913 Webster]
      (j) A thin coat of metal applied in a liquid form on any
          object, for beauty or preservation; -- called also
          {washing}.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   7. (Naut.)
      (a) The blade of an oar, or the thin part which enters the
          water.
      (b) The backward current or disturbed water caused by the
          action of oars, or of a steamer's screw or paddles,
          etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. The flow, swash, or breaking of a body of water, as a
      wave; also, the sound of it.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Ten strikes, or bushels, of oysters. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   10. [Western U. S.] (Geol.)
       (a) Gravel and other rock d['e]bris transported and
           deposited by running water; coarse alluvium.
       (b) An alluvial cone formed by a stream at the base of a
           mountain.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. The dry bed of an intermittent stream, sometimes at the
       bottom of a ca[~n]on; as, the Amargosa wash, Diamond
       wash; -- called also {dry wash}. [Western U. S.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. (Arch.) The upper surface of a member or material when
       given a slope to shed water. Hence, a structure or
       receptacle shaped so as to receive and carry off water,
       as a carriage wash in a stable.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   13. an action or situation in which the gains and losses are
       equal, or closely compensate each other.
       [PJC]

   14. (Aeronautics) the disturbance of the air left behind in
       the wake of a moving airplane or one of its parts.
       [PJC]

   {Wash ball}, a ball of soap to be used in washing the hands
      or face. --Swift.

   {Wash barrel} (Fisheries), a barrel nearly full of split
      mackerel, loosely put in, and afterward filled with salt
      water in order to soak the blood from the fish before
      salting.

   {Wash bottle}. (Chem.)
       (a) A bottle partially filled with some liquid through
           which gases are passed for the purpose of purifying
           them, especially by removing soluble constituents.
       (b) A washing bottle. See under {Washing}.

   {Wash gilding}. See {Water gilding}.

   {Wash leather}, split sheepskin dressed with oil, in
      imitation of chamois, or shammy, and used for dusting,
      cleaning glass or plate, etc.; also, alumed, or buff,
      leather for soldiers' belts.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wash</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wash \Wash\, a.
   1. Washy; weak. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Their bodies of so weak and wash a temper. --Beau. &amp;
                                                  Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Capable of being washed without injury; washable; as, wash
      goods. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wash</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wash
     n 1: a thin coat of water-base paint
     2: the work of cleansing (usually with soap and water) [syn: {washing},
         {lavation}]
     3: the dry bed of an intermittent stream (as at the bottom of a
        canyon) [syn: {dry wash}]
     4: the erosive process of washing away soil or gravel by water
        (as from a roadway); "from the house they watched the
        washout of their newly seeded lawn by the water" [syn: {washout}]
     5: the flow of air that is driven backwards by an aircraft
        propeller [syn: {slipstream}, {airstream}, {race}, {backwash}]
     6: a watercolor made by applying a series of monochrome washes
        one over the other [syn: {wash drawing}]
     7: garments or white goods that can be cleaned by laundering
        [syn: {laundry}, {washing}, {washables}]
     8: any enterprise in which losses and gains cancel out; "at the
        end of the year the accounting department showed that it
        was a wash"
     v 1: clean with some chemical process [syn: {rinse}]
     2: cleanse (one's body) with soap and water [syn: {lave}]
     3: cleanse with a cleaning agent, such as soap, and water;
        "Wash the towels, please!" [syn: {launder}]
     4: move by or as if by water; "The swollen river washed away
        the footbridge"
     5: be capable of being washed; "Does this material wash?"
     6: admit to testing or proof; "This silly excuse won't wash in
        traffic court"
     7: separate dirt or gravel from (precious minerals)
     8: apply a thin coating of paint, metal, etc., to
     9: remove by the application of water or other liquid and soap
        or some other cleaning agent; "he washed the dirt from his
        coat"; "The nurse washed away the blood"; "Can you wash
        away the spots on the windows?"; "he managed to wash out
        the stains" [syn: {wash out}, {wash off}, {wash away}]
     10: form by erosion; "The river washed a ravine into the
         mountainside"
     11: make moist; "The dew moistened the meadows" [syn: {moisten},
          {dampen}]
     12: wash or flow against; "the waves laved the shore" [syn: {lave},
          {lap}]
     13: to cleanse (itself or another animal) by licking; "The cat
         washes several times a day"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
