<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>washed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>washed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wash \Wash\ (w[o^]sh), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Washed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Washing}.] [OE. waschen, AS. wascan; akin to D.
   wasschen, G. waschen, OHG. wascan, Icel. &amp; Sw. vaska, Dan.
   vaske, and perhaps to E. water. [root]150.]
   1. To cleanse by ablution, or dipping or rubbing in water; to
      apply water or other liquid to for the purpose of
      cleansing; to scrub with water, etc., or as with water;
      as, to wash the hands or body; to wash garments; to wash
      sheep or wool; to wash the pavement or floor; to wash the
      bark of trees.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Pilate saw that he could prevail nothing, . . .
            he took water and washed his hands before the
            multitude, saying, I am innocent of the blood of
            this just person.                     --Matt. xxvii.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover with water or any liquid; to wet; to fall on and
      moisten; hence, to overflow or dash against; as, waves
      wash the shore.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fresh-blown roses washed with dew.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The landscape] washed with a cold, gray mist.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To waste or abrade by the force of water in motion; as,
      heavy rains wash a road or an embankment.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To remove by washing to take away by, or as by, the action
      of water; to drag or draw off as by the tide; -- often
      with away, off, out, etc.; as, to wash dirt from the
      hands.
      [1913 Webster]

            Arise, and be baptized, and wash away thy sins.
                                                  --Acts xxii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

            The tide will wash you off.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cover with a thin or watery coat of color; to tint
      lightly and thinly.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To overlay with a thin coat of metal; as, steel washed
      with silver.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cause dephosphorisation of (molten pig iron) by adding
      substances containing iron oxide, and sometimes manganese
      oxide.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. To pass (a gas or gaseous mixture) through or over a
      liquid for the purpose of purifying it, esp. by removing
      soluble constituents.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To wash gold}, etc., to treat earth or gravel, or crushed
      ore, with water, in order to separate the gold or other
      metal, or metallic ore, through their higher density.

   {To wash the hands of}. See under {Hand}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>washed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Washed \Washed\, a. (Zo["o]l.)
   Appearing as if overlaid with a thin layer of different
   color; -- said of the colors of certain birds and insects.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>washed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>washed
     adj 1: clean by virtue of having been washed in water [syn: {water-washed}]
     2: wet as from washing; sometimes used in combination;
        "rain-washed"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
