<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wasp</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wasp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wasp \Wasp\, n. [OE. waspe, AS. w[ae]ps, w[ae]fs; akin to D.
   wesp, G. wespe, OHG. wafsa, wefsa, Lith. vapsa gadfly, Russ.
   osa wasp, L. vespa, and perhaps to E. weave.] (Zo["o]l.)
   Any one of numerous species of stinging hymenopterous
   insects, esp. any of the numerous species of the genus
   {Vespa}, which includes the true, or social, wasps, some of
   which are called {yellow jackets}.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The social wasps make a complex series of combs, of a
         substance like stiff paper, often of large size, and
         protect them by a paperlike covering. The larv[ae] are
         reared in the cells of the combs, and eat insects and
         insect larv[ae] brought to them by the adults, but the
         latter feed mainly on the honey and pollen of flowers,
         and on the sweet juices of fruit. See Illust. in
         Appendix.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Digger wasp}, any one of numerous species of solitary wasps
      that make their nests in burrows which they dig in the
      ground, as the sand wasps. See {Sand wasp}, under {Sand}.
      

   {Mud wasp}. See under {Mud}.

   {Potter wasp}. See under {Potter}.

   {Wasp fly}, a species of fly resembling a wasp, but without a
      sting.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wasp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>WASP
     Web stAndardS Project (WWW, W3C)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wasp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>WASP
     n 1: a white person of Anglo-Saxon ancestry who belongs to a
          Protestant denomination [syn: {white Anglo-Saxon
          Protestant}]
     2: social or solitary hymenopterans typically having a slender
        body with the abdomen attached by a narrow stalk and
        having a formidable sting
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
