<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>waste</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>waste</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Waste \Waste\, a. [OE. wast, OF. wast, from L. vastus,
   influenced by the kindred German word; cf. OHG. wuosti, G.
   w["u]st, OS. w?sti, D. woest, AS. w[=e]ste. Cf. {Vast}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Desolate; devastated; stripped; bare; hence, dreary;
      dismal; gloomy; cheerless.
      [1913 Webster]

            The dismal situation waste and wild.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            His heart became appalled as he gazed forward into
            the waste darkness of futurity.       --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Lying unused; unproductive; worthless; valueless; refuse;
      rejected; as, waste land; waste paper.
      [1913 Webster]

            But his waste words returned to him in vain.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not a waste or needless sound,
            Till we come to holier ground.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ill day which made this beauty waste. --Emerson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Lost for want of occupiers or use; superfluous.
      [1913 Webster]

            And strangled with her waste fertility. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Waste gate}, a gate by which the superfluous water of a
      reservoir, or the like, is discharged.

   {Waste paper}. See under {Paper}.

   {Waste pipe}, a pipe for carrying off waste, or superfluous,
      water or other fluids. Specifically:
      (a) (Steam Boilers) An escape pipe. See under {Escape}.
      (b) (Plumbing) The outlet pipe at the bottom of a bowl,
          tub, sink, or the like.

   {Waste steam}.
      (a) Steam which escapes the air.
      (b) Exhaust steam.

   {Waste trap}, a trap for a waste pipe, as of a sink.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>waste</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Waste \Waste\, n. [OE. waste; cf. the kindred AS. w[=e]sten,
   OHG. w[=o]st[=i], wuost[=i], G. w["u]ste. See {Waste}, a. &amp;
   v.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of wasting, or the state of being wasted; a
      squandering; needless destruction; useless consumption or
      expenditure; devastation; loss without equivalent gain;
      gradual loss or decrease, by use, wear, or decay; as, a
      waste of property, time, labor, words, etc. ``Waste . . .
      of catel and of time.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            For all this waste of wealth loss of blood.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            He will never . . . in the way of waste, attempt us
            again.                                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Little wastes in great establishments, constantly
            occurring, may defeat the energies of a mighty
            capital.                              --L. Beecher.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is wasted or desolate; a devastated,
      uncultivated, or wild country; a deserted region; an
      unoccupied or unemployed space; a dreary void; a desert; a
      wilderness. ``The wastes of Nature.'' --Emerson.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the leafy nation sinks at last,
            And Vulcan rides in triumph o'er the waste.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gloomy waste of waters which bears his name is
            his tomb and his monument.            --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is of no value; worthless remnants; refuse.
      Specifically: Remnants of cops, or other refuse resulting
      from the working of cotton, wool, hemp, and the like, used
      for wiping machinery, absorbing oil in the axle boxes of
      railway cars, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) Spoil, destruction, or injury, done to houses,
      woods, fences, lands, etc., by a tenant for life or for
      years, to the prejudice of the heir, or of him in
      reversion or remainder.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Waste is voluntary, as by pulling down buildings; or
         permissive, as by suffering them to fall for want of
         necessary repairs. Whatever does a lasting damage to
         the freehold is a {waste}. --Blackstone.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mining) Old or abandoned workings, whether left as vacant
      space or filled with refuse.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Phys. Geog.) Material derived by mechanical and chemical
      erosion from the land, carried by streams to the sea.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Syn: Prodigality; diminution; loss; dissipation; destruction;
        devastation; havoc; desolation; ravage.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>waste</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Waste \Waste\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wasted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Wasting}.] [OE. wasten, OF. waster, guaster, gaster, F.
   g[^a]ter to spoil, L. vastare to devastate, to lay waste, fr.
   vastus waste, desert, uncultivated, ravaged, vast, but
   influenced by a kindred German word; cf. OHG. wuosten, G.
   w["u]sten, AS. w[=e]stan. See {Waste}, a.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To bring to ruin; to devastate; to desolate; to destroy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou barren ground, whom winter's wrath hath wasted,
            Art made a mirror to behold my plight. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Tiber
            Insults our walls, and wastes our fruitful grounds.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To wear away by degrees; to impair gradually; to diminish
      by constant loss; to use up; to consume; to spend; to wear
      out.
      [1913 Webster]

            Until your carcasses be wasted in the wilderness.
                                                  --Num. xiv.
                                                  33.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, were I able
            To waste it all myself, and leave ye none! --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here condemned
            To waste eternal days in woe and pain. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wasted by such a course of life, the infirmities of
            age daily grew on him.                --Robertson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To spend unnecessarily or carelessly; to employ
      prodigally; to expend without valuable result; to apply to
      useless purposes; to lavish vainly; to squander; to cause
      to be lost; to destroy by scattering or injury.
      [1913 Webster]

            The younger son gathered all together, and . . .
            wasted his substance with riotous living. --Luke xv.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            Full many a flower is born to blush unseen,
            And waste its sweetness on the desert air. --Gray.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) To damage, impair, or injure, as an estate,
      voluntarily, or by suffering the buildings, fences, etc.,
      to go to decay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To squander; dissipate; lavish; desolate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>waste</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Waste \Waste\ (w[=a]st), v. i.
   1. To be diminished; to lose bulk, substance, strength,
      value, or the like, gradually; to be consumed; to dwindle;
      to grow less; -- commonly used with away.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            The time wasteth night and day.       --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The barrel of meal shall not waste.   --1 Kings
                                                  xvii. 14.
      [1913 Webster]

            But man dieth, and wasteth away.      --Job xiv. 10.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Sporting) To procure or sustain a reduction of flesh; --
      said of a jockey in preparation for a race, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>waste</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>waste
     adj 1: disposed of as useless; "waste paper" [syn: {cast-off(a)}, {discarded},
             {junked}, {scrap(a)}]
     2: located in a dismal or remote area; desolate; "a desert
        island"; "a godforsaken wilderness crossroads"; "a wild
        stretch of land"; "waste places" [syn: {desert}, {godforsaken},
         {wild}]
     n 1: any materials unused and rejected as worthless or unwanted;
          "they collect the waste once a week"; "much of the waste
          material is carried off in the sewers" [syn: {waste
          material}, {waste matter}, {waste product}]
     2: useless or profitless activity; using or expending or
        consuming thoughtlessly or carelessly; "if the effort
        brings no compensating gain it is a waste"; "mindless
        dissipation of natural resources" [syn: {wastefulness}, {dissipation}]
     3: the trait of wasting resources; "a life characterized by
        thriftlessness and waste"; "the wastefulness of missed
        opportunities" [syn: {thriftlessness}, {wastefulness}]
     4: an uninhabited wilderness that is worthless for cultivation;
        "the barrens of central Africa"; "the trackless wastes of
        the desert" [syn: {barren}, {wasteland}]
     5: (law) reduction in the value of an estate caused by act or
        neglect [syn: {permissive waste}]
     v 1: spend thoughtlessly; throw away; "He wasted his inheritance
          on his insincere friends"; "You squandered the
          opportunity to get and advanced degree" [syn: {blow}, {squander}]
          [ant: {conserve}]
     2: use inefficiently or inappropriately; "waste heat"; "waste a
        joke on an unappreciative audience"
     3: get rid of; "We waste the dirty water by channeling it into
        the sewer"
     4: run off as waste; "The water wastes back into the ocean"
        [syn: {run off}]
     5: get rid of (someone who may be a threat) by killing; "The
        mafia liquidated the informer"; "the double agent was
        neutralized" [syn: {neutralize}, {neutralise}, {liquidate},
         {knock off}, {do in}]
     6: spend extravagantly; "waste not, want not" [syn: {consume},
        {squander}, {ware}]
     7: lose vigor, health, or flesh, as through grief; "After her
        husband died, she just pined away" [syn: {pine away}, {languish}]
     8: cause to grow thin or weak; "The treatment emaciated him"
        [syn: {emaciate}, {macerate}]
     9: devastate or ravage; "The enemy lay waste to the countryside
        after the invasion" [syn: {lay waste to}, {devastate}, {desolate},
         {ravage}, {scourge}]
     10: waste away; "Political prisoners are wasting away in many
         prisons all over the world" [syn: {rot}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
