<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wasting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wasting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wasting \Wast"ing\, a.
   Causing waste; also, undergoing waste; diminishing; as, a
   wasting disease; a wasting fortune.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Wasting palsy} (Med.), progressive muscular atrophy. See
      under {Progressive}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wasting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Waste \Waste\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wasted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Wasting}.] [OE. wasten, OF. waster, guaster, gaster, F.
   g[^a]ter to spoil, L. vastare to devastate, to lay waste, fr.
   vastus waste, desert, uncultivated, ravaged, vast, but
   influenced by a kindred German word; cf. OHG. wuosten, G.
   w["u]sten, AS. w[=e]stan. See {Waste}, a.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To bring to ruin; to devastate; to desolate; to destroy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou barren ground, whom winter's wrath hath wasted,
            Art made a mirror to behold my plight. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Tiber
            Insults our walls, and wastes our fruitful grounds.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To wear away by degrees; to impair gradually; to diminish
      by constant loss; to use up; to consume; to spend; to wear
      out.
      [1913 Webster]

            Until your carcasses be wasted in the wilderness.
                                                  --Num. xiv.
                                                  33.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, were I able
            To waste it all myself, and leave ye none! --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here condemned
            To waste eternal days in woe and pain. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wasted by such a course of life, the infirmities of
            age daily grew on him.                --Robertson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To spend unnecessarily or carelessly; to employ
      prodigally; to expend without valuable result; to apply to
      useless purposes; to lavish vainly; to squander; to cause
      to be lost; to destroy by scattering or injury.
      [1913 Webster]

            The younger son gathered all together, and . . .
            wasted his substance with riotous living. --Luke xv.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            Full many a flower is born to blush unseen,
            And waste its sweetness on the desert air. --Gray.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) To damage, impair, or injure, as an estate,
      voluntarily, or by suffering the buildings, fences, etc.,
      to go to decay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To squander; dissipate; lavish; desolate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wasting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wasting
     n 1: any general reduction in vitality and strength of body and
          mind resulting from a debilitating chronic disease [syn:
           {cachexia}, {cachexy}]
     2: a decrease in size of an organ caused by disease or disuse
        [syn: {atrophy}, {wasting away}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
