<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>watering</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>watering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Water \Wa"ter\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Watered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Watering}.] [AS. w[ae]terian, gew[ae]terian.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To wet or supply with water; to moisten; to overflow with
      water; to irrigate; as, to water land; to water flowers.
      [1913 Webster]

            With tears watering the ground.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men whose lives gilded on like rivers that water the
            woodlands.                            --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To supply with water for drink; to cause or allow to
      drink; as, to water cattle and horses.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To wet and calender, as cloth, so as to impart to it a
      lustrous appearance in wavy lines; to diversify with
      wavelike lines; as, to water silk. Cf. {Water}, n., 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To add water to (anything), thereby extending the quantity
      or bulk while reducing the strength or quality; to extend;
      to dilute; to weaken.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To water stock}, to increase the capital stock of a company
      by issuing new stock, thus diminishing the value of the
      individual shares. Cf. {Water}, n., 7. [Brokers' Cant]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>watering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Watering \Wa"ter*ing\,
   a. &amp; n. from {Water}, v.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Watering call} (Mil.), a sound of trumpet or bugle summoning
      cavalry soldiers to assemble for the purpose of watering
      their horses.

   {Watering cart}, a sprinkling cart. See {Water}.

   {Watering place}.
   (a) A place where water may be obtained, as for a ship, for
       cattle, etc.
   (b) A place where there are springs of medicinal water, or a
       place by the sea, or by some large body of water, to
       which people resort for bathing, recreation, boating,
       etc.

   {Watering pot}.
   (a) A kind of bucket fitted with a rose, or perforated
       nozzle, -- used for watering flowers, paths, etc.
   (b) (Zo["o]l.) Any one of several species of marine bivalve
       shells of the genus {Aspergillum}, or {Brechites}. The
       valves are small, and consolidated with the capacious
       calcareous tube which incases the entire animal. The tube
       is closed at the anterior end by a convex disk perforated
       by numerous pores, or tubules, and resembling the rose of
       a watering pot.

   {Watering trough}, a trough from which cattle, horses, and
      other animals drink.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>watering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>watering
     n 1: shedding tears [syn: {lacrimation}, {lachrymation}, {tearing}]
     2: wetting with water; "the lawn needs a great deal of
        watering"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
