<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>water</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>water</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Water \Wa"ter\ (w[add]"t[~e]r), n. [AS. w[ae]ter; akin to OS.
   watar, OFries. wetir, weter, LG. &amp; D. water, G. wasser, OHG.
   wazzar, Icel. vatn, Sw. vatten, Dan. vand, Goth. wat[=o], O.
   Slav. &amp; Russ. voda, Gr. 'y`dwr, Skr. udan water, ud to wet,
   and perhaps to L. unda wave. [root]137. Cf. {Dropsy},
   {Hydra}, {Otter}, {Wet}, {Whisky}.]
   1. The fluid which descends from the clouds in rain, and
      which forms rivers, lakes, seas, etc. ``We will drink
      water.'' --Shak. ``Powers of fire, air, water, and
      earth.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Pure water consists of hydrogen and oxygen, {H2O}, and
         is a colorless, odorless, tasteless, transparent
         liquid, which is very slightly compressible. At its
         maximum density, 39[deg] Fahr. or 4[deg] C., it is the
         standard for specific gravities, one cubic centimeter
         weighing one gram. It freezes at 32[deg] Fahr. or
         0[deg] C. and boils at 212[deg] Fahr. or 100[deg] C.
         (see {Ice}, {Steam}). It is the most important natural
         solvent, and is frequently impregnated with foreign
         matter which is mostly removed by distillation; hence,
         rain water is nearly pure. It is an important
         ingredient in the tissue of animals and plants, the
         human body containing about two thirds its weight of
         water.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A body of water, standing or flowing; a lake, river, or
      other collection of water.
      [1913 Webster]

            Remembering he had passed over a small water a poor
            scholar when first coming to the university, he
            kneeled.                              --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any liquid secretion, humor, or the like, resembling
      water; esp., the urine.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Pharm.) A solution in water of a gaseous or readily
      volatile substance; as, ammonia water. --U. S. Pharm.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The limpidity and luster of a precious stone, especially a
      diamond; as, a diamond of the first water, that is,
      perfectly pure and transparent. Hence, of the first water,
      that is, of the first excellence.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A wavy, lustrous pattern or decoration such as is imparted
      to linen, silk, metals, etc. See {Water}, v. t., 3,
      {Damask}, v. t., and {Damaskeen}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. An addition to the shares representing the capital of a
      stock company so that the aggregate par value of the
      shares is increased while their value for investment is
      diminished, or ``diluted.'' [Brokers' Cant]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Water is often used adjectively and in the formation of
         many self-explaining compounds; as, water drainage;
         water gauge, or water-gauge; waterfowl, water-fowl, or
         water fowl; water-beaten; water-borne, water-circled,
         water-girdled, water-rocked, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Hard water}. See under {Hard}.

   {Inch of water}, a unit of measure of quantity of water,
      being the quantity which will flow through an orifice one
      inch square, or a circular orifice one inch in diameter,
      in a vertical surface, under a stated constant head; also
      called {miner's inch}, and {water inch}. The shape of the
      orifice and the head vary in different localities. In the
      Western United States, for hydraulic mining, the standard
      aperture is square and the head from 4 to 9 inches above
      its center. In Europe, for experimental hydraulics, the
      orifice is usually round and the head from 1/2 of an inch
      to 1 inch above its top.

   {Mineral water}, waters which are so impregnated with foreign
      ingredients, such as gaseous, sulphureous, and saline
      substances, as to give them medicinal properties, or a
      particular flavor or temperature.

   {Soft water}, water not impregnated with lime or mineral
      salts.

   {To hold water}. See under {Hold}, v. t.

   {To keep one's head above water}, to keep afloat; fig., to
      avoid failure or sinking in the struggles of life.
      [Colloq.]

   {To make water}.
      (a) To pass urine. --Swift.
      (b) (Naut.) To admit water; to leak.

   {Water of crystallization} (Chem.), the water combined with
      many salts in their crystalline form. This water is
      loosely, but, nevertheless, chemically, combined, for it
      is held in fixed and definite amount for each substance
      containing it. Thus, while pure copper sulphate, {CuSO4},
      is a white amorphous substance, blue vitriol, the
      crystallized form, {CuSO4.5H2O}, contains five molecules
      of water of crystallization.

   {Water on the brain} (Med.), hydrocephalus.

   {Water on the chest} (Med.), hydrothorax.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Other phrases, in which water occurs as the first
         element, will be found in alphabetical order in the
         Vocabulary.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>water</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Water \Wa"ter\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Watered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Watering}.] [AS. w[ae]terian, gew[ae]terian.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To wet or supply with water; to moisten; to overflow with
      water; to irrigate; as, to water land; to water flowers.
      [1913 Webster]

            With tears watering the ground.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men whose lives gilded on like rivers that water the
            woodlands.                            --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To supply with water for drink; to cause or allow to
      drink; as, to water cattle and horses.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To wet and calender, as cloth, so as to impart to it a
      lustrous appearance in wavy lines; to diversify with
      wavelike lines; as, to water silk. Cf. {Water}, n., 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To add water to (anything), thereby extending the quantity
      or bulk while reducing the strength or quality; to extend;
      to dilute; to weaken.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To water stock}, to increase the capital stock of a company
      by issuing new stock, thus diminishing the value of the
      individual shares. Cf. {Water}, n., 7. [Brokers' Cant]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>water</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Water \Wa"ter\, v. i.
   1. To shed, secrete, or fill with, water or liquid matter;
      as, his eyes began to water.
      [1913 Webster]

            If thine eyes can water for his death. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To get or take in water; as, the ship put into port to
      water.
      [1913 Webster]

   {The mouth waters}, a phrase denoting that a person or animal
      has a longing desire for something, since the sight of
      food often causes one who is hungry to have an increased
      flow of saliva.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>water</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>water
     n 1: binary compound that occurs at room temperature as a clear
          colorless odorless tasteless liquid; freezes into ice
          below 0 degrees centigrade and boils above 100 degrees
          centigrade; widely used as a solvent [syn: {H2O}]
     2: the part of the earth's surface covered with water (such as
        a river or lake or ocean); "they invaded our territorial
        waters"; "they were sitting by the water's edge" [syn: {body
        of water}]
     3: facility that provides a source of water; "the town debated
        the purification of the water supply"; "first you have to
        cut off the water" [syn: {water system}, {water supply}]
     4: once thought to be one of four elements composing the
        universe (Empedocles)
     5: liquid excretory product; "there was blood in his urine";
        "the child had to make water" [syn: {urine}, {piss}, {pee},
         {piddle}, {weewee}]
     6: a fluid necessary for the life of most animals and plants;
        "he asked for a drink of water"
     v 1: supply with water, as with channels or ditches or streams;
          "Water the fields" [syn: {irrigate}]
     2: provide with water; "We watered the buffalo"
     3: secrete or form water, as tears or saliva; "My mouth watered
        at the prospect of a good dinner"; "His eyes watered"
     4: fill with tears; "His eyes were watering"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
