<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>way</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>way</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Way \Way\, v. t.
   To go or travel to; to go in, as a way or path. [Obs.] ``In
   land not wayed.'' --Wyclif.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>way</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Way \Way\, v. i.
   To move; to progress; to go. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         On a time as they together wayed.        --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>way</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Way \Way\, n. [OE. wey, way, AS. weg; akin to OS., D., OHG., &amp;
   G. weg, Icel. vegr, Sw. v["a]g, Dan. vei, Goth. wigs, L. via,
   and AS. wegan to move, L. vehere to carry, Skr. vah.
   [root]136. Cf. {Convex}, {Inveigh}, {Vehicle}, {Vex}, {Via},
   {Voyage}, {Wag}, {Wagon}, {Wee}, {Weigh}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. That by, upon, or along, which one passes or processes;
      opportunity or room to pass; place of passing; passage;
      road, street, track, or path of any kind; as, they built a
      way to the mine. ``To find the way to heaven.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I shall him seek by way and eke by street.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The way seems difficult, and steep to scale.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The season and ways were very improper for his
            majesty's forces to march so great a distance.
                                                  --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Length of space; distance; interval; as, a great way; a
      long way.
      [1913 Webster]

            And whenever the way seemed long,
            Or his heart began to fail.           --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A moving; passage; procession; journey.
      [1913 Webster]

            I prythee, now, lead the way.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Course or direction of motion or process; tendency of
      action; advance.
      [1913 Webster]

            If that way be your walk, you have not far.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            And let eternal justice take the way. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The means by which anything is reached, or anything is
      accomplished; scheme; device; plan.
      [1913 Webster]

            My best way is to creep under his gaberdine. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            By noble ways we conquest will prepare. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            What impious ways my wishes took!     --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Manner; method; mode; fashion; style; as, the way of
      expressing one's ideas.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Regular course; habitual method of life or action; plan of
      conduct; mode of dealing. ``Having lost the way of
      nobleness.'' --Sir. P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her ways are ways of pleasantness, and all her paths
            are peace.                            --Prov. iii.
                                                  17.
      [1913 Webster]

            When men lived in a grander way.      --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Sphere or scope of observation. --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The public ministers that fell in my way. --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Determined course; resolved mode of action or conduct; as,
      to have one's way.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Naut.)
       (a) Progress; as, a ship has way.
       (b) pl. The timbers on which a ship is launched.
           [1913 Webster]

   11. pl. (Mach.) The longitudinal guides, or guiding surfaces,
       on the bed of a planer, lathe, or the like, along which a
       table or carriage moves.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Law) Right of way. See below.
       [1913 Webster]

   {By the way}, in passing; apropos; aside; apart from, though
      connected with, the main object or subject of discourse.
      

   {By way of}, for the purpose of; as being; in character of.
      

   {Covert way}. (Fort.) See {Covered way}, under {Covered}.

   {In the family way}. See under {Family}.

   {In the way}, so as to meet, fall in with, obstruct, hinder,
      etc.

   {In the way with}, traveling or going with; meeting or being
      with; in the presence of.

   {Milky way}. (Astron.) See {Galaxy}, 1.

   {No way}, {No ways}. See {Noway}, {Noways}, in the
      Vocabulary.

   {On the way}, traveling or going; hence, in process;
      advancing toward completion; as, on the way to this
      country; on the way to success.

   {Out of the way}. See under {Out}.

   {Right of way} (Law), a right of private passage over
      another's ground. It may arise either by grant or
      prescription. It may be attached to a house, entry, gate,
      well, or city lot, as well as to a country farm. --Kent.
      

   {To be under way}, or {To have way} (Naut.), to be in motion,
      as when a ship begins to move.

   {To give way}. See under {Give}.

   {To go one's way}, or {To come one's way}, to go or come; to
      depart or come along. --Shak.

   {To go one's way} to proceed in a manner favorable to one; --
      of events.

   {To come one's way} to come into one's possession (of
      objects) or to become available, as an opportunity; as,
      good things will come your way.

   {To go the way of all the earth} or

   {to go the way of all flesh} to die.

   {To make one's way}, to advance in life by one's personal
      efforts.

   {To make way}. See under {Make}, v. t.

   {Ways and means}.
       (a) Methods; resources; facilities.
       (b) (Legislation) Means for raising money; resources for
           revenue.

   {Way leave}, permission to cross, or a right of way across,
      land; also, rent paid for such right. [Eng]

   {Way of the cross} (Eccl.), the course taken in visiting in
      rotation the stations of the cross. See {Station}, n., 7
       (c) .

   {Way of the rounds} (Fort.), a space left for the passage of
      the rounds between a rampart and the wall of a fortified
      town.

   {Way pane}, a pane for cartage in irrigated land. See {Pane},
      n., 4. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Way passenger}, a passenger taken up, or set down, at some
      intermediate place between the principal stations on a
      line of travel.

   {Ways of God}, his providential government, or his works.

   {Way station}, an intermediate station between principal
      stations on a line of travel, especially on a railroad.

   {Way train}, a train which stops at the intermediate, or way,
      stations; an accommodation train.

   {Way warden}, the surveyor of a road.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Street; highway; road.

   Usage: {Way}, {Street}, {Highway}, {Road}. Way is generic,
          denoting any line for passage or conveyance; a highway
          is literally one raised for the sake of dryness and
          convenience in traveling; a road is, strictly, a way
          for horses and carriages; a street is, etymologically,
          a paved way, as early made in towns and cities; and,
          hence, the word is distinctively applied to roads or
          highways in compact settlements.
          [1913 Webster]

                All keep the broad highway, and take delight
                With many rather for to go astray. --Spenser.
          [1913 Webster]

                There is but one road by which to climb up.
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

                When night
                Darkens the streets, then wander forth the sons
                Of Belial, flown with insolence and wine.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>way</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Way \Way\, adv. [Aphetic form of away.]
   Away. [Obs. or Archaic] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To do way}, to take away; to remove. [Obs.] ``Do way your
      hands.'' --Chaucer.

   {To make way with}, to make away with. See under {Away}.
      [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>way</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>way
     n 1: how something is done or how it happens; "her dignified
          manner"; "his rapid manner of talking"; "their nomadic
          mode of existence"; "in the characteristic New York
          style"; "a lonely way of life"; "in an abrasive fashion"
          [syn: {manner}, {mode}, {style}, {fashion}]
     2: how a result is obtained or an end is achieved; "a means of
        control"; "an example is the best agency of instruction";
        "the true way to success" [syn: {means}, {agency}]
     3: a journey or passage; "they are on the way"
     4: the condition of things generally; "that's the way it is";
        "I felt the same way"
     5: a course of conduct; "the path of virtue"; "we went our
        separate ways"; "our paths in life led us apart"; "genius
        usually follows a revolutionary path" [syn: {path}, {way
        of life}]
     6: any artifact consisting of a road or path affording passage
        from one place to another; "he said he was looking for the
        way out"
     7: a line leading to a place or point; "he looked the other
        direction"; "didn't know the way home" [syn: {direction}]
     8: the property of distance in general; "it's a long way to
        Moscow"; "he went a long ways" [syn: {ways}]
     9: doing as one pleases or chooses; "if I had my way"
     10: a general category of things; used in the expression `in the
         way of'; "they didn't have much in the way of clothing"
     11: space for movement; "room to pass"; "make way for"; "hardly
         enough elbow room to turn around" [syn: {room}, {elbow
         room}]
     12: a portion of something divided into shares; "the split the
         loot three ways"
     adv : to a great degree or by a great distance; very much (`right
           smart' is regional in the United States); "way over
           budget"; "way off base"; "the other side of the hill is
           right smart steeper than the side we are on" [syn: {right
           smart}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
