<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>weaker</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weaker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Weak \Weak\ (w[=e]k), a. [Compar. {Weaker} (w[=e]k"[~e]r);
   superl. {Weakest}.] [OE. weik, Icel. veikr; akin to Sw. vek,
   Dan. veg soft, flexible, pliant, AS. w[=a]c weak, soft,
   pliant, D. week, G. weich, OHG. weih; all from the verb seen
   in Icel. v[=i]kja to turn, veer, recede, AS. w[=i]can to
   yield, give way, G. weichen, OHG. w[=i]hhan, akin to Skr.
   vij, and probably to E. week, L. vicis a change, turn, Gr.
   e'i`kein to yield, give way. [root]132. Cf. {Week}, {Wink},
   v. i. {Vicissitude}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Wanting physical strength. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) Deficient in strength of body; feeble; infirm; sickly;
          debilitated; enfeebled; exhausted.
          [1913 Webster]

                A poor, infirm, weak, and despised old man.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                Weak with hunger, mad with love.  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) Not able to sustain a great weight, pressure, or
          strain; as, a weak timber; a weak rope.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) Not firmly united or adhesive; easily broken or
          separated into pieces; not compact; as, a weak ship.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) Not stiff; pliant; frail; soft; as, the weak stalk of
          a plant.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) Not able to resist external force or onset; easily
          subdued or overcome; as, a weak barrier; as, a weak
          fortress.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) Lacking force of utterance or sound; not sonorous;
          low; small; feeble; faint.
          [1913 Webster]

                A voice not soft, weak, piping, and womanish.
                                                  --Ascham.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) Not thoroughly or abundantly impregnated with the
          usual or required ingredients, or with stimulating and
          nourishing substances; of less than the usual
          strength; as, weak tea, broth, or liquor; a weak
          decoction or solution; a weak dose of medicine.
          [1913 Webster]
      (h) Lacking ability for an appropriate function or office;
          as, weak eyes; a weak stomach; a weak magistrate; a
          weak regiment, or army.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Not possessing or manifesting intellectual, logical,
      moral, or political strength, vigor, etc. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) Feeble of mind; wanting discernment; lacking vigor;
          spiritless; as, a weak king or magistrate.
          [1913 Webster]

                To think every thing disputable is a proof of a
                weak mind and captious temper.    --Beattie.
          [1913 Webster]

                Origen was never weak enough to imagine that
                there were two Gods.              --Waterland.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) Resulting from, or indicating, lack of judgment,
          discernment, or firmness; unwise; hence, foolish.
          [1913 Webster]

                If evil thence ensue,
                She first his weak indulgence will accuse.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) Not having full confidence or conviction; not decided
          or confirmed; vacillating; wavering.
          [1913 Webster]

                Him that is weak in the faith receive ye, but
                not to doubtful disputations.     --Rom. xiv. 1.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) Not able to withstand temptation, urgency, persuasion,
          etc.; easily impressed, moved, or overcome;
          accessible; vulnerable; as, weak resolutions; weak
          virtue.
          [1913 Webster]

                Guard thy heart
                On this weak side, where most our nature fails.
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) Wanting in power to influence or bind; as, weak ties;
          a weak sense of honor of duty.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) Not having power to convince; not supported by force
          of reason or truth; unsustained; as, a weak argument
          or case. ``Convinced of his weak arguing.'' --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                A case so weak . . . hath much persisted in.
                                                  --Hooker.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) Wanting in point or vigor of expression; as, a weak
          sentence; a weak style.
          [1913 Webster]
      (h) Not prevalent or effective, or not felt to be
          prevalent; not potent; feeble. ``Weak prayers.''
          --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (i) Lacking in elements of political strength; not
          wielding or having authority or energy; deficient in
          the resources that are essential to a ruler or nation;
          as, a weak monarch; a weak government or state.
          [1913 Webster]

                I must make fair weather yet awhile,
                Till Henry be more weak, and I more strong.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (k) (Stock Exchange) Tending towards lower prices; as, a
          weak market.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Gram.)
      (a) Pertaining to, or designating, a verb which forms its
          preterit (imperfect) and past participle by adding to
          the present the suffix -ed, -d, or the variant form
          -t; as in the verbs abash, abashed; abate, abated;
          deny, denied; feel, felt. See {Strong}, 19
      (a) .
      (b) Pertaining to, or designating, a noun in Anglo-Saxon,
          etc., the stem of which ends in -n. See {Strong}, 19
      (b) .
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Stock Exchange) Tending toward a lower price or lower
      prices; as, wheat is weak; a weak market.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   5. (Card Playing) Lacking in good cards; deficient as to
      number or strength; as, a hand weak in trumps.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. (Photog.) Lacking contrast; as, a weak negative.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: Weak is often used in the formation of self-explaining
         compounds; as, weak-eyed, weak-handed, weak-hearted,
         weak-minded, weak-spirited, and the like.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Weak conjugation} (Gram.), the conjugation of weak verbs; --
      called also {new conjugation}, or {regular conjugation},
      and distinguished from the {old conjugation}, or
      {irregular conjugation}.

   {Weak declension} (Anglo-Saxon Gram.), the declension of weak
      nouns; also, one of the declensions of adjectives.

   {Weak side}, the side or aspect of a person's character or
      disposition by which he is most easily affected or
      influenced; weakness; infirmity.

   {weak sore} or {weak ulcer} (Med.), a sore covered with pale,
      flabby, sluggish granulations.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
