<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>weather</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weather</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>WEATHER, n.  The climate of the hour.  A permanent topic of
conversation among persons whom it does not interest, but who have
inherited the tendency to chatter about it from naked arboreal
ancestors whom it keenly concerned.  The setting up official weather
bureaus and their maintenance in mendacity prove that even governments
are accessible to suasion by the rude forefathers of the jungle.

    Once I dipt into the future far as human eye could see,
    And I saw the Chief Forecaster, dead as any one can be --
    Dead and damned and shut in Hades as a liar from his birth,
    With a record of unreason seldom paralleled on earth.
    While I looked he reared him solemnly, that incadescent youth,
    From the coals that he'd preferred to the advantages of truth.
    He cast his eyes about him and above him; then he wrote
    On a slab of thin asbestos what I venture here to quote --
    For I read it in the rose-light of the everlasting glow:
    "Cloudy; variable winds, with local showers; cooler; snow."
                                                         Halcyon Jones


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weather</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Weather \Weath"er\, v. i.
   To undergo or endure the action of the atmosphere; to suffer
   meteorological influences; sometimes, to wear away, or alter,
   under atmospheric influences; to suffer waste by weather.
   [1913 Webster]

         The organisms . . . seem indestructible, while the hard
         matrix in which they are imbedded has weathered from
         around them.                             --H. Miller.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weather</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Weather \Weath"er\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Weathered}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Weathering}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To expose to the air; to air; to season by exposure to
      air.
      [1913 Webster]

            [An eagle] soaring through his wide empire of the
            air
            To weather his broad sails.           --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            This gear lacks weathering.           --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to sustain the trying effect of; to bear up against
      and overcome; to sustain; to endure; to resist; as, to
      weather the storm.
      [1913 Webster]

            For I can weather the roughest gale.  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

            You will weather the difficulties yet. --F. W.
                                                  Robertson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) To sail or pass to the windward of; as, to weather
      a cape; to weather another ship.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Falconry) To place (a hawk) unhooded in the open air.
      --Encyc. Brit.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To weather a point}.
      (a) (Naut.) To pass a point of land, leaving it on the lee
          side.
      (b) Hence, to gain or accomplish anything against
          opposition.

   {To weather out}, to encounter successfully, though with
      difficulty; as, to weather out a storm.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weather</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Weather \Weath"er\, n. [OE. weder, AS. weder; akin to OS. wedar,
   OFries. weder, D. weder, we[^e]r, G. wetter, OHG. wetar,
   Icel. ve[eth]r, Dan. veir, Sw. v["a]der wind, air, weather,
   and perhaps to OSlav. vedro fair weather; or perhaps to Lith.
   vetra storm, Russ. vieter', vietr', wind, and E. wind. Cf.
   {Wither}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The state of the air or atmosphere with respect to heat or
      cold, wetness or dryness, calm or storm, clearness or
      cloudiness, or any other meteorological phenomena;
      meteorological condition of the atmosphere; as, warm
      weather; cold weather; wet weather; dry weather, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not amiss to cool a man's stomach this hot weather.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fair weather cometh out of the north. --Job xxxvii.
                                                  22.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Vicissitude of season; meteorological change; alternation
      of the state of the air. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Storm; tempest.
      [1913 Webster]

            What gusts of weather from that gathering cloud
            My thoughts presage!                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A light rain; a shower. [Obs.] --Wyclif.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Stress of weather}, violent winds; force of tempests.

   {To make fair weather}, to flatter; to give flattering
      representations. [R.]

   {To make good weather}, or {To make bad weather} (Naut.), to
      endure a gale well or ill; -- said of a vessel. --Shak.

   {Under the weather}, ill; also, financially embarrassed.
      [Colloq. U. S.] --Bartlett.

   {Weather box}. Same as {Weather house}, below. --Thackeray.

   {Weather breeder}, a fine day which is supposed to presage
      foul weather.

   {Weather bureau}, a popular name for the signal service. See
      {Signal service}, under {Signal}, a. [U. S.]

   {Weather cloth} (Naut.), a long piece of canvas of tarpaulin
      used to preserve the hammocks from injury by the weather
      when stowed in the nettings.

   {Weather door}. (Mining) See {Trapdoor}, 2.

   {Weather gall}. Same as {Water gall}, 2. [Prov. Eng.]
      --Halliwell.

   {Weather house}, a mechanical contrivance in the form of a
      house, which indicates changes in atmospheric conditions
      by the appearance or retirement of toy images.
      [1913 Webster]

            Peace to the artist whose ingenious thought
            Devised the weather house, that useful toy!
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Weather molding}, or

   {Weather moulding} (Arch.), a canopy or cornice over a door
      or a window, to throw off the rain.

   {Weather of a windmill sail}, the obliquity of the sail, or
      the angle which it makes with its plane of revolution.

   {Weather report}, a daily report of meteorological
      observations, and of probable changes in the weather;
      esp., one published by government authority.

   {Weather spy}, a stargazer; one who foretells the weather.
      [R.] --Donne.

   {Weather strip} (Arch.), a strip of wood, rubber, or other
      material, applied to an outer door or window so as to
      cover the joint made by it with the sill, casings, or
      threshold, in order to exclude rain, snow, cold air, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weather</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Weather \Weath"er\, a. (Naut.)
   Being toward the wind, or windward -- opposed to lee; as,
   weather bow, weather braces, weather gauge, weather lifts,
   weather quarter, weather shrouds, etc.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Weather gauge}.
   (a) (Naut.) The position of a ship to the windward of
       another.
   (b) Fig.: A position of advantage or superiority; advantage
       in position.
       [1913 Webster]

             To veer, and tack, and steer a cause
             Against the weather gauge of laws.   --Hudibras.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Weather helm} (Naut.), a tendency on the part of a sailing
      vessel to come up into the wind, rendering it necessary to
      put the helm up, that is, toward the weather side.

   {Weather shore} (Naut.), the shore to the windward of a ship.
      --Totten.

   {Weather tide} (Naut.), the tide which sets against the lee
      side of a ship, impelling her to the windward. --Mar.
      Dict.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weather</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>weather
     adj : towards the side exposed to wind [syn: {upwind}, {weather(a)}]
     n : the meteorological conditions: temperature and wind and
         clouds and precipitation; "they were hoping for good
         weather"; "every day we have weather conditions and
         yesterday was no exception" [syn: {weather condition}, {atmospheric
         condition}]
     v 1: face or endure with courage; "She braved the elements" [syn:
           {endure}, {brave}, {brave out}]
     2: cause to slope
     3: sail to the windward of
     4: change under the action or influence of the weather; "A
        weathered old hut"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
