<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wedge</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wedge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wedge \Wedge\ (w[e^]j), n. [OE. wegge, AS. wecg; akin to D. wig,
   wigge, OHG. wecki, G. weck a (wedge-shaped) loaf, Icel.
   veggr, Dan. v[ae]gge, Sw. vigg, and probably to Lith. vagis a
   peg. Cf. {Wigg}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A piece of metal, or other hard material, thick at one
      end, and tapering to a thin edge at the other, used in
      splitting wood, rocks, etc., in raising heavy bodies, and
      the like. It is one of the six elementary machines called
      the mechanical powers. See Illust. of {Mechanical powers},
      under {Mechanical}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geom.) A solid of five sides, having a rectangular base,
      two rectangular or trapezoidal sides meeting in an edge,
      and two triangular ends.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A mass of metal, especially when of a wedgelike form.
      ``Wedges of gold.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything in the form of a wedge, as a body of troops drawn
      up in such a form.
      [1913 Webster]

            In warlike muster they appear,
            In rhombs, and wedges, and half-moons, and wings.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The person whose name stands lowest on the list of the
      classical tripos; -- so called after a person (Wedgewood)
      who occupied this position on the first list of 1828.
      [Cant, Cambridge Univ., Eng.] --C. A. Bristed.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Golf) A golf club having an iron head with the face
      nearly horizontal, used for lofting the golf ball at a
      high angle, as when hitting the ball out of a sand trap or
      the rough.
      [PJC]

   {Fox wedge}. (Mach. &amp; Carpentry) See under {Fox}.

   {Spherical wedge} (Geom.), the portion of a sphere included
      between two planes which intersect in a diameter.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wedge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wedge \Wedge\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wedged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Wedging}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To cleave or separate with a wedge or wedges, or as with a
      wedge; to rive. ``My heart, as wedged with a sigh, would
      rive in twain.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To force or drive as a wedge is driven.
      [1913 Webster]

            Among the crowd in the abbey where a finger
            Could not be wedged in more.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He 's just the sort of man to wedge himself into a
            snug berth.                           --Mrs. J. H.
                                                  Ewing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To force by crowding and pushing as a wedge does; as, to
      wedge one's way. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To press closely; to fix, or make fast, in the manner of a
      wedge that is driven into something.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wedged in the rocky shoals, and sticking fast.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To fasten with a wedge, or with wedges; as, to wedge a
      scythe on the snath; to wedge a rail or a piece of timber
      in its place.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Pottery) To cut, as clay, into wedgelike masses, and work
      by dashing together, in order to expel air bubbles, etc.
      --Tomlinson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wedge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wedge
     n 1: any shape that is triangular in cross section [syn: {wedge
          shape}, {cuneus}]
     2: a large sandwich made of a long crusty roll split lengthwise
        and filled with meats and cheese (and tomato and onion and
        lettuce and condiments); different names are used in
        different sections of the United States [syn: {bomber}, {grinder},
         {hero}, {hero sandwich}, {hoagie}, {hoagy}, {Cuban
        sandwich}, {Italian sandwich}, {poor boy}, {sub}, {submarine},
         {submarine sandwich}, {torpedo}, {zep}]
     3: a diacritical mark (an inverted circumflex) placed above
        certain letters (such as c) to indicate pronunciation
        [syn: {hacek}]
     4: a heel that is an extension of the sole of the shoe [syn: {wedge
        heel}]
     5: (golf) an iron with considerable loft and a broad sole
     6: something solid that is usable as an inclined plane (shaped
        like a V) that can be pushed between two things to
        separate them
     7: a block of wood used to prevent the sliding or rolling of a
        heavy object [syn: {chock}]
     v 1: fix, force, or implant; "lodge a bullet in the table" [syn:
          {lodge}, {stick}, {deposit}] [ant: {dislodge}]
     2: squeeze like a wedge into a tight space; "I squeezed myself
        into the corner" [syn: {squeeze}, {force}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
