<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>weight</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Weight \Weight\, n. [OE. weght, wight, AS. gewiht; akin to D.
   gewigt, G. gewicht, Icel. v[ae]tt, Sw. vigt, Dan. v[ae]gt.
   See {Weigh}, v. t.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The quality of being heavy; that property of bodies by
      which they tend toward the center of the earth; the effect
      of gravitative force, especially when expressed in certain
      units or standards, as pounds, grams, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Weight differs from gravity in being the effect of
         gravity, or the downward pressure of a body under the
         influence of gravity; hence, it constitutes a measure
         of the force of gravity, and being the resultant of all
         the forces exerted by gravity upon the different
         particles of the body, it is proportional to the
         quantity of matter in the body.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The quantity of heaviness; comparative tendency to the
      center of the earth; the quantity of matter as estimated
      by the balance, or expressed numerically with reference to
      some standard unit; as, a mass of stone having the weight
      of five hundred pounds.
      [1913 Webster]

            For sorrow, like a heavy-hanging bell,
            Once set on ringing, with his own weight goes.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, pressure; burden; as, the weight of care or
      business. ``The weight of this said time.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            For the public all this weight he bears. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            [He] who singly bore the world's sad weight.
                                                  --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Importance; power; influence; efficacy; consequence;
      moment; impressiveness; as, a consideration of vast
      weight.
      [1913 Webster]

            In such a point of weight, so near mine honor.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A scale, or graduated standard, of heaviness; a mode of
      estimating weight; as, avoirdupois weight; troy weight;
      apothecaries' weight.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A ponderous mass; something heavy; as, a clock weight; a
      paper weight.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man leapeth better with weights in his hands.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A definite mass of iron, lead, brass, or other metal, to
      be used for ascertaining the weight of other bodies; as,
      an ounce weight.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mech.) The resistance against which a machine acts, as
      opposed to the power which moves it. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Atomic weight}. (Chem.) See under {Atomic}, and cf.
      {Element}.

   {Dead weight}, {Feather weight}, {Heavy weight}, {Light
   weight}, etc. See under {Dead}, {Feather}, etc.

   {Weight of observation} (Astron. &amp; Physics), a number
      expressing the most probable relative value of each
      observation in determining the result of a series of
      observations of the same kind.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Ponderousness; gravity; heaviness; pressure; burden;
        load; importance; power; influence; efficacy;
        consequence; moment; impressiveness.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Weight \Weight\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Weighted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Weighting}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To load with a weight or weights; to load down; to make
      heavy; to attach weights to; as, to weight a horse or a
      jockey at a race; to weight a whip handle.
      [1913 Webster]

            The arrows of satire, . . . weighted with sense.
                                                  --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Astron. &amp; Physics) To assign a weight to; to express by a
      number the probable accuracy of, as an observation. See
      {Weight of observations}, under {Weight}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Dyeing) To load (fabrics) as with barite, to increase the
      weight, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. (Math.) to assign a numerical value expressing relative
      importance to (a measurement), to be multiplied by the
      value of the measurement in determining averages or other
      aggregate quantities; as, they weighted part one of the
      test twice as heavily as part 2.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>weight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>weight
     n 1: the vertical force exerted by a mass as a result of gravity
     2: sports equipment used in calisthenic exercises and
        weightlifting; a weight that is not attached to anything
        and is raised and lowered by use of the hands and arms
        [syn: {free weight}, {exercising weight}]
     3: the relative importance granted to something; "his opinion
        carries great weight"
     4: an artifact that is heavy
     5: an oppressive feeling of heavy force; "bowed down by the
        weight of responsibility"
     6: a system of units used to express the weight of something
        [syn: {system of weights}]
     7: a unit used to measure weight; "he placed two weights in the
        scale pan" [syn: {weight unit}]
     8: (statistics) a coefficient assigned to elements of a
        frequency distribution in order to represent their
        relative importance [syn: {weighting}]
     v 1: weight down with a load [syn: {burden}, {burthen}, {weight
          down}] [ant: {unburden}]
     2: present with a bias; "He biased his presentation so as to
        please the share holders" [syn: {slant}, {angle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
