<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>west</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>west</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>West, MS (town, FIPS 78680)
  Location: 33.19812 N, 89.78142 W
  Population (1990): 184 (105 housing units)
  Area: 1.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 39192
West, TX (city, FIPS 77332)
  Location: 31.80321 N, 97.09283 W
  Population (1990): 2515 (1159 housing units)
  Area: 3.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 76691
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>west</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>West \West\, adv. [AS. west.]
   Westward.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>west</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>West \West\, v. i.
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To pass to the west; to set, as the sun. [Obs.] ``The hot
      sun gan to west.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To turn or move toward the west; to veer from the north or
      south toward the west.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>west</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>West \West\, n. [AS. west, adv.; akin to D. west, G. west,
   westen, OHG. westan, Icel. vestr, Sw. vest, vester, vestan,
   Dan. vest, vesten, and perhaps to L. vesper evening, Gr. ?.
   ????. Cf. {Vesper}, {Visigoth}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The point in the heavens where the sun is seen to set at
      the equinox; or, the corresponding point on the earth;
      that one of the four cardinal points of the compass which
      is in a direction at right angles to that of north and
      south, and on the left hand of a person facing north; the
      point directly opposite to east.
      [1913 Webster]

            And fresh from the west is the free wind's breath.
                                                  --Bryant.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A country, or region of country, which, with regard to
      some other country or region, is situated in the direction
      toward the west.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically:
      (a) The Westen hemisphere, or the New World so called, it
          having been discovered by sailing westward from
          Europe; the Occident.
      (b) (U. S. Hist. &amp; Geog.) Formerly, that part of the
          United States west of the Alleghany mountains; now,
          commonly, the whole region west of the Mississippi
          river; esp., that part which is north of the Indian
          Territory, New Mexico, etc. Usually with the definite
          article.
          [1913 Webster]

   {West by north}, {West by south}, according to the notation
      of the mariner's compass, that point which lies 111/4[deg]
      to the north or south, respectively, of the point due
      west.

   {West northwest}, {West southwest}, that point which lies
      221/2[deg] to the north or south of west, or halfway
      between west and northwest or southwest, respectively. See
      Illust. of {Compass}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>west</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>West \West\, a.
   1. Lying toward the west; situated at the west, or in a
      western direction from the point of observation or
      reckoning; proceeding toward the west, or coming from the
      west; as, a west course is one toward the west; an east
      and west line; a west wind blows from the west.
      [1913 Webster]

            This shall be your west border.       --Num. xxxiv.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Eccl.) Designating, or situated in, that part of a church
      which is opposite to, and farthest from, the east, or the
      part containing the chancel and choir.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {West end}, the fashionable part of London, commencing from
      the east, at Charing Cross.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>west</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>west
     adj : situated in or facing or moving toward the west [ant: {east}]
     n 1: the countries of (originally) Europe and (now including)
          North and South America [syn: {Occident}]
     2: the cardinal compass point that is a 270 degrees [syn: {due
        west}, {W}]
     3: the region of the United States lying to the west of the
        Mississippi River [syn: {western United States}]
     4: British writer (born in Ireland) (1892-1983) [syn: {Rebecca
        West}, {Dame Rebecca West}, {Cicily Isabel Fairfield}]
     5: United States film actress (1892-1980) [syn: {Mae West}]
     6: English painter (born in America) who became the second
        president of the Royal Academy (1738-1820) [syn: {Benjamin
        West}]
     adv : to, toward, or in the west; "we moved west to Arizona"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
