<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>whale</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Whale
   The Hebrew word _tan_ (plural, tannin) is so rendered in Job
   7:12 (A.V.; but R.V., "sea-monster"). It is rendered by
   "dragons" in Deut. 32:33; Ps. 91:13; Jer. 51:34; Ps. 74:13
   (marg., "whales;" and marg. of R.V., "sea-monsters"); Isa. 27:1;
   and "serpent" in Ex. 7:9 (R.V. marg., "any large reptile," and
   so in ver. 10, 12). The words of Job (7:12), uttered in bitter
   irony, where he asks, "Am I a sea or a whale?" simply mean,
   "Have I a wild, untamable nature, like the waves of the sea,
   which must be confined and held within bounds, that they cannot
   pass?" "The serpent of the sea, which was but the wild, stormy
   sea itself, wound itself around the land, and threatened to
   swallow it up...Job inquires if he must be watched and plagued
   like this monster, lest he throw the world into disorder"
   (Davidson's Job).
   
     The whale tribe are included under the general Hebrew name
   _tannin_ (Gen. 1:21; Lam. 4:3). "Even the sea-monsters
   [tanninim] draw out the breast." The whale brings forth its
   young alive, and suckles them.
   
     It is to be noticed of the story of Jonah's being "three days
   and three nights in the whale's belly," as recorded in Matt.
   12:40, that here the Gr. ketos means properly any kind of
   sea-monster of the shark or the whale tribe, and that in the
   book of Jonah (1:17) it is only said that "a great fish" was
   prepared to swallow Jonah. This fish may have been, therefore,
   some great shark. The white shark is known to frequent the
   Mediterranean Sea, and is sometimes found 30 feet in length.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Whale \Whale\, n. [OE. whal, AS. hw[ae]l; akin to D. walvisch,
   G. wal, walfisch, OHG. wal, Icel. hvalr, Dan. &amp; Sw. hval,
   hvalfisk. Cf. {Narwhal}, {Walrus}.] (Zo["o]l.)
   Any aquatic mammal of the order {Cetacea}, especially any one
   of the large species, some of which become nearly one hundred
   feet long. Whales are hunted chiefly for their oil and
   baleen, or whalebone.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The existing whales are divided into two groups: the
         toothed whales ({Odontocete}), including those that
         have teeth, as the cachalot, or sperm whale (see {Sperm
         whale}); and the baleen, or whalebone, whales
         ({Mysticete}), comprising those that are destitute of
         teeth, but have plates of baleen hanging from the upper
         jaw, as the right whales. The most important species of
         whalebone whales are the bowhead, or Greenland, whale
         (see Illust. of {Right whale}), the Biscay whale, the
         Antarctic whale, the gray whale (see under {Gray}), the
         humpback, the finback, and the rorqual.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Whale bird}. (Zo["o]l.)
   (a) Any one of several species of large Antarctic petrels
       which follow whaling vessels, to feed on the blubber and
       floating oil; especially, {Prion turtur} (called also
       {blue petrel}), and {Pseudoprion desolatus}.
   (b) The turnstone; -- so called because it lives on the
       carcasses of whales. [Canada]

   {Whale fin} (Com.), whalebone. --Simmonds.

   {Whale fishery}, the fishing for, or occupation of taking,
      whales.

   {Whale louse} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      degraded amphipod crustaceans belonging to the genus
      {Cyamus}, especially {Cyamus ceti}. They are parasitic on
      various cetaceans.

   {Whale's bone}, ivory. [Obs.]

   {Whale shark}. (Zo["o]l.)
   (a) The basking, or liver, shark.
   (b) A very large harmless shark ({Rhinodon typicus}) native
       of the Indian Ocean. It sometimes becomes sixty feet
       long.

   {Whale shot}, the name formerly given to spermaceti.

   {Whale's tongue} (Zo["o]l.), a balanoglossus.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>whale
     n 1: a very large person; impressive in size or qualities [syn: {giant},
           {hulk}, {heavyweight}]
     2: any of the larger cetacean mammals having a streamlined body
        and breathing through a blowhole on the head
     v : hunt for whales
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
