<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>which</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>which</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Which \Which\, pron. [OE. which, whilk, AS. hwilc, hwylc, hwelc,
   from the root of hw[=a] who + l[=i]c body; hence properly, of
   what sort or kind; akin to OS. hwilik which, OFries. hwelik,
   D. welk, G. welch, OHG. wel[=i]h, hwel[=i]h, Icel.
   hv[=i]l[=i]kr, Dan. &amp; Sw. hvilken, Goth. hwileiks, hw?leiks;
   cf. L. qualis. ????. See {Who}, and {Like}, a., and cf.
   {Such}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Of what sort or kind; what; what a; who. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            And which they weren and of what degree. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A interrogative pronoun, used both substantively and
      adjectively, and in direct and indirect questions, to ask
      for, or refer to, an individual person or thing among
      several of a class; as, which man is it? which woman was
      it? which is the house? he asked which route he should
      take; which is best, to live or to die? See the Note under
      {What}, pron., 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Which of you convinceth me of sin?    --John viii.
                                                  46.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A relative pronoun, used esp. in referring to an
      antecedent noun or clause, but sometimes with reference to
      what is specified or implied in a sentence, or to a
      following noun or clause (generally involving a reference,
      however, to something which has preceded). It is used in
      all numbers and genders, and was formerly used of persons.
      [1913 Webster]

            And when thou fail'st -- as God forbid the hour! 
            Must Edward fall, which peril heaven forfend!
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            God . . . rested on the seventh day from all his
            work which he had made.               --Gen. ii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our Father, which art in heaven.      --Matt. vi. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            The temple of God is holy, which temple ye are. --1
                                                  Cor. iii. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A compound relative or indefinite pronoun, standing for
      any one which, whichever, that which, those which, the . .
      . which, and the like; as, take which you will.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The which was formerly often used for which. The
         expressions which that, which as, were also sometimes
         used by way of emphasis.
         [1913 Webster]

               Do not they blaspheme that worthy name by the
               which ye are called?               --James ii. 7.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: Which, referring to a series of preceding sentences, or
         members of a sentence, may have all joined to it
         adjectively. ``All which, as a method of a
         proclamation, is very convenient.'' --Carlyle.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
