<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>whipped</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whipped</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Whip \Whip\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Whipped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Whipping}.] [OE. whippen to overlay, as a cord, with other
   cords, probably akin to G. &amp; D. wippen to shake, to move up
   and down, Sw. vippa, Dan. vippe to swing to and fro, to
   shake, to toss up, and L. vibrare to shake. Cf. {Vibrate}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To strike with a lash, a cord, a rod, or anything slender
      and lithe; to lash; to beat; as, to whip a horse, or a
      carpet.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To drive with lashes or strokes of a whip; to cause to
      rotate by lashing with a cord; as, to whip a top.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To punish with a whip, scourge, or rod; to flog; to beat;
      as, to whip a vagrant; to whip one with thirty nine
      lashes; to whip a perverse boy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who, for false quantities, was whipped at school.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To apply that which hurts keenly to; to lash, as with
      sarcasm, abuse, or the like; to apply cutting language to.
      [1913 Webster]

            They would whip me with their fine wits. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To thrash; to beat out, as grain, by striking; as, to whip
      wheat.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To beat (eggs, cream, or the like) into a froth, as with a
      whisk, fork, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To conquer; to defeat, as in a contest or game; to beat;
      to surpass. [Slang, U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To overlay (a cord, rope, or the like) with other cords
      going round and round it; to overcast, as the edge of a
      seam; to wrap; -- often with about, around, or over.
      [1913 Webster]

            Its string is firmly whipped about with small gut.
                                                  --Moxon.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To sew lightly; specifically, to form (a fabric) into
      gathers by loosely overcasting the rolled edge and drawing
      up the thread; as, to whip a ruffle.
      [1913 Webster]

            In half-whipped muslin needles useless lie. --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To take or move by a sudden motion; to jerk; to snatch;
       -- with into, out, up, off, and the like.
       [1913 Webster]

             She, in a hurry, whips up her darling under her
             arm.                                 --L'Estrange.
       [1913 Webster]

             He whips out his pocketbook every moment, and
             writes descriptions of everything he sees.
                                                  --Walpole.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Naut.)
       (a) To hoist or purchase by means of a whip.
       (b) To secure the end of (a rope, or the like) from
           untwisting by overcasting it with small stuff.
           [1913 Webster]

   12. To fish (a body of water) with a rod and artificial fly,
       the motion being that employed in using a whip.
       [1913 Webster]

             Whipping their rough surface for a trout.
                                                  --Emerson.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To whip in}, to drive in, or keep from scattering, as hounds
      in a hurt; hence, to collect, or to keep together, as
      member of a party, or the like.

   {To whip the cat}.
       (a) To practice extreme parsimony. [Prov. Eng.] --Forby.
       (b) To go from house to house working by the day, as
           itinerant tailors and carpenters do. [Prov. &amp; U. S.]
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whipped</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>whipped
     See {whip}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whipped</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>whip
     n 1: an instrument with a handle and a flexible lash that is used
          for whipping
     2: a legislator appointed by the party to enforce discipline
        [syn: {party whip}]
     3: a dessert made of sugar and stiffly beaten egg whites or
        cream and usually flavored with fruit
     4: (golf) the flexibility of the shaft of a golf club
     5: a quick blow with a whip [syn: {lash}, {whiplash}]
     v 1: beat severely with a whip or rod; "The teacher often flogged
          the students"; "The children were severely trounced"
          [syn: {flog}, {welt}, {lather}, {lash}, {slash}, {strap},
           {trounce}]
     2: defeat thoroughly; "He mopped up the floor with his
        opponents" [syn: {worst}, {pip}, {mop up}, {rack up}]
     3: thrash about flexibly in the manner of a whiplash; "The tall
        grass whipped in the wind"
     4: strike as if by whipping; "The curtain whipped her face"
        [syn: {lash}]
     5: whip with or as if with a wire whisk; "whisk the eggs" [syn:
         {whisk}]
     6: subject to harsh criticism; "The Senator blistered the
        administration in his speech on Friday"; "the professor
        scaled the students"; "your invectives scorched the
        community" [syn: {blister}, {scald}]
     [also: {whipping}, {whipped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
