<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>whole</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whole</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Whole \Whole\, n.
   1. The entire thing; the entire assemblage of parts;
      totality; all of a thing, without defect or exception; a
      thing complete in itself.
      [1913 Webster]

            ``This not the whole of life to live,
            Nor all of death to die.              --J.
                                                  Montgomery.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A regular combination of parts; a system.
      [1913 Webster]

            Parts answering parts shall slide into a whole.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Committee of the whole}. See under {Committee}.

   {Upon the whole}, considering all things; taking everything
      into account; in view of all the circumstances or
      conditions.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Totality; total; amount; aggregate; gross.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whole</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Whole \Whole\, a. [OE. hole, hol, hal, hool, AS. h[=a]l well,
   sound, healthy; akin to OFries. &amp; OS. h?l, D. heel, G. heil,
   Icel. heill, Sw. hel whole, Dan. heel, Goth. hails well,
   sound, OIr. c?l augury. Cf. {Hale}, {Hail} to greet, {Heal}
   to cure, {Health}, {Holy}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Containing the total amount, number, etc.; comprising all
      the parts; free from deficiency; all; total; entire; as,
      the whole earth; the whole solar system; the whole army;
      the whole nation. ``On their whole host I flew unarmed.''
      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The whole race of mankind.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Complete; entire; not defective or imperfect; not broken
      or fractured; unimpaired; uninjured; integral; as, a whole
      orange; the egg is whole; the vessel is whole.
      [1913 Webster]

            My life is yet whole in me.           --2 Sam. i. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Possessing, or being in a state of, heath and soundness;
      healthy; sound; well.
      [1913 Webster]

            [She] findeth there her friends hole and sound.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            They that be whole need not a physician. --Matt. ix.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Sir Lancelot's deadly hurt was whole.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Whole blood}. (Law of Descent) See under {Blood}, n., 2.

   {Whole note} (Mus.), the note which represents a note of
      longest duration in common use; a semibreve.

   {Whole number} (Math.), a number which is not a fraction or
      mixed number; an integer.

   {Whole snipe} (Zo["o]l.), the common snipe, as distinguished
      from the smaller jacksnipe. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: All; total; complete; entire; integral; undivided;
        uninjured; unimpaired; unbroken; healthy.

   Usage: {Whole}, {Total}, {Entire}, {Complete}. When we use
          the word whole, we refer to a thing as made up of
          parts, none of which are wanting; as, a whole week; a
          whole year; the whole creation. When we use the word
          total, we have reference to all as taken together, and
          forming a single totality; as, the total amount; the
          total income. When we speak of a thing as entire, we
          have no reference to parts at all, but regard the
          thing as an integer, i. e., continuous or unbroken;
          as, an entire year; entire prosperity. When we speak
          of a thing as complete, there is reference to some
          progress which results in a filling out to some end or
          object, or a perfected state with no deficiency; as,
          complete success; a complete victory.
          [1913 Webster]

                All the whole army stood agazed on him. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                One entire and perfect chrysolite. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                Lest total darkness should by night regain
                Her old possession, and extinguish life.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                So absolute she seems,
                And in herself complete.          --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whole</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>whole
     adj 1: including all components without exception; being one unit
            or constituting the full amount or extent or duration;
            complete; "gave his whole attention"; "a whole
            wardrobe for the tropics"; "the whole hog"; "a whole
            week"; "the baby cried the whole trip home"; "a whole
            loaf of bread" [ant: {fractional}]
     2: (of siblings) having the same parents; "whole brothers and
        sisters" [ant: {half}]
     3: exhibiting or restored to vigorous good health; "hale and
        hearty"; "whole in mind and body"; "a whole person again"
        [syn: {hale}]
     n 1: all of something including all its component elements or
          parts; "Europe considered as a whole"; "the whole of
          American literature"
     2: an assemblage of parts that is regarded as a single entity;
        "how big is that part compared to the whole?"; "the team
        is a unit" [syn: {whole thing}, {unit}]
     adv : to a complete degree or to the full or entire extent
           (`whole' is often used informally for `wholly'); "he
           was wholly convinced"; "entirely satisfied with the
           meal"; "it was completely different from what we
           expected"; "was completely at fault"; "a totally new
           situation"; "the directions were all wrong"; "it was
           not altogether her fault"; "an altogether new
           approach"; "a whole new idea" [syn: {wholly}, {entirely},
            {completely}, {totally}, {all}, {altogether}] [ant: {partially}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
