<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>whose</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Who \Who\, pron. [Possess. {whose}; object. {Whom}.] [OE. who,
   wha, AS. hw[=a], interrogative pron., neut. hw[ae]t; akin to
   OFries. hwa, neut. hwet, OS. hw[=e], neut. hwat, D. wie,
   neut. wat, G. wer, neut. was, OHG. wer, hwer, neut. waz,
   hwaz, Icel. hvat, neut., Dan. hvo, neut. hvad, Sw. ho, hvem,
   neut. hvad, Goth. hwas, fem. hw[=o], neut. hwa, Lith. kas,
   Ir. &amp; Gael. co, W. pwy, L. quod, neuter of qui, Gr. po`teros
   whether, Skr. kas. [root]182. Cf. {How}, {Quantity},
   {Quorum}, {Quote}, {Ubiquity}, {What}, {When}, {Where},
   {Whether}, {Which}, {Whither}, {Whom}, {Why}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Originally, an interrogative pronoun, later, a relative
      pronoun also; -- used always substantively, and either as
      singular or plural. See the Note under {What}, pron., 1.
      As interrogative pronouns, who and whom ask the question:
      What or which person or persons? Who and whom, as relative
      pronouns (in the sense of that), are properly used of
      persons (corresponding to which, as applied to things),
      but are sometimes, less properly and now rarely, used of
      animals, plants, etc. Who and whom, as compound relatives,
      are also used especially of persons, meaning the person
      that; the persons that; the one that; whosoever. ``Let who
      will be President.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            [He] should not tell whose children they were.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            There thou tell'st of kings, and who aspire;
            Who fall, who rise, who triumph, who do moan.
                                                  --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Adders who with cloven tongues
            Do hiss into madness.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whom I could pity thus forlorn.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            How hard is our fate, who serve in the state.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who cheapens life, abates the fear of death.
                                                  --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

            The brace of large greyhounds, who were the
            companions of his sports.             --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One; any; one. [Obs., except in the archaic phrase, as who
      should say.]
      [1913 Webster]

            As who should say, it were a very dangerous matter
            if a man in any point should be found wiser than his
            forefathers were.                     --Robynson
                                                  (More's
                                                  Utopia).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>whose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Whose \Whose\ (h[=oo]z), pron. [OE. whos, whas, AS. hw[ae]s,
   gen. of hw[=a]. See {Who}.]
   The possessive case of who or which. See {Who}, and {Which}.
   [1913 Webster]

         Whose daughter art thou? tell me, I pray thee. --Gen.
                                                  xxiv. 23.
   [1913 Webster]

         The question whose solution I require.   --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
