<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wider</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wide \Wide\ (w[imac]d), a. [Compar. {Wider} (-[~e]r); superl.
   {Widest}.] [OE. wid, wyde, AS. w[=i]d; akin to OFries. &amp; OS.
   w[=i]d, D. wijd, G. weit, OHG. w[=i]t, Icel. v[=i][eth]r, Sw.
   &amp; Dan. vid; of uncertain origin.]
   1. Having considerable distance or extent between the sides;
      spacious across; much extended in a direction at right
      angles to that of length; not narrow; broad; as, wide
      cloth; a wide table; a wide highway; a wide bed; a wide
      hall or entry.
      [1913 Webster]

            The chambers and the stables weren wyde. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wide is the gate . . . that leadeth to destruction.
                                                  --Matt. vii.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Having a great extent every way; extended; spacious;
      broad; vast; extensive; as, a wide plain; the wide ocean;
      a wide difference. ``This wyde world.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            For sceptered cynics earth were far too wide a den.
                                                  --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the wide bloom, on earth that lies,
            Seems of a brighter world than ours.  --Bryant.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Of large scope; comprehensive; liberal; broad; as, wide
      views; a wide understanding.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men of strongest head and widest culture. --M.
                                                  Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Of a certain measure between the sides; measuring in a
      direction at right angles to that of length; as, a table
      three feet wide.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Remote; distant; far.
      [1913 Webster]

            The contrary being so wide from the truth of
            Scripture and the attributes of God.  --Hammond.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Far from truth, from propriety, from necessity, or the
      like. ``Our wide expositors.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is far wide that the people have such judgments.
                                                  --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

            How wide is all this long pretense !  --Herbert.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. On one side or the other of the mark; too far side-wise
      from the mark, the wicket, the batsman, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Surely he shoots wide on the bow hand. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was but two bows wide.              --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Phon.) Made, as a vowel, with a less tense, and more open
      and relaxed, condition of the mouth organs; -- opposed to
      primary as used by Mr. Bell, and to narrow as used by Mr.
      Sweet. The effect, as explained by Mr. Bell, is due to the
      relaxation or tension of the pharynx; as explained by Mr.
      Sweet and others, it is due to the action of the tongue.
      The wide of [=e] ([=e]ve) is [i^] ([i^]ll); of [=a]
      ([=a]te) is [e^] ([e^]nd), etc. See Guide to
      Pronunciation, [sect] 13-15.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Stock Exchanges) Having or showing a wide difference
      between the highest and lowest price, amount of supply,
      etc.; as, a wide opening; wide prices, where the prices
      bid and asked differ by several points.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: Wide is often prefixed to words, esp. to participles
         and participial adjectives, to form self-explaining
         compounds; as, wide-beaming, wide-branched,
         wide-chopped, wide-echoing, wide-extended,
         wide-mouthed, wide-spread, wide-spreading, and the
         like.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Far and wide}. See under {Far}.

   {Wide gauge}. See the Note under {Cauge}, 6.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
