<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>width</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>width</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Set \Set\, n.
   1. The act of setting, as of the sun or other heavenly body;
      descent; hence, the close; termination. ``Locking at the
      set of day.'' --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            The weary sun hath made a golden set. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is set, placed, or fixed. Specifically:
      (a) A young plant for growth; as, a set of white thorn.
      (b) That which is staked; a wager; a venture; a stake;
          hence, a game at venture. [Obs. or R.]
          [1913 Webster]

                We will in France, by God's grace, play a set
                Shall strike his father's crown into the hazard.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                That was but civil war, an equal set. --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) (Mech.) Permanent change of figure in consequence of
          excessive strain, as from compression, tension,
          bending, twisting, etc.; as, the set of a spring.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) A kind of punch used for bending, indenting, or giving
          shape to, metal; as, a saw set.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) (Pile Driving) A piece placed temporarily upon the
          head of a pile when the latter cannot be reached by
          the weight, or hammer, except by means of such an
          intervening piece. [Often incorrectly written {sett}.]
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) (Carp.) A short steel spike used for driving the head
          of a nail below the surface. Called also {nail set}.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. [Perhaps due to confusion with sect, sept.] A number of
      things of the same kind, ordinarily used or classed
      together; a collection of articles which naturally
      complement each other, and usually go together; an
      assortment; a suit; as, a set of chairs, of china, of
      surgical or mathematical instruments, of books, etc. [In
      this sense, sometimes incorrectly written {sett}.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A number of persons associated by custom, office, common
      opinion, quality, or the like; a division; a group; a
      clique. ``Others of our set.'' --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            This falls into different divisions, or sets, of
            nations connected under particular religions. --R.
                                                  P. Ward.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Direction or course; as, the set of the wind, or of a
      current.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. In dancing, the number of persons necessary to execute a
      quadrille; also, the series of figures or movements
      executed.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The deflection of a tooth, or of the teeth, of a saw,
      which causes the the saw to cut a kerf, or make an
      opening, wider than the blade.
      [1913 Webster]

   8.
      (a) A young oyster when first attached.
      (b) Collectively, the crop of young oysters in any
          locality.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Tennis) A series of as many games as may be necessary to
      enable one side to win six. If at the end of the tenth
      game the score is a tie, the set is usually called a deuce
      set, and decided by an application of the rules for
      playing off deuce in a game. See {Deuce}.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Type Founding) That dimension of the body of a type
       called by printers the {width}.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Textiles) Any of various standards of measurement of the
       fineness of cloth; specif., the number of reeds in one
       inch and the number of threads in each reed. The exact
       meaning varies according to the location where it is
       used. Sometimes written {sett}.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. A stone, commonly of granite, shaped like a short brick
       and usually somewhat larger than one, used for street
       paving. Commonly written {sett}.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   13. Camber of a curved roofing tile.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   14. The manner, state, or quality of setting or fitting; fit;
       as, the set of a coat. [Colloq.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   15. Any collection or group of objects considered together.
       [PJC]

   {Dead set}.
       (a) The act of a setter dog when it discovers the game,
           and remains intently fixed in pointing it out.
       (b) A fixed or stationary condition arising from obstacle
           or hindrance; a deadlock; as, to be at a dead set.
       (c) A concerted scheme to defraud by gaming; a determined
           onset.

   {To make a dead set}, to make a determined onset, literally
      or figuratively.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Collection; series; group. See {Pair}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>width</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Width \Width\, n. [From {Wide}.]
   The quality of being wide; extent from side to side; breadth;
   wideness; as, the width of cloth; the width of a door.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>width</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>width
     n : the extent of something from side to side [syn: {breadth}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
