<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wielding</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wielding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wield \Wield\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wielded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Wielding}.] [OE. welden to govern, to have power over, to
   possess, AS. geweldan, gewyldan, from wealdan; akin to OS.
   waldan, OFries. walda, G. walten, OHG. waltan, Icel. valda,
   Sw. v[*a]lla to occasion, to cause, Dan. volde, Goth. waldan
   to govern, rule, L. valere to be strong. Cf. {Herald},
   {Valiant}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To govern; to rule; to keep, or have in charge; also, to
      possess. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            When a strong armed man keepeth his house, all
            things that he wieldeth ben in peace. --Wyclif (Luke
                                                  xi. 21).
      [1913 Webster]

            Wile [ne will] ye wield gold neither silver ne money
            in your girdles.                      --Wyclif
                                                  (Matt. x. 9.)
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To direct or regulate by influence or authority; to
      manage; to control; to sway.
      [1913 Webster]

            The famous orators . . . whose resistless eloquence
            Wielded at will that fierce democraty. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her newborn power was wielded from the first by
            unprincipled and ambitions men.       --De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To use with full command or power, as a thing not too
      heavy for the holder; to manage; to handle; hence, to use
      or employ; as, to wield a sword; to wield the scepter.
      [1913 Webster]

            Base Hungarian wight! wilt thou the spigot wield!
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Part wield their arms, part curb the foaming steed.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing but the influence of a civilized power could
            induce a savage to wield a spade.     --S. S. Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To wield the scepter}, to govern with supreme command.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wielding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wielding \Wield"ing\, n.
   Power; authority; rule. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         To have them in your might and in your wielding.
                                                  --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
