<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wife</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wife</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wife
   The ordinance of marriage was sanctioned in Paradise (Gen. 2:24;
   Matt. 19:4-6). Monogamy was the original law under which man
   lived, but polygamy early commenced (Gen. 4:19), and continued
   to prevail all down through Jewish history. The law of Moses
   regulated but did not prohibit polygamy. A man might have a
   plurality of wives, but a wife could have only one husband. A
   wife's legal rights (Ex. 21:10) and her duties (Prov. 31:10-31;
   1 Tim. 5:14) are specified. She could be divorced in special
   cases (Deut. 22:13-21), but could not divorce her husband.
   Divorce was restricted by our Lord to the single case of
   adultery (Matt. 19:3-9). The duties of husbands and wives in
   their relations to each other are distinctly set forth in the
   New Testament (1 Cor. 7:2-5; Eph. 5:22-33; Col. 3:18, 19; 1 Pet.
   3:1-7).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wife</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wife \Wife\, n.; pl. {Wives}. [OE. wif, AS. wif; akin to OFries.
   &amp; OS. wif, D. wijf, G. weib, OHG. w[=i]b, Icel. v[=i]f, Dan.
   viv; and perhaps to Skr. vip excited, agitated, inspired, vip
   to tremble, L. vibrare to vibrate, E. vibrate. Cf. Tacitus,
   [`` Germania'' 8]: Inesse quin etiam sanctum aliquid et
   providum putant, nec aut consilia earum aspernantur aut
   responsa neglegunt. Cf. {Hussy} a jade, {Woman}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A woman; an adult female; -- now used in literature only
      in certain compounds and phrases, as alewife, fishwife,
      goodwife, and the like. `` Both men and wives.'' --Piers
      Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            On the green he saw sitting a wife.   --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The lawful consort of a man; a woman who is united to a
      man in wedlock; a woman who has a husband; a married
      woman; -- correlative of husband. `` The husband of one
      wife.'' --1 Tin. iii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let every one you . . . so love his wife even as
            himself, and the wife see that she reverence her
            husband.                              --Eph. v. 33.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To give to wife}, {To take to wife}, to give or take (a
      woman) in marriage.

   {Wife's equity} (Law), the equitable right or claim of a
      married woman to a reasonable and adequate provision, by
      way of settlement or otherwise, out of her choses in
      action, or out of any property of hers which is under the
      jurisdiction of the Court of Chancery, for the support of
      herself and her children. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wife</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wife
     n : a married woman; a man's partner in marriage [syn: {married
         woman}] [ant: {husband}]
     [also: {wives} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
