<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wind</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wound} (wound) (rarely
   {Winded}); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Winding}.] [OE. winden, AS.
   windan; akin to OS. windan, D. &amp; G. winden, OHG. wintan,
   Icel. &amp; Sw. vinda, Dan. vinde, Goth. windan (in comp.). Cf.
   {Wander}, {Wend}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To turn completely, or with repeated turns; especially, to
      turn about something fixed; to cause to form convolutions
      about anything; to coil; to twine; to twist; to wreathe;
      as, to wind thread on a spool or into a ball.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether to wind
            The woodbine round this arbor.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To entwist; to infold; to encircle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sleep, and I will wind thee in arms.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To have complete control over; to turn and bend at one's
      pleasure; to vary or alter or will; to regulate; to
      govern. ``To turn and wind a fiery Pegasus.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In his terms so he would him wind.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gifts blind the wise, and bribes do please
            And wind all other witnesses.         --Herrick.
      [1913 Webster]

            Were our legislature vested in the prince, he might
            wind and turn our constitution at his pleasure.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To introduce by insinuation; to insinuate.
      [1913 Webster]

            You have contrived . . . to wind
            Yourself into a power tyrannical.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Little arts and dexterities they have to wind in
            such things into discourse.           --Gov. of
                                                  Tongue.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cover or surround with something coiled about; as, to
      wind a rope with twine.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To wind off}, to unwind; to uncoil.

   {To wind out}, to extricate. [Obs.] --Clarendon.

   {To wind up}.
      (a) To coil into a ball or small compass, as a skein of
          thread; to coil completely.
      (b) To bring to a conclusion or settlement; as, to wind up
          one's affairs; to wind up an argument.
      (c) To put in a state of renewed or continued motion, as a
          clock, a watch, etc., by winding the spring, or that
          which carries the weight; hence, to prepare for
          continued movement or action; to put in order anew.
          ``Fate seemed to wind him up for fourscore years.''
          --Dryden. ``Thus they wound up his temper to a
          pitch.'' --Atterbury.
      (d) To tighten (the strings) of a musical instrument, so
          as to tune it. ``Wind up the slackened strings of thy
          lute.'' --Waller.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\, n.
   The act of winding or turning; a turn; a bend; a twist; a
   winding.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\ (w[i^]nd, in poetry and singing often w[imac]nd;
   277), n. [AS. wind; akin to OS., OFries., D., &amp; G. wind, OHG.
   wint, Dan. &amp; Sw. vind, Icel. vindr, Goth winds, W. gwynt, L.
   ventus, Skr. v[=a]ta (cf. Gr. 'ah`ths a blast, gale, 'ah^nai
   to breathe hard, to blow, as the wind); originally a p. pr.
   from the verb seen in Skr. v[=a] to blow, akin to AS.
   w[=a]wan, D. waaijen, G. wehen, OHG. w[=a]en, w[=a]jen, Goth.
   waian. [root]131. Cf. {Air}, {Ventail}, {Ventilate},
   {Window}, {Winnow}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Air naturally in motion with any degree of velocity; a
      current of air.
      [1913 Webster]

            Except wind stands as never it stood,
            It is an ill wind that turns none to good. --Tusser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Winds were soft, and woods were green. --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Air artificially put in motion by any force or action; as,
      the wind of a cannon ball; the wind of a bellows.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Breath modulated by the respiratory and vocal organs, or
      by an instrument.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their instruments were various in their kind,
            Some for the bow, and some for breathing wind.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Power of respiration; breath.
      [1913 Webster]

            If my wind were but long enough to say my prayers, I
            would repent.                         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Air or gas generated in the stomach or bowels; flatulence;
      as, to be troubled with wind.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Air impregnated with an odor or scent.
      [1913 Webster]

            A pack of dogfish had him in the wind. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A direction from which the wind may blow; a point of the
      compass; especially, one of the cardinal points, which are
      often called the four winds.
      [1913 Webster]

            Come from the four winds, O breath, and breathe upon
            these slain.                          --Ezek.
                                                  xxxvii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: This sense seems to have had its origin in the East.
         The Hebrews gave to each of the four cardinal points
         the name of wind.
         [1913 Webster]

   8. (Far.) A disease of sheep, in which the intestines are
      distended with air, or rather affected with a violent
      inflammation. It occurs immediately after shearing.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Mere breath or talk; empty effort; idle words.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor think thou with wind
            Of airy threats to awe.               --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Zo["o]l.) The dotterel. [Prov. Eng.]
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Boxing) The region of the pit of the stomach, where a
       blow may paralyze the diaphragm and cause temporary loss
       of breath or other injury; the mark. [Slang or Cant]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: Wind is often used adjectively, or as the first part of
         compound words.
         [1913 Webster]

   {All in the wind}. (Naut.) See under {All}, n.

   {Before the wind}. (Naut.) See under {Before}.

   {Between wind and water} (Naut.), in that part of a ship's
      side or bottom which is frequently brought above water by
      the rolling of the ship, or fluctuation of the water's
      surface. Hence, colloquially, (as an injury to that part
      of a vessel, in an engagement, is particularly dangerous)
      the vulnerable part or point of anything.

   {Cardinal winds}. See under {Cardinal}, a.

   {Down the wind}.
       (a) In the direction of, and moving with, the wind; as,
           birds fly swiftly down the wind.
       (b) Decaying; declining; in a state of decay. [Obs.] ``He
           went down the wind still.'' --L'Estrange.

   {In the wind's eye} (Naut.), directly toward the point from
      which the wind blows.

   {Three sheets in the wind}, unsteady from drink. [Sailors'
      Slang]

   {To be in the wind}, to be suggested or expected; to be a
      matter of suspicion or surmise. [Colloq.]

   {To carry the wind} (Man.), to toss the nose as high as the
      ears, as a horse.

   {To raise the wind}, to procure money. [Colloq.]

   {To take the wind} or {To have the wind}, to gain or have the
      advantage. --Bacon.

   {To take the wind out of one's sails}, to cause one to stop,
      or lose way, as when a vessel intercepts the wind of
      another; to cause one to lose enthusiasm, or momentum in
      an activity. [Colloq.]

   {To take wind}, or {To get wind}, to be divulged; to become
      public; as, the story got wind, or took wind.

   {Wind band} (Mus.), a band of wind instruments; a military
      band; the wind instruments of an orchestra.

   {Wind chest} (Mus.), a chest or reservoir of wind in an
      organ.

   {Wind dropsy}. (Med.)
       (a) Tympanites.
       (b) Emphysema of the subcutaneous areolar tissue.

   {Wind egg}, an imperfect, unimpregnated, or addled egg.

   {Wind furnace}. See the Note under {Furnace}.

   {Wind gauge}. See under {Gauge}.

   {Wind gun}. Same as {Air gun}.

   {Wind hatch} (Mining), the opening or place where the ore is
      taken out of the earth.

   {Wind instrument} (Mus.), an instrument of music sounded by
      means of wind, especially by means of the breath, as a
      flute, a clarinet, etc.

   {Wind pump}, a pump moved by a windmill.

   {Wind rose}, a table of the points of the compass, giving the
      states of the barometer, etc., connected with winds from
      the different directions.

   {Wind sail}.
       (a) (Naut.) A wide tube or funnel of canvas, used to
           convey a stream of air for ventilation into the lower
           compartments of a vessel.
       (b) The sail or vane of a windmill.

   {Wind shake}, a crack or incoherence in timber produced by
      violent winds while the timber was growing.

   {Wind shock}, a wind shake.

   {Wind side}, the side next the wind; the windward side. [R.]
      --Mrs. Browning.

   {Wind rush} (Zo["o]l.), the redwing. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Wind wheel}, a motor consisting of a wheel moved by wind.

   {Wood wind} (Mus.), the flutes and reed instruments of an
      orchestra, collectively.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\, v. i.
   1. To turn completely or repeatedly; to become coiled about
      anything; to assume a convolved or spiral form; as, vines
      wind round a pole.
      [1913 Webster]

            So swift your judgments turn and wind. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To have a circular course or direction; to crook; to bend;
      to meander; as, to wind in and out among trees.
      [1913 Webster]

            And where the valley winded out below,
            The murmuring main was heard, and scarcely heard, to
            flow.                                 --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

            He therefore turned him to the steep and rocky path
            which . . . winded through the thickets of wild
            boxwood and other low aromatic shrubs. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To go to the one side or the other; to move this way and
      that; to double on one's course; as, a hare pursued turns
      and winds.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lowing herd wind ?lowly o'er the lea. --Gray.
      [1913 Webster]

            To wind out, to extricate one's self; to escape.
            Long struggling underneath are they could wind
            Out of such prison.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Winded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Winding}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To expose to the wind; to winnow; to ventilate.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perceive or follow by the scent; to scent; to nose; as,
      the hounds winded the game.
      [1913 Webster]

   3.
      (a) To drive hard, or force to violent exertion, as a
          horse, so as to render scant of wind; to put out of
          breath.
      (b) To rest, as a horse, in order to allow the breath to
          be recovered; to breathe.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To wind a ship} (Naut.), to turn it end for end, so that the
      wind strikes it on the opposite side.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\, v. t. [From {Wind}, moving air, but confused in
   sense and in conjugation with wind to turn.] [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Wound} (wound), R. {Winded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Winding}.]
   To blow; to sound by blowing; esp., to sound with prolonged
   and mutually involved notes. ``Hunters who wound their
   horns.'' --Pennant.
   [1913 Webster]

         Ye vigorous swains, while youth ferments your blood, .
         . .
         Wind the shrill horn.                    --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]

         That blast was winded by the king.       --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wind
     n 1: air moving (sometimes with considerable force) from an area
          of high pressure to an area of low pressure; "trees bent
          under the fierce winds"; "when there is no wind, row";
          "the radioactivity was being swept upwards by the air
          current and out into the atmosphere" [syn: {air current},
           {current of air}]
     2: a tendency or force that influences events; "the winds of
        change"
     3: breath; "the collision knocked the wind out of him"
     4: empty rhetoric or insincere or exaggerated talk; "that's a
        lot of wind"; "don't give me any of that jazz" [syn: {idle
        words}, {jazz}, {nothingness}]
     5: an indication of potential opportunity; "he got a tip on the
        stock market"; "a good lead for a job" [syn: {tip}, {lead},
         {steer}, {confidential information}, {hint}]
     6: a musical instrument in which the sound is produced by an
        enclosed column of air that is moved by the breath [syn: {wind
        instrument}]
     7: a reflex that expels intestinal gas through the anus [syn: {fart},
         {farting}, {flatus}, {breaking wind}]
     8: the act of winding or twisting; "he put the key in the old
        clock and gave it a good wind" [syn: {winding}, {twist}]
     v 1: to move or cause to move in a sinuous, spiral, or circular
          course; "the river winds through the hills"; "the path
          meanders through the vineyards"; "sometimes, the gout
          wanders through the entire body" [syn: {weave}, {thread},
           {meander}, {wander}]
     2: extend in curves and turns; "The road winds around the lake"
        [syn: {curve}]
     3: wrap or coil around; "roll your hair around your finger";
        "Twine the thread around the spool" [syn: {wrap}, {roll},
        {twine}] [ant: {unwind}]
     4: catch the scent of; get wind of; "The dog nosed out the
        drugs" [syn: {scent}, {nose}]
     5: coil the spring of (some mechanical device) by turning a
        stem; "wind your watch" [syn: {wind up}]
     6: form into a wreath [syn: {wreathe}]
     7: raise or haul up with or as if with mechanical help; "hoist
        the bicycle onto the roof of the car" [syn: {hoist}, {lift}]
     [also: {wound}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
