<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>window</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>window</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Window
   properly only an opening in a house for the admission of light
   and air, covered with lattice-work, which might be opened or
   closed (2 Kings 1:2; Acts 20:9). The spies in Jericho and Paul
   at Damascus were let down from the windows of houses abutting on
   the town wall (Josh. 2:15; 2 Cor. 11:33). The clouds are
   metaphorically called the "windows of heaven" (Gen. 7:11; Mal.
   3:10). The word thus rendered in Isa. 54:12 ought rather to be
   rendered "battlements" (LXX., "bulwarks;" R.V., "pinnacles"), or
   as Gesenius renders it, "notched battlements, i.e., suns or rays
   of the sun"= having a radiated appearance like the sun.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>window</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Window \Win"dow\, n. [OE. windowe, windoge, Icel. vindauga
   window, properly, wind eye; akin to Dan. vindue. ????. See
   {Wind}, n., and {Eye}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. An opening in the wall of a building for the admission of
      light and air, usually closed by casements or sashes
      containing some transparent material, as glass, and
      capable of being opened and shut at pleasure.
      [1913 Webster]

            I leaped from the window of the citadel. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then to come, in spite of sorrow,
            And at my window bid good morrow.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) The shutter, casement, sash with its fittings, or
      other framework, which closes a window opening.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A figure formed of lines crossing each other. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Till he has windows on his bread and butter. --King.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. a period of time in which some activity may be uniquely
      possible, more easily accomplished, or more likely to
      succeed; as, a launch window for a mission to Mars.
      [PJC]

   5. (Computers) a region on a computer display screen which
      represents a separate computational process, controlled
      more or less independently from the remaining part of the
      screen, and having widely varying functions, from simply
      displaying information to comprising a separate conceptual
      screen in which output can be visualized, input can be
      controlled, program dialogs may be accomplished, and a
      program may be controlled independently of any other
      processes occurring in the computer. The window may have a
      fixed location and size, or (as in modern Graphical User
      Interfaces) may have its size and location on the screen
      under the control of the operator.
      [PJC]

   {French window} (Arch.), a casement window in two folds,
      usually reaching to the floor; -- called also {French
      casement}.

   {Window back} (Arch.), the inside face of the low, and
      usually thin, piece of wall between the window sill and
      the floor below.

   {Window blind}, a blind or shade for a window.

   {Window bole}, part of a window closed by a shutter which can
      be opened at will. [Scot.]

   {Window box}, one of the hollows in the sides of a window
      frame for the weights which counterbalance a lifting sash.
      

   {Window frame}, the frame of a window which receives and
      holds the sashes or casement.

   {Window glass}, panes of glass for windows; the kind of glass
      used in windows.

   {Window martin} (Zo["o]l.), the common European martin.
      [Prov. Eng.]

   {Window oyster} (Zo["o]l.), a marine bivalve shell ({Placuna
      placenta}) native of the East Indies and China. Its valves
      are very broad, thin, and translucent, and are said to
      have been used formerly in place of glass.

   {Window pane}.
      (a) (Arch.) See {Pane}, n., 3
      (b) .
      (b) (Zo["o]l.) See {Windowpane}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Window sash}, the sash, or light frame, in which panes of
      glass are set for windows.

   {Window seat}, a seat arranged in the recess of a window. See
      {Window stool}, under {Stool}.

   {Window shade}, a shade or blind for a window; usually, one
      that is hung on a roller.

   {Window shell} (Zo["o]l.), the window oyster.

   {Window shutter}, a shutter or blind used to close or darken
      windows.

   {Window sill} (Arch.), the flat piece of wood, stone, or the
      like, at the bottom of a window frame.

   {Window swallow} (Zo["o]l.), the common European martin.
      [Prov. Eng.]

   {Window tax}, a tax or duty formerly levied on all windows,
      or openings for light, above the number of eight in houses
      standing in cities or towns. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>window</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Window \Win"dow\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Windowed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Windowing}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To furnish with windows.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To place at or in a window. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Wouldst thou be windowed in great Rome and see
            Thy master thus with pleach'd arms, bending down
            His corrigible neck?                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>window</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>window
     n 1: a framework of wood or metal that contains a glass
          windowpane and is built into a wall or roof to admit
          light or air
     2: a transparent opening in a vehicle that allow vision out of
        the sides or back; usually is capable of being opened
     3: a transparent panel (as of an envelope) inserted in an
        otherwise opaque material
     4: an opening that resembles a window in appearance or
        function; "he could see them through a window in the
        trees"
     5: the time period that is considered best for starting or
        finishing something; "the expanded window will give us
        time to catch the thieves"; "they had a window of less
        than an hour when an attack would have succeeded"
     6: a pane in a window; "the ball shattered the window" [syn: {windowpane}]
     7: an opening in the wall of a building (usually to admit light
        and air); "he stuck his head in the window"
     8: (computer science) a rectangular part of a computer screen
        that contains a display different from the rest of the
        screen
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
