<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wine</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>WINE, n.  Fermented grape-juice known to the Women's Christian Union
as "liquor," sometimes as "rum."  Wine, madam, is God's next best gift
to man.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wine
   The common Hebrew word for wine is _yayin_, from a root meaning
   "to boil up," "to be in a ferment." Others derive it from a root
   meaning "to tread out," and hence the juice of the grape trodden
   out. The Greek word for wine is _oinos_, and the Latin _vinun_.
   But besides this common Hebrew word, there are several others
   which are thus rendered.
   
     (1.) Ashishah (2 Sam. 6:19; 1 Chr. 16:3; Cant. 2:5; Hos. 3:1),
   which, however, rather denotes a solid cake of pressed grapes,
   or, as in the Revised Version, a cake of raisins.
   
     (2.) 'Asis, "sweet wine," or "new wine," the product of the
   same year (Cant. 8:2; Isa. 49:26; Joel 1:5; 3:18; Amos 9:13),
   from a root meaning "to tread," hence juice trodden out or
   pressed out, thus referring to the method by which the juice is
   obtained. The power of intoxication is ascribed to it.
   
     (3.) Hometz. See {VINEGAR}.
   
     (4.) Hemer, Deut. 32:14 (rendered "blood of the grape") Isa.
   27:2 ("red wine"), Ezra 6:9; 7:22; Dan. 5:1, 2, 4. This word
   conveys the idea of "foaming," as in the process of
   fermentation, or when poured out. It is derived from the root
   _hamar_, meaning "to boil up," and also "to be red," from the
   idea of boiling or becoming inflamed.
   
     (5.) 'Enabh, a grape (Deut. 32:14). The last clause of this
   verse should be rendered as in the Revised Version, "and of the
   blood of the grape ['enabh] thou drankest wine [hemer]." In Hos.
   3:1 the phrase in Authorized Version, "flagons of wine," is in
   the Revised Version correctly "cakes of raisins." (Comp. Gen.
   49:11; Num. 6:3; Deut. 23:24, etc., where this Hebrew word is
   rendered in the plural "grapes.")
   
     (6.) Mesekh, properly a mixture of wine and water with spices
   that increase its stimulating properties (Isa. 5:22). Ps. 75:8,
   "The wine [yayin] is red; it is full of mixture [mesekh];" Prov.
   23:30, "mixed wine;" Isa. 65:11, "drink offering" (R.V.,
   "mingled wine").
   
     (7.) Tirosh, properly "must," translated "wine" (Deut. 28:51);
   "new wine" (Prov. 3:10); "sweet wine" (Micah 6:15; R.V.,
   "vintage"). This Hebrew word has been traced to a root meaning
   "to take possession of" and hence it is supposed that tirosh is
   so designated because in intoxicating it takes possession of the
   brain. Among the blessings promised to Esau (Gen. 27:28) mention
   is made of "plenty of corn and tirosh." Palestine is called "a
   land of corn and tirosh" (Deut. 33:28; comp. Isa. 36:17). See
   also Deut. 28:51; 2 Chr. 32:28; Joel 2:19; Hos. 4:11, ("wine
   [yayin] and new wine [tirosh] take away the heart").
   
     (8.) Sobhe (root meaning "to drink to excess," "to suck up,"
   "absorb"), found only in Isa. 1:22, Hos. 4:18 ("their drink;"
   Gesen. and marg. of R.V., "their carouse"), and Nah. 1:10
   ("drunken as drunkards;" lit., "soaked according to their
   drink;" R.V., "drenched, as it were, in their drink", i.e.,
   according to their sobhe).
   
     (9.) Shekar, "strong drink," any intoxicating liquor; from a
   root meaning "to drink deeply," "to be drunken", a generic term
   applied to all fermented liquors, however obtained. Num. 28:7,
   "strong wine" (R.V., "strong drink"). It is sometimes
   distinguished from wine, c.g., Lev. 10:9, "Do not drink wine
   [yayin] nor strong drink [shekar];" Num. 6:3; Judg. 13:4, 7;
   Isa. 28:7 (in all these places rendered "strong drink").
   Translated "strong drink" also in Isa. 5:11; 24:9; 29:9; 56:12;
   Prov. 20:1; 31:6; Micah 2:11.
   
     (10.) Yekebh (Deut. 16:13, but in R.V. correctly
   "wine-press"), a vat into which the new wine flowed from the
   press. Joel 2:24, "their vats;" 3:13, "the fats;" Prov. 3:10,
   "Thy presses shall burst out with new wine [tirosh];" Hag. 2:16;
   Jer. 48:33, "wine-presses;" 2 Kings 6:27; Job. 24:11.
   
     (11.) Shemarim (only in plural), "lees" or "dregs" of wine. In
   Isa. 25:6 it is rendered "wines on the lees", i.e., wine that
   has been kept on the lees, and therefore old wine.
   
     (12.) Mesek, "a mixture," mixed or spiced wine, not diluted
   with water, but mixed with drugs and spices to increase its
   strength, or, as some think, mingled with the lees by being
   shaken (Ps. 75:8; Prov. 23:30).
   
     In Acts 2:13 the word _gleukos_, rendered "new wine," denotes
   properly "sweet wine." It must have been intoxicating.
   
     In addition to wine the Hebrews also made use of what they
   called _debash_, which was obtained by boiling down must to
   one-half or one-third of its original bulk. In Gen. 43:11 this
   word is rendered "honey." It was a kind of syrup, and is called
   by the Arabs at the present day dibs. This word occurs in the
   phrase "a land flowing with milk and honey" (debash), Ex. 3:8,
   17; 13:5; 33:3; Lev. 20:24; Num. 13: 27. (See {HONEY}.)
   
     Our Lord miraculously supplied wine at the marriage feast in
   Cana of Galilee (John 2:1-11). The Rechabites were forbidden the
   use of wine (Jer. 35). The Nazarites also were to abstain from
   its use during the period of their vow (Num. 6:1-4); and those
   who were dedicated as Nazarites from their birth were
   perpetually to abstain from it (Judg. 13:4, 5; Luke 1:15; 7:33).
   The priests, too, were forbidden the use of wine and strong
   drink when engaged in their sacred functions (Lev. 10:1, 9-11).
   "Wine is little used now in the East, from the fact that
   Mohammedans are not allowed to taste it, and very few of other
   creeds touch it. When it is drunk, water is generally mixed with
   it, and this was the custom in the days of Christ also. The
   people indeed are everywhere very sober in hot climates; a
   drunken person, in fact, is never seen", (Geikie's Life of
   Christ). The sin of drunkenness, however, must have been not
   uncommon in the olden times, for it is mentioned either
   metaphorically or literally more than seventy times in the
   Bible.
   
     A drink-offering of wine was presented with the daily
   sacrifice (Ex. 29:40, 41), and also with the offering of the
   first-fruits (Lev. 23:13), and with various other sacrifices
   (Num. 15:5, 7, 10). Wine was used at the celebration of the
   Passover. And when the Lord's Supper was instituted, the wine
   and the unleavened bread then on the paschal table were by our
   Lord set apart as memorials of his body and blood.
   
     Several emphatic warnings are given in the New Testament
   against excess in the use of wine (Luke 21:34; Rom. 13:13; Eph.
   5:18; 1 Tim. 3:8; Titus 1:7).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wine \Wine\, n. [OE. win, AS. win, fr. L. vinum (cf. Icel.
   v[=i]n; all from the Latin); akin to Gr. o'i^nos, ?, and E.
   withy. Cf. {Vine}, {Vineyard}, {Vinous}, {Withy}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The expressed juice of grapes, esp. when fermented; a
      beverage or liquor prepared from grapes by squeezing out
      their juice, and (usually) allowing it to ferment. ``Red
      wine of Gascoigne.'' --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wine is a mocker, strong drink is raging, and
            whosoever is deceived thereby is not wise. --Prov.
                                                  xx. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bacchus, that first from out the purple grape
            Crushed the sweet poison of misused wine. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Wine is essentially a dilute solution of ethyl alcohol,
         containing also certain small quantities of ethers and
         ethereal salts which give character and bouquet.
         According to their color, strength, taste, etc., wines
         are called {red}, {white}, {spirituous}, {dry},
         {light}, {still}, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A liquor or beverage prepared from the juice of any fruit
      or plant by a process similar to that for grape wine; as,
      currant wine; gooseberry wine; palm wine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The effect of drinking wine in excess; intoxication.
      [1913 Webster]

            Noah awoke from his wine.             --Gen. ix. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Birch wine}, {Cape wine}, etc. See under {Birch}, {Cape},
      etc.

   {Spirit of wine}. See under {Spirit}.

   {To have drunk wine of ape} or {To have drunk wine ape}, to
      be so drunk as to be foolish. [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {Wine acid}. (Chem.) See {Tartaric acid}, under {Tartaric}.
      [Colloq.]

   {Wine apple} (Bot.), a large red apple, with firm flesh and a
      rich, vinous flavor.

   {Wine fly} (Zo["o]l.), small two-winged fly of the genus
      {Piophila}, whose larva lives in wine, cider, and other
      fermented liquors.

   {Wine grower}, one who cultivates a vineyard and makes wine.
      

   {Wine measure}, the measure by which wines and other spirits
      are sold, smaller than beer measure.

   {Wine merchant}, a merchant who deals in wines.

   {Wine of opium} (Pharm.), a solution of opium in aromatized
      sherry wine, having the same strength as ordinary
      laudanum; -- also {Sydenham's laudanum}.

   {Wine press}, a machine or apparatus in which grapes are
      pressed to extract their juice.

   {Wine skin}, a bottle or bag of skin, used, in various
      countries, for carrying wine.

   {Wine stone}, a kind of crust deposited in wine casks. See
      1st {Tartar}, 1.

   {Wine vault}.
      (a) A vault where wine is stored.
      (b) A place where wine is served at the bar, or at tables;
          a dramshop. --Dickens.

   {Wine vinegar}, vinegar made from wine.

   {Wine whey}, whey made from milk coagulated by the use of
      wine.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wine
     n 1: fermented juice (of grapes especially) [syn: {vino}]
     2: a red as dark as red wine [syn: {wine-colored}]
     v 1: drink wine
     2: treat to wine; "Our relatives in Italy wined and dined us
        for a week"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
