<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wing, AL
  Zip code(s): 36483
Wing, ND (city, FIPS 86780)
  Location: 47.14258 N, 100.28220 W
  Population (1990): 208 (97 housing units)
  Area: 1.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 58494
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wing \Wing\, n. [OE. winge, wenge; probably of Scand. origin;
   cf. Dan. &amp; Sw. vinge, Icel. v[ae]ngr.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. One of the two anterior limbs of a bird, pterodactyl, or
      bat. They correspond to the arms of man, and are usually
      modified for flight, but in the case of a few species of
      birds, as the ostrich, auk, etc., the wings are used only
      as an assistance in running or swimming.
      [1913 Webster]

            As an eagle stirreth up her nest, fluttereth over
            her young, spreadeth abroad her wings, taketh them,
            beareth them on her wings.            --Deut. xxxii.
                                                  11.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the wing of a bird the long quill feathers are in
         series. The primaries are those attached to the ulnar
         side of the hand; the secondaries, or wing coverts,
         those of the forearm: the scapulars, those that lie
         over the humerus; and the bastard feathers, those of
         the short outer digit. See Illust. of {Bird}, and
         {Plumage}.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Any similar member or instrument used for the purpose of
      flying. Specifically: (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) One of the two pairs of upper thoracic appendages of
          most hexapod insects. They are broad, fanlike organs
          formed of a double membrane and strengthened by
          chitinous veins or nervures.
      (b) One of the large pectoral fins of the flying fishes.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Passage by flying; flight; as, to take wing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Light thickens; and the crow
            Makes wing to the rooky wood.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Motive or instrument of flight; means of flight or of
      rapid motion.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fiery expedition be my wing.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Anything which agitates the air as a wing does, or which
      is put in winglike motion by the action of the air, as a
      fan or vane for winnowing grain, the vane or sail of a
      windmill, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An ornament worn on the shoulder; a small epaulet or
      shoulder knot.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Any appendage resembling the wing of a bird or insect in
      shape or appearance. Specifically:
      (a) (Zo["o]l.) One of the broad, thin, anterior lobes of
          the foot of a pteropod, used as an organ in swimming.
      (b) (Bot.) Any membranaceous expansion, as that along the
          sides of certain stems, or of a fruit of the kind
          called samara.
      (c) (Bot.) Either of the two side petals of a
          papilionaceous flower.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. One of two corresponding appendages attached; a sidepiece.
      Hence:
      (a) (Arch.) A side building, less than the main edifice;
          as, one of the wings of a palace.
      (b) (Fort.) The longer side of crownworks, etc.,
          connecting them with the main work.
      (c) (Hort.) A side shoot of a tree or plant; a branch
          growing up by the side of another. [Obs.]
      (d) (Mil.) The right or left division of an army,
          regiment, etc.
      (e) (Naut.) That part of the hold or orlop of a vessel
          which is nearest the sides. In a fleet, one of the
          extremities when the ships are drawn up in line, or
          when forming the two sides of a triangle. --Totten.
      (f) One of the sides of the stags in a theater.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Aeronautics) Any surface used primarily for supporting a
      flying machine in flight, especially the flat or slightly
      curved planes on a heavier-than-air aircraft which provide
      most of the lift. In fixed-wing aircraft there are usually
      two main wings fixed on opposite sides of the fuselage.
      Smaller wings are typically placed near the tail primarily
      for stabilization, but may be absent in certain kinds of
      aircraft. Helicopters usually have no fixed wings, the
      lift being supplied by the rotating blade.
      [PJC]

   10. One of two factions within an organization, as a
       political party, which are opposed to each other; as,
       right wing or left wing.
       [PJC]

   11. An administrative division of the air force or of a naval
       air group, consisting of a certain number of airplanes
       and the personnel associated with them.
       [PJC]

   {On the wing}.
       (a) Supported by, or flying with, the wings another.

   {On the wings of the wind}, with the utmost velocity.

   {Under the wing of}, or {Under the wings of}, under the care
      or protection of.

   {Wing and wing} (Naut.), with sails hauled out on either
      side; -- said of a schooner, or her sails, when going
      before the wind with the foresail on one side and the
      mainsail on the other; also said of a square-rigged vessel
      which has her studding sails set. Cf. {Goosewinged}.

   {Wing case} (Zo["o]l.), one of the anterior wings of beetles,
      and of some other insects, when thickened and used to
      protect the hind wings; an elytron; -- called also {wing
      cover}.

   {Wing covert} (Zo["o]l.), one of the small feathers covering
      the bases of the wing quills. See {Covert}, n., 2.

   {Wing gudgeon} (Mach.), an iron gudgeon for the end of a
      wooden axle, having thin, broad projections to prevent it
      from turning in the wood. See Illust. of {Gudgeon}.

   {Wing shell} (Zo["o]l.), wing case of an insect.

   {Wing stroke}, the stroke or sweep of a wing.

   {Wing transom} (Naut.), the uppermost transom of the stern;
      -- called also {main transom}. --J. Knowles.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wing \Wing\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Winged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Winging}.]
   1. To furnish with wings; to enable to fly, or to move with
      celerity.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who heaves old ocean, and whowings the storms.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Living, to wing with mirth the weary hours.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To supply with wings or sidepieces.
      [1913 Webster]

            The main battle, whose puissance on either side
            Shall be well winged with our chiefest horse.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To transport by flight; to cause to fly.
      [1913 Webster]

            I, an old turtle,
            Will wing me to some withered bough.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To move through in flight; to fly through.
      [1913 Webster]

            There's not an arrow wings the sky
            But fancy turns its point to him.     --Moore.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cut off the wings of or to wound in the wing; to
      disable a wing of; as, to wing a bird; also, [fig.] to
      wound the arm of a person.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   {To wing a flight}, to exert the power of flying; to fly.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wing
     n 1: a movable organ for flying (one of a pair)
     2: one of the horizontal airfoils on either side of the
        fuselage of an airplane
     3: a stage area out of sight of the audience [syn: {offstage},
        {backstage}]
     4: a unit of military aircraft
     5: the side of military or naval formation; "they attacked the
        enemy's right flank" [syn: {flank}]
     6: a hockey player stationed in a forward positin on either
        side
     7: the wing of a fowl; "he preferred the drumsticks to the
        wings"
     8: a barrier that surrounds the wheels of a vehicle to block
        splashing water or mud; "in England they call a fender a
        wing" [syn: {fender}]
     9: an addition that extends a main building [syn: {annex}, {annexe},
         {extension}]
     v : travel through the air; be airborne; "Man cannot fly" [syn:
         {fly}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
