<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wireless</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wireless</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wireless
     
        &lt;networking&gt; A term describing a computer {network} where
        there is no physical connection (either copper cable or {fibre
        optics}) between sender and receiver, but instead they are
        connected by radio.
     
        Applications for wireless networks include multi-party
        {teleconferencing}, distributed work sessions, {personal
        digital assistant}s, and electronic newspapers.  They include
        the transmission of voice, video, {image}s, and data, each
        traffic type with possibly differing {bandwidth} and
        quality-of-service requirements.  The wireless network
        components of a complete source-destination path requires
        consideration of mobility, {hand-off}, and varying
        transmission and {bandwidth} conditions.  The wired/wireless
        network combination provides a severe bandwidth mismatch, as
        well as vastly different error conditions.  The processing
        capability of fixed vs. mobile terminals may be expected to
        differ significantly.  This then leads to such issues to be
        addressed in this environment as {admission control},
        {capacity assignment} and {hand-off} control in the wireless
        domain, flow and error control over the complete end-to-end
        path, dynamic bandwidth control to accommodate bandwidth
        mismatch and/or varying processing capability.
     
        {Usenet} newsgroup {news:comp.std.wireless}.
     
        (1995-02-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wireless</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wireless \Wire"less\, a.
   Having no wire; specif. (Elec.), designating, or pertaining
   to, a method of telegraphy, telephony, or other information
   transmisssion, in which the messages, data, etc., are
   transmitted through space by electric waves; as, a wireless
   message; a wireless network; a wireless keyboard.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   {Wireless telegraphy} or {Wireless telegraph} (Elec.), any
      system of telegraphy employing no connecting wire or wires
      between the transmitting and receiving stations.

   Note: Although more or less successful researchers were made
         on the subject by Joseph Henry, Hertz, Oliver Lodge,
         and others, the first commercially successful system
         was that of Guglielmo Marconi, patented in March, 1897.
         Marconi employed electric waves of high frequency set
         up by an induction coil in an oscillator, these waves
         being launched into space through a lofty antenna. The
         receiving apparatus consisted of another antenna in
         circuit with a coherer and small battery for operating
         through a relay the ordinary telegraphic receiver. This
         apparatus contains the essential features of all the
         systems now in use.

   {Wireless telephone}, an apparatus or contrivance for
      wireless telephony.

   {Wireless telephony}, telephony without wires, usually
      employing electric waves of high frequency emitted from an
      oscillator or generator, as in wireless telegraphy. A
      telephone transmitter causes fluctuations in these waves,
      it being the fluctuations only which affect the receiver.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wireless</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wireless \Wire"less\, n.
   Short for {Wireless telegraphy}, {Wireless telephony}, etc.;
   as, to send a message by wireless.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wireless</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wireless
     adj : having no wires; "a wireless security system" [ant: {wired}]
     n 1: medium for communication [syn: {radio}, {radiocommunication}]
     2: transmission by radio waves
     3: an electronic receiver that detects and demodulates and
        amplifies transmitted signals [syn: {radio receiver}, {receiving
        set}, {radio set}, {radio}, {tuner}]
     4: a communication system based on broadcasting electromagnetic
        waves [syn: {radio}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
