<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wisest</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wisest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wise \Wise\, a. [Compar. {Wiser}; superl. {Wisest}.] [OE. wis,
   AS. w[=i]s; akin to OS. &amp; OFries. w[=i]s, D. wijs, G. weise,
   OHG. w[=i]s, w[=i]si, Icel. v[=i]ss, Sw. vis, Dan. viis,
   Goth. weis; akin to wit, v. i. See {Wit}, v., and cf.
   {Righteous}, {Wisdom}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Having knowledge; knowing; enlightened; of extensive
      information; erudite; learned.
      [1913 Webster]

            They are wise to do evil, but to do good they have
            no knowledge.                         --Jer. iv. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, especially, making due use of knowledge; discerning
      and judging soundly concerning what is true or false,
      proper or improper; choosing the best ends and the best
      means for accomplishing them; sagacious.
      [1913 Webster]

            When clouds appear, wise men put their cloaks.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            From a child thou hast known the holy scriptures,
            which are able to make thee wise unto salvation. --2
                                                  Tim. iii. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Versed in art or science; skillful; dexterous;
      specifically, skilled in divination.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fal. There was, mine host, an old fat woman even now
            with me; but she's gone.
            Sim. Pray you, sir, was't not the wise woman of
            Brentford?                            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, prudent; calculating; shrewd; wary; subtle; crafty.
      [R.] ``Thou art . . . no novice, but a governor wily and
      wise.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor, on the other side,
            Will I be penuriously wise
            As to make money, that's my slave, my idol. --Beau.
                                                  &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lords do not care for me:
            I am too wise to die yet.             --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Dictated or guided by wisdom; containing or exhibiting
      wisdom; well adapted to produce good effects; judicious;
      discreet; as, a wise saying; a wise scheme or plan; wise
      conduct or management; a wise determination. ``Eminent in
      wise deport.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To make it wise}, to make it a matter of deliberation.
      [Obs.] `` We thought it was not worth to make it wise.''
      --Chaucer.

   {Wise in years}, old enough to be wise; wise from age and
      experience; hence, aged; old. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            A very grave, state bachelor, my dainty one;
            He's wise in years, and of a temperate warmth.
                                                  --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

            You are too wise in years, too full of counsel,
            For my green experience.              --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
