<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>with</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>with</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Acquaintance \Ac*quaint"ance\, n. [OE. aqueintance, OF.
   acointance, fr. acointier. See {Acquaint}.]
   1. A state of being acquainted, or of having intimate, or
      more than slight or superficial, knowledge; personal
      knowledge gained by intercourse short of that of
      friendship or intimacy; as, I know the man; but have no
      acquaintance with him.
      [1913 Webster]

            Contract no friendship, or even acquaintance, with a
            guileful man.                         --Sir W.
                                                  Jones.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A person or persons with whom one is acquainted.
      [1913 Webster]

            Montgomery was an old acquaintance of Ferguson.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense the collective term acquaintance was
         formerly both singular and plural, but it is now
         commonly singular, and has the regular plural
         acquaintances.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To be of acquaintance}, to be intimate.

   {To take acquaintance of} or {with}, to make the acquaintance
      of. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Familiarity; intimacy; fellowship; knowledge.

   Usage: {Acquaintance}, {Familiarity}, {Intimacy}. These words
          mark different degrees of closeness in social
          intercourse. Acquaintance arises from occasional
          intercourse; as, our acquaintance has been a brief
          one. We can speak of a slight or an intimate
          acquaintance. Familiarity is the result of continued
          acquaintance. It springs from persons being frequently
          together, so as to wear off all restraint and reserve;
          as, the familiarity of old companions. Intimacy is the
          result of close connection, and the freest interchange
          of thought; as, the intimacy of established
          friendship.
          [1913 Webster]

                Our admiration of a famous man lessens upon our
                nearer acquaintance with him.     --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

                We contract at last such a familiarity with them
                as makes it difficult and irksome for us to call
                off our minds.                    --Atterbury.
          [1913 Webster]

                It is in our power to confine our friendships
                and intimacies to men of virtue.  --Rogers.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>with</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Accredit \Ac*cred"it\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Accredited}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Accrediting}.] [F. accr['e]diter; [`a] (L. ad) +
   cr['e]dit credit. See {Credit}.]
   1. To put or bring into credit; to invest with credit or
      authority; to sanction.
      [1913 Webster]

            His censure will . . . accredit his praises.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

            These reasons . . . which accredit and fortify mine
            opinion.                              --Shelton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To send with letters credential, as an ambassador, envoy,
      or diplomatic agent; to authorize, as a messenger or
      delegate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Beton . . . was accredited to the Court of France.
                                                  --Froude.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To believe; to credit; to put trust in.
      [1913 Webster]

            The version of early Roman history which was
            accredited in the fifth century.      --Sir G. C.
                                                  Lewis.
      [1913 Webster]

            He accredited and repeated stories of apparitions
            and witchcraft.                       --Southey.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To credit; to vouch for or consider (some one) as doing
      something, or (something) as belonging to some one.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To accredit} (one) {with} (something), to attribute
      something to him; as, Mr. Clay was accredited with these
      views; they accredit him with a wise saying.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>with</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>With \With\, prep. [OE. with, AS. wi? with, against; akin to AS.
   wi?er against, OFries. with, OS. wi?, wi?ar, D. weder,
   we[^e]r (in comp.), G. wider against, wieder gain, OHG. widar
   again, against, Icel. vi? against, with, by, at, Sw. vid at,
   by, Dan. ved, Goth. wipra against, Skr. vi asunder. Cf.
   {Withdraw}, {Withers}, {Withstand}.]
   With denotes or expresses some situation or relation of
   nearness, proximity, association, connection, or the like. It
   is used especially: 
   [1913 Webster]

   1. To denote a close or direct relation of opposition or
      hostility; -- equivalent to against.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy servant will . . . fight with this Philistine.
                                                  --1 Sam. xvii.
                                                  32.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense, common in Old English, it is now
         obsolete except in a few compounds; as, withhold;
         withstand; and after the verbs fight, contend,
         struggle, and the like.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To denote association in respect of situation or
      environment; hence, among; in the company of.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will buy with you, talk with you, walk with you,
            and so following; but I will not eat with you, drink
            with you, nor pray with you.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pity your own, or pity our estate,
            Nor twist our fortunes with your sinking fate.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            See where on earth the flowery glories lie;
            With her they flourished, and with her they die.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is no living with thee nor without thee.
                                                  --Tatler.
      [1913 Webster]

            Such arguments had invincible force with those pagan
            philosophers.                         --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To denote a connection of friendship, support, alliance,
      assistance, countenance, etc.; hence, on the side of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fear not, for I am with thee, and will bless thee.
                                                  --Gen. xxvi.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To denote the accomplishment of cause, means, instrument,
      etc; -- sometimes equivalent to by.
      [1913 Webster]

            That with these fowls I be all to-rent. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou wilt be like a lover presently,
            And tire the hearer with a book of words. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            [He] entertained a coffeehouse with the following
            narrative.                            --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            With receiving your friends within and amusing them
            without, you lead a good, pleasant, bustling life of
            it.                                   --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To denote association in thought, as for comparison or
      contrast.
      [1913 Webster]

            Can blazing carbuncles with her compare. --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To denote simultaneous happening, or immediate succession
      or consequence.
      [1913 Webster]

            With that she told me . . . that she would hide no
            truth from me.                        --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

            With her they flourished, and with her they die.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            With this he pointed to his face.     --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To denote having as a possession or an appendage; as, the
      firmament with its stars; a bride with a large fortune.
      ``A maid with clean hands.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: With and by are closely allied in many of their uses,
         and it is not easy to lay down a rule by which to
         distinguish their uses. See the Note under {By}.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>with</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>With \With\, n.
   See {Withe}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>with</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Withe \Withe\ (?; 277), n. [OE. withe. ????. See {Withy}, n.]
   [Written also {with}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A flexible, slender twig or branch used as a band; a
      willow or osier twig; a withy.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A band consisting of a twig twisted.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) An iron attachment on one end of a mast or boom,
      with a ring, through which another mast or boom is rigged
      out and secured; a wythe. --R. H. Dana, Jr.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Arch.) A partition between flues in a chimney.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
