<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>witness</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>witness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Witness
   More than one witness was required in criminal cases (Deut.
   17:6; 19:15). They were the first to execute the sentence on the
   condemned (Deut. 13:9; 17:7; 1 Kings 21:13; Matt. 27:1; Acts
   7:57, 58). False witnesses were liable to punishment (Deut.
   19:16-21). It was also an offence to refuse to bear witness
   (Lev. 5:1).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>witness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Witness \Wit"ness\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Witnessed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Witnessing}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To see or know by personal presence; to have direct
      cognizance of.
      [1913 Webster]

            This is but a faint sketch of the incalculable
            calamities and horrors we must expect, should we
            ever witness the triumphs of modern infidelity. --R.
                                                  Hall.
      [1913 Webster]

            General Washington did not live to witness the
            restoration of peace.                 --Marshall.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give testimony to; to testify to; to attest.
      [1913 Webster]

            Behold how many things they witness against thee.
                                                  --Mark xv. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) To see the execution of, as an instrument, and
      subscribe it for the purpose of establishing its
      authenticity; as, to witness a bond or a deed.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>witness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Witness \Wit"ness\, n. [AS. witness, gewitnes, from witan to
   know. [root]133. See {Wit}, v. i.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Attestation of a fact or an event; testimony.
      [1913 Webster]

            May we with . . . the witness of a good conscience,
            pursue him with any further revenge?  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If I bear witness of myself, my witness is not true.
                                                  --John v. 31.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which furnishes evidence or proof.
      [1913 Webster]

            Laban said to Jacob, . . . This heap be witness, and
            this pillar be witness.               --Gen. xxxi.
                                                  51, 52.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who is cognizant; a person who beholds, or otherwise
      has personal knowledge of, anything; as, an eyewitness; an
      earwitness. ``Thyself art witness I am betrothed.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon my looking round, I was witness to appearances
            which filled me with melancholy and regret. --R.
                                                  Hall.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law)
      (a) One who testifies in a cause, or gives evidence before
          a judicial tribunal; as, the witness in court agreed
          in all essential facts.
      (b) One who sees the execution of an instrument, and
          subscribes it for the purpose of confirming its
          authenticity by his testimony; one who witnesses a
          will, a deed, a marriage, or the like.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Privileged witnesses}. (Law) See under {Privileged}.

   {With a witness}, effectually; to a great degree; with great
      force, so as to leave some mark as a testimony. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This, I confess, is haste with a witness. --South.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>witness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Witness \Wit"ness\, v. i.
   To bear testimony; to give evidence; to testify. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

         The men of Belial witnessed against him. --1 Kings xxi.
                                                  13.
   [1913 Webster]

         The witnessing of the truth was then so generally
         attended with this event [martyrdom] that martyrdom now
         signifies not only to witness, but to witness to death.
                                                  --South.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>witness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>witness
     n 1: someone who sees an event and reports what happened [syn: {witnesser},
           {informant}]
     2: a close observer; someone who looks at something (such as an
        exhibition of some kind); "the spectators applauded the
        performance"; "television viewers"; "sky watchers
        discovered a new star" [syn: {spectator}, {viewer}, {watcher},
         {looker}]
     3: testimony by word or deed to your religious faith
     4: (law) a person who attests to the genuineness of a document
        or signature by adding their own signature [syn: {attestant},
         {attestor}, {attestator}]
     5: (law) a person who testifies under oath in a court of law
     v 1: be a witness to
     2: perceive or be contemporaneous with; "We found Republicans
        winning the offices"; "You'll see a lot of cheating in
        this school"; "I want to see results"; "The 1960 saw the
        rebellion of the younger generation against established
        traditions"; "I want to see results" [syn: {find}, {see}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
