<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>work</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>work</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Work \Work\ (w[^u]rk), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Worked} (w[^u]rkt),
   or {Wrought} (r[add]t); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Working}.] [AS.
   wyrcean (imp. worthe, wrohte, p. p. geworht, gewroht); akin
   to OFries. werka, wirka, OS. wirkian, D. werken, G. wirken,
   Icel. verka, yrkja, orka, Goth. wa['u]rkjan. [root]145. See
   {Work}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To exert one's self for a purpose; to put forth effort for
      the attainment of an object; to labor; to be engaged in
      the performance of a task, a duty, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            O thou good Kent, how shall I live and work,
            To match thy goodness?                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go therefore now, and work; for there shall no straw
            be given you.                         --Ex. v. 18.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether we work or play, or sleep or wake,
            Our life doth pass.                   --Sir J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, in a general sense, to operate; to act; to perform;
      as, a machine works well.
      [1913 Webster]

            We bend to that the working of the heart. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, figuratively, to be effective; to have effect or
      influence; to conduce.
      [1913 Webster]

            We know that all things work together for good to
            them that love God.                   --Rom. viii.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

            This so wrought upon the child, that afterwards he
            desired to be taught.                 --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            She marveled how she could ever have been wrought
            upon to marry him.                    --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To carry on business; to be engaged or employed
      customarily; to perform the part of a laborer; to labor;
      to toil.
      [1913 Webster]

            They that work in fine flax . . . shall be
            confounded.                           --Isa. xix. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be in a state of severe exertion, or as if in such a
      state; to be tossed or agitated; to move heavily; to
      strain; to labor; as, a ship works in a heavy sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            Confused with working sands and rolling waves.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To make one's way slowly and with difficulty; to move or
      penetrate laboriously; to proceed with effort; -- with a
      following preposition, as down, out, into, up, through,
      and the like; as, scheme works out by degrees; to work
      into the earth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Till body up to spirit work, in bounds
            Proportioned to each kind.            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To ferment, as a liquid.
      [1913 Webster]

            The working of beer when the barm is put in.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To act or operate on the stomach and bowels, as a
      cathartic.
      [1913 Webster]

            Purges . . . work best, that is, cause the blood so
            to do, . . . in warm weather or in a warm room.
                                                  --Grew.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To work at}, to be engaged in or upon; to be employed in.

   {To work to windward} (Naut.), to sail or ply against the
      wind; to tack to windward. --Mar. Dict.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>work</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Work \Work\ (w[^u]rk), v. t.
   1. To labor or operate upon; to give exertion and effort to;
      to prepare for use, or to utilize, by labor.
      [1913 Webster]

            He could have told them of two or three gold mines,
            and a silver mine, and given the reason why they
            forbare to work them at that time.    --Sir W.
                                                  Raleigh.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To produce or form by labor; to bring forth by exertion or
      toil; to accomplish; to originate; to effect; as, to work
      wood or iron into a form desired, or into a utensil; to
      work cotton or wool into cloth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Each herb he knew, that works or good or ill.
                                                  --Harte.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To produce by slow degrees, or as if laboriously; to bring
      gradually into any state by action or motion. ``Sidelong
      he works his way.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            So the pure, limpid stream, when foul with stains
            Of rushing torrents and descending rains,
            Works itself clear, and as it runs, refines,
            Till by degrees the floating mirror shines.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To influence by acting upon; to prevail upon; to manage;
      to lead. ``Work your royal father to his ruin.''
      --Philips.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To form with a needle and thread or yarn; especially, to
      embroider; as, to work muslin.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To set in motion or action; to direct the action of; to
      keep at work; to govern; to manage; as, to work a machine.
      [1913 Webster]

            Knowledge in building and working ships.
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now, Marcus, thy virtue's the proof;
            Put forth thy utmost strength, work every nerve.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mariners all 'gan work the ropes,
            Where they were wont to do.           --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cause to ferment, as liquor.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To work a passage} (Naut.), to pay for a passage by doing
      work.

   {To work double tides} (Naut.), to perform the labor of three
      days in two; -- a phrase which alludes to a practice of
      working by the night tide as well as by the day.

   {To work in}, to insert, introduce, mingle, or interweave by
      labor or skill.

   {To work into}, to force, urge, or insinuate into; as, to
      work one's self into favor or confidence.

   {To work off}, to remove gradually, as by labor, or a gradual
      process; as, beer works off impurities in fermenting.

   {To work out}.
      (a) To effect by labor and exertion. ``Work out your own
          salvation with fear and trembling.'' --Phil. ii. 12.
      (b) To erase; to efface. [R.]
          [1913 Webster]

                Tears of joy for your returning spilt,
                Work out and expiate our former guilt. --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To solve, as a problem.
      (d) To exhaust, as a mine, by working.

   {To work up}.
      (a) To raise; to excite; to stir up; as, to work up the
          passions to rage.
          [1913 Webster]

                The sun, that rolls his chariot o'er their
                heads,
                Works up more fire and color in their cheeks.
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To expend in any work, as materials; as, they have
          worked up all the stock.
      (c) (Naut.) To make over or into something else, as yarns
          drawn from old rigging, made into spun yarn, foxes,
          sennit, and the like; also, to keep constantly at work
          upon needless matters, as a crew in order to punish
          them. --R. H. Dana, Jr.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>work</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Work \Work\ (w[^u]rk), n. [OE. work, werk, weorc, AS. weorc,
   worc; akin to OFries. werk, wirk, OS., D., &amp; G. werk, OHG.
   werc, werah, Icel. &amp; Sw. verk, Dan. v[ae]rk, Goth.
   gawa['u]rki, Gr. 'e`rgon, [digamma]e`rgon, work, "re`zein to
   do, 'o`rganon an instrument, 'o`rgia secret rites, Zend verez
   to work. [root]145. Cf. {Bulwark}, {Energy}, {Erg},
   {Georgic}, {Liturgy}, {Metallurgy}, {Organ}, {Orgy},
   {Surgeon}, {Wright}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Exertion of strength or faculties; physical or
      intellectual effort directed to an end; industrial
      activity; toil; employment; sometimes, specifically,
      physical labor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man hath his daily work of body or mind
            Appointed.                            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The matter on which one is at work; that upon which one
      spends labor; material for working upon; subject of
      exertion; the thing occupying one; business; duty; as, to
      take up one's work; to drop one's work.
      [1913 Webster]

            Come on, Nerissa; I have work in hand
            That you yet know not of.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In every work that he began . . . he did it with all
            his heart, and prospered.             --2 Chron.
                                                  xxxi. 21.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is produced as the result of labor; anything
      accomplished by exertion or toil; product; performance;
      fabric; manufacture; in a more general sense, act, deed,
      service, effect, result, achievement, feat.
      [1913 Webster]

            To leave no rubs or blotches in the work. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The work some praise,
            And some the architect.               --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fancy . . .
            Wild work produces oft, and most in dreams.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The composition or dissolution of mixed bodies . . .
            is the chief work of elements.        --Sir K.
                                                  Digby.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically:
      (a) That which is produced by mental labor; a composition;
          a book; as, a work, or the works, of Addison.
      (b) Flowers, figures, or the like, wrought with the
          needle; embroidery.
          [1913 Webster]

                I am glad I have found this napkin; . . .
                I'll have the work ta'en out,
                And give 't Iago.                 --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) pl. Structures in civil, military, or naval
          engineering, as docks, bridges, embankments, trenches,
          fortifications, and the like; also, the structures and
          grounds of a manufacturing establishment; as, iron
          works; locomotive works; gas works.
      (d) pl. The moving parts of a mechanism; as, the works of
          a watch.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. Manner of working; management; treatment; as, unskillful
      work spoiled the effect. --Bp. Stillingfleet.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mech.) The causing of motion against a resisting force.
      The amount of work is proportioned to, and is measured by,
      the product of the force into the amount of motion along
      the direction of the force. See {Conservation of energy},
      under {Conservation}, {Unit of work}, under {Unit}, also
      {Foot pound}, {Horse power}, {Poundal}, and {Erg}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Energy is the capacity of doing work . . . Work is
            the transference of energy from one system to
            another.                              --Clerk
                                                  Maxwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining) Ore before it is dressed. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. pl. (Script.) Performance of moral duties; righteous
      conduct.
      [1913 Webster]

            He shall reward every man according to his works.
                                                  --Matt. xvi.
                                                  27.
      [1913 Webster]

            Faith, if it hath not works, is dead. --James ii.
                                                  17.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Cricket) Break; twist. [Cant]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. (Mech.) The causing of motion against a resisting force,
       measured by the product of the force into the component
       of the motion resolved along the direction of the force.

             Energy is the capacity of doing work. . . . Work is
             the transference of energy from one system to
             another.                             --Clerk
                                                  Maxwell.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. (Mining) Ore before it is dressed.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Muscular work} (Physiol.), the work done by a muscle through
      the power of contraction.

   {To go to work}, to begin laboring; to commence operations;
      to contrive; to manage. ``I 'll go another way to work
      with him.'' --Shak.

   {To set on work}, to cause to begin laboring; to set to work.
      [Obs.] --Hooker.

   {To set to work}, to employ; to cause to engage in any
      business or labor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>work</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>work
     n 1: activity directed toward making or doing something; "she
          checked several points needing further work"
     2: a product produced or accomplished through the effort or
        activity or agency of a person or thing; "it is not
        regarded as one of his more memorable works"; "the
        symphony was hailed as an ingenious work"; "he was
        indebted to the pioneering work of John Dewey"; "the work
        of an active imagination"; "erosion is the work of wind or
        water over time" [syn: {piece of work}]
     3: the occupation for which you are paid; "he is looking for
        employment"; "a lot of people are out of work" [syn: {employment}]
     4: applying the mind to learning and understanding a subject
        (especially by reading); "mastering a second language
        requires a lot of work"; "no schools offer graduate study
        in interior design" [syn: {study}]
     5: the total output of a writer or artist (or a substantial
        part of it); "he studied the entire Wagnerian oeuvre";
        "Picasso's work can be divided into periods" [syn: {oeuvre},
         {body of work}]
     6: a place where work is done; "he arrived at work early today"
        [syn: {workplace}]
     7: (physics) a manifestation of energy; the transfer of energy
        from one physical system to another expressed as the
        product of a force and the distance through which it moves
        a body in the direction of that force; "work equals force
        times distance"
     v 1: exert oneself by doing mental or physical work for a purpose
          or out of necessity; "I will work hard to improve my
          grades"; "she worked hard for better living conditions
          for the poor" [ant: {idle}]
     2: be employed; "Is your husband working again?"; "My wife
        never worked"; "Do you want to work after the age of 60?";
        "She never did any work because she inherited a lot of
        money"; "She works as a waitress to put herself through
        college" [syn: {do work}]
     3: have an effect or outcome; often the one desired or
        expected; "The voting process doesn't work as well as
        people thought"; "How does your idea work in practice?";
        "This method doesn't work"; "The breaks of my new car act
        quickly"; "The medicine works only if you take it with a
        lot of water" [syn: {act}]
     4: perform as expected when applied; "The washing machine won't
        go unless it's plugged in"; "Does this old car still run
        well?"; "This old radio doesn't work anymore" [syn: {function},
         {operate}, {go}, {run}] [ant: {malfunction}]
     5: shape, form, or improve a material; "work stone into tools";
        "process iron"; "work the metal" [syn: {work on}, {process}]
     6: give a work-out to; "Some parents exercise their infants";
        "My personal trainer works me hard"; "work one's muscles"
        [syn: {exercise}, {work out}]
     7: proceed along a path; "work one's way through the crowd";
        "make one's way into the forest" [syn: {make}]
     8: operate in a certain place, area, or specialty; "She works
        the night clubs"; "The salesman works the Midwest"; "This
        artist works mostly in acrylics"
     9: proceed towards a goal or along a path or through an
        activity; "work your way through every problem or task";
        "She was working on her second martini when the guests
        arrived"; "Start from the bottom and work towards the top"
     10: move in an agitated manner; "His fingers worked with
         tension"
     11: cause to happen or to occur as a consequence; "I cannot work
         a miracle"; "wreak havoc"; "bring comments"; "play a
         joke"; "The rain brought relief to the drought-stricken
         area" [syn: {bring}, {play}, {wreak}, {make for}]
     12: cause to work; "he is working his servants hard" [syn: {put
         to work}]
     13: prepare for crops; "Work the soil"; "cultivate the land"
         [syn: {cultivate}, {crop}]
     14: behave in a certain way when handled; "This dough does not
         work easily"; "The soft metal works well"
     15: have and exert influence or effect; "The artist's work
         influenced the young painter"; "She worked on her friends
         to support the political candidate" [syn: {influence}, {act
         upon}]
     16: operate in or through; "Work the phones"
     17: cause to operate or function; "This pilot works the
         controls"; "Can you work an electric drill?"
     18: provoke or excite; "The rock musician worked the crowd of
         young girls into a frenzy"
     19: gratify and charm, usually in order to influence; "the
         political candidate worked the crowds"
     20: make something, usually for a specific function; "She molded
         the riceballs carefully"; "Form cylinders from the
         dough"; "shape a figure"; "Work the metal into a sword"
         [syn: {shape}, {form}, {mold}, {mould}, {forge}]
     21: move into or onto; "work the raisins into the dough"; "the
         student worked a few jokes into his presentation"; "work
         the body onto the flatbed truck"
     22: make uniform; "knead dough"; "work the clay until it is
         soft" [syn: {knead}]
     23: use or manipulate to one's advantage; "He exploit the new
         taxation system"; "She knows how to work the system"; "he
         works his parents for sympathy" [syn: {exploit}]
     24: find the solution to (a problem or question) or understand
         the meaning of; "did you solve the problem?"; "Work out
         your problems with the boss"; "this unpleasant situation
         isn't going to work itself out"; "did you get it?"; "Did
         you get my meaning?"; "He could not work the math
         problem" [syn: {solve}, {work out}, {figure out}, {puzzle
         out}, {lick}]
     25: cause to undergo fermentation; "We ferment the grapes for a
         very long time to achieve high alcohol content"; "The
         vintner worked the wine in big oak vats" [syn: {ferment}]
     26: go sour or spoil; "The milk has soured"; "The wine worked";
         "The cream has turned--we have to throw it out" [syn: {sour},
          {turn}, {ferment}]
     27: arrive at a certain condition through repeated motion; "The
         stitches of the hem worked loose after she wore the skirt
         many times"
     [also: {wrought}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
