<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>working</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>working</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Work \Work\ (w[^u]rk), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Worked} (w[^u]rkt),
   or {Wrought} (r[add]t); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Working}.] [AS.
   wyrcean (imp. worthe, wrohte, p. p. geworht, gewroht); akin
   to OFries. werka, wirka, OS. wirkian, D. werken, G. wirken,
   Icel. verka, yrkja, orka, Goth. wa['u]rkjan. [root]145. See
   {Work}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To exert one's self for a purpose; to put forth effort for
      the attainment of an object; to labor; to be engaged in
      the performance of a task, a duty, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            O thou good Kent, how shall I live and work,
            To match thy goodness?                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go therefore now, and work; for there shall no straw
            be given you.                         --Ex. v. 18.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether we work or play, or sleep or wake,
            Our life doth pass.                   --Sir J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, in a general sense, to operate; to act; to perform;
      as, a machine works well.
      [1913 Webster]

            We bend to that the working of the heart. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, figuratively, to be effective; to have effect or
      influence; to conduce.
      [1913 Webster]

            We know that all things work together for good to
            them that love God.                   --Rom. viii.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

            This so wrought upon the child, that afterwards he
            desired to be taught.                 --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            She marveled how she could ever have been wrought
            upon to marry him.                    --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To carry on business; to be engaged or employed
      customarily; to perform the part of a laborer; to labor;
      to toil.
      [1913 Webster]

            They that work in fine flax . . . shall be
            confounded.                           --Isa. xix. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be in a state of severe exertion, or as if in such a
      state; to be tossed or agitated; to move heavily; to
      strain; to labor; as, a ship works in a heavy sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            Confused with working sands and rolling waves.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To make one's way slowly and with difficulty; to move or
      penetrate laboriously; to proceed with effort; -- with a
      following preposition, as down, out, into, up, through,
      and the like; as, scheme works out by degrees; to work
      into the earth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Till body up to spirit work, in bounds
            Proportioned to each kind.            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To ferment, as a liquid.
      [1913 Webster]

            The working of beer when the barm is put in.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To act or operate on the stomach and bowels, as a
      cathartic.
      [1913 Webster]

            Purges . . . work best, that is, cause the blood so
            to do, . . . in warm weather or in a warm room.
                                                  --Grew.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To work at}, to be engaged in or upon; to be employed in.

   {To work to windward} (Naut.), to sail or ply against the
      wind; to tack to windward. --Mar. Dict.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>working</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Working \Work"ing\,
   a &amp; n. from {Work}.
   [1913 Webster]

         The word must cousin be to the working.  --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Working beam}. See {Beam}, n. 10.

   {Working class}, the class of people who are engaged in
      manual labor, or are dependent upon it for support;
      laborers; operatives; -- chiefly used in the plural.

   {Working day}. See under {Day}, n.

   {Working drawing}, a drawing, as of the whole or part of a
      structure, machine, etc., made to a scale, and intended to
      be followed by the workmen. Working drawings are either
      general or detail drawings.

   {Working house}, a house where work is performed; a
      workhouse.

   {Working point} (Mach.), that part of a machine at which the
      effect required; the point where the useful work is done.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>working</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>working
     adj 1: actively engaged in paid work; "the working population";
            "the ratio of working men to unemployed"; "a working
            mother"; "robots can be on the job day and night"
            [syn: {working(a)}, {on the job(p)}]
     2: adequate for practical use; especially sufficient in
        strength or numbers to accomplish something; "the party
        has a working majority in the House"; "a working knowledge
        of Spanish"
     3: adopted as a temporary basis for further work; "a working
        draft"; "a working hypothesis" [syn: {working(a)}]
     4: (of e.g. a machine) performing or capable of performing; "in
        running (or working) order"; "a functional set of brakes"
        [syn: {running(a)}, {operative}, {functional}, {working(a)}]
     5: serving to permit or facilitate further work or activity;
        "discussed the working draft of a peace treaty"; "they
        need working agreements with their neighbor states on
        interstate projects"
     n : a mine or quarry that is being or has been worked [syn: {workings}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
