<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wound</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wound} (wound) (rarely
   {Winded}); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Winding}.] [OE. winden, AS.
   windan; akin to OS. windan, D. &amp; G. winden, OHG. wintan,
   Icel. &amp; Sw. vinda, Dan. vinde, Goth. windan (in comp.). Cf.
   {Wander}, {Wend}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To turn completely, or with repeated turns; especially, to
      turn about something fixed; to cause to form convolutions
      about anything; to coil; to twine; to twist; to wreathe;
      as, to wind thread on a spool or into a ball.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether to wind
            The woodbine round this arbor.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To entwist; to infold; to encircle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sleep, and I will wind thee in arms.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To have complete control over; to turn and bend at one's
      pleasure; to vary or alter or will; to regulate; to
      govern. ``To turn and wind a fiery Pegasus.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In his terms so he would him wind.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gifts blind the wise, and bribes do please
            And wind all other witnesses.         --Herrick.
      [1913 Webster]

            Were our legislature vested in the prince, he might
            wind and turn our constitution at his pleasure.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To introduce by insinuation; to insinuate.
      [1913 Webster]

            You have contrived . . . to wind
            Yourself into a power tyrannical.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Little arts and dexterities they have to wind in
            such things into discourse.           --Gov. of
                                                  Tongue.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cover or surround with something coiled about; as, to
      wind a rope with twine.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To wind off}, to unwind; to uncoil.

   {To wind out}, to extricate. [Obs.] --Clarendon.

   {To wind up}.
      (a) To coil into a ball or small compass, as a skein of
          thread; to coil completely.
      (b) To bring to a conclusion or settlement; as, to wind up
          one's affairs; to wind up an argument.
      (c) To put in a state of renewed or continued motion, as a
          clock, a watch, etc., by winding the spring, or that
          which carries the weight; hence, to prepare for
          continued movement or action; to put in order anew.
          ``Fate seemed to wind him up for fourscore years.''
          --Dryden. ``Thus they wound up his temper to a
          pitch.'' --Atterbury.
      (d) To tighten (the strings) of a musical instrument, so
          as to tune it. ``Wind up the slackened strings of thy
          lute.'' --Waller.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wind \Wind\, v. t. [From {Wind}, moving air, but confused in
   sense and in conjugation with wind to turn.] [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Wound} (wound), R. {Winded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Winding}.]
   To blow; to sound by blowing; esp., to sound with prolonged
   and mutually involved notes. ``Hunters who wound their
   horns.'' --Pennant.
   [1913 Webster]

         Ye vigorous swains, while youth ferments your blood, .
         . .
         Wind the shrill horn.                    --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]

         That blast was winded by the king.       --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wound \Wound\,
   imp. &amp; p. p. of {Wind} to twist, and {Wind} to sound by
   blowing.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wound \Wound\ (?; 277), n. [OE. wounde, wunde, AS. wund; akin to
   OFries. wunde, OS. wunda, D. wonde, OHG. wunta, G. wunde,
   Icel. und, and to AS., OS., &amp; G. wund sore, wounded, OHG.
   wunt, Goth. wunds, and perhaps also to Goth. winnan to
   suffer, E. win. [root]140. Cf. Zounds.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A hurt or injury caused by violence; specifically, a
      breach of the skin and flesh of an animal, or in the
      substance of any creature or living thing; a cut, stab,
      rent, or the like. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Showers of blood
            Rained from the wounds of slaughtered Englishmen.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: An injury, hurt, damage, detriment, or the like, to
      feeling, faculty, reputation, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Criminal Law) An injury to the person by which the skin
      is divided, or its continuity broken; a lesion of the
      body, involving some solution of continuity.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Walker condemns the pronunciation woond as a
         ``capricious novelty.'' It is certainly opposed to an
         important principle of our language, namely, that the
         Old English long sound written ou, and pronounced like
         French ou or modern English oo, has regularly changed,
         when accented, into the diphthongal sound usually
         written with the same letters ou in modern English, as
         in ground, hound, round, sound. The use of ou in Old
         English to represent the sound of modern English oo was
         borrowed from the French, and replaced the older and
         Anglo-Saxon spelling with u. It makes no difference
         whether the word was taken from the French or not,
         provided it is old enough in English to have suffered
         this change to what is now the common sound of ou; but
         words taken from the French at a later time, or
         influenced by French, may have the French sound.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Wound gall} (Zo["o]l.), an elongated swollen or tuberous
      gall on the branches of the grapevine, caused by a small
      reddish brown weevil ({Ampeloglypter sesostris}) whose
      larv[ae] inhabit the galls.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wound \Wound\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wounded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Wounding}.] [AS. wundian. [root]140. See {Wound}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To hurt by violence; to produce a breach, or separation of
      parts, in, as by a cut, stab, blow, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            The archers hit him; and he was sore wounded of the
            archers.                              --1 Sam. xxxi.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To hurt the feelings of; to pain by disrespect,
      ingratitude, or the like; to cause injury to.
      [1913 Webster]

            When ye sin so against the brethren, and wound their
            weak conscience, ye sin against Christ. --1 Cor.
                                                  viii. 12.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>coiled \coiled\ (koild), adj.
   curled or wound especially in concentric rings or spirals;
   as, a coiled snake ready to strike; the rope lay coiled on
   the deck. Opposite of {uncoiled}.

   Note: [Narrower terms: {coiling, helical, spiral, spiraling,
         volute, voluted, whorled}; {convolute rolled
         longitudinally upon itself};{curled, curled up};
         {involute closely coiled so that the axis is
         obscured)}; {looped, whorled}; {twined, twisted};
         {convoluted}; {involute, rolled esp of petals or leaves
         in bud: having margins rolled inward)}; {wound}]
         [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wind
     n 1: air moving (sometimes with considerable force) from an area
          of high pressure to an area of low pressure; "trees bent
          under the fierce winds"; "when there is no wind, row";
          "the radioactivity was being swept upwards by the air
          current and out into the atmosphere" [syn: {air current},
           {current of air}]
     2: a tendency or force that influences events; "the winds of
        change"
     3: breath; "the collision knocked the wind out of him"
     4: empty rhetoric or insincere or exaggerated talk; "that's a
        lot of wind"; "don't give me any of that jazz" [syn: {idle
        words}, {jazz}, {nothingness}]
     5: an indication of potential opportunity; "he got a tip on the
        stock market"; "a good lead for a job" [syn: {tip}, {lead},
         {steer}, {confidential information}, {hint}]
     6: a musical instrument in which the sound is produced by an
        enclosed column of air that is moved by the breath [syn: {wind
        instrument}]
     7: a reflex that expels intestinal gas through the anus [syn: {fart},
         {farting}, {flatus}, {breaking wind}]
     8: the act of winding or twisting; "he put the key in the old
        clock and gave it a good wind" [syn: {winding}, {twist}]
     v 1: to move or cause to move in a sinuous, spiral, or circular
          course; "the river winds through the hills"; "the path
          meanders through the vineyards"; "sometimes, the gout
          wanders through the entire body" [syn: {weave}, {thread},
           {meander}, {wander}]
     2: extend in curves and turns; "The road winds around the lake"
        [syn: {curve}]
     3: wrap or coil around; "roll your hair around your finger";
        "Twine the thread around the spool" [syn: {wrap}, {roll},
        {twine}] [ant: {unwind}]
     4: catch the scent of; get wind of; "The dog nosed out the
        drugs" [syn: {scent}, {nose}]
     5: coil the spring of (some mechanical device) by turning a
        stem; "wind your watch" [syn: {wind up}]
     6: form into a wreath [syn: {wreathe}]
     7: raise or haul up with or as if with mechanical help; "hoist
        the bicycle onto the roof of the car" [syn: {hoist}, {lift}]
     [also: {wound}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wound
     adj : put in a coil
     n 1: any break in the skin or an organ caused by violence or
          surgical incision [syn: {lesion}]
     2: a casualty to military personnel resulting from combat [syn:
         {injury}, {combat injury}]
     3: a figurative injury (to your feelings or pride); "he feared
        that mentioning it might reopen the wound"; "deep in her
        breast lives the silent wound"; "The right reader of a
        good poem can tell the moment it strikes him that he has
        taken an immortal wound--that he will never get over
        it"--Robert Frost
     4: the act of inflicting a wound [syn: {wounding}]
     v 1: cause injuries or bodily harm to [syn: {injure}]
     2: hurt the feelings of; "She hurt me when she did not include
        me among her guests"; "This remark really bruised me ego"
        [syn: {hurt}, {injure}, {bruise}, {offend}, {spite}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wound</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wound
     See {wind}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
