<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wrath</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>WRATH, n.  Anger of a superior quality and degree, appropriate to
exalted characters and momentous occasions; as, "the wrath of God,"
"the day of wrath," etc.  Amongst the ancients the wrath of kings was
deemed sacred, for it could usually command the agency of some god for
its fit manifestation, as could also that of a priest.  The Greeks
before Troy were so harried by Apollo that they jumped out of the
frying-pan of the wrath of Cryses into the fire of the wrath of
Achilles, though Agamemnon, the sole offender, was neither fried nor
roasted.  A similar noted immunity was that of David when he incurred
the wrath of Yahveh by numbering his people, seventy thousand of whom
paid the penalty with their lives.  God is now Love, and a director of
the census performs his work without apprehension of disaster.


                                  X


X in our alphabet being a needless letter has an added invincibility
to the attacks of the spelling reformers, and like them, will
doubtless last as long as the language.  X is the sacred symbol of ten
dollars, and in such words as Xmas, Xn, etc., stands for Christ, not,
as is popular supposed, because it represents a cross, but because the
corresponding letter in the Greek alphabet is the initial of his name
-- _Xristos_.  If it represented a cross it would stand for St.
Andrew, who "testified" upon one of that shape.  In the algebra of
psychology x stands for Woman's mind.  Words beginning with X are
Grecian and will not be defined in this standard English dictionary.


                                  Y



</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrath \Wrath\ (?; 277), n. [OE. wrathe, wra[thorn][thorn]e,
   wrethe, wr[ae][eth][eth]e, AS. wr[=ae][eth][eth]o, fr.
   wr[=a][eth] wroth; akin to Icel. rei[eth]i wrath. See
   {Wroth}, a.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Violent anger; vehement exasperation; indignation; rage;
      fury; ire.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wrath is a fire, and jealousy a weed. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the wrath of king Ahasuerus was appeased.
                                                  --Esther ii.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now smoking and frothing
            Its tumult and wrath in.              --Southey.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The effects of anger or indignation; the just punishment
      of an offense or a crime. ``A revenger to execute wrath
      upon him that doeth evil.'' --Rom. xiii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Anger; fury; rage; ire; vengeance; indignation;
        resentment; passion. See {Anger}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrath \Wrath\, a.
   See {Wroth}. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrath \Wrath\, v. t.
   To anger; to enrage; -- also used impersonally. [Obs.] ``I
   will not wrathen him.'' --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

         If him wratheth, be ywar and his way shun. --Piers
                                                  Plowman.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrath</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wrath
     n 1: intense anger (usually on an epic scale)
     2: belligerence aroused by a real or supposed wrong
        (personified as one of the deadly sins) [syn: {anger}, {ire},
         {ira}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
