<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wreck</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wreck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wreck \Wreck\, v. t. &amp; n.
   See 2d &amp; 3d {Wreak}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wreck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wreck \Wreck\, n. [OE. wrak, AS. wr[ae]c exile, persecution,
   misery, from wrecan to drive out, punish; akin to D. wrak,
   adj., damaged, brittle, n., a wreck, wraken to reject, throw
   off, Icel. rek a thing drifted ashore, Sw. vrak refuse, a
   wreck, Dan. vrag. See {Wreak}, v. t., and cf. {Wrack} a
   marine plant.] [Written also {wrack}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The destruction or injury of a vessel by being cast on
      shore, or on rocks, or by being disabled or sunk by the
      force of winds or waves; shipwreck.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hard and obstinate
            As is a rock amidst the raging floods,
            'Gainst which a ship, of succor desolate,
            Doth suffer wreck, both of herself and goods.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Destruction or injury of anything, especially by violence;
      ruin; as, the wreck of a railroad train.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wreck of matter and the crush of worlds.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Its intellectual life was thus able to go on amidst
            the wreck of its political life.      --J. R. Green.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The ruins of a ship stranded; a ship dashed against rocks
      or land, and broken, or otherwise rendered useless, by
      violence and fracture; as, they burned the wreck.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The remain of anything ruined or fatally injured.
      [1913 Webster]

            To the fair haven of my native home,
            The wreck of what I was, fatigued I come. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) Goods, etc., which, after a shipwreck, are cast upon
      the land by the sea. --Bouvier.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wreck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wreck \Wreck\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wrecked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Wrecking}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To destroy, disable, or seriously damage, as a vessel, by
      driving it against the shore or on rocks, by causing it to
      become unseaworthy, to founder, or the like; to shipwreck.
      [1913 Webster]

            Supposing that they saw the king's ship wrecked.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring wreck or ruin upon by any kind of violence; to
      destroy, as a railroad train.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To involve in a wreck; hence, to cause to suffer ruin; to
      balk of success, and bring disaster on.
      [1913 Webster]

            Weak and envied, if they should conspire,
            They wreck themselves.                --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wreck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wreck \Wreck\, v. i.
   1. To suffer wreck or ruin. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To work upon a wreck, as in saving property or lives, or
      in plundering.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wreck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wreck
     n 1: something or someone that has suffered ruin or dilapidation;
          "the house was a wreck when they bought it"; "thanks to
          that quack I am a human wreck"
     2: an accident that destroys a ship at sea [syn: {shipwreck}]
     3: a serious accident (usually involving one or more vehicles);
        "they are still investigating the crash of the TWA plane"
        [syn: {crash}]
     4: a ship that has been destroyed at sea
     v : smash or break forcefully; "The kid busted up the car" [syn:
          {bust up}, {wrack}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
