<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wrestling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrestling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrestle \Wres"tle\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wrestled}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Wrestling}.] [OE. wrestlen, wrastlen, AS. wr?stlian,
   freq. of wr?stan to wrest; akin to OD. wrastelen to wrestle.
   See {Wrest}, v. t.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To contend, by grappling with, and striving to trip or
      throw down, an opponent; as, they wrestled skillfully.
      [1913 Webster]

            To-morrow, sir, I wrestle for my credit, and he that
            escapes me without some broken limb shall acquit him
            well.                                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Another, by a fall in wrestling, started the end of
            the clavicle from the sternum.        --Wiseman.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to struggle; to strive earnestly; to contend.
      [1913 Webster]

            Come, wrestle with thy affections.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            We wrestle not against flesh and blood. --Eph. vi.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Difficulties with which he had himself wrestled.
                                                  --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrestling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrestling \Wres"tling\, n.
   Act of one who wrestles; specif., the sport consisting of the
   hand-to-hand combat between two unarmed contestants who seek
   to throw each other.

   Note: The various styles of wrestling differ in their
         definition of a fall and in the governing rules. In

   {Greco-Roman wrestling}, tripping and taking hold of the legs
      are forbidden, and a fall is gained (that is, the bout is
      won), by the contestant who pins both his opponent's
      shoulders to the ground. In

   {catch-as-catch-can wrestling}, all holds are permitted
      except such as may be barred by mutual consent, and a fall
      is defined as in Greco-Roman style.

   {Lancashire style wrestling} is essentially the same as
      catch-as-catch-can. In

   {Cumberland and Westmorland wrestling} the contestants stand
      chest to chest, grasping each other around the body. The
      one first losing his hold, or touching the ground with any
      part of his body except his feet, loses the bout. If both
      fall to the ground at the same time, it is a dogfall, and
      must be wrestled over. In the

   {Cornwall and Devon wrestling}, the wrestlers complete in
      strong loose linen jackets, catching hold of the jacket,
      or anywhere above the waist. Two shoulders and one hip, or
      two hips and one shoulder, must touch the ground to
      constitute a fall, and if a man is thrown otherwise than
      on his back the contestants get upon their feet and the
      bout recommences.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrestling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wrestling
     n 1: the act of engaging in close hand-to-hand combat; "they had
          a fierce wrestle"; "we watched his grappling and
          wrestling with the bully" [syn: {wrestle}, {grapple}, {grappling},
           {hand-to-hand struggle}]
     2: the sport of hand-to-hand struggle between unarmed
        contestants who try to throw each other down [syn: {rassling},
         {grappling}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
