<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>writ</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>writ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Write \Write\, v. t. [imp. {Wrote}; p. p. {Written}; Archaic
   imp. &amp; p. p. {Writ}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Writing}.] [OE. writen,
   AS. wr[=i]tan; originally, to scratch, to score; akin to OS.
   wr[=i]tan to write, to tear, to wound, D. rijten to tear, to
   rend, G. reissen, OHG. r[=i]zan, Icel. r[=i]ta to write,
   Goth. writs a stroke, dash, letter. Cf. {Race} tribe,
   lineage.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To set down, as legible characters; to form the conveyance
      of meaning; to inscribe on any material by a suitable
      instrument; as, to write the characters called letters; to
      write figures.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To set down for reading; to express in legible or
      intelligible characters; to inscribe; as, to write a deed;
      to write a bill of divorcement; hence, specifically, to
      set down in an epistle; to communicate by letter.
      [1913 Webster]

            Last night she enjoined me to write some lines to
            one she loves.                        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I chose to write the thing I durst not speak
            To her I loved.                       --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, to compose or produce, as an author.
      [1913 Webster]

            I purpose to write the history of England from the
            accession of King James the Second down to a time
            within the memory of men still living. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To impress durably; to imprint; to engrave; as, truth
      written on the heart.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To make known by writing; to record; to prove by one's own
      written testimony; -- often used reflexively.
      [1913 Webster]

            He who writes himself by his own inscription is like
            an ill painter, who, by writing on a shapeless
            picture which he hath drawn, is fain to tell
            passengers what shape it is, which else no man could
            imagine.                              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To write to}, to communicate by a written document to.

   {Written laws}, laws deriving their force from express
      legislative enactment, as contradistinguished from
      unwritten, or common, law. See the Note under {Law}, and
      {Common law}, under {Common}, a.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>writ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Writ \Writ\, obs.
   3d pers. sing. pres. of {Write}, for writeth. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>writ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Writ \Writ\, archaic
   imp. &amp; p. p. of {Write}. --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>writ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Writ \Writ\, n. [AS. writ, gewrit. See {Write}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. That which is written; writing; scripture; -- applied
      especially to the Scriptures, or the books of the Old and
      New testaments; as, sacred writ. ``Though in Holy Writ not
      named.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then to his hands that writ he did betake,
            Which he disclosing read, thus as the paper spake.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Babylon, so much spoken of in Holy Writ. --Knolles.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) An instrument in writing, under seal, in an
      epistolary form, issued from the proper authority,
      commanding the performance or nonperformance of some act
      by the person to whom it is directed; as, a writ of entry,
      of error, of execution, of injunction, of mandamus, of
      return, of summons, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Writs are usually witnessed, or tested, in the name of
         the chief justice or principal judge of the court out
         of which they are issued; and those directed to a
         sheriff, or other ministerial officer, require him to
         return them on a day specified. In former English law
         and practice, writs in civil cases were either original
         or judicial; the former were issued out of the Court of
         Chancery, under the great seal, for the summoning of a
         defendant to appear, and were granted before the suit
         began and in order to begin the same; the latter were
         issued out of the court where the original was
         returned, after the suit was begun and during the
         pendency of it. Tomlins. Brande. Encyc. Brit. The term
         writ is supposed by Mr. Reeves to have been derived
         from the fact of these formul[ae] having always been
         expressed in writing, being, in this respect,
         distinguished from the other proceedings in the ancient
         action, which were conducted orally.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Writ of account}, {Writ of capias}, etc. See under
      {Account}, {Capias}, etc.

   {Service of a writ}. See under {Service}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>writ</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>writ
     n : (law) a legal document issued by a court or judicial officer
         [syn: {judicial writ}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
