<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>wrong</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrong</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Private \Pri"vate\ (?; 48), a. [L. privatus apart from the
   state, peculiar to an individual, private, properly p. p. of
   privare to bereave, deprive, originally, to separate, fr.
   privus single, private, perhaps originally, put forward
   (hence, alone, single) and akin to prae before. See {Prior},
   a., and cf. {Deprive}, {Privy}, a.]
   1. Belonging to, or concerning, an individual person,
      company, or interest; peculiar to one's self; unconnected
      with others; personal; one's own; not public; not general;
      separate; as, a man's private opinion; private property; a
      private purse; private expenses or interests; a private
      secretary.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Sequestered from company or observation; appropriated to
      an individual; secret; secluded; lonely; solitary; as, a
      private room or apartment; private prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Reason . . . then retires
            Into her private cell when nature rests. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not invested with, or engaged in, public office or
      employment; as, a private citizen; private life. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A private person may arrest a felon.  --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Not publicly known; not open; secret; as, a private
      negotiation; a private understanding.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Having secret or private knowledge; privy. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Private act} or {Private statute}, a statute exclusively for
      the settlement of private and personal interests, of which
      courts do not take judicial notice; -- opposed to a
      {general law}, which operates on the whole community. In
      the United States Congress, similar private acts are
      referred to as {private law} and a general law as a
      {public law}.

   {Private nuisance} or {wrong}. See {Nuisance}.

   {Private soldier}. See {Private}, n., 5.

   {Private way}, a right of private passage over another man's
      ground; also, a road on private land, contrasted with
      {public road}, which is on a public right of way. --Kent.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrong</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrong \Wrong\ (?; 115), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Wronged}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Wronging}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To treat with injustice; to deprive of some right, or to
      withhold some act of justice from; to do undeserved harm
      to; to deal unjustly with; to injure.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that sinneth . . . wrongeth his own soul. --Prov.
                                                  viii. 36.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To impute evil to unjustly; as, if you suppose me capable
      of a base act, you wrong me.
      [1913 Webster]

            I rather choose
            To wrong the dead, to wrong myself and you,
            Than I will wrong such honorable men. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrong</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrong \Wrong\, adv.
   In a wrong manner; not rightly; amiss; morally ill;
   erroneously; wrongly.
   [1913 Webster]

         Ten censure wrong for one that writes amiss. --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrong</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrong \Wrong\, obs.
   imp. of {Wring}. Wrung. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrong</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrong \Wrong\ (?; 115), a. [OE. wrong, wrang, a. &amp; n., AS.
   wrang, n.; originally, awry, wrung, fr. wringan to wring;
   akin to D. wrang bitter, Dan. vrang wrong, Sw. vr[*a]ng,
   Icel. rangr awry, wrong. See {Wring}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Twisted; wry; as, a wrong nose. [Obs.] --Wyclif (Lev. xxi.
      19).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not according to the laws of good morals, whether divine
      or human; not suitable to the highest and best end; not
      morally right; deviating from rectitude or duty; not just
      or equitable; not true; not legal; as, a wrong practice;
      wrong ideas; wrong inclinations and desires.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not fit or suitable to an end or object; not appropriate
      for an intended use; not according to rule; unsuitable;
      improper; incorrect; as, to hold a book with the wrong end
      uppermost; to take the wrong way.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have deceived you both; I have directed you to
            wrong places.                         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Not according to truth; not conforming to fact or intent;
      not right; mistaken; erroneous; as, a wrong statement.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Designed to be worn or placed inward; as, the wrong side
      of a garment or of a piece of cloth.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Injurious; unjust; faulty; detrimental; incorrect;
        erroneous; unfit; unsuitable.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrong</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wrong \Wrong\, n. [AS. wrang. See {Wrong}, a.]
   That which is not right. Specifically:
   (a) Nonconformity or disobedience to lawful authority, divine
       or human; deviation from duty; -- the opposite of moral
       {right}.
       [1913 Webster]

             When I had wrong and she the right.  --Chaucer.
       [1913 Webster]

             One spake much of right and wrong.   --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]
   (b) Deviation or departure from truth or fact; state of
       falsity; error; as, to be in the wrong.
   (c) Whatever deviates from moral rectitude; usually, an act
       that involves evil consequences, as one which inflicts
       injury on a person; any injury done to, or received from;
       another; a trespass; a violation of right.
       [1913 Webster]

             Friend, I do thee no wrong.          --Matt. xx.
                                                  18.
       [1913 Webster]

             As the king of England can do no wrong, so neither
             can he do right but in his courts and by his
             courts.                              --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

             The obligation to redress a wrong is at least as
             binding as that of paying a debt.    --E. Evereth.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Wrongs, legally, are private or public. Private wrongs
         are civil injuries, immediately affecting individuals;
         public wrongs are crimes and misdemeanors which affect
         the community. --Blackstone.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>wrong</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>wrong
     adj 1: not correct; not in conformity with fact or truth; "an
            incorrect calculation"; "the report in the paper is
            wrong"; "your information is wrong"; "the clock showed
            the wrong time"; "found themselves on the wrong road";
            "based on the wrong assumptions" [syn: {incorrect}]
            [ant: {correct}, {correct}]
     2: contrary to conscience or morality or law; "it is wrong for
        the rich to take advantage of the poor"; "cheating is
        wrong"; "it is wrong to lie" [ant: {right}]
     3: not appropriate for a purpose or occasion; "unsuitable
        attire for the office"; "said all the wrong things" [syn:
        {unsuitable}, {improper}]
     4: not functioning properly; "something is amiss"; "has gone
        completely haywire"; "something is wrong with the engine"
        [syn: {amiss(p)}, {awry(p)}, {haywire}, {wrong(p)}]
     5: not according with the facts; "unfortunately the statement
        was simply untrue"; "the facts as reported were wrong"
        [syn: {untrue}]
     6: based on or acting or judging in error; "it is wrong to
        think that way" [ant: {right}]
     7: not in accord with established usage or procedure; "the
        wrong medicine"; "the wrong way to shuck clams"
     8: not conforming with accepted standards of propriety or
        taste; undesirable; "incorrect behavior"; "she was seen in
        all the wrong places"; "He thought it was wrong for her to
        go out to work" [syn: {inappropriate}, {incorrect}]
     9: used of the side of cloth or clothing intended to face
        inward; "socks worn wrong side out"
     10: badly timed; "an ill-timed intervention"; "you think my
         intrusion unseasonable"; "an untimely remark"; "it was
         the wrong moment for a joke" [syn: {ill-timed(a)}, {ill
         timed(p)}, {unseasonable}, {untimely}]
     n 1: that which is contrary to the principles of justice or law;
          "he feels that you are in the wrong" [syn: {wrongfulness}]
          [ant: {right}, {right}]
     2: a legal injury is any damage resulting from a violation of a
        legal right [syn: {legal injury}, {damage}]
     adv : in an incorrect manner; "she guessed wrong" [syn: {incorrectly},
            {wrongly}] [ant: {correctly}, {correctly}]
     v : treat unjustly; do wrong to [ant: {right}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
