<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>name</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>name</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Name \Name\ (n[=a]m), n. [AS. nama; akin to D. naam, OS. &amp; OHG.
   namo, G. name, Icel. nafn, for namn, Dan. navn, Sw. namn,
   Goth. nam[=o], L. nomen (perh. influenced by noscere,
   gnoscere, to learn to know), Gr. 'o`mona, Scr. n[=a]man.
   [root]267. Cf. {Anonymous}, {Ignominy}, {Misnomer},
   {Nominal}, {Noun}.]
   1. The title by which any person or thing is known or
      designated; a distinctive specific appellation, whether of
      an individual or a class.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whatsoever Adam called every living creature, that
            was the name thereof.                 --Gen. ii. 19.
      [1913 Webster]

            What's in a name? That which we call a rose
            By any other name would smell as sweet. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A descriptive or qualifying appellation given to a person
      or thing, on account of a character or acts.
      [1913 Webster]

            His name shall be called Wonderful, Counsellor, The
            mighty God, The everlasting Father, The Prince of
            Peace.                                --Is. ix. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Reputed character; reputation, good or bad; estimation;
      fame; especially, illustrious character or fame; honorable
      estimation; distinction.
      [1913 Webster]

            What men of name resort to him?       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Far above . . . every name that is named, not only
            in this world, but also in that which is to come.
                                                  --Eph. i. 21.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will get me a name and honor in the kingdom. --1
                                                  Macc. iii. 14.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hath brought up an evil name upon a virgin.
                                                  --Deut. xxii.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king's army . . . had left no good name behind.
                                                  --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Those of a certain name; a race; a family.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ministers of the republic, mortal enemies of his
            name, came every day to pay their feigned
            civilities.                           --Motley.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A person, an individual. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            They list with women each degenerate name. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Christian name}.
      (a) The name a person receives at baptism, as
          distinguished from {surname}; baptismal name; in
          western countries, it is also called a {first name}.
      (b) A given name, whether received at baptism or not.

   {Given name}. See under {Given}.

   {In name}, in profession, or by title only; not in reality;
      as, a friend in name.

   {In the name of}.
      (a) In behalf of; by the authority of. `` I charge you in
          the duke's name to obey me.''           --Shak.
      (b) In the represented or assumed character of. ``I'll to
          him again in name of Brook.''           --Shak.

   {Name plate}, a plate as of metal, glass, etc., having a name
      upon it, as a sign; a doorplate.

   {Pen name}, a name assumed by an author; a pseudonym or {nom
      de plume}. --Bayard Taylor.

   {Proper name} (Gram.), a name applied to a particular person,
      place, or thing.

   {To call names}, to apply opprobrious epithets to; to call by
      reproachful appellations.

   {To take a name in vain}, to use a name lightly or profanely;
      to use a name in making flippant or dishonest oaths. --Ex.
      xx. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Appellation; title; designation; cognomen; denomination;
        epithet.

   Usage: {Name}, {Appellation}, {Title}, {Denomination}. Name
          is generic, denoting that combination of sounds or
          letters by which a person or thing is known and
          distinguished. Appellation, although sometimes put for
          name simply, denotes, more properly, a descriptive
          term (called also {agnomen} or {cognomen}), used by
          way of marking some individual peculiarity or
          characteristic; as, Charles the Bold, Philip the
          Stammerer. A title is a term employed to point out
          one's rank, office, etc.; as, the Duke of Bedford,
          Paul the Apostle, etc. Denomination is to particular
          bodies what appellation is to individuals; thus, the
          church of Christ is divided into different
          denominations, as Congregationalists, Episcopalians,
          Presbyterians, etc.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>name</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Name \Name\ (n[=a]m), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Named} (n[=a]md); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Naming}.] [AS. namian. See {Name}, n.]
   1. To give a distinctive name or appellation to; to entitle;
      to denominate; to style; to call.
      [1913 Webster]

            She named the child Ichabod.          --1 Sam. iv.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus was the building left
            Ridiculous, and the work Confusion named. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mention by name; to utter or publish the name of; to
      refer to by distinctive title; to mention.
      [1913 Webster]

            None named thee but to praise.        --Halleck.
      [1913 Webster]

            Old Yew, which graspest at the stones
            That name the underlying dead.        --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To designate by name or specifically for any purpose; to
      nominate; to specify; to appoint; as, to name a day for
      the wedding; to name someone as ambassador.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whom late you have named for consul.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (House of Commons) To designate (a member) by name, as the
      Speaker does by way of reprimand.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To denominate; style; term; call; mention; specify;
        designate; nominate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>name</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>name
     n 1: a language unit by which a person or thing is known; "his
          name really is George Washington"; "those are two names
          for the same thing"
     2: by the sanction or authority of; "halt in the name of the
        law"
     3: a person's reputation; "he wanted to protect his good name"
     4: a well-known or notable person; "they studied all the great
        names in the history of France"; "she is an important
        figure in modern music" [syn: {figure}, {public figure}]
     5: family based on male descent; "he had no sons and there was
        no one to carry on his name" [syn: {gens}]
     6: a defamatory or abusive word or phrase; "sticks and stones
        may break my bones but names can never hurt me" [syn: {epithet}]
     v 1: assign a specified, proper name to; "They named their son
          David"; "The new school was named after the famous Civil
          Rights leader" [syn: {call}]
     2: give the name or identifying characteristics of; refer to by
        name or some other identifying characteristic property;
        "Many senators were named in connection with the scandal";
        "The almanac identifies the auspicious months" [syn: {identify}]
     3: charge with a function; charge to be; "She was named Head of
        the Committee"; "She was made president of the club" [syn:
         {nominate}, {make}]
     4: create and charge with a task or function; "nominate a
        committee" [syn: {appoint}, {nominate}, {constitute}]
     5: mention and identify by name; "name your accomplices!"
     6: identify as in botany or biology, for example [syn: {identify},
         {discover}, {key}, {key out}, {distinguish}, {describe}]
     7: make reference to; "His name was mentioned in connection
        with the invention" [syn: {mention}, {advert}, {bring up},
         {cite}, {refer}]
     8: give or make a list of; name individually; give the names
        of; "List the states west of the Mississippi" [syn: {list}]
     9: determine or distinguish the nature of a problem or an
        illness through a diagnostic analysis [syn: {diagnose}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
