<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>navigate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>navigate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Navigate \Nav"i*gate\, v. t.
   1. To pass over in ships; to sail over or on; as, to navigate
      the Atlantic.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To steer, direct, or manage in sailing; to conduct (ships)
      upon the water by the art or skill of seamen; as, to
      navigate a ship.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass through, over, or around; -- used especially of a
      course having obstacles; as, to navigate all the randomly
      scattered tables to the far side of the room.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>navigate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Navigate \Nav"i*gate\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Navigated}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Navigating}.] [L. navigatus, p. p. of navigare, v.t.
   &amp; i.; navis ship + agere to move, direct. See {Nave}, and
   {Agent}.]
   1. To journey by water; to go in a vessel or ship; to perform
      the duties of a navigator; to use the waters as a highway
      or channel for commerce or communication; to sail.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Phenicians navigated to the extremities of the
            Western Ocean.                        --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To direct or operate a vehicle, especially a ship or
      aircraft.
      [PJC]

   3. To pass through, over, or around; -- used especially of a
      course having obstacles; as, to navigate around all the
      randomly scattered tables to the far side of the room.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>navigate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>navigate
     v 1: travel by boat on a boat propelled by wind or by other
          means; "The QE2 will sail to Southampton tomorrow" [syn:
           {voyage}, {sail}]
     2: act as the navigator in a car, plane, or vessel and plan,
        direct, plot the path and position of the conveyance; "Is
        anyone volunteering to navigate during the trip?"; "Who
        was navigating the ship during the accident?" [syn: {pilot}]
     3: direct carefully and safely; "He navigated his way to the
        altar"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
