<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>negative</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>negative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Negative \Neg"a*tive\ (n[e^]g"[.a]*t[i^]v), a. [F. n['e]gatif,
   L. negativus, fr. negare to deny. See {Negation}.]
   1. Denying; implying, containing, or asserting denial,
      negation or refusal; returning the answer no to an inquiry
      or request; refusing assent; as, a negative answer; a
      negative opinion; -- opposed to {affirmative}.
      [1913 Webster]

            If thou wilt confess,
            Or else be impudently negative.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Denying me any power of a negative voice. --Eikon
                                                  Basilike.
      [1913 Webster]

            Something between an affirmative bow and a negative
            shake.                                --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not positive; without affirmative statement or
      demonstration; indirect; consisting in the absence of
      something; privative; as, a negative argument; negative
      evidence; a negative morality; negative criticism.
      [1913 Webster]

            There in another way of denying Christ, . . . which
            is negative, when we do not acknowledge and confess
            him.                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Logic) Asserting absence of connection between a subject
      and a predicate; as, a negative proposition.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Photog.) Of or pertaining to a picture upon glass or
      other material, in which the lights and shades of the
      original, and the relations of right and left, are
      reversed.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Chem.) Metalloidal; nonmetallic; -- contrasted with
      {positive} or {basic}; as, the nitro group is negative.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: This word, derived from electro-negative, is now
         commonly used in a more general sense, when acidiferous
         is the intended signification.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Negative crystal}.
      (a) A cavity in a mineral mass, having the form of a
          crystal.
      (b) A crystal which has the power of negative double
          refraction. See {refraction}.

   {negative electricity} (Elec.), the kind of electricity which
      is developed upon resin or ebonite when rubbed, or which
      appears at that pole of a voltaic battery which is
      connected with the plate most attacked by the exciting
      liquid; -- formerly called {resinous electricity}. Opposed
      to {positive electricity}. Formerly, according to
      Franklin's theory of a single electric fluid, negative
      electricity was supposed to be electricity in a degree
      below saturation, or the natural amount for a given body.
      See {Electricity}.

   {Negative eyepiece}. (Opt.) see under {Eyepiece}.

   {Negative quantity} (Alg.), a quantity preceded by the
      negative sign, or which stands in the relation indicated
      by this sign to some other quantity. See {Negative sign}
      (below).

   {Negative rotation}, right-handed rotation. See
      {Right-handed}, 3.

   {Negative sign}, the sign -, or {minus} (opposed in
      signification to +, or {plus}), indicating that the
      quantity to which it is prefixed is to be subtracted from
      the preceding quantity, or is to be reckoned from zero or
      cipher in the opposite direction to that of quanties
      having the sign plus either expressed or understood; thus,
      in a - b, b is to be substracted from a, or regarded as
      opposite to it in value; and -10[deg] on a thermometer
      means 10[deg] below the zero of the scale.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>negative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Negative \Neg"a*tive\ (n[e^]g"[.a]*t[i^]v), n. [Cf. F.
   n['e]gative.]
   1. A proposition by which something is denied or forbidden; a
      conception or term formed by prefixing the negative
      particle to one which is positive; an opposite or
      contradictory term or conception.
      [1913 Webster]

            This is a known rule in divinity, that there is no
            command that runs in negatives but couches under it
            a positive duty.                      --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A word used in denial or refusal; as, not, no.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In Old England two or more negatives were often joined
         together for the sake of emphasis, whereas now such
         expressions are considered ungrammatical, being chiefly
         heard in iliterate speech. A double negative is now
         sometimes used as nearly or quite equivalent to an
         affirmative.
         [1913 Webster]

               No wine ne drank she, neither white nor red.
                                                  --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

               These eyes that never did nor never shall
               So much as frown on you.           --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The refusal or withholding of assents; veto.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a kind without his kingdom be, in a civil sense,
            nothing, then . . . his negative is as good as
            nothing.                              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That side of a question which denies or refuses, or which
      is taken by an opposing or denying party; the relation or
      position of denial or opposition; as, the question was
      decided in the negative.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Photog.) A picture upon glass or other material, in which
      the light portions of the original are represented in some
      opaque material (usually reduced silver), and the dark
      portions by the uncovered and transparent or
      semitransparent ground of the picture.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A negative is chiefly used for producing photographs by
         means of passing light through it and acting upon
         sensitized paper, thus producing on the paper a
         positive picture.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. (Elect.) The negative plate of a voltaic or electrolytic
      cell.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Negative pregnant} (Law), a negation which implies an
      affirmation.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>negative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Negative \Neg"a*tive\ (n[e^]g"[.a]*t[i^]v), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Negatived} (n[e^]g"[.a]*t[i^]vd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Negativing}.]
   1. To prove unreal or untrue; to disprove.
      [1913 Webster]

            The omission or infrequency of such recitals does
            not negative the existence of miracles. --Paley.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To reject by vote; to refuse to enact or sanction; as, the
      Senate negatived the bill.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To neutralize the force of; to counteract.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>negative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>eyepiece \eye"piece`\ eye-piece \eye"-piece`\, n. (Opt.)
   The lens, or combination of lenses, at the eye end of a
   microscope, telescope or other optical instrument, through
   which the image formed by the mirror or object glass is
   viewed.

   Syn: ocular.
        [1913 Webster]

   {Collimating eyepiece}. See under {Collimate}.

   {Negative}, or {Huyghenian}, {eyepiece}, an eyepiece
      consisting of two plano-convex lenses with their curved
      surfaces turned toward the object glass, and separated
      from each other by about half the sum of their focal
      distances, the image viewed by the eye being formed
      between the two lenses. it was devised by Huyghens, who
      applied it to the telescope. Campani applied it to the
      microscope, whence it is sometimes called {Campani's
      eyepiece}.

   {Positive eyepiece}, an eyepiece consisting of two
      plano-convex lenses placed with their curved surfaces
      toward each other, and separated by a distance somewhat
      less than the focal distance of the one nearest eye, the
      image of the object viewed being beyond both lenses; --
      called also, from the name of the inventor, {Ramsden's
      eyepiece}.

   {terrestrial}, or {Erecting eyepiece}, an eyepiece used in
      telescopes for viewing terrestrial objects, consisting of
      three, or usually four, lenses, so arranged as to present
      the image of the object viewed in an erect position.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>negative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>negative
     adj 1: characterized by or displaying negation or denial or
            opposition or resistance; having no positive features;
            "a negative outlook on life"; "a colorless negative
            personality"; "a negative evaluation"; "a negative
            reaction to an advertising campaign" [ant: {neutral},
            {positive}]
     2: reckoned in a direction opposite to that regarded as
        positive
     3: having a negative electric charge; "electrons are negative"
        [syn: {electronegative}] [ant: {neutral}, {positive}]
     4: expressing or consisting of a negation or refusal or denial
        [ant: {affirmative}]
     5: having the quality of something harmful or unpleasant; "ran
        a negative campaign"; "delinquents retarded by their
        negative outlook on life"
     6: not indicating the presence of microorganisms or disease or
        a specific condition; "the HIV test was negative" [syn: {disconfirming}]
        [ant: {positive}]
     7: less than zero; "a negative number"
     8: designed or tending to discredit, especially without
        positive or helpful suggestions; "negative criticism"
        [syn: {damaging}]
     9: involving disadvantage or harm; "minus (or negative)
        factors" [syn: {minus}]
     n 1: a reply of denial; "he answered in the negative" [ant: {affirmative}]
     2: a piece of photographic film showing an image with black and
        white tones reversed
     v : vote against; refuse to endorse; refuse to assent; "The
         President vetoed the bill" [syn: {veto}, {blackball}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
