<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>neon</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>neon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>elements</Id>
        <Name>Elements database 20001107</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>neon
Symbol: Ne
Atomic number: 10
Atomic weight: 20.183
Colourless gaseous element of group 18 on the periodic table (noble
gases). Neon occurs in the atmosphere, and comprises 0.0018% of the volume
of the atmosphere. It has a distinct reddish glow when used in discharge
tubes and neon based lamps. It forms almost no chemical compounds. Neon
was discovered in 1898 by Sir William Ramsey and M.W. Travers.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>neon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Neon
     
        Charles Duff.  An object-oriented extension of FORTH, for the
        Mac.  Inheritance, SANE {floating-point}, system classes and
        objects for Mac interfacing, overlays.  Sold by Kriya Systems,
        1985-1988.  Modified, made PD and renamed Yerk.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>neon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noble \No"ble\, a. [Compar. {Nobler}; superl. {Noblest}.] [F.
   noble, fr. L. nobilis that can be or is known, well known,
   famous, highborn, noble, fr. noscere to know. See {know}.]
   1. Possessing eminence, elevation, dignity, etc.; above
      whatever is low, mean, degrading, or dishonorable;
      magnanimous; as, a noble nature or action; a noble heart.
      [1913 Webster]

            Statues, with winding ivy crowned, belong
            To nobler poets for a nobler song.    --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Grand; stately; magnificent; splendid; as, a noble
      edifice.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Of exalted rank; of or pertaining to the nobility;
      distinguished from the masses by birth, station, or title;
      highborn; as, noble blood; a noble personage.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Noble is used in the formation of self-explaining
         compounds; as, noble-born, noble-hearted, noble-minded.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Noble gas} (Chem.), a gaseous element belonging to group
      VIII of the periodic table of elements, not combining with
      other elements under normal reaction conditions;
      specifically, {helium}, {neon}, {argon}, {krypton},
      {xenon}, or {radon}; also called {inert gas}.

   {Noble metals} (Chem.), silver, gold, and platinum; -- so
      called from their resistance to oxidation by air and to
      dissolution by acids. Copper, mercury, aluminium,
      palladium, rhodium, iridium, and osmium are sometimes
      included.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Honorable; worthy; dignified; elevated; exalted;
        superior; sublime; great; eminent; illustrious;
        renowned; stately; splendid; magnificent; grand;
        magnanimous; generous; liberal; free.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>neon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>neon
     n : a colorless odorless gaseous element that give a red glow in
         a vacuum tube; one of the six inert gasses; occurs in the
         air in small amounts [syn: {Ne}, {atomic number 10}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
