<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>network</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>network</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>network
     
        &lt;networking&gt; Hardware and software data communication systems.
     
        The {OSI} seven layer model attempts to provide a way of
        partitioning any computer network into independent modules
        from the lowest (physical) layer to the highest (application)
        layer.  Many different specifications exist at each of these
        layers.
     
        Networks are often also classified according to their
        geographical extent: {local area network} (LAN), {metropolitan
        area network} (MAN), {wide area network} (WAN) and also
        according to the {protocol}s used.
     
        See {BITNET}, {Ethernet}, {Internet}, {Novell}, {PSTN},
        {network, the}.
     
        [Tanenbaum, A., "Computer Networks; 2nd ed.", Prentice Hall,
        Englewood Cliffs, NJ, 1989.]
     
        (1995-03-10)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>network</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Network \Net"work`\, n.
   1. A fabric of threads, cords, or wires crossing each other
      at certain intervals, and knotted or secured at the
      crossings, thus leaving spaces or meshes between them.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any system of lines or channels interlacing or crossing
      like the fabric of a net; as, a network of veins; a
      network of railroads.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: (Computers) A system of computers linked together
      by communications channels allowing the exchange of data
      between the linked computers.
      [PJC]

   4. (Radio, Television) A group of transmitting stations
      connected by communications channels that permit the same
      program to be broadcast simultaneously from multiple
      stations over a very wide area; as, the CBS television
      network; also, the organization that controls the
      programming that is broadcast over such a network.
      Contrasted with a {local station} or {local transmitter}.
      [PJC]

   5. (Electricity, Electronics) Any arrangement of electrical
      devices or elements connected together by conducting
      wires; as, a power transmission network.
      [PJC]

   6. A group of buildings connected by means of transportation
      and communication between them, and controlled by a
      central organization for a common purpose; as, a book
      distribution network.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>network</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>network \net"work`\, v. i.
   To take steps to make and cultivate the acquaintance of
   people who can be helpful to oneself, especially in finding
   new employment, advancing to a higher position in one's
   occupation, or exchanging information.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>network</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>network \net"work`\, v. t.
   To connect together into a network; as, to network computers;
   to network the printer with computers.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>network</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>network
     n 1: an interconnected system of things or people; "he owned a
          network of shops"; "retirement meant dropping out of a
          whole network of people who had been part of my life";
          "tangled in a web of cloth" [syn: {web}]
     2: (broadcasting) a communication system consisting of a group
        of broadcasting stations that all transmit the same
        programs; "the networks compete to broadcast important
        sports events"
     3: an open fabric of string or rope or wire woven together at
        regular intervals [syn: {net}, {mesh}, {meshing}, {meshwork}]
     4: a system of intersecting lines or channels; "a railroad
        network"; "a network of canals"
     5: (electronics) a system of interconnected electronic
        components or circuits [syn: {electronic network}]
     v : communicate with and within a group; "You have to network if
         you want to get a good job"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
