<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>night</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>night</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Night \Night\ (n[imac]t), n. [OE. night, niht, AS. neaht, niht;
   akin to D. nacht, OS. &amp; OHG. naht, G. nacht, Icel. n[=o]tt,
   Sw. natt, Dan. nat, Goth. nahts, Lith. naktis, Russ. noche,
   W. nos, Ir. nochd, L. nox, noctis, Gr. ny`x, nykto`s, Skr.
   nakta, nakti. [root]265. Cf. {Equinox}, {Nocturnal}.]
   1. That part of the natural day when the sun is beneath the
      horizon, or the time from sunset to sunrise; esp., the
      time between dusk and dawn, when there is no light of the
      sun, but only moonlight, starlight, or artificial light.
      [1913 Webster]

            And God called the light Day, and the darkness he
            called Night.                         --Gen. i. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence:
      (a) Darkness; obscurity; concealment.
          [1913 Webster]

                Nature and nature's laws lay hid in night.
                                                  --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) Intellectual and moral darkness; ignorance.
      (c) A state of affliction; adversity; as, a dreary night
          of sorrow.
      (d) The period after the close of life; death.
          [1913 Webster]

                She closed her eyes in everlasting night.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

                Do not go gentle into that good night
                Rage, rage against the dying of the light.
                                                  --Dylan
                                                  Thomas.
          [PJC]
      (e) A lifeless or unenlivened period, as when nature seems
          to sleep. ``Sad winter's night''. --Spenser.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Night is sometimes used, esp. with participles, in the
         formation of self-explaining compounds; as,
         night-blooming, night-born, night-warbling, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Night by night}, {Night after night}, nightly; many nights.
      [1913 Webster]

            So help me God, as I have watched the night,
            Ay, night by night, in studying good for England.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Night bird}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The moor hen ({Gallinula chloropus}).
      (b) The Manx shearwater ({Puffinus Anglorum}).

   {Night blindness}. (Med.) See {Hemeralopia}.

   {Night cart}, a cart used to remove the contents of privies
      by night.

   {Night churr}, (Zo["o]l.), the nightjar.

   {Night crow}, a bird that cries in the night.

   {Night dog}, a dog that hunts in the night, -- used by
      poachers.

   {Night fire}.
      (a) Fire burning in the night.
      (b) Ignis fatuus; Will-o'-the-wisp; Jask-with-a-lantern.
          

   {Night flyer} (Zo["o]l.), any creature that flies in the
      night, as some birds and insects.

   {night glass}, a spyglass constructed to concentrate a large
      amount of light, so as see objects distinctly at night.
      --Totten.

   {Night green}, iodine green.

   {Night hag}, a witch supposed to wander in the night.

   {Night hawk} (Zo["o]l.), an American bird ({Chordeiles
      Virginianus}), allied to the goatsucker. It hunts the
      insects on which it feeds toward evening, on the wing, and
      often, diving down perpendicularly, produces a loud
      whirring sound, like that of a spinning wheel. Also
      sometimes applied to the European goatsuckers. It is
      called also {bull bat}.

   {Night heron} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      herons of the genus {Nycticorax}, found in various parts
      of the world. The best known species is {Nycticorax
      griseus}, or {Nycticorax nycticorax}, of Europe, and the
      American variety (var. n[ae]vius). The yellow-crowned
      night heron ({Nyctanassa violacea} syn. {Nycticorax
      violaceus}) inhabits the Southern States. Called also
      {qua-bird}, and {squawk}.

   {Night house}, a public house, or inn, which is open at
      night.

   {Night key}, a key for unfastening a night latch.

   {Night latch}, a kind of latch for a door, which is operated
      from the outside by a key.

   {Night monkey} (Zo["o]l.), an owl monkey.

   {night moth} (Zo["o]l.), any one of the noctuids.

   {Night parrot} (Zo["o]l.), the kakapo.

   {Night piece}, a painting representing some night scene, as a
      moonlight effect, or the like.

   {Night rail}, a loose robe, or garment, worn either as a
      nightgown, or over the dress at night, or in sickness.
      [Obs.]

   {Night raven} (Zo["o]l.), a bird of ill omen that cries in
      the night; esp., the bittern.

   {Night rule}.
      (a) A tumult, or frolic, in the night; -- as if a
          corruption, of night revel. [Obs.]
      (b) Such conduct as generally rules, or prevails, at
          night.

                What night rule now about this haunted grove?
                                                  --Shak.

   {Night sight}. (Med.) See {Nyctolopia}.

   {Night snap}, a night thief. [Cant] --Beau. &amp; Fl.

   {Night soil}, human excrement; -- so called because in cities
      it is collected by night and carried away for manure.

   {Night spell}, a charm against accidents at night.

   {Night swallow} (Zo["o]l.), the nightjar.

   {Night walk}, a walk in the evening or night.

   {Night walker}.
      (a) One who walks in his sleep; a somnambulist; a
          noctambulist.
      (b) One who roves about in the night for evil purposes;
          specifically, a prostitute who walks the streets.

   {Night walking}.
      (a) Walking in one's sleep; sleep walking; somnambulism;
          noctambulism.
      (b) Walking the streets at night with evil designs.

   {Night warbler} (Zo["o]l.), the sedge warbler ({Acrocephalus
      phragmitis}); -- called also {night singer}. [Prov. Eng.]
      

   {Night watch}.
      (a) A period in the night, as distinguished by the change
          of watch.
      (b) A watch, or guard, to aford protection in the night.
          

   {Night watcher}, one who watches in the night; especially,
      one who watches with evil designs.

   {Night witch}. Same as {Night hag}, above.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>night</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>night
     n 1: the time after sunset and before sunrise while it is dark
          outside [syn: {nighttime}, {dark}] [ant: {day}]
     2: the time between sunset and midnight; "he watched television
        every night"
     3: the period spent sleeping; "I had a restless night"
     4: the dark part of the diurnal cycle considered a time unit;
        "three nights later he collapsed"
     5: darkness; "it vanished into the night"
     6: a shortening of nightfall; "they worked from morning to
        night"
     7: a period of ignorance or backwardness or gloom
     8: Roman goddess of night; daughter of Erebus; counterpart of
        Greek Nyx [syn: {Nox}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
