<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>no</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>No
   or No-A'mon, the home of Amon, the name of Thebes, the ancient
   capital of what is called the Middle Empire, in Upper or
   Southern Egypt. "The multitude of No" (Jer. 46:25) is more
   correctly rendered, as in the Revised Version, "Amon of No",
   i.e., No, where Jupiter Amon had his temple. In Ezek. 30:14, 16
   it is simply called "No;" but in ver. 15 the name has the Hebrew
   Hamon prefixed to it, "Hamon No." This prefix is probably the
   name simply of the god usually styled Amon or Ammon. In Nah. 3:8
   the "populous No" of the Authorized Version is in the Revised
   Version correctly rendered "No-Amon."
   
     It was the Diospolis or Thebes of the Greeks, celebrated for
   its hundred gates and its vast population. It stood on both
   sides of the Nile, and is by some supposed to have included
   Karnak and Luxor. In grandeur and extent it can only be compared
   to Nineveh. It is mentioned only in the prophecies referred to,
   which point to its total destruction. It was first taken by the
   Assyrians in the time of Sargon (Isa. 20). It was afterwards
   "delivered into the hand" of Nebuchadnezzar and Assurbani-pal
   (Jer. 46:25, 26). Cambyses, king of the Persians (B.C. 525),
   further laid it waste by fire. Its ruin was completed (B.C. 81)
   by Ptolemy Lathyrus. The ruins of this city are still among the
   most notable in the valley of the Nile. They have formed a great
   storehouse of interesting historic remains for more than two
   thousand years. "As I wandered day after day with ever-growing
   amazement amongst these relics of ancient magnificence, I felt
   that if all the ruins in Europe, classical, Celtic, and
   medieval, were brought together into one centre, they would fall
   far short both in extent and grandeur of those of this single
   Egyptian city." Manning, The Land of the Pharaohs.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>no
     
        &lt;networking&gt; The {country code} for Norway.
     
        (1999-01-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nitric \Ni"tric\, a. [Cf. F. nitrique. See {Niter}.] (Chem.)
   Of, pertaining to, or containing, nitrogen; specifically,
   designating any one of those compounds in which, as
   contrasted with {nitrous} compounds, the element has a higher
   valence; as, nitric oxide; nitric acid.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Nitric acid}, a colorless or yellowish liquid obtained by
      distilling a nitrate with sulphuric acid. It is powerfully
      corrosive, being a strong acid, and in decomposition a
      strong oxidizer.

   {Nitric anhydride}, a white crystalline oxide of nitrogen
      ({N2O5}), called {nitric pentoxide}, and regarded as the
      anhydride of nitric acid.

   {Nitric oxide}, a colorless poisous gas ({NO}) obtained by
      treating nitric acid with copper. On contact with the air
      or with oxygen, it becomes reddish brown from the
      formation of nitrogen dioxide ({NO2}, also called nitric
      dioxide or nitric peroxide).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nitroso- \Ni*tro"so-\
   (? or ?). (Chem.) A prefix (also used adjectively)
   designating the group or radical {-NO}, called the nitroso
   group, or its compounds.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nitrosyl \Ni*tro"syl\, n. [Nitroso- + -yl.] (Chem.)
   The radical {-NO}, called also the {nitroso group}. The term
   is sometimes loosely used to designate certain nitro
   compounds; as, nitrosyl sulphuric acid. Used also
   adjectively.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>No \No\ (n[=o]), a. [OE. no, non, the same word as E. none; cf.
   E. a, an. See {None}.]
   Not any; not one; none; as, yes, we have no bananas; -- often
   used as a quantifier.
   [1913 Webster]

         Let there be no strife . . . between me and thee.
                                                  --Gen. xiii.
                                                  8.
   [1913 Webster]

         That goodness is no name, and happiness no dream.
                                                  --Byron.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: In Old England before a vowel the form non or noon was
         used. ``No man.'' ``Noon apothercary.'' --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>no \no.\ n.
   Number; -- the number designating place in an ordered
   sequence; as, no. 2. [abbrev.]
   [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>No \No\, adv. [OE. no, na, AS. n[=a]; ne not + [=a] ever. AS. ne
   is akin to OHG. ni, Goth. ni, Russ. ne, Ir., Gael. &amp; W. ni,
   L. ne, Gr. nh (in comp.), Skr. na, and also to E. prefix un-.
   [root] 193. See {Aye}, and cf. {Nay}, {Not}, {Nice},
   {Nefarious}.]
   Nay; not; not at all; not in any respect or degree; -- a word
   expressing negation, denial, or refusal. Before or after
   another negative, no is emphatic.
   [1913 Webster]

         We do no otherwise than we are willed.   --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         I am perplx'd and doubtful whether or no
         I dare accept this your congratulation.  --Coleridge.
   [1913 Webster]

         There is none righteous, no, not one.    --Rom. iii.
                                                  10.
   [1913 Webster]

         No! Nay, Heaven forbid.                  --Coleridge.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>No \No\ (n[=o]), n.; pl. {Noes} (n[=o]z).
   1. A refusal by use of the word no; a denial.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A negative vote; one who votes in the negative; as, to
      call for the ayes and noes; the noes have it.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nay \nay\ (n[=a]), adv. [Icel. nei; akin to E. no. See {No},
   adv.]
   1. No; -- a negative answer to a question asked, or a request
      made, now superseded by {no}. Opposed to {aye} or {yea}.
      See also {Yes}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            And eke when I say ``ye,'' ne say not ``nay.''
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I tell you nay; but except ye repent, ye shall all
            likewise perish.                      --Luke xiii.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

            And now do they thrust us out privily? nay, verily;
            but let them come themselves and fetch us out.
                                                  --Acts xvi.
                                                  37.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that will not when he may,
            When he would he shall have nay.      --Old Prov.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Before the time of Henry VIII. nay was used to answer
         simple questions, and no was used when the form of the
         question involved a negative expression; nay was the
         simple form, no the emphatic. --Skeat.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Not this merely, but also; not only so, but; -- used to
      mark the addition or substitution of a more explicit or
      more emphatic phrase.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Nay in this sense may be interchanged with yea. ``Were
         he my brother, nay, my kingdom's heir.'' --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>No, stirring up; forbidding

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>no
     adj : quantifier; used with either mass nouns or plural count
           nouns for indicating a complete or almost complete lack
           or zero quantity of; "we have no bananas"; "no eggs
           left and no money to buy any"; "have you no decency?";
           "did it with no help"; "I'll get you there in no time"
           [syn: {no(a)}] [ant: {all(a)}, {some(a)}]
     n 1: a negative; "his no was loud and clear" [ant: {yes}]
     2: a radioactive transuranic element synthesized by bombarding
        curium with carbon ions; 7 isotopes are known [syn: {nobelium},
         {atomic number 102}]
     adv 1: referring to the degree to which a certain quality is
            present; "he was no heavier than a child" [syn: {no
            more}]
     2: not in any degree or manner; not at all; "he is no better
        today"
     3: used to express refusal or denial or disagreement etc or
        especially to emphasize a negative statement; "no, you are
        wrong"
     [also: {noes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>no</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>no.
     n : the number designating place in an ordered sequence [syn: {ordinal
         number}, {ordinal}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
