<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>noah</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noah
   rest, (Heb. Noah) the grandson of Methuselah (Gen. 5:25-29), who
   was for two hundred and fifty years contemporary with Adam, and
   the son of Lamech, who was about fifty years old at the time of
   Adam's death. This patriarch is rightly regarded as the
   connecting link between the old and the new world. He is the
   second great progenitor of the human family.
   
     The words of his father Lamech at his birth (Gen. 5:29) have
   been regarded as in a sense prophetical, designating Noah as a
   type of Him who is the true "rest and comfort" of men under the
   burden of life (Matt.11:28).
   
     He lived five hundred years, and then there were born unto him
   three sons, Shem, Ham, and Japheth (Gen. 5:32). He was a "just
   man and perfect in his generation," and "walked with God" (comp.
   Ezek. 14:14,20). But now the descendants of Cain and of Seth
   began to intermarry, and then there sprang up a race
   distinguished for their ungodliness. Men became more and more
   corrupt, and God determined to sweep the earth of its wicked
   population (Gen. 6:7). But with Noah God entered into a
   covenant, with a promise of deliverance from the threatened
   deluge (18). He was accordingly commanded to build an ark
   (6:14-16) for the saving of himself and his house. An interval
   of one hundred and twenty years elapsed while the ark was being
   built (6:3), during which Noah bore constant testimony against
   the unbelief and wickedness of that generation (1 Pet. 3:18-20;
   2 Pet. 2:5).
   
     When the ark of "gopher-wood" (mentioned only here) was at
   length completed according to the command of the Lord, the
   living creatures that were to be preserved entered into it; and
   then Noah and his wife and sons and daughters-in-law entered it,
   and the "Lord shut him in" (Gen.7:16). The judgment-threatened
   now fell on the guilty world, "the world that then was, being
   overflowed with water, perished" (2 Pet. 3:6). The ark floated
   on the waters for one hundred and fifty days, and then rested on
   the mountains of Ararat (Gen. 8:3,4); but not for a considerable
   time after this was divine permission given him to leave the
   ark, so that he and his family were a whole year shut up within
   it (Gen. 6-14).
   
     On leaving the ark Noah's first act was to erect an altar, the
   first of which there is any mention, and offer the sacrifices of
   adoring thanks and praise to God, who entered into a covenant
   with him, the first covenant between God and man, granting him
   possession of the earth by a new and special charter, which
   remains in force to the present time (Gen. 8:21-9:17). As a sign
   and witness of this covenant, the rainbow was adopted and set
   apart by God, as a sure pledge that never again would the earth
   be destroyed by a flood.
   
     But, alas! Noah after this fell into grievous sin (Gen. 9:21);
   and the conduct of Ham on this sad occasion led to the memorable
   prediction regarding his three sons and their descendants. Noah
   "lived after the flood three hundred and fifty years, and he
   died" (28:29). (See {DELUGE}).
   
     Noah, motion, (Heb. No'ah) one of the five daughters of
   Zelophehad (Num.26:33; 27:1; 36:11; Josh. 17:3).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noah \No"ah\, prop. n. [Heb. N[=o]akh rest.]
   A patriarch of Biblical history, in the time of the Deluge.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noah, repose; consolation

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noah, that quavers or totters (Zelophehad's daughter)

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noah
     n : the Hebrew patriarch who saved himself and his family and
         the animals by building an ark in which they survived 40
         days and 40 nights of rain; the story of Noah and the
         flood is told in the Book of Genesis
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
