<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>noise</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>NOISE, n.  A stench in the ear.  Undomesticated music.  The chief
product and authenticating sign of civilization.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>noise
     
        &lt;communications&gt; Any part of a signal that is not the true or
        original signal but is introduced by the communication
        mechanism.
     
        A common example would be an electrical signal travelling down
        a wire to which noise is added by inductive and capacitive
        coupling with other nearby signals (this kind of noise is
        known as "{crosstalk}").
     
        A less obvious form of noise is {quantisation} noise, such as
        the error between the true colour of a point in a scene in the
        real world and its representation as a {pixel} in a digital
        image.
     
        (2003-07-05)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noise \Noise\, v. i.
   To sound; to make a noise. --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noise \Noise\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Noised}; p pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Noising}.]
   1. To spread by rumor or report.
      [1913 Webster]

            All these sayings were noised abroad. --Luke i. 65.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To disturb with noise. [Obs.] --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Noise \Noise\, n. [F. noise noisy strife, quarrel, brawl, fr. L.
   nausea seasickness, sickness, disgust. See {Nausea}.]
   1. Sound of any kind.
      [1913 Webster]

            The heavens turn about in a most rapid motion
            without noise
            to us perceived.                      --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Noise is either a sound of too short a duration to be
         determined, like the report of a cannon; or else it is
         a confused mixture of many discordant sounds, like the
         rolling of thunder or the noise of the waves.
         Nevertheless, the difference between sound and noise is
         by no means precise. --Ganot.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, loud, confused, or senseless sound; clamor;
      din.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Loud or continuous talk; general talk or discussion;
      rumor; report. ``The noise goes.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            What noise have we had about transplantation of
            diseases and transfusion of blood!    --T. Baker.
      [1913 Webster]

            Socrates lived in Athens during the great plague
            which has made so much noise in all ages.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Music, in general; a concert; also, a company of
      musicians; a band. [Obs.] --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king has his noise of gypsies.    --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Cry; outcry; clamor; din; clatter; uproar.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>background \back"ground`\, n. [Back, a. + ground.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Ground in the rear or behind, or in the distance, as
      opposed to the {foreground}, or the ground in front.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Paint.) The space which is behind and subordinate to a
      portrait or group of figures.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The distance in a picture is usually divided into
         foreground, middle distance, and background.
         --Fairholt.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything behind, serving as a foil; as, the statue had a
      background of red hangings.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A place in obscurity or retirement, or out of sight.
      [1913 Webster]

            I fancy there was a background of grinding and
            waiting before Miss Torry could produce this highly
            finished . . . performance.           --Mrs.
                                                  Alexander.
      [1913 Webster]

            A husband somewhere in the background. --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The set of conditions within which an action takes place,
      including the social and physical conditions as well as
      the psychological states of the participants; as, within
      the background of the massive budget deficits of the
      1980's, new spending programs had little chance of passage
      by the congress.
      [PJC]

   6. The set of conditions that precede and affect an action,
      such as the social and historical precedents for the
      event, as well as the general background[5]; as, against
      the background of their expulsion by the Serbs, the desire
      of Kosovars for vengeance is understandable though
      regrettable.
      [PJC]

   7. (Science) The signals that may be detected by a
      measurement which are not due to the phenomenon being
      studied, and tend to make the measurement uncertain to a
      greater or lesser degree. Specifically: (Physics)
      Electronic noise present in a system using electronic
      measuring instrument or in a telecommunications system,
      which may hide and which must be differentiated from the
      desired signal; also called background noise or {noise}.
      [PJC]

   8. (Journalism) An agreement between a journalist and an
      interviewee that the name of the interviewee will not be
      quoted in any publication, although the substance of the
      remarks may be reported; -- often used in the phrase ``on
      background''. Compare {deep background}.
      [PJC]

   {To place in the background}, to make of little consequence.

   {To keep in the background}, to remain unobtrusive,
      inconspicuous or out of sight; -- of people.

   {deep background}, (Journalism) the status of an interview
      which must not be quoted in a publication, even without
      attribution. Compare {background}[8].
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>noise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>noise
     n 1: sound of any kind (especially unintelligible or dissonant
          sound); "he enjoyed the street noises"; "they heard
          indistinct noises of people talking"; "during the
          firework display that ended the gala the noise reached
          98 decibels"
     2: the auditory experience of sound that lacks musical quality;
        sound that is a disagreeable auditory experience; "modern
        music is just noise to me" [syn: {dissonance}, {racket}]
     3: electrical or acoustic activity that can disturb
        communication [syn: {interference}, {disturbance}]
     4: a loud outcry of protest or complaint; "the announcement of
        the election recount caused a lot of noise"; "whatever it
        was he didn't like it and he was going to let them know by
        making as loud a noise as he could"
     5: incomprehensibility resulting from irrelevant information or
        meaningless facts or remarks; "all the noise in his speech
        concealed the fact that he didn't have anything to say"
     6: the quality of lacking any predictable order or plan [syn: {randomness},
         {haphazardness}, {stochasticity}]
     v : emit a noise [syn: {make noise}, {resound}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
