<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>nonlinear</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nonlinear</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nonlinear
     
        (Scientific computation) A property of a system whose output
        is not proportional to its input.  For example, a {transistor}
        has a region of input voltages for which its output voltage is
        found by multiplying the input voltage by the gain of the
        transistor.  Outside this region though, the transistor
        behaves non-linearly, meaning that it does not obey this
        simple equation.  The behaviour of a system containing
        non-linear components is thus harder to model and to predict.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nonlinear</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nonlinear \nonlinear\ adj.
   1. (Math.) Not depictable graphically as a straight line; not
      changing by a constant amount for each unit of time,
      distance, or other independent variable. Opposite of
      {linear}.
      [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]

   2. (Math.) Containing variables of greater than the first
      degree; -- of an equation. Opposite of {linear}.
      [PJC]

   3. (Physics) Represented by equations containing variables of
      greater than the first degree; -- of physical processes or
      relationships. Opposite of {linear}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nonlinear</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nonlinear adj. [scientific computation] 1. Behaving in an erratic and
   unpredictable fashion; unstable. When used to describe the behavior of a
   machine or program, it suggests that said machine or program is being
   forced to run far outside of design specifications. This behavior may be
   induced by unreasonable inputs, or may be triggered when a more mundane
   bug sends the computation far off from its expected course. 2. When
   describing the behavior of a person, suggests a tantrum or a {flame}.
   "When you talk to Bob, don't mention the drug problem or he'll go
   nonlinear for hours." In this context, `go nonlinear' connotes `blow up
   out of proportion' (proportion connotes linearity).


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nonlinear</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nonlinear
     adj : designating or involving an equation whose terms are not of
           the first degree [ant: {linear}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
