<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>nose</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>NOSE, n.  The extreme outpost of the face.  From the circumstance that
great conquerors have great noses, Getius, whose writings antedate the
age of humor, calls the nose the organ of quell.  It has been observed
that one's nose is never so happy as when thrust into the affairs of
others, from which some physiologists have drawn the inference that
the nose is devoid of the sense of smell.

        There's a man with a Nose,
        And wherever he goes
    The people run from him and shout:
        "No cotton have we
        For our ears if so be
    He blow that interminous snout!"

        So the lawyers applied
        For injunction.  "Denied,"
    Said the Judge:  "the defendant prefixion,
        Whate'er it portend,
        Appears to transcend
    The bounds of this court's jurisdiction."
                                                         Arpad Singiny


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nose \Nose\ (n[=o]z), n. [AS. nosu; akin to D. neus, G. nase,
   OHG. nasa, Icel. n["o]s, Sw. n["a]sa, Dan. n["a]se, Lith.
   nosis, Russ. nos', L. nasus, nares, Skr. n[=a]s[=a], n[=a]s.
   [root]261. Cf. {Nasal}, {Nasturtium}, {Naze}, {Nostril},
   {Nozzle}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Anat.) The prominent part of the face or anterior
      extremity of the head containing the nostrils and
      olfactory cavities; the olfactory organ. See {Nostril},
      and {Olfactory organ} under {Olfactory}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The power of smelling; hence, scent.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are not offended with a dog for a better nose
            than his master.                      --Collier.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A projecting end or beak at the front of an object; a
      snout; a nozzle; a spout; as, the nose of a bellows; the
      nose of a teakettle.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Nose bit} (Carp.), a bit similar to a gouge bit, but having
      a cutting edge on one side of its boring end.

   {Nose hammer} (Mach.), a frontal hammer.

   {Nose hole} (Glass Making), a small opening in a furnace,
      before which a globe of crown glass is held and kept soft
      at the beginning of the flattening process.

   {Nose key} (Carp.), a fox wedge.

   {Nose leaf} (Zo["o]l.), a thin, broad, membranous fold of
      skin on the nose of many species of bats. It varies
      greatly in size and form.

   {Nose of wax}, (fig.), a person who is pliant and easily
      influenced. ``A nose of wax to be turned every way.''
      --Massinger

   {Nose piece}, the nozzle of a pipe, hose, bellows, etc.; the
      end piece of a microscope body, to which an objective is
      attached.

   {To hold one's nose to the grindstone}, {To put one's nose to
   the grindstone}, or {To bring one's nose to the grindstone}.
      See under {Grindstone}.

   {To lead by the nose}, to lead at pleasure, or to cause to
      follow submissively; to lead blindly, as a person leads a
      beast. --Shak.

   {To put one's nose out of joint}, to humiliate one's pride,
      esp. by supplanting one in the affections of another.
      [Slang]

   {To thrust one's nose into}, to meddle officiously in.

   {To wipe one's nose of}, to deprive of; to rob. [Slang]

   {on the nose},
      (a) exactly, accurately.
      (b) (racing) to win, as opposed to {to place} or {to
          show}.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nose \Nose\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Nosed} (n[=o]zd); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Nosing}.]
   1. To smell; to scent; hence, to track, or trace out.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To touch with the nose; to push the nose into or against;
      hence, to interfere with; to treat insolently.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lambs . . . nosing the mother's udder. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            A sort of national convention, dubious in its nature
            . . . nosed Parliament in the very seat of its
            authority.                            --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To utter in a nasal manner; to pronounce with a nasal
      twang; as, to nose a prayer. [R.] --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To confront; be closely face to face or opposite to; meet.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   5. To furnish with a nose; as, to nose a stair tread.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. To examine with the nose or sense of smell.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. To make by advancing the nose or front end; as, the train
      nosed its way into the station;
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. (Racing Slang) to beat by (the length of) a nose. Hence,
      to defeat in a contest by a small margin; also used in the
      form {nose out}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nose \Nose\, v. i.
   To push or move with the nose or front forward.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

         A train of cable cars came nosing along. --Hamlin
                                                  Garland.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nose \Nose\ (n[=o]z), v. i.
   1. To smell; to sniff; to scent. --Audubon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pry officiously into what does not concern one; to
      {nose around}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nose
     n 1: the organ of smell and entrance to the respiratory tract;
          the prominent part of the face of man or other mammals;
          "he has a cold in the nose" [syn: {olfactory organ}]
     2: a front that resembles a human nose (especially the front of
        an aircraft); "the nose of the rocket heated up on
        reentry"
     3: the front or forward projection of a tool or weapon; "he
        ducked under the nose of the gun"
     4: a small distance; "my horse lost the race by a nose"
     5: the sense of smell (especially in animals); "the hound has a
        good nose"
     6: a natural skill; "he has a nose for good deals"
     7: a projecting spout from which a fluid is discharged [syn: {nozzle}]
     v 1: search or inquire in a meddlesome way; "This guy is always
          nosing around the office" [syn: {pry}, {poke}]
     2: advance the forward part of with caution; "She nosed the car
        into the left lane"
     3: catch the scent of; get wind of; "The dog nosed out the
        drugs" [syn: {scent}, {wind}]
     4: push or move with the nose
     5: rub noses [syn: {nuzzle}]
     6: defeat by a narrow margin
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
