<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>note</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Note \Note\ (n[=o]t), v. t. [AS. hn[=i]tan to strike against,
   imp. hn[=a]t.]
   To butt; to push with the horns. [Prov. Eng.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Note \Note\ (n[=o]t). [AS. n[=a]t; ne not + w[=a]t wot. See
   {Not}, and {Wot}.]
   Know not; knows not. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Note \Note\, n.
   Nut. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Note \Note\, n. [AS. notu use, profit.]
   Need; needful business. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Note \Note\, n. [F. note, L. nota; akin to noscere, notum, to
   know. See {Know}.]
   1. A mark or token by which a thing may be known; a visible
      sign; a character; a distinctive mark or feature; a
      characteristic quality.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whosoever appertain to the visible body of the
            church, they have also the notes of external
            profession.                           --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            She [the Anglican church] has the note of
            possession, the note of freedom from party
            titles,the note of life -- a tough life and a
            vigorous.                             --J. H.
                                                  Newman.
      [1913 Webster]

            What a note of youth, of imagination, of impulsive
            eagerness, there was through it all ! --Mrs. Humphry
                                                  Ward.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A mark, or sign, made to call attention, to point out
      something to notice, or the like; a sign, or token,
      proving or giving evidence.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A brief remark; a marginal comment or explanation; hence,
      an annotation on a text or author; a comment; a critical,
      explanatory, or illustrative observation.
      [1913 Webster]

            The best writers have been perplexed with notes, and
            obscured with illustrations.          --Felton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A brief writing intended to assist the memory; a
      memorandum; a minute.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. Hence, a writing intended to be used in speaking;
      memoranda to assist a speaker, being either a synopsis, or
      the full text of what is to be said; as, to preach from
      notes; also, a reporter's memoranda; the original report
      of a speech or of proceedings.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A short informal letter; a billet.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A diplomatic missive or written communication.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A written or printed paper acknowledging a debt, and
      promising payment; as, a promissory note; a note of hand;
      a negotiable note.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A list of items or of charges; an account. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Here is now the smith's note for shoeing. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mus.)
       (a) A character, variously formed, to indicate the length
           of a tone, and variously placed upon the staff to
           indicate its pitch. Hence:
       (b) A musical sound; a tone; an utterance; a tune.
       (c) A key of the piano or organ.
           [1913 Webster]

                 The wakeful bird . . . tunes her nocturnal
                 note.                            --Milton.
           [1913 Webster]

                 That note of revolt against the eighteenth
                 century, which we detect in Goethe, was struck
                 by Winckelmann.                  --W. Pater.
           [1913 Webster]

   11. Observation; notice; heed.
       [1913 Webster]

             Give orders to my servants that they take
             No note at all of our being absent hence. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Notification; information; intelligence. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

             The king . . . shall have note of this. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. State of being under observation. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

             Small matters . . . continually in use and in note.
                                                  --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Reputation; distinction; as, a poet of note.
       [1913 Webster]

             There was scarce a family of note which had not
             poured out its blood on the field or the scaffold.
                                                  --Prescott.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. Stigma; brand; reproach. [Obs.] --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Note of hand}, a promissory note.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Note \Note\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Noted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Noting}.] [F. noter, L. notare, fr. nota. See {Note}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To notice with care; to observe; to remark; to heed; to
      attend to. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            No more of that; I have noted it well. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The world will little note, nor long remember, what
            we say here, but it can never forget what they did
            here.                                 --Abraham
                                                  Lincoln
                                                  (Gettysburg
                                                  Address,
                                                  1863).
      [PJC]

   2. To record in writing; to make a memorandum of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every unguarded word . . . was noted down.
                                                  --Maccaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To charge, as with crime (with of or for before the thing
      charged); to brand. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They were both noted of incontinency. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To denote; to designate. --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To annotate. [R.] --W. H. Dixon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To set down in musical characters.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To note a bill} or {To note a draft}, to record on the back
      of it a refusal of acceptance, as the ground of a protest,
      which is done officially by a notary.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Accommodation \Ac*com`mo*da"tion\, n. [L. accommodatio, fr.
   accommodare: cf. F. accommodation.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of fitting or adapting, or the state of being
      fitted or adapted; adaptation; adjustment; -- followed by
      to. ``The organization of the body with accommodation to
      its functions.'' --Sir M. Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Willingness to accommodate; obligingness.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Whatever supplies a want or affords ease, refreshment, or
      convenience; anything furnished which is desired or
      needful; -- often in the plural; as, the accommodations --
      that is, lodgings and food -- at an inn.    --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An adjustment of differences; state of agreement;
      reconciliation; settlement. ``To come to terms of
      accommodation.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The application of a writer's language, on the ground of
      analogy, to something not originally referred to or
      intended.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many of those quotations from the Old Testament were
            probably intended as nothing more than
            accommodations.                       --Paley.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Com.)
      (a) A loan of money.
      (b) An accommodation bill or note.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Accommodation bill}, or {note} (Com.), a bill of exchange
      which a person accepts, or a note which a person makes and
      delivers to another, not upon a consideration received,
      but for the purpose of raising money on credit.

   {Accommodation coach}, or {train}, one running at moderate
      speed and stopping at all or nearly all stations.

   {Accommodation ladder} (Naut.), a light ladder hung over the
      side of a ship at the gangway, useful in ascending from,
      or descending to, small boats.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Raise \Raise\ (r[=a]z), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Raised} (r[=a]zd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Raising}.] [OE. reisen, Icel. reisa,
   causative of r[=i]sa to rise. See {Rise}, and cf. {Rear} to
   raise.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To cause to rise; to bring from a lower to a higher place;
      to lift upward; to elevate; to heave; as, to raise a stone
      or weight. Hence, figuratively: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To bring to a higher condition or situation; to
          elevate in rank, dignity, and the like; to increase
          the value or estimation of; to promote; to exalt; to
          advance; to enhance; as, to raise from a low estate;
          to raise to office; to raise the price, and the like.
          [1913 Webster]

                This gentleman came to be raised to great
                titles.                           --Clarendon.
          [1913 Webster]

                The plate pieces of eight were raised three
                pence in the piece.               --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To increase the strength, vigor, or vehemence of; to
          excite; to intensify; to invigorate; to heighten; as,
          to raise the pulse; to raise the voice; to raise the
          spirits or the courage; to raise the heat of a
          furnace.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To elevate in degree according to some scale; as, to
          raise the pitch of the voice; to raise the temperature
          of a room.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to rise up, or assume an erect position or
      posture; to set up; to make upright; as, to raise a mast
      or flagstaff. Hence: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To cause to spring up from a recumbent position, from
          a state of quiet, or the like; to awaken; to arouse.
          [1913 Webster]

                They shall not awake, nor be raised out of their
                sleep.                            --Job xiv. 12.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To rouse to action; to stir up; to incite to tumult,
          struggle, or war; to excite.
          [1913 Webster]

                He commandeth, and raiseth the stormy wind.
                                                  --Ps. cvii.
                                                  25.
          [1913 Webster]

                [AE]neas . . . employs his pains,
                In parts remote, to raise the Tuscan swains.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To bring up from the lower world; to call up, as a
          spirit from the world of spirits; to recall from
          death; to give life to.
          [1913 Webster]

                Why should it be thought a thing incredible with
                you, that God should raise the dead ? --Acts
                                                  xxvi. 8.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to arise, grow up, or come into being or to
      appear; to give rise to; to originate, produce, cause,
      effect, or the like. Hence, specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To form by the accumulation of materials or
          constituent parts; to build up; to erect; as, to raise
          a lofty structure, a wall, a heap of stones.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will raise forts against thee.  --Isa. xxix.
                                                  3.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To bring together; to collect; to levy; to get
          together or obtain for use or service; as, to raise
          money, troops, and the like. ``To raise up a rent.''
          --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To cause to grow; to procure to be produced, bred, or
          propagated; to grow; as, to raise corn, barley, hops,
          etc.; toraise cattle. ``He raised sheep.'' ``He raised
          wheat where none grew before.'' --Johnson's Dict.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: In some parts of the United States, notably in the
         Southern States, raise is also commonly applied to the
         rearing or bringing up of children.
         [1913 Webster]

               I was raised, as they say in Virginia, among the
               mountains of the North.            --Paulding.
         [1913 Webster]
      (d) To bring into being; to produce; to cause to arise,
          come forth, or appear; -- often with up.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will raise them up a prophet from among their
                brethren, like unto thee.         --Deut. xviii.
                                                  18.
          [1913 Webster]

                God vouchsafes to raise another world
                From him [Noah], and all his anger to forget.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To give rise to; to set agoing; to occasion; to start;
          to originate; as, to raise a smile or a blush.
          [1913 Webster]

                Thou shalt not raise a false report. --Ex.
                                                  xxiii. 1.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) To give vent or utterance to; to utter; to strike up.
          [1913 Webster]

                Soon as the prince appears, they raise a cry.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) To bring to notice; to submit for consideration; as,
          to raise a point of order; to raise an objection.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. To cause to rise, as by the effect of leaven; to make
      light and spongy, as bread.
      [1913 Webster]

            Miss Liddy can dance a jig, and raise paste.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.)
      (a) To cause (the land or any other object) to seem higher
          by drawing nearer to it; as, to raise Sandy Hook
          light.
      (b) To let go; as in the command, Raise tacks and sheets,
          i. e., Let go tacks and sheets.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law) To create or constitute; as, to raise a use, that
      is, to create it. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To raise a blockade} (Mil.), to remove or break up a
      blockade, either by withdrawing the ships or forces
      employed in enforcing it, or by driving them away or
      dispersing them.

   {To raise a check}, {note}, {bill of exchange}, etc., to
      increase fraudulently its nominal value by changing the
      writing, figures, or printing in which the sum payable is
      specified.

   {To raise a siege}, to relinquish an attempt to take a place
      by besieging it, or to cause the attempt to be
      relinquished.

   {To raise steam}, to produce steam of a required pressure.

   {To raise the wind}, to procure ready money by some temporary
      expedient. [Colloq.]

   {To raise Cain}, or {To raise the devil}, to cause a great
      disturbance; to make great trouble. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To lift; exalt; elevate; erect; originate; cause;
        produce; grow; heighten; aggravate; excite.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>note</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>note
     n 1: a short personal letter; "drop me a line when you get there"
          [syn: {short letter}, {line}, {billet}]
     2: a brief written record; "he made a note of the appointment"
     3: a characteristic emotional quality; "it ended on a sour
        note"; "there was a note of gaiety in her manner"; "he
        detected a note of sarcasm"
     4: a piece of paper money (especially one issued by a central
        bank); "he peeled off five one-thousand-zloty notes" [syn:
         {bill}, {government note}, {bank bill}, {banker's bill},
        {bank note}, {banknote}, {Federal Reserve note}, {greenback}]
     5: a notation representing the pitch and duration of a musical
        sound; "the singer held the note too long" [syn: {musical
        note}, {tone}]
     6: a comment or instruction (usually added); "his notes were
        appended at the end of the article"; "he added a short
        notation to the address on the envelope" [syn: {annotation},
         {notation}]
     7: high status importance owing to marked superiority; "a
        scholar of great eminence" [syn: {eminence}, {distinction},
         {preeminence}]
     8: a tone of voice that shows what the speaker is feeling;
        "there was a note of uncertainty in his voice"
     9: a promise to pay a specified amount on demand or at a
        certain time; "I had to co-sign his note at the bank"
        [syn: {promissory note}, {note of hand}]
     v 1: make mention of; "She observed that his presentation took up
          too much time"; "They noted that it was a fine day to go
          sailing" [syn: {observe}, {mention}, {remark}]
     2: notice or perceive; "She noted that someone was following
        her"; "mark my words" [syn: {notice}, {mark}] [ant: {ignore}]
     3: observe with care or pay close attention to; "Take note of
        this chemical reaction" [syn: {take note}, {observe}]
     4: make a written note of; "she noted everything the teacher
        said that morning" [syn: {take down}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
