<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>notion</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>notion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Notion \No"tion\, [L. notio, fr. noscere to know: cf. F. notion.
   See {Know}.]
   1. Mental apprehension of whatever may be known or imagined;
      an idea; a conception; more properly, a general or
      universal conception, as distinguishable or definable by
      marks or not[ae].
      [1913 Webster]

            What hath been generally agreed on, I content myself
            to assume under the notion of principles. --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Few agree in their notions about these words.
                                                  --Cheyne.
      [1913 Webster]

            That notion of hunger, cold, sound, color, thought,
            wish, or fear which is in the mind, is called the
            ``idea'' of hunger, cold, etc.        --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

            Notion, again, signifies either the act of
            apprehending, signalizing, that is, the remarking or
            taking note of, the various notes, marks, or
            characters of an object which its qualities afford,
            or the result of that act.            --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A sentiment; an opinion.
      [1913 Webster]

            The extravagant notion they entertain of themselves.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            A perverse will easily collects together a system of
            notions to justify itself in its obliquity. --J. H.
                                                  Newman.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Sense; mind. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An invention; an ingenious device; a knickknack; as,
      Yankee notions. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Inclination; intention; disposition; as, I have a notion
      to do it. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Miscellaneous small objects; sundries; -- usually
      referring to articles displayed together for sale.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>notion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>notion
     n 1: a vague idea in which some confidence is placed; "his
          impression of her was favorable"; "what are your
          feelings about the crisis?"; "it strengthened my belief
          in his sincerity"; "I had a feeling that she was lying"
          [syn: {impression}, {feeling}, {belief}, {opinion}]
     2: a general inclusive concept
     3: an odd or fanciful or capricious idea; "the theatrical
        notion of disguise is associated with disaster in his
        stories"; "he had a whimsy about flying to the moon";
        "whimsy can be humorous to someone with time to enjoy it"
        [syn: {whim}, {whimsy}, {whimsey}]
     4: (usually plural) small personal articles or clothing or
        sewing items; "buttons and needles are notions"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
