<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>nucleus</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nucleus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nucleus \Nu"cle*us\, n.; pl. E. {Nucleuses}, L. {Nuclei}. [L., a
   kernel, dim. fr. nux, nucis, nut. Cf. {Newel} post.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A kernel; hence, a central mass or point about which
      matter is gathered, or to which accretion is made; the
      central or material portion; -- used both literally and
      figuratively.
      [1913 Webster]

            It must contain within itself a nucleus of truth.
                                                  --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Astron.) The body or the head of a comet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.)
      (a) An incipient ovule of soft cellular tissue.
      (b) A whole seed, as contained within the seed coats.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Biol.) A body, usually spheroidal, in a eukaryotic cell,
      distinguished from the surrounding protoplasm by a
      difference in refrangibility and in behavior towards
      chemical reagents, which contains the chromosomal genetic
      material, including the chromosomal DNA. It is more or
      less protoplasmic, and consists of a clear fluid
      (achromatin) through which extends a network of fibers
      (chromatin) in which may be suspended a second rounded
      body, the nucleolus (see {Nucleoplasm}). See {Cell
      division}, under {Division}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: The nucleus is sometimes termed the endoplast or
         endoblast, and in the protozoa is supposed to be
         concerned in the female part of the reproductive
         process. See {Karyokinesis}.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The tip, or earliest part, of a univalve or bivalve
          shell.
      (b) The central part around which additional growths are
          added, as of an operculum.
      (c) A visceral mass, containing the stomach and other
          organs, in Tunicata and some mollusks.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nucleus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nucleus
     n 1: a part of the cell containing DNA and RNA and responsible
          for growth and reproduction [syn: {cell nucleus}, {karyon}]
     2: the positively charged dense center of an atom
     3: a small group of indispensable persons or things; "five
        periodicals make up the core of their publishing program"
        [syn: {core}, {core group}]
     4: (astronomy) the center of the head of a comet; consists of
        small solid particles of ice and frozen gas that vaporizes
        on approaching the sun to form the coma and tail
     5: any histologically identifiable mass of neural cell bodies
        in the brain or spinal cord
     [also: {nuclei} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
