<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>number</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>number</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Number \Num"ber\ (n[u^]m"b[~e]r), n. [OE. nombre, F. nombre, L.
   numerus; akin to Gr. no`mos that which is dealt out, fr.
   ne`mein to deal out, distribute. See {Numb}, {Nomad}, and cf.
   {Numerate}, {Numero}, {Numerous}.]
   1. That which admits of being counted or reckoned; a unit, or
      an aggregate of units; a numerable aggregate or collection
      of individuals; an assemblage made up of distinct things
      expressible by figures.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A collection of many individuals; a numerous assemblage; a
      multitude; many.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ladies are always of great use to the party they
            espouse, and never fail to win over numbers.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A numeral; a word or character denoting a number; as, to
      put a number on a door.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Numerousness; multitude.
      [1913 Webster]

            Number itself importeth not much in armies where the
            people are of weak courage.           --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The state or quality of being numerable or countable.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of whom came nations, tribes, people, and kindreds
            out of number.                        --2 Esdras
                                                  iii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Quantity, regarded as made up of an aggregate of separate
      things.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. That which is regulated by count; poetic measure, as
      divisions of time or number of syllables; hence, poetry,
      verse; -- chiefly used in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            I lisped in numbers, for the numbers came. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Gram.) The distinction of objects, as one, or more than
      one (in some languages, as one, or two, or more than two),
      expressed (usually) by a difference in the form of a word;
      thus, the singular number and the plural number are the
      names of the forms of a word indicating the objects
      denoted or referred to by the word as one, or as more than
      one.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Math.) The measure of the relation between quantities or
      things of the same kind; that abstract species of quantity
      which is capable of being expressed by figures; numerical
      value.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Abstract number}, {Abundant number}, {Cardinal number}, etc.
      See under {Abstract}, {Abundant}, etc.

   {In numbers}, in numbered parts; as, a book published in
      numbers.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>number</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Number \Num"ber\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Numbered}
   (n[u^]m"b[~e]rd); p. pr &amp; vb. n. {Numbering}.] [OE. nombren,
   noumbren, F. nombrer, fr. L. numerare, numeratum. See
   {Number}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To count; to reckon; to ascertain the units of; to
      enumerate.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a man can number the dust of the earth, then
            shall thy seed also be numbered.      --Gen. xiii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To reckon as one of a collection or multitude.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was numbered with the transgressors. --Is. liii.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give or apply a number or numbers to; to assign the
      place of in a series by order of number; to designate the
      place of by a number or numeral; as, to number the houses
      in a street, or the apartments in a building.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To amount; to equal in number; to contain; to consist of;
      as, the army numbers fifty thousand.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy tears can not number the dead.    --Campbell.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Numbering machine}, a machine for printing consecutive
      numbers, as on railway tickets, bank bills, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To count; enumerate; calculate; tell.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>number</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>number
     n 1: the property possessed by a sum or total or indefinite
          quantity of units or individuals; "he had a number of
          chores to do"; "the number of parameters is small"; "the
          figure was about a thousand" [syn: {figure}]
     2: a concept of quantity derived from zero and units; "every
        number has a unique position in the sequence"
     3: a short theatrical performance that is part of a longer
        program; "he did his act three times every evening"; "she
        had a catchy little routine"; "it was one of the best
        numbers he ever did" [syn: {act}, {routine}, {turn}, {bit}]
     4: a numeral or string of numerals that is used for
        identification; "she refused to give them her Social
        Security number" [syn: {identification number}]
     5: the number is used in calling a particular telephone; "he
        has an unlisted number" [syn: {phone number}, {telephone
        number}]
     6: a symbol used to represent a number; "he learned to write
        the numerals before he went to school" [syn: {numeral}]
     7: one of a series published periodically; "she found an old
        issue of the magazine in her dentist's waitingroom" [syn:
        {issue}]
     8: a select company of people; "I hope to become one of their
        number before I die"
     9: the grammatical category for the forms of nouns and pronouns
        and verbs that are used depending on the number of
        entities involved (singular or dual or plural); "in
        English the subject and the verb must agree in number"
     10: an item of merchandise offered for sale; "she preferred the
         black nylon number"; "this sweater is an all-wool number"
     11: a clothing measurement; "a number 13 shoe"
     v 1: add up in number or quantity; "The bills amounted to
          $2,000"; "The bill came to $2,000" [syn: {total}, {add
          up}, {come}, {amount}]
     2: give numbers to; "You should number the pages of the thesis"
     3: enumerate; "We must number the names of the great
        mathematicians" [syn: {list}]
     4: put into a group; "The academy counts several Nobel Prize
        winners among its members" [syn: {count}]
     5: determine the number or amount of; "Can you count the books
        on your shelf?"; "Count your change" [syn: {count}, {enumerate},
         {numerate}]
     6: place a limit on the number of [syn: {keep down}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
