<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>nuts</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nuts</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Nuts
   were among the presents Jacob sent into Egypt for the purpose of
   conciliating Joseph (Gen. 43:11). This was the fruit of the
   pistachio tree, which resembles the sumac. It is of the size of
   an olive. In Cant. 6:11 a different Hebrew word ('egoz), which
   means "walnuts," is used.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nuts</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fruit \Fruit\, n. [OE. fruit, frut, F. fruit, from L. fructus
   enjoyment, product, fruit, from frui, p. p. fructus, to
   enjoy; akin to E. brook, v. t. See {Brook}, v. t., and cf.
   {Fructify}, {Frugal}.]
   1. Whatever is produced for the nourishment or enjoyment of
      man or animals by the processes of vegetable growth, as
      corn, grass, cotton, flax, etc.; -- commonly used in the
      plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            Six years thou shalt sow thy land, and shalt gather
            in the
            fruits thereof.                       --Ex. xxiii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Hort.) The pulpy, edible seed vessels of certain plants,
      especially those grown on branches above ground, as
      apples, oranges, grapes, melons, berries, etc. See 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) The ripened ovary of a flowering plant, with its
      contents and whatever parts are consolidated with it.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Fruits are classified as fleshy, drupaceous, and dry.
         {Fleshy fruits} include berries, gourds, and melons,
         orangelike fruits and pomes; {drupaceous fruits} are
         stony within and fleshy without, as peaches, plums, and
         cherries; and {dry fruits} are further divided into
         {achenes}, {follicles}, {legumes}, {capsules}, {nuts},
         and several other kinds.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bot.) The spore cases or conceptacles of flowerless
      plants, as of ferns, mosses, algae, etc., with the spores
      contained in them.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The produce of animals; offspring; young; as, the fruit of
      the womb, of the loins, of the body.
      [1913 Webster]

            King Edward's fruit, true heir to the English crown.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That which is produced; the effect or consequence of any
      action; advantageous or desirable product or result;
      disadvantageous or evil consequence or effect; as, the
      fruits of labor, of self-denial, of intemperance.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fruit of rashness.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            What I obtained was the fruit of no bargain.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shall eat the fruit of their doings. --Is. iii
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fruits of this education became visible.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Fruit is frequently used adjectively, signifying of,
         for, or pertaining to a fruit or fruits; as, fruit bud;
         fruit frame; fruit jar; fruit knife; fruit loft; fruit
         show; fruit stall; fruit tree; etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Fruit bat} (Zo["o]l.), one of the Frugivora; -- called also
      {fruit-eating bat}.

   {Fruit bud} (Bot.), a bud that produces fruit; -- in most
      oplants the same as the power bud.

   {Fruit dot} (Bot.), a collection of fruit cases, as in ferns.
      See {Sorus}.

   {Fruit fly} (Zo["o]l.), a small dipterous insect of the genus
      {Drosophila}, which lives in fruit, in the larval state.
      There are seveal species, some of which are very damaging
      to fruit crops. One species, {Drosophila melanogaster},
      has been intensively studied as a model species for
      genetic reserach.

   {Fruit jar}, a jar for holding preserved fruit, usually made
      of glass or earthenware.

   {Fruit pigeon} (Zo["o]l.), one of numerous species of pigeons
      of the family {Carpophagid[ae]}, inhabiting India,
      Australia, and the Pacific Islands. They feed largely upon
      fruit. and are noted for their beautiful colors.

   {Fruit sugar} (Chem.), a kind of sugar occurring, naturally
      formed, in many ripe fruits, and in honey; levulose. The
      name is also, though rarely, applied to {invert sugar}, or
      to the natural mixture or dextrose and levulose resembling
      it, and found in fruits and honey.

   {Fruit tree} (Hort.), a tree cultivated for its edible fruit.
      

   {Fruit worm} (Zo["o]l.), one of numerous species of insect
      larv[ae]: which live in the interior of fruit. They are
      mostly small species of Lepidoptera and Diptera.

   {Small fruits} (Hort.), currants, raspberries, strawberries,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nuts</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nuts \nuts\ (n[u^]ts), pred. a.
   Crazy; loony; insane; batty; -- used in a predicate position,
   ususually in phrases such as to go nuts, went nuts, are you
   nuts? [slang]
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nuts</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nuts \nuts\ (n[u^]ts), interj.
   An expression of disapproval, defiance, or displeasure, as
   in: ``Ah, nuts! My knife just broke.'' [slang]
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>nuts</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>nuts
     adj : informal or slang terms for mentally irregular; "it used to
           drive my husband balmy" [syn: {balmy}, {barmy}, {bats},
            {batty}, {bonkers}, {buggy}, {cracked}, {crackers}, {daft},
            {dotty}, {fruity}, {haywire}, {kooky}, {kookie}, {loco},
            {loony}, {loopy}, {nutty}, {round the bend}, {around
           the bend}, {wacky}, {whacky}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
