<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>game</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>game</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Game \Game\, a. [Cf. W. cam crooked, and E. gambol, n.]
   Crooked; lame; as, a game leg. [Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>game</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Game \Game\, n. [OE. game, gamen, AS. gamen, gomen, play, sport;
   akin to OS., OHG., &amp; Icel. gaman, Dan. gammen mirth,
   merriment, OSw. gamman joy. Cf. {Gammon} a game,
   {Backgammon}, {Gamble} v. i.]
   1. Sport of any kind; jest, frolic.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have had pastimes here, and pleasant game.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A contest, physical or mental, according to certain rules,
      for amusement, recreation, or for winning a stake; as, a
      game of chance; games of skill; field games, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            But war's a game, which, were their subject wise,
            Kings would not play at.              --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Among the ancients, especially the Greeks and Romans,
         there were regularly recurring public exhibitions of
         strength, agility, and skill under the patronage of the
         government, usually accompanied with religious
         ceremonies. Such were the Olympic, the Pythian, the
         Nemean, and the Isthmian games.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The use or practice of such a game; a single match at
      play; a single contest; as, a game at cards.
      [1913 Webster]

            Talk the game o'er between the deal.  --Lloyd.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is gained, as the stake in a game; also, the
      number of points necessary to be scored in order to win a
      game; as, in short whist five points are game.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Card Playing) In some games, a point credited on the
      score to the player whose cards counts up the highest.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A scheme or art employed in the pursuit of an object or
      purpose; method of procedure; projected line of
      operations; plan; project.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your murderous game is nearly up.     --Blackw. Mag.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was obviously Lord Macaulay's game to blacken the
            greatest literary champion of the cause he had set
            himself to attack.                    --Saintsbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Animals pursued and taken by sportsmen; wild meats
      designed for, or served at, table.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those species of animals . . . distinguished from
            the rest by the well-known appellation of game.
                                                  --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Confidence game}. See under {Confidence}.

   {To make game of}, to make sport of; to mock. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>game</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Game \Game\ (g[=a]m), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Gamed} (g[=a]md); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Gaming}.] [OE. gamen, game?en, to rejoice, AS.
   gamenian to play. See {Game}, n.]
   1. To rejoice; to be pleased; -- often used, in Old English,
      impersonally with dative. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            God loved he best with all his whole hearte
            At alle times, though him gamed or smarte.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To play at any sport or diversion.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To play for a stake or prize; to use cards, dice,
      billiards, or other instruments, according to certain
      rules, with a view to win money or some other thing waged
      upon the issue of the contest; to gamble.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>game</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Game \Game\, a.
   1. Having a resolute, unyielding spirit, like the gamecock;
      ready to fight to the last; plucky.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was game . . . .I felt that I could have fought
            even to the death.                    --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of or pertaining to such animals as are hunted for game,
      or to the act or practice of hunting.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Game bag}, a sportsman's bag for carrying small game
      captured; also, the whole quantity of game taken.

   {Game bird}, any bird commonly shot for food, esp. grouse,
      partridges, quails, pheasants, wild turkeys, and the shore
      or wading birds, such as plovers, snipe, woodcock, curlew,
      and sandpipers. The term is sometimes arbitrarily
      restricted to birds hunted by sportsmen, with dogs and
      guns.

   {Game egg}, an egg producing a gamecock.

   {Game laws}, laws regulating the seasons and manner of taking
      game for food or for sport.

   {Game preserver}, a land owner who regulates the killing of
      game on his estate with a view to its increase. [Eng.]

   {To be game}.
      (a) To show a brave, unyielding spirit.
      (b) To be victor in a game. [Colloq.]

   {To die game}, to maintain a bold, unyielding spirit to the
      last; to die fighting.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>game</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>game
     adj 1: disabled in the feet or legs; "a crippled soldier"; "a game
            leg" [syn: {crippled}, {halt}, {halting}, {lame}]
     2: willing to face danger [syn: {gamy}, {gamey}, {gritty}, {mettlesome},
         {spirited}, {spunky}]
     n 1: a single play of a game; "the game lasted 2 hours"
     2: a contest with rules to determine a winner; "you need four
        people to play this game"
     3: an amusement or pastime; "they played word games"; "he
        thought of his painting as a game that filled his empty
        time"; "his life was all fun and games"
     4: animal hunted for food or sport
     5: the game equipment needed to play a game; "the child
        received several games for his birthday"
     6: your occupation or line of work; "he's in the plumbing
        game"; "she's in show biz" [syn: {biz}]
     7: (games) the score at a particular point or the score needed
        to win; "the game is 6 all"; "he is serving for the game"
     8: the flesh of wild animals that is used for food
     9: a secret scheme to do something (especially something
        underhand or illegal); "they concocted a plot to discredit
        the governor"; "I saw through his little game from the
        start" [syn: {plot}, {secret plan}]
     10: frivolous or trifling behavior; "for actors, memorizing
         lines is no game"; "for him, life is all fun and games"
     v : place a bet on; "Which horse are you backing?"; "I'm betting
         on the new horse" [syn: {bet on}, {back}, {gage}, {stake},
          {punt}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
