<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>gas</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gas</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>gas
     
        {GNU assembler}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gas</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gas, KS (city, FIPS 25975)
  Location: 37.92271 N, 95.34470 W
  Population (1990): 505 (227 housing units)
  Area: 1.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gas</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gas \Gas\ (g[a^]s), n.; pl. {Gases} (g[a^]s"[e^]z). [Invented by
   the chemist Van Helmont of Brussels, who died in 1644.]
   1. An a["e]riform fluid; -- a term used at first by chemists
      as synonymous with air, but since restricted to fluids
      supposed to be permanently elastic, as oxygen, hydrogen,
      etc., in distinction from vapors, as steam, which become
      liquid on a reduction of temperature. In present usage,
      since all of the supposed permanent gases have been
      liquified by cold and pressure, the term has resumed
      nearly its original signification, and is applied to any
      substance in the elastic or a["e]riform state.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Popular Usage)
      (a) A complex mixture of gases, of which the most
          important constituents are marsh gas, olefiant gas,
          and hydrogen, artificially produced by the destructive
          distillation of gas coal, or sometimes of peat, wood,
          oil, resin, etc. It gives a brilliant light when
          burned, and is the common gas used for illuminating
          purposes.
      (b) Laughing gas.
      (c) Any irrespirable a["e]riform fluid.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. same as {gasoline}; -- a shortened form. Also, the
      accelerator pedal of a motor vehicle; used in the term ``
      step on the gas''.
      [PJC]

   4. the accelerator pedal of a motor vehicle; used in the term
      `` step on the gas''.
      [PJC]

   5. Same as {natural gas}.
      [PJC]

   6. an exceptionally enjoyable event; a good time; as, The
      concert was a gas. [slang]
      [PJC]

   Note: Gas is often used adjectively or in combination; as,
         gas fitter or gasfitter; gas meter or gas-meter, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Air gas} (Chem.), a kind of gas made by forcing air through
      some volatile hydrocarbon, as the lighter petroleums. The
      air is so saturated with combustible vapor as to be a
      convenient illuminating and heating agent.

   {Gas battery} (Elec.), a form of voltaic battery, in which
      gases, especially hydrogen and oxygen, are the active
      agents.

   {Gas carbon}, {Gas coke}, etc. See under {Carbon}, {Coke},
      etc.

   {Gas coal}, a bituminous or hydrogenous coal yielding a high
      percentage of volatile matters, and therefore available
      for the manufacture of illuminating gas. --R. W. Raymond.

   {Gas engine}, an engine in which the motion of the piston is
      produced by the combustion or sudden production or
      expansion of gas; -- especially, an engine in which an
      explosive mixture of gas and air is forced into the
      working cylinder and ignited there by a gas flame or an
      electric spark.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gas</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gas \Gas\ (g[a^]s), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Gassed} (g[a^]st); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Gassing}.]
   1. (Textiles) To singe, as in a gas flame, so as to remove
      loose fibers; as, to gas thread.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. To impregnate with gas; as, to gas lime with chlorine in
      the manufacture of bleaching powder.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. to expose to a poisonous or noxious gas ``The protest
      threatened to become violent, and the police gassed the
      demonstrators to force them to disperse.''
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gas</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>gas [as in `gas chamber'] 1. interj. A term of disgust and hatred,
   implying that gas should be dispensed in generous quantities, thereby
   exterminating the source of irritation. "Some loser just reloaded the
   system for no reason! Gas!" 2. interj. A suggestion that someone or
   something ought to be flushed out of mercy. "The system's getting
   {wedged} every few minutes. Gas!" 3. vt. To {flush} (sense 1). "You
   should gas that old crufty software." 4. [IBM] n. Dead space in
   nonsequentially organized files that was occupied by data that has since
   been deleted; the compression operation that removes it is called
   `degassing' (by analogy, perhaps, with the use of the same term in
   vacuum technology). 5. [IBM] n. Empty space on a disk that has been
   clandestinely allocated against future need.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gas</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>gas
     n 1: the state of matter distinguished from the solid and liquid
          states by: relatively low density and viscosity;
          relatively great expansion and contraction with changes
          in pressure and temperature; the ability to diffuse
          readily; and the spontaneous tendency to become
          distributed uniformly throughout any container
     2: a fluid in the gaseous state having neither independent
        shape nor volume and being able to expand indefinitely
     3: a volatile flammable mixture of hydrocarbons (hexane and
        heptane and octane etc.) derived from petroleum; used
        mainly as a fuel in internal-combustion engines [syn: {gasoline},
         {gasolene}, {petrol}]
     4: a state of excessive gas in the alimentary canal [syn: {flatulence},
         {flatulency}]
     5: a pedal that controls the throttle valve; "he stepped on the
        gas" [syn: {accelerator}, {accelerator pedal}, {gas pedal},
         {throttle}, {gun}]
     6: a fossil fuel in the gaseous state; used for cooking and
        heating homes [syn: {natural gas}]
     v 1: attack with gas; subject to gas fumes; "The despot gassed
          the rebellious tribes"
     2: show off [syn: {boast}, {tout}, {swash}, {shoot a line}, {brag},
         {blow}, {bluster}, {vaunt}, {gasconade}]
     [also: {gassing}, {gasses}, {gassed}, {gasses} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
