<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>geology</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>geology</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>GEOLOGY, n.  The science of the earth's crust -- to which, doubtless,
will be added that of its interior whenever a man shall come up
garrulous out of a well.  The geological formations of the globe
already noted are catalogued thus:  The Primary, or lower one,
consists of rocks, bones or mired mules, gas-pipes, miners' tools,
antique statues minus the nose, Spanish doubloons and ancestors.  The
Secondary is largely made up of red worms and moles.  The Tertiary
comprises railway tracks, patent pavements, grass, snakes, mouldy
boots, beer bottles, tomato cans, intoxicated citizens, garbage,
anarchists, snap-dogs and fools.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>geology</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Geology \Ge*ol"o*gy\, n.; pl. {Geologies}. [Gr. ge`a, gh^, the
   earth + -logy: cf. F. g['e]ologie.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The science which treats:
      (a) Of the structure and mineral constitution of the
          globe; structural geology.
      (b) Of its history as regards rocks, minerals, rivers,
          valleys, mountains, climates, life, etc.; historical
          geology.
      (c) Of the causes and methods by which its structure,
          features, changes, and conditions have been produced;
          dynamical geology.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A treatise on the science.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The science of geology, as treating of the history of
         the globe, involves a description of the different
         strata which compose its crust, their order of
         succession, characteristic forms of animal and
         vegetable life, etc. The principal subdivisions of
         geological time, and the most important strata, with
         their relative positions, are often indicated in a
         diagram called "The Geological Series"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>geology</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Natural \Nat"u*ral\ (?; 135), a. [OE. naturel, F. naturel, fr.
   L. naturalis, fr. natura. See {Nature}.]
   1. Fixed or determined by nature; pertaining to the
      constitution of a thing; belonging to native character;
      according to nature; essential; characteristic; innate;
      not artificial, foreign, assumed, put on, or acquired; as,
      the natural growth of animals or plants; the natural
      motion of a gravitating body; natural strength or
      disposition; the natural heat of the body; natural color.
      [1913 Webster]

            With strong natural sense, and rare force of will.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Conformed to the order, laws, or actual facts, of nature;
      consonant to the methods of nature; according to the
      stated course of things, or in accordance with the laws
      which govern events, feelings, etc.; not exceptional or
      violent; legitimate; normal; regular; as, the natural
      consequence of crime; a natural death; anger is a natural
      response to insult.
      [1913 Webster]

            What can be more natural than the circumstances in
            the behavior of those women who had lost their
            husbands on this fatal day?           --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Having to do with existing system to things; dealing with,
      or derived from, the creation, or the world of matter and
      mind, as known by man; within the scope of human reason or
      experience; not supernatural; as, a natural law; natural
      science; history, theology.
      [1913 Webster]

            I call that natural religion which men might know .
            . . by the mere principles of reason, improved by
            consideration and experience, without the help of
            revelation.                           --Bp. Wilkins.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Conformed to truth or reality; as:
      (a) Springing from true sentiment; not artificial or
          exaggerated; -- said of action, delivery, etc.; as, a
          natural gesture, tone, etc.
      (b) Resembling the object imitated; true to nature;
          according to the life; -- said of anything copied or
          imitated; as, a portrait is natural.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. Having the character or sentiments properly belonging to
      one's position; not unnatural in feelings.
      [1913 Webster]

            To leave his wife, to leave his babes, . . .
            He wants the natural touch.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Connected by the ties of consanguinity. especially,
      Related by birth rather than by adoption; as, one's
      natural mother. ``Natural friends.'' --J. H. Newman.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   7. Hence: Begotten without the sanction of law; born out of
      wedlock; illegitimate; bastard; as, a natural child.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Of or pertaining to the lower or animal nature, as
      contrasted with the higher or moral powers, or that which
      is spiritual; being in a state of nature; unregenerate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The natural man receiveth not the things of the
            Spirit of God.                        --1 Cor. ii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Math.) Belonging to, to be taken in, or referred to, some
      system, in which the base is 1; -- said of certain
      functions or numbers; as, natural numbers, those
      commencing at 1; natural sines, cosines, etc., those taken
      in arcs whose radii are 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mus.)
       (a) Produced by natural organs, as those of the human
           throat, in distinction from instrumental music.
       (b) Of or pertaining to a key which has neither a flat
           nor a sharp for its signature, as the key of C major.
       (c) Applied to an air or modulation of harmony which
           moves by easy and smooth transitions, digressing but
           little from the original key.
       (d) Neither flat nor sharp; -- of a tone.
       (e) Changed to the pitch which is neither flat nor sharp,
           by appending the sign [natural]; as, A natural.
           --Moore (Encyc. of Music).
           [1913 Webster +PJC]

   11. Existing in nature or created by the forces of nature, in
       contrast to production by man; not made, manufactured, or
       processed by humans; as, a natural ruby; a natural
       bridge; natural fibers; a deposit of natural calcium
       sulfate. Opposed to {artificial}, {man-made},
       {manufactured}, {processed} and {synthetic}. [WordNet
       sense 2]
       [PJC]

   12. Hence: Not processed or refined; in the same statre as
       that existing in nature; as, natural wood; natural foods.
       [PJC]

   {Natural day}, the space of twenty-four hours. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Natural fats}, {Natural gas}, etc. See under {Fat}, {Gas}.
      etc.

   {Natural Harmony} (Mus.), the harmony of the triad or common
      chord.

   {Natural history}, in its broadest sense, a history or
      description of nature as a whole, including the sciences
      of {botany}, {zo["o]logy}, {geology}, {mineralogy},
      {paleontology}, {chemistry}, and {physics}. In recent
      usage the term is often restricted to the sciences of
      botany and zo["o]logy collectively, and sometimes to the
      science of zoology alone.

   {Natural law}, that instinctive sense of justice and of right
      and wrong, which is native in mankind, as distinguished
      from specifically revealed divine law, and formulated
      human law.

   {Natural modulation} (Mus.), transition from one key to its
      relative keys.

   {Natural order}. (Nat. Hist.) See under {order}.

   {Natural person}. (Law) See under {person}, n.

   {Natural philosophy}, originally, the study of nature in
      general; the natural sciences; in modern usage, that
      branch of physical science, commonly called {physics},
      which treats of the phenomena and laws of matter and
      considers those effects only which are unaccompanied by
      any change of a chemical nature; -- contrasted with
      {mental philosophy} and {moral philosophy}.

   {Natural scale} (Mus.), a scale which is written without
      flats or sharps.

   Note: Model would be a preferable term, as less likely to
         mislead, the so-called artificial scales (scales
         represented by the use of flats and sharps) being
         equally natural with the so-called natural scale.

   {Natural science}, the study of objects and phenomena
      existing in nature, especially biology, chemistry, physics
      and their interdisciplinary related sciences; {natural
      history}, in its broadest sense; -- used especially in
      contradistinction to {social science}, {mathematics},
      {philosophy}, {mental science} or {moral science}.

   {Natural selection} (Biol.), the operation of natural laws
      analogous, in their operation and results, to designed
      selection in breeding plants and animals, and resulting in
      the survival of the fittest; the elimination over time of
      species unable to compete in specific environments with
      other species more adapted to survival; -- the essential
      mechanism of evolution. The principle of natural selection
      is neutral with respect to the mechanism by which
      inheritable changes occur in organisms (most commonly
      thought to be due to mutation of genes and reorganization
      of genomes), but proposes that those forms which have
      become so modified as to be better adapted to the existing
      environment have tended to survive and leave similarly
      adapted descendants, while those less perfectly adapted
      have tended to die out through lack of fitness for the
      environment, thus resulting in the survival of the
      fittest. See {Darwinism}.

   {Natural system} (Bot. &amp; Zo["o]l.), a classification based
      upon real affinities, as shown in the structure of all
      parts of the organisms, and by their embryology.

            It should be borne in mind that the natural system
            of botany is natural only in the constitution of its
            genera, tribes, orders, etc., and in its grand
            divisions.                            --Gray.
      

   {Natural theology}, or {Natural religion}, that part of
      theological science which treats of those evidences of the
      existence and attributes of the Supreme Being which are
      exhibited in nature; -- distinguished from {revealed
      religion}. See Quotation under {Natural}, a., 3.

   {Natural vowel}, the vowel sound heard in urn, furl, sir,
      her, etc.; -- so called as being uttered in the easiest
      open position of the mouth organs. See {Neutral vowel},
      under {Neutral} and Guide to Pronunciation, [sect] 17.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Syn: See {Native}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>geology</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>geology
     n : a science that deals with the history of the earth as
         recorded in rocks
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
