<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>gift</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gift
   (1.) An gratuity (Prov. 19:6) to secure favour (18:16; 21:14), a
   thank-offering (Num. 18:11), or a dowry (Gen. 34:12).
   
     (2.) An oblation or proppitatory gift (2Sa 8:2,6; 1Ch 18:2,6;
   2Ch 26:8; Ps. 45:12; 72:10).
   
     (3.) A bribe to a judge to obtain a favourable verdict (Ex.
   23:8; Deut. 16:19).
   
     (4.) Simply a thing given (Matt. 7:11; Luke 11:13; Eph. 4:8);
   sacrifical (Matt. 5:23, 24; 8:4); eleemosynary (Luke 21:1); a
   gratuity (John 4:10; Acts 8:20). In Acts 2:38 the generic word
   dorea is rendered "gift." It differs from the charisma (1 Cor.
   12:4) as denoting not miraculous powers but the working of a new
   spirit in men, and that spirit from God.
   
     The giving of presents entered largely into the affairs of
   common life in the East. The nature of the presents was as
   various as were the occasions: food (1 Sam. 9:7; 16:20), sheep
   and cattle (Gen. 32:13-15), gold (2 Sam. 18:11), jewels (Gen.
   24:53), furniture, and vessels for eating and drinking (2 Sam.
   17:28); delicacies, as spices, honey, etc. (1 Kings 10:25; 2
   Kings 5: 22). The mode of presentation was with as much parade
   as possible: the presents were conveyed by the hands of servants
   (Judg. 3:18), or still better, on the backs of beasts of burden
   (2 Kings 8:9). The refusal of a present was regarded as a high
   indignity; and this constituted the aggravated insult noticed in
   Matt. 22:11, the marriage robe having been offered and refused.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gift \Gift\, n. [OE. gift, yift, yeft, AS. gift, fr. gifan to
   give; akin to D. &amp; G. gift, Icel. gift, gipt, Goth. gifts (in
   comp.). See {Give}, v. t.]
   1. Anything given; anything voluntarily transferred by one
      person to another without compensation; a present; an
      offering.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shall I receive by gift, what of my own, . . .
            I can command ?                       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act, right, or power of giving or bestowing; as, the
      office is in the gift of the President.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A bribe; anything given to corrupt.
      [1913 Webster]

            Neither take a gift, for a gift doth blind the eyes
            of the wise.                          --Deut. xvi.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Some exceptional inborn quality or characteristic; a
      striking or special talent or aptitude; power; faculty;
      as, the gift of wit; a gift for speaking.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law) A voluntary transfer of real or personal property,
      without any consideration. It can be perfected only by
      deed, or in case of personal property, by an actual
      delivery of possession. --Bouvier. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Gift rope} (Naut), a rope extended to a boat for towing it;
      a guest rope.

   Syn: Present; donation; grant; largess; benefaction; boon;
        bounty; gratuity; endowment; talent; faculty.

   Usage: {Gift}, {Present}, {Donation}. These words, as here
          compared, denote something gratuitously imparted to
          another out of one's property. A gift is something
          given whether by a superior or an inferior, and is
          usually designed for the relief or benefit of him who
          receives it. A present is ordinarly from an equal or
          inferior, and is always intended as a compliment or
          expression of kindness. Donation is a word of more
          dignity, denoting, properly, a gift of considerable
          value, and ordinarly a gift made either to some public
          institution, or to an individual on account of his
          services to the public; as, a donation to a hospital,
          a charitable society, or a minister.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gift \Gift\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Gifted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Gifting}.]
   To endow with some power or faculty. See {gift}[4].
   [1913 Webster]

         He was gifted . . . with philosophical sagacity. --I.
                                                  Taylor.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>gift
     n 1: something acquired without compensation
     2: natural qualities or talents [syn: {endowment}, {talent}, {natural
        endowment}]
     3: the act of giving [syn: {giving}]
     v 1: give qualities or abilities to [syn: {endow}, {indue}, {empower},
           {invest}, {endue}]
     2: give as a present; make a gift of; "What will you give her
        for her birthday?" [syn: {give}, {present}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
