<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>go</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>go</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Go
     
        &lt;games, application&gt; A thinking game with an oriental origin
        estimated to be around 4000 years old.  Nowadays, the game is
        played by millions of people in (most notably) China, Japan,
        Korea and Taiwan.  In the Western world the game is practised
        by a yearly increasing number of players.  On the {Internet}
        Go players meet, play and talk 24 hours/day on the {Internet
        Go Server} (IGS).
     
        {(http://www.cwi.nl/~jansteen/go/go.html)}.
     
        {Usenet} newsgroup: {news:rec.games.go}.
     
        (1995-03-17)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>go</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Go \Go\ (g[=o]), obs. p. p. of {Go}.
   Gone. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>go</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Go \Go\, v. i. [imp. {Went} (w[e^]nt); p. p. {Gone} (g[o^]n;
   115); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Going}. Went comes from the AS,
   wendan. See {Wend}, v. i.] [OE. gan, gon, AS. g[=a]n, akin to
   D. gaan, G. gehn, gehen, OHG. g[=e]n, g[=a]n, SW. g[*a], Dan.
   gaae; cf. Gr. kicha`nai to reach, overtake, Skr. h[=a] to go,
   AS. gangan, and E. gang. The past tense in AS., eode, is from
   the root i to go, as is also Goth. iddja went. [root]47a. Cf.
   {Gang}, v. i., {Wend}.]
   1. To pass from one place to another; to be in motion; to be
      in a state not motionless or at rest; to proceed; to
      advance; to make progress; -- used, in various
      applications, of the movement of both animate and
      inanimate beings, by whatever means, and also of the
      movements of the mind; also figuratively applied.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move upon the feet, or step by step; to walk; also, to
      walk step by step, or leisurely.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In old writers go is much used as opposed to run, or
         ride. ``Whereso I go or ride.'' --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

               You know that love
               Will creep in service where it can not go.
                                                  --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

               Thou must run to him; for thou hast staid so long
               that going will scarce serve the turn. --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

               He fell from running to going, and from going to
               clambering upon his hands and his knees.
                                                  --Bunyan.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: In Chaucer go is used frequently with the pronoun in
         the objective used reflexively; as, he goeth him home.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. To be passed on fron one to another; to pass; to
      circulate; hence, with for, to have currency; to be taken,
      accepted, or regarded.
      [1913 Webster]

            The man went among men for an old man in the days of
            Saul.                                 --1 Sa. xvii.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The money] should go according to its true value.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To proceed or happen in a given manner; to fare; to move
      on or be carried on; to have course; to come to an issue
      or result; to succeed; to turn out.
      [1913 Webster]

            How goes the night, boy ?             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I think, as the world goes, he was a good sort of
            man enough.                           --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether the cause goes for me or against me, you
            must pay me the reward.               --I Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To proceed or tend toward a result, consequence, or
      product; to tend; to conduce; to be an ingredient; to
      avail; to apply; to contribute; -- often with the
      infinitive; as, this goes to show.
      [1913 Webster]

            Against right reason all your counsels go. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            To master the foul flend there goeth some complement
            knowledge of theology.                --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To apply one's self; to set one's self; to undertake.
      [1913 Webster]

            Seeing himself confronted by so many, like a
            resolute orator, he went not to denial, but to
            justify his cruel falsehood.          --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Go, in this sense, is often used in the present
         participle with the auxiliary verb to be, before an
         infinitive, to express a future of intention, or to
         denote design; as, I was going to say; I am going to
         begin harvest.
         [1913 Webster]

   7. To proceed by a mental operation; to pass in mind or by an
      act of the memory or imagination; -- generally with over
      or through.
      [1913 Webster]

            By going over all these particulars, you may receive
            some tolerable satisfaction about this great
            subject.                              --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To be with young; to be pregnant; to gestate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fruit she goes with,
            I pray for heartily, that it may find
            Good time, and live.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To move from the person speaking, or from the point whence
      the action is contemplated; to pass away; to leave; to
      depart; -- in opposition to stay and come.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will let you go, that ye may sacrifice to the Lord
            your God; . . . only ye shall not go very far away.
                                                  --Ex. viii.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To pass away; to depart forever; to be lost or ruined; to
       perish; to decline; to decease; to die.
       [1913 Webster]

             By Saint George, he's gone!
             That spear wound hath our master sped. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To reach; to extend; to lead; as, a line goes across the
       street; his land goes to the river; this road goes to New
       York.
       [1913 Webster]

             His amorous expressions go no further than virtue
             may allow.                           --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To have recourse; to resort; as, to go to law.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Go is used, in combination with many prepositions and
         adverbs, to denote motion of the kind indicated by the
         preposition or adverb, in which, and not in the verb,
         lies the principal force of the expression; as, to go
         against to go into, to go out, to go aside, to go
         astray, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Go to}, come; move; go away; -- a phrase of exclamation,
      serious or ironical.

   {To go a-begging}, not to be in demand; to be undesired.

   {To go about}.
       (a) To set about; to enter upon a scheme of action; to
           undertake. ``They went about to slay him.'' --Acts
           ix. 29.
           [1913 Webster]

                 They never go about . . . to hide or palliate
                 their vices.                     --Swift.
       (b) (Naut.) To tack; to turn the head of a ship; to wear.
           

   {To go abraod}.
       (a) To go to a foreign country.
       (b) To go out of doors.
       (c) To become public; to be published or disclosed; to be
           current.
           [1913 Webster]

                 Then went this saying abroad among the
                 brethren.                        --John xxi.
                                                  23.

   {To go against}.
       (a) To march against; to attack.
       (b) To be in opposition to; to be disagreeable to.

   {To go ahead}.
       (a) To go in advance.
       (b) To go on; to make progress; to proceed.

   {To go and come}. See {To come and go}, under {Come}.

   {To go aside}.
       (a) To withdraw; to retire.
           [1913 Webster]

                 He . . . went aside privately into a desert
                 place.                           --Luke. ix.
                                                  10.
       (b) To go from what is right; to err. --Num. v. 29.

   {To go back on}.
       (a) To retrace (one's path or footsteps).
       (b) To abandon; to turn against; to betray. [Slang, U.
           S.]

   {To go below}
       (Naut), to go below deck.

   {To go between}, to interpose or mediate between; to be a
      secret agent between parties; in a bad sense, to pander.
      

   {To go beyond}. See under {Beyond}.

   {To go by}, to pass away unnoticed; to omit.

   {To go by the board} (Naut.), to fall or be carried
      overboard; as, the mast went by the board.

   {To go down}.
       (a) To descend.
       (b) To go below the horizon; as, the sun has gone down.
       (c) To sink; to founder; -- said of ships, etc.
       (d) To be swallowed; -- used literally or figuratively.
           [Colloq.]
           [1913 Webster]

                 Nothing so ridiculous, . . . but it goes down
                 whole with him for truth.        --L' Estrange.

   {To go far}.
       (a) To go to a distance.
       (b) To have much weight or influence.

   {To go for}.
       (a) To go in quest of.
       (b) To represent; to pass for.
       (c) To favor; to advocate.
       (d) To attack; to assault. [Low]
       (e) To sell for; to be parted with for (a price).

   {To go for nothing}, to be parted with for no compensation or
      result; to have no value, efficacy, or influence; to count
      for nothing.

   {To go forth}.
       (a) To depart from a place.
       (b) To be divulged or made generally known; to emanate.
           [1913 Webster]

                 The law shall go forth of Zion, and the word of
                 the Lord from Jerusalem.         --Micah iv. 2.

   {To go hard with}, to trouble, pain, or endanger.

   {To go in}, to engage in; to take part. [Colloq.]

   {To go in and out}, to do the business of life; to live; to
      have free access. --John x. 9.

   {To go in for}. [Colloq.]
       (a) To go for; to favor or advocate (a candidate, a
           measure, etc.).
       (b) To seek to acquire or attain to (wealth, honor,
           preferment, etc.)
       (c) To complete for (a reward, election, etc.).
       (d) To make the object of one's labors, studies, etc.
           [1913 Webster]

                 He was as ready to go in for statistics as for
                 anything else.                   --Dickens.
           

   {To go in to} or {To go in unto}.
       (a) To enter the presence of. --Esther iv. 16.
       (b) To have sexual intercourse with. [Script.]

   {To go into}.
       (a) To speak of, investigate, or discuss (a question,
           subject, etc.).
       (b) To participate in (a war, a business, etc.).

   {To go large}.
       (Naut) See under {Large}.

   {To go off}.
       (a) To go away; to depart.
           [1913 Webster]

                 The leaders . . . will not go off until they
                 hear you.                        --Shak.
       (b) To cease; to intermit; as, this sickness went off.
       (c) To die. --Shak.
       (d) To explode or be discharged; -- said of gunpowder, of
           a gun, a mine, etc.
       (e) To find a purchaser; to be sold or disposed of.
       (f) To pass off; to take place; to be accomplished.
           [1913 Webster]

                 The wedding went off much as such affairs do.
                                                  --Mrs.
                                                  Caskell.

   {To go on}.
       (a) To proceed; to advance further; to continue; as, to
           go on reading.
       (b) To be put or drawn on; to fit over; as, the coat will
           not go on.

   {To go all fours}, to correspond exactly, point for point.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is not easy to make a simile go on all fours.
                                                  --Macaulay.

   {To go out}.
       (a) To issue forth from a place.
       (b) To go abroad; to make an excursion or expedition.
           [1913 Webster]

                 There are other men fitter to go out than I.
                                                  --Shak.
           [1913 Webster]

                 What went ye out for to see ?    --Matt. xi. 7,
                                                  8, 9.
       (c) To become diffused, divulged, or spread abroad, as
           news, fame etc.
       (d) To expire; to die; to cease; to come to an end; as,
           the light has gone out.
           [1913 Webster]

                 Life itself goes out at thy displeasure.
                                                  --Addison.

   {To go over}.
       (a) To traverse; to cross, as a river, boundary, etc.; to
           change sides.
           [1913 Webster]

                 I must not go over Jordan.       --Deut. iv.
                                                  22.
           [1913 Webster]

                 Let me go over, and see the good land that is
                 beyond Jordan.                   --Deut. iii.
                                                  25.
           [1913 Webster]

                 Ishmael . . . departed to go over to the
                 Ammonites.                       --Jer. xli.
                                                  10.
       (b) To read, or study; to examine; to review; as, to go
           over one's accounts.
           [1913 Webster]

                 If we go over the laws of Christianity, we
                 shall find that . . . they enjoin the same
                 thing.                           --Tillotson.
       (c) To transcend; to surpass.
       (d) To be postponed; as, the bill went over for the
           session.
       (e) (Chem.) To be converted (into a specified substance
           or material); as, monoclinic sulphur goes over into
           orthorhombic, by standing; sucrose goes over into
           dextrose and levulose.

   {To go through}.
       (a) To accomplish; as, to go through a work.
       (b) To suffer; to endure to the end; as, to go through a
           surgical operation or a tedious illness.
       (c) To spend completely; to exhaust, as a fortune.
       (d) To strip or despoil (one) of his property. [Slang]
       (e) To botch or bungle a business. [Scot.]

   {To go through with}, to perform, as a calculation, to the
      end; to complete.

   {To go to ground}.
       (a) To escape into a hole; -- said of a hunted fox.
       (b) To fall in battle.

   {To go to naught} (Colloq.), to prove abortive, or
      unavailling.

   {To go under}.
       (a) To set; -- said of the sun.
       (b) To be known or recognized by (a name, title, etc.).
       (c) To be overwhelmed, submerged, or defeated; to perish;
           to succumb.

   {To go up}, to come to nothing; to prove abortive; to fail.
      [Slang]

   {To go upon}, to act upon, as a foundation or hypothesis.

   {To go with}.
       (a) To accompany.
       (b) To coincide or agree with.
       (c) To suit; to harmonize with.

   {To go well with}, {To go ill with}, {To go hard with}, to
      affect (one) in such manner.

   {To go without}, to be, or to remain, destitute of.

   {To go wrong}.
       (a) To take a wrong road or direction; to wander or
           stray.
       (b) To depart from virtue.
       (c) To happen unfortunately; to unexpectedly cause a
           mishap or failure.
       (d) To miss success; to fail.

   {To let go}, to allow to depart; to quit one's hold; to
      release.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>go</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Go \Go\, v. t.
   1. To take, as a share in an enterprise; to undertake or
      become responsible for; to bear a part in.
      [1913 Webster]

            They to go equal shares in the booty. --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bet or wager; as, I'll go you a shilling. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {To go halves}, to share with another equally.

   {To go it}, to behave in a wild manner; to be uproarious; to
      carry on; also, to proceed; to make progress. [Colloq.]

   {To go it alone} (Card Playing), to play a hand without the
      assistance of one's partner.

   {To go one's way}, to set forth; to depart.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>go</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Go \Go\, n.
   1. Act; working; operation. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            So gracious were the goes of marriage. --Marston.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A circumstance or occurrence; an incident. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

            This is a pretty go.                  --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The fashion or mode; as, quite the go. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Noisy merriment; as, a high go. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A glass of spirits. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Power of going or doing; energy; vitality; perseverance;
      push; as, there is no go in him. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Cribbage) That condition in the course of the game when a
      player can not lay down a card which will not carry the
      aggregate count above thirty-one.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Something that goes or is successful; a success; as, he
      made a go of it; also, an agreement.

            ``Well,'' said Fleming, ``is it a go?'' --Bret
                                                  Harte.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Great go}, {Little go}, the final and the preliminary
      examinations for a degree. [Slang, Eng. Univ.]

   {No go}, a failure; a fiasco. [Slang] --Thackeray.

   {On the go}, moving about; unsettled. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>go</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>go
     adj : functioning correctly and ready for action; "all systems are
           go" [ant: {no-go}]
     n 1: a time for working (after which you will be relieved by
          someone else); "it's my go"; "a spell of work" [syn: {spell},
           {tour}, {turn}]
     2: street names for methylenedioxymethamphetamine [syn: {Adam},
         {ecstasy}, {XTC}, {disco biscuit}, {cristal}, {X}, {hug
        drug}]
     3: a usually brief attempt; "he took a crack at it"; "I gave it
        a whirl" [syn: {crack}, {fling}, {pass}, {whirl}, {offer}]
     4: a board game for two players who place counters on a grid;
        the object is to surround and so capture the opponent's
        counters [syn: {go game}]
     v 1: change location; move, travel, or proceed; "How fast does
          your new car go?"; "We travelled from Rome to Naples by
          bus"; "The policemen went from door to door looking for
          the suspect"; "The soldiers moved towards the city in an
          attempt to take it before night fell" [syn: {travel}, {move},
           {locomote}] [ant: {stay in place}]
     2: follow a procedure or take a course; "We should go farther
        in this matter"; "She went through a lot of trouble"; "go
        about the world in a certain manner"; "Messages must go
        through diplomatic channels" [syn: {proceed}, {move}]
     3: move away from a place into another direction; "Go away
        before I start to cry"; "The train departs at noon" [syn:
        {go away}, {depart}] [ant: {come}]
     4: enter or assume a certain state or condition; "He became
        annoyed when he heard the bad news"; "It must be getting
        more serious"; "her face went red with anger"; "She went
        into ecstasy"; "Get going!" [syn: {become}, {get}]
     5: be awarded; be allotted; "The first prize goes to Mary";
        "Her money went on clothes"
     6: have a particular form; "the story or argument runs as
        follows"; "as the saying goes..." [syn: {run}]
     7: stretch out over a distance, space, time, or scope; run or
        extend between two points or beyond a certain point;
        "Service runs all the way to Cranbury"; "His knowledge
        doesn't go very far"; "My memory extends back to my fourth
        year of life"; "The facts extend beyond a consideration of
        her personal assets" [syn: {run}, {pass}, {lead}, {extend}]
     8: follow a certain course; "The inauguration went well"; "how
        did your interview go?" [syn: {proceed}]
     9: be abolished or discarded; "These ugly billboards have to
        go!"; "These luxuries all had to go under the Khmer Rouge"
     10: be or continue to be in a certain condition; "The children
         went hungry that day"
     11: make a certain noise or sound; "She went `Mmmmm'"; "The gun
         went `bang'" [syn: {sound}]
     12: perform as expected when applied; "The washing machine won't
         go unless it's plugged in"; "Does this old car still run
         well?"; "This old radio doesn't work anymore" [syn: {function},
          {work}, {operate}, {run}] [ant: {malfunction}]
     13: to be spent or finished; "The money had gone after a few
         days"; "Gas is running low at the gas stations in the
         Midwest" [syn: {run low}, {run short}]
     14: progress by being changed; "The speech has to go through
         several more drafts"; "run through your presentation
         before the meeting" [syn: {move}, {run}]
     15: continue to live; endure or last; "We went without water and
         food for 3 days"; "These superstitions survive in the
         backwaters of America"; "The racecar driver lived through
         several very serious accidents" [syn: {survive}, {last},
         {live}, {live on}, {endure}, {hold up}, {hold out}]
     16: pass, fare, or elapse; of a certain state of affairs or
         action; "How is it going?"; "The day went well until I
         got your call"
     17: pass from physical life and lose all all bodily attributes
         and functions necessary to sustain life; "She died from
         cancer"; "They children perished in the fire"; "The
         patient went peacefully" [syn: {die}, {decease}, {perish},
          {exit}, {pass away}, {expire}, {pass}] [ant: {be born}]
     18: be in the right place or situation; "Where do these books
         belong?"; "Let's put health care where it belongs--under
         the control of the government"; "Where do these books
         go?" [syn: {belong}]
     19: be ranked or compare; "This violinist is as good as
         Juilliard-trained violinists go"
     20: begin or set in motion; "I start at eight in the morning";
         "Ready, set, go!" [syn: {start}, {get going}] [ant: {stop}]
     21: have a turn; make one's move in a game; "Can I go now?"
         [syn: {move}]
     22: be contained in; "How many times does 18 go into 54?"
     23: be sounded, played, or expressed; "How does this song go
         again?"
     24: blend or harmonize; "This flavor will blend with those in
         your dish"; "This sofa won't go with the chairs" [syn: {blend},
          {blend in}]
     25: lead, extend, or afford access; "This door goes to the
         basement"; "The road runs South" [syn: {lead}]
     26: be the right size or shape; fit correctly or as desired;
         "This piece won't fit into the puzzle" [syn: {fit}]
     27: go through in search of something; search through someone's
         belongings in an unauthorized way; "Who rifled through my
         desk drawers?" [syn: {rifle}]
     28: be spent; "All my money went for food and rent"
     29: give support (to) or make a choice (of) one out of a group
         or number; "I plumped for the losing candidates" [syn: {plump}]
     30: stop operating or functioning; "The engine finally went";
         "The car died on the road"; "The bus we travelled in
         broke down on the way to town"; "The coffee maker broke";
         "The engine failed on the way to town"; "her eyesight
         went after the accident" [syn: {fail}, {go bad}, {give
         way}, {die}, {give out}, {conk out}, {break}, {break down}]
     [also: {went}, {gone}, {goes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
