<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>goal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>goal
     
        &lt;programming&gt; In {logic programming}, a {predicate} applied to
        its {arguments} which the system attempts to prove by matching
        it against the {clauses} of the program.  A goal may fail or
        it may succeed in one or more ways.
     
        (1997-07-14)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Goal \Goal\, n. [F. gaule pole, Prov. F. waule, of German
   origin; cf. Fries. walu staff, stick, rod, Goth. walus, Icel.
   v["o]lr a round stick; prob. akin to E. wale.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The mark set to bound a race, and to or around which the
      constestants run, or from which they start to return to it
      again; the place at which a race or a journey is to end.
      [1913 Webster]

            Part curb their fiery steeds, or shun the goal
            With rapid wheels.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The final purpose or aim; the end to which a design tends,
      or which a person aims to reach or attain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Each individual seeks a several goal. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A base, station, or bound used in various games as the
      point or object which a team must reach in order to score
      points; in certain games, the point which the ball or puck
      must pass in order for points to be scored. In football,
      it is a line between two posts across which the ball must
      pass in order to score points; in soccer or ice hockey, it
      is a net at each end of the soccer field into which the
      soccer ball or hocjey puck must be propelled; in
      basketball, it is the basket[7] suspended from the
      backboard, through which the basketball must pass.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. (Sport) The act or instance of propelling the ball or puck
      into or through the goal[3], thus scoring points; as, to
      score a goal.
      [PJC]

   {Goal keeper}, (Sport) the player charged with the defense of
      the goal, such as in soccer or ice hockey.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>goal
     n 1: the state of affairs that a plan is intended to achieve and
          that (when achieved) terminates behavior intended to
          achieve it; "the ends justify the means" [syn: {end}]
     2: a successful attempt at scoring; "the winning goal came with
        less than a minute left to play"
     3: game equipment consisting of the place toward which players
        of a game try to advance a ball or puck in order to score
        points
     4: the place designated as the end (as of a race or journey);
        "a crowd assembled at the finish"; "he was nearly
        exhuasted as their destination came into view" [syn: {finish},
         {destination}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
