<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>god</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>god</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>God
   (A.S. and Dutch God; Dan. Gud; Ger. Gott), the name of the
   Divine Being. It is the rendering (1) of the Hebrew _'El_, from
   a word meaning to be strong; (2) of _'Eloah_, plural _'Elohim_.
   The singular form, _Eloah_, is used only in poetry. The plural
   form is more commonly used in all parts of the Bible, The Hebrew
   word Jehovah (q.v.), the only other word generally employed to
   denote the Supreme Being, is uniformly rendered in the
   Authorized Version by "LORD," printed in small capitals. The
   existence of God is taken for granted in the Bible. There is
   nowhere any argument to prove it. He who disbelieves this truth
   is spoken of as one devoid of understanding (Ps. 14:1).
   
     The arguments generally adduced by theologians in proof of the
   being of God are:
   
     (1.) The a priori argument, which is the testimony afforded by
   reason.
   
     (2.) The a posteriori argument, by which we proceed logically
   from the facts of experience to causes. These arguments are,
   
     (a) The cosmological, by which it is proved that there must be
   a First Cause of all things, for every effect must have a cause.
   
     (b) The teleological, or the argument from design. We see
   everywhere the operations of an intelligent Cause in nature.
   
     (c) The moral argument, called also the anthropological
   argument, based on the moral consciousness and the history of
   mankind, which exhibits a moral order and purpose which can only
   be explained on the supposition of the existence of God.
   Conscience and human history testify that "verily there is a God
   that judgeth in the earth."
   
     The attributes of God are set forth in order by Moses in Ex.
   34:6,7. (see also Deut. 6:4; 10:17; Num. 16:22; Ex. 15:11;
   33:19; Isa. 44:6; Hab. 3:6; Ps. 102:26; Job 34:12.) They are
   also systematically classified in Rev. 5:12 and 7:12.
   
     God's attributes are spoken of by some as absolute, i.e., such
   as belong to his essence as Jehovah, Jah, etc.; and relative,
   i.e., such as are ascribed to him with relation to his
   creatures. Others distinguish them into communicable, i.e.,
   those which can be imparted in degree to his creatures:
   goodness, holiness, wisdom, etc.; and incommunicable, which
   cannot be so imparted: independence, immutability, immensity,
   and eternity. They are by some also divided into natural
   attributes, eternity, immensity, etc.; and moral, holiness,
   goodness, etc.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>god</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>God \God\, a. &amp; n.
   Good. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>god</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>God \God\ (g[o^]d), n. [AS. god; akin to OS. &amp; D. god, OHG. got,
   G. gott, Icel. gu[eth], go[eth], Sw. &amp; Dan. gud, Goth. gup,
   prob. orig. a p. p. from a root appearing in Skr. h[=u], p.
   p. h[=u]ta, to call upon, invoke, implore. [root]30. Cf.
   {Goodbye}, {Gospel}, {Gossip}.]
   1. A being conceived of as possessing supernatural power, and
      to be propitiated by sacrifice, worship, etc.; a divinity;
      a deity; an object of worship; an idol.
      [1913 Webster]

            He maketh a god, and worshipeth it.   --Is. xliv.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

            The race of Israel . . . bowing lowly down
            To bestial gods.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The Supreme Being; the eternal and infinite Spirit, the
      Creator, and the Sovereign of the universe; Jehovah.
      [1913 Webster]

            God is a Spirit; and they that worship him must
            worship him in spirit and in truth.   --John iv. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A person or thing deified and honored as the chief good;
      an object of supreme regard.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whose god is their belly.             --Phil. iii.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Figuratively applied to one who wields great or despotic
      power. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Act of God}. (Law) See under {Act}.

   {Gallery gods}, the occupants of the highest and cheapest
      gallery of a theater. [Colloq.]

   {God's acre}, {God's field}, a burial place; a churchyard.
      See under {Acre}.

   {God's house}.
      (a) An almshouse. [Obs.]
      (b) A church.

   {God's penny}, earnest penny. [Obs.] --Beau. &amp; Fl.

   {God's Sunday}, Easter.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>god</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>God \God\, v. t.
   To treat as a god; to idolize. [Obs.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>god</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>GOD
     Global OutDial
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>god</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>GOD
     Grundsaetze ordnungsmaessiger Datenverarbeitung, "GoD"
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>god</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>God
     n 1: the supernatural being conceived as the perfect and
          omnipotent and omniscient originator and ruler of the
          universe; the object of worship in monotheistic
          religions [syn: {Supreme Being}]
     2: any supernatural being worshipped as controlling some part
        of the world or some aspect of life or who is the
        personification of a force [syn: {deity}, {divinity}, {immortal}]
     3: a man of such superior qualities that he seems like a deity
        to other people; "he was a god among men"
     4: a material effigy that is worshipped as a god; "thou shalt
        not make unto thee any graven image"; "money was his god"
        [syn: {idol}, {graven image}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
