<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>goldfish</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goldfish</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Goldfish \Gold"fish`\, n. (Zo["o]l.)
   (a) A small domesticated cyprinoid fish ({Carassius
       auratus}); -- so named from its color. It is a native of
       China, and is said to have been introduced into Europe in
       1691. It is often kept as an ornament, in small ponds or
       glass globes. Many varieties are known. Called also
       {golden fish}, and {golden carp}. See {Telescope fish},
       under {Telescope}.
   (b) A California marine fish of an orange or red color; the
       garibaldi.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goldfish</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>King \King\, n. [AS. cyng, cyning; akin to OS. kuning, D.
   koning, OHG. kuning, G. k["o]nig, Icel. konungr, Sw. konung,
   Dan. konge; formed with a patronymic ending, and fr. the root
   of E. kin; cf. Icel. konr a man of noble birth. [root]44. See
   {Kin}.]
   1. A chief ruler; a sovereign; one invested with supreme
      authority over a nation, country, or tribe, usually by
      hereditary succession; a monarch; a prince. ``Ay, every
      inch a king.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Kings will be tyrants from policy, when subjects are
            rebels from principle.                --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

            There was a State without king or nobles. --R.
                                                  Choate.
      [1913 Webster]

            But yonder comes the powerful King of Day,
            Rejoicing in the east                 --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who, or that which, holds a supreme position or rank;
      a chief among competitors; as, a railroad king; a money
      king; the king of the lobby; the king of beasts.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A playing card having the picture of a king[1]; as, the
      king of diamonds.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The chief piece in the game of chess.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A crowned man in the game of draughts.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. pl. The title of two historical books in the Old
      Testament.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: King is often used adjectively, or in combination, to
         denote pre["e]minence or superiority in some
         particular; as, kingbird; king crow; king vulture.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Apostolic king}. See {Apostolic}.

   {King-at-arms}, or {King-of-arms}, the chief heraldic officer
      of a country. In England the king-at-arms was formerly of
      great authority. His business is to direct the heralds,
      preside at their chapters, and have the jurisdiction of
      armory. There are three principal kings-at-arms, viz.,
      Garter, Clarencieux, and Norroy. The latter (literally
      north roy or north king) officiates north of the Trent.

   {King auk} (Zo["o]l.), the little auk or sea dove.

   {King bird of paradise}. (Zo["o]l.), See {Bird of paradise}.
      

   {King card}, in whist, the best unplayed card of each suit;
      thus, if the ace and king of a suit have been played, the
      queen is the king card of the suit.

   {King Cole}, a legendary king of Britain, who is said to have
      reigned in the third century.

   {King conch} (Zo["o]l.), a large and handsome univalve shell
      ({Cassis cameo}), found in the West Indies. It is used for
      making cameos. See {Helmet shell}, under {Helmet}.

   {King Cotton}, a popular personification of the great staple
      production of the southern United States.

   {King crab}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The limulus or horseshoe crab. See {Limulus}.
      (b) The large European spider crab or thornback ({Maia
          squinado}).
      (c) A large crab of the northern Pacific ({Paralithodes
          camtshatica}), especially abundant on the coasts of
          Alaska and Japan, and popular as a food; called also
          {Alaskan king crab}.

   {King crow}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A black drongo shrike ({Buchanga atra}) of India; --
          so called because, while breeding, they attack and
          drive away hawks, crows, and other large birds.
      (b) The {Dicrurus macrocercus} of India, a crested bird
          with a long, forked tail. Its color is black, with
          green and blue reflections. Called also {devil bird}.
          

   {King duck} (Zo["o]l.), a large and handsome eider duck
      ({Somateria spectabilis}), inhabiting the arctic regions
      of both continents.

   {King eagle} (Zo["o]l.), an eagle ({Aquila heliaca}) found in
      Asia and Southeastern Europe. It is about as large as the
      golden eagle. Some writers believe it to be the imperial
      eagle of Rome.

   {King hake} (Zo["o]l.), an American hake ({Phycis regius}),
      found in deep water along the Atlantic coast.

   {King monkey} (Zo["o]l.), an African monkey ({Colobus
      polycomus}), inhabiting Sierra Leone.

   {King mullet} (Zo["o]l.), a West Indian red mullet ({Upeneus
      maculatus}); -- so called on account of its great beauty.
      Called also {goldfish}.

   {King of terrors}, death.

   {King parrakeet} (Zo["o]l.), a handsome Australian parrakeet
      ({Platycercys scapulatus}), often kept in a cage. Its
      prevailing color is bright red, with the back and wings
      bright green, the rump blue, and tail black.

   {King penguin} (Zo["o]l.), any large species of penguin of
      the genus {Aptenodytes}; esp., {Aptenodytes longirostris},
      of the Falkland Islands and Kerguelen Land, and
      {Aptenodytes Patagonica}, of Patagonia.

   {King rail} (Zo["o]l.), a small American rail ({Rallus
      elegans}), living in fresh-water marshes. The upper parts
      are fulvous brown, striped with black; the breast is deep
      cinnamon color.

   {King salmon} (Zo["o]l.), the quinnat. See {Quinnat}.

   {King's counsel}, or {Queen's counsel} (Eng. Law), barristers
      learned in the law, who have been called within the bar,
      and selected to be the king's or queen's counsel. They
      answer in some measure to the advocates of the revenue
      (advocati fisci) among the Romans. They can not be
      employed against the crown without special license.
      --Wharton's Law Dict.

   {King's cushion}, a temporary seat made by two persons
      crossing their hands. [Prov. Eng.] --Halliwell.

   {The king's English}, correct or current language of good
      speakers; pure English. --Shak.

   {King's evidence} or {Queen's evidence}, testimony in favor
      of the Crown by a witness who confesses his guilt as an
      accomplice. See under {Evidence}. [Eng.]

   {King's evil}, scrofula; -- so called because formerly
      supposed to be healed by the touch of a king.

   {King snake} (Zo["o]l.), a large, nearly black, harmless
      snake ({Ophiobolus getulus}) of the Southern United
      States; -- so called because it kills and eats other kinds
      of snakes, including even the rattlesnake.

   {King's spear} (Bot.), the white asphodel ({Asphodelus
      albus}).

   {King's yellow}, a yellow pigment, consisting essentially of
      sulphide and oxide of arsenic; -- called also {yellow
      orpiment}.

   {King tody} (Zo["o]l.), a small fly-catching bird
      ({Eurylaimus serilophus}) of tropical America. The head is
      adorned with a large, spreading, fan-shaped crest, which
      is bright red, edged with black.

   {King vulture} (Zo["o]l.), a large species of vulture
      ({Sarcorhamphus papa}), ranging from Mexico to Paraguay,
      The general color is white. The wings and tail are black,
      and the naked carunculated head and the neck are
      briliantly colored with scarlet, yellow, orange, and blue.
      So called because it drives away other vultures while
      feeding.

   {King wood}, a wood from Brazil, called also {violet wood},
      beautifully streaked in violet tints, used in turning and
      small cabinetwork. The tree is probably a species of
      {Dalbergia}. See {Jacaranda}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goldfish</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>goldfish
     n : small golden or orange-red freshwater fishes of Eurasia used
         as pond or aquarium fishes [syn: {Carassius auratus}]
     [also: {goldfishes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
