<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>goodwill</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goodwill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Good \Good\, a. [Compar. {Better}; superl. {Best}. These words,
   though used as the comparative and superlative of good, are
   from a different root.] [AS. G[=o]d, akin to D. goed, OS.
   g[=o]d, OHG. guot, G. gut, Icel. g[=o][eth]r, Sw. &amp; Dan. god,
   Goth. g[=o]ds; prob. orig., fitting, belonging together, and
   akin to E. gather. [root]29 Cf. {Gather}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Possessing desirable qualities; adapted to answer the end
      designed; promoting success, welfare, or happiness;
      serviceable; useful; fit; excellent; admirable;
      commendable; not bad, corrupt, evil, noxious, offensive,
      or troublesome, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            And God saw everything that he had made, and behold,
            it was very good.                     --Gen. i. 31.
      [1913 Webster]

            Good company, good wine, good welcome. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Possessing moral excellence or virtue; virtuous; pious;
      religious; -- said of persons or actions.
      [1913 Webster]

            In all things showing thyself a pattern of good
            works.                                --Tit. ii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Kind; benevolent; humane; merciful; gracious; polite;
      propitious; friendly; well-disposed; -- often followed by
      to or toward, also formerly by unto.
      [1913 Webster]

            The men were very good unto us.       --1 Sam. xxv.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Serviceable; suited; adapted; suitable; of use; to be
      relied upon; -- followed especially by for.
      [1913 Webster]

            All quality that is good for anything is founded
            originally in merit.                  --Collier.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Clever; skillful; dexterous; ready; handy; -- followed
      especially by at.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . is a good workman; a very good tailor.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those are generally good at flattering who are good
            for nothing else.                     --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Adequate; sufficient; competent; sound; not fallacious;
      valid; in a commercial sense, to be depended on for the
      discharge of obligations incurred; having pecuniary
      ability; of unimpaired credit.
      [1913 Webster]

            My reasons are both good and weighty. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            My meaning in saying he is a good man is . . . that
            he is sufficient . . . I think I may take his bond.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Real; actual; serious; as in the phrases in good earnest;
      in good sooth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Love no man in good earnest.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Not small, insignificant, or of no account; considerable;
      esp., in the phrases a good deal, a good way, a good
      degree, a good share or part, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Not lacking or deficient; full; complete.
      [1913 Webster]

            Good measure, pressed down, and shaken together, and
            running over.                         --Luke vi. 38.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Not blemished or impeached; fair; honorable; unsullied;
       as in the phrases a good name, a good report, good
       repute, etc.
       [1913 Webster]

             A good name is better than precious ointment.
                                                  --Eccl. vii.
                                                  1.
       [1913 Webster]

   {As good as}. See under {As}.

   {For good}, or {For good and all}, completely and finally;
      fully; truly.
      [1913 Webster]

            The good woman never died after this, till she came
            to die for good and all.              --L'Estrange.

   {Good breeding}, polite or polished manners, formed by
      education; a polite education.
      [1913 Webster]

            Distinguished by good humor and good breeding.
                                                  --Macaulay.

   {Good cheap}, literally, good bargain; reasonably cheap.

   {Good consideration} (Law).
       (a) A consideration of blood or of natural love and
           affection. --Blackstone.
       (b) A valuable consideration, or one which will sustain a
           contract.

   {Good fellow}, a person of companionable qualities.
      [Familiar]

   {Good folk}, {or Good people}, fairies; brownies; pixies,
      etc. [Colloq. Eng. &amp; Scot.]

   {Good for nothing}.
       (a) Of no value; useless; worthless.
       (b) Used substantively, an idle, worthless person.
           [1913 Webster]

                 My father always said I was born to be a good
                 for nothing.                     --Ld. Lytton.

   {Good Friday}, the Friday of Holy Week, kept in some churches
      as a fast, in memoory of our Savior's passion or
      suffering; the anniversary of the crucifixion.

   {Good humor}, or {Good-humor}, a cheerful or pleasant temper
      or state of mind.

   {Good humor man}, a travelling vendor who sells Good Humor
      ice-cream (or some similar ice-cream) from a small
      refrigerated truck; he usually drives slowly through
      residential neighborhoods in summertime, loudly playing
      some distinctive recorded music to announce his presence.
      [U. S.]

   {Good nature}, or {Good-nature}, habitual kindness or
      mildness of temper or disposition; amiability; state of
      being in good humor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The good nature and generosity which belonged to his
            character.                            --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            The young count's good nature and easy
            persuadability were among his best characteristics.
                                                  --Hawthorne.

   {Good people}. See {Good folk} (above).

   {Good speed}, good luck; good success; godspeed; -- an old
      form of wishing success. See {Speed}.

   {Good turn}, an act of kidness; a favor.

   {Good will}.
       (a) Benevolence; well wishing; kindly feeling.
       (b) (Law) The custom of any trade or business; the
           tendency or inclination of persons, old customers and
           others, to resort to an established place of
           business; the advantage accruing from tendency or
           inclination.
           [1913 Webster]

                 The good will of a trade is nothing more than
                 the probability that the old customers will
                 resort to the old place.         --Lord Eldon.

   {In good time}.
       (a) Promptly; punctually; opportunely; not too soon nor
           too late.
       (b) (Mus.) Correctly; in proper time.

   {To hold good}, to remain true or valid; to be operative; to
      remain in force or effect; as, his promise holds good; the
      condition still holds good.

   {To make good}, to fulfill; to establish; to maintain; to
      supply (a defect or deficiency); to indemmify; to prove or
      verify (an accusation); to prove to be blameless; to
      clear; to vindicate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Each word made good and true.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of no power to make his wishes good.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I . . . would by combat make her good. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Convenient numbers to make good the city. --Shak.

   {To think good}, to approve; to be pleased or satisfied with;
      to consider expedient or proper.
      [1913 Webster]

            If ye think good, give me my price; and if not,
            forbear.                              --Zech. xi.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Good, in the sense of wishing well, is much used in
         greeting and leave-taking; as, good day, good night,
         good evening, good morning, etc.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goodwill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Will \Will\, n. [OE. wille, AS. willa; akin to OFries. willa,
   OS. willeo, willio, D. wil, G. wille, Icel. vili, Dan.
   villie, Sw. vilja, Goth wilja. See {Will}, v.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The power of choosing; the faculty or endowment of the
      soul by which it is capable of choosing; the faculty or
      power of the mind by which we decide to do or not to do;
      the power or faculty of preferring or selecting one of two
      or more objects.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is necessary to form a distinct notion of what is
            meant by the word ``volition'' in order to
            understand the import of the word will, for this
            last word expresses the power of mind of which
            ``volition'' is the act.              --Stewart.
      [1913 Webster]

            Will is an ambiguous word, being sometimes put for
            the faculty of willing; sometimes for the act of
            that faculty, besides [having] other meanings. But
            ``volition'' always signifies the act of willing,
            and nothing else.                     --Reid.
      [1913 Webster]

            Appetite is the will's solicitor, and the will is
            appetite's controller; what we covet according to
            the one, by the other we often reject. --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            The will is plainly that by which the mind chooses
            anything.                             --J. Edwards.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The choice which is made; a determination or preference
      which results from the act or exercise of the power of
      choice; a volition.
      [1913 Webster]

            The word ``will,'' however, is not always used in
            this its proper acceptation, but is frequently
            substituted for ``volition'', as when I say that my
            hand mover in obedience to my will.   --Stewart.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The choice or determination of one who has authority; a
      decree; a command; discretionary pleasure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy will be done.                     --Matt. vi.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our prayers should be according to the will of God.
                                                  --Law.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Strong wish or inclination; desire; purpose.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: ``Inclination is another word with which will is
         frequently confounded. Thus, when the apothecary says,
         in Romeo and Juliet, 
         [1913 Webster]

               My poverty, but not my will, consents; . . .
               Put this in any liquid thing you will,
               And drink it off.
         [1913 Webster] the word will is plainly used as,
         synonymous with inclination; not in the strict logical
         sense, as the immediate antecedent of action. It is
         with the same latitude that the word is used in common
         conversation, when we speak of doing a thing which duty
         prescribes, against one's own will; or when we speak of
         doing a thing willingly or unwillingly.'' --Stewart.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is strongly wished or desired.
      [1913 Webster]

            What's your will, good friar?         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mariner hath his will.            --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Arbitrary disposal; power to control, dispose, or
      determine.
      [1913 Webster]

            Deliver me not over unto the will of mine enemies.
                                                  --Ps. xxvii.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) The legal declaration of a person's mind as to the
      manner in which he would have his property or estate
      disposed of after his death; the written instrument,
      legally executed, by which a man makes disposition of his
      estate, to take effect after his death; testament; devise.
      See the Note under {Testament}, 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Wills are written or nuncupative, that is, oral. See
         {Nuncupative will}, under {Nuncupative}.
         [1913 Webster]

   {At will} (Law), at pleasure. To hold an estate at the will
      of another, is to enjoy the possession at his pleasure,
      and be liable to be ousted at any time by the lessor or
      proprietor. An estate at will is at the will of both
      parties.

   {Good will}. See under {Good}.

   {Ill will}, enmity; unfriendliness; malevolence.

   {To have one's will}, to obtain what is desired; to do what
      one pleases.

   {Will worship}, worship according to the dictates of the will
      or fancy; formal worship. [Obs.]

   {Will worshiper}, one who offers will worship. [Obs.] --Jer.
      Taylor.

   {With a will}, with willingness and zeal; with all one's
      heart or strength; earnestly; heartily.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goodwill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>good will
     n 1: a disposition to kindness and compassion; benign good will;
          "the victor's grace in treating the vanquished" [syn: {grace},
           {goodwill}]
     2: (accounting) an intangible asset valued according to the
        advantage or reputation a business has acquired (over and
        above its tangible assets) [syn: {goodwill}]
     3: the friendly hope that something will succeed [syn: {goodwill}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>goodwill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>goodwill
     n 1: (accounting) an intangible asset valued according to the
          advantage or reputation a business has acquired (over
          and above its tangible assets) [syn: {good will}]
     2: the friendly hope that something will succeed [syn: {good
        will}]
     3: a disposition to kindness and compassion; benign good will;
        "the victor's grace in treating the vanquished" [syn: {grace},
         {good will}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
