<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>gothic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gothic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gothic \Goth"ic\, a. [L. Gothicus: cf. F. gothique.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Pertaining to the Goths; as, Gothic customs; also, rude;
      barbarous.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) Of or pertaining to a style of architecture with
      pointed arches, steep roofs, windows large in proportion
      to the wall spaces, and, generally, great height in
      proportion to the other dimensions -- prevalent in Western
      Europe from about 1200 to 1475 a. d. See Illust. of
      {Abacus}, and {Capital}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gothic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gothic \Goth"ic\, n.
   1. The language of the Goths; especially, the language of
      that part of the Visigoths who settled in Moesia in the
      4th century. See {Goth}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Bishop Ulfilas or Walfila translated most of the Bible
         into Gothic about the Middle of the 4th century. The
         portion of this translaton which is preserved is the
         oldest known literary document in any Teutonic
         language.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A kind of square-cut type, with no hair lines.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: This is Nonpareil GOTHIC.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.) The style described in {Gothic}, a., 2.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gothic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pointed \Point"ed\, a.
   1. Sharp; having a sharp point; as, a pointed rock.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Characterized by sharpness, directness, or pithiness of
      expression; terse; epigrammatic; especially, directed to a
      particular person or thing.
      [1913 Webster]

            His moral pleases, not his pointed wit. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Pointed arch} (Arch.), an arch with a pointed crown.

   {Pointed style} (Arch.), a name given to that style of
      architecture in which the pointed arch is the predominant
      feature; -- more commonly called {Gothic}.
      [1913 Webster] -- {Point"ed*ly}, adv. -- {Point"ed*ness},
      n.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gothic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Moesogothic \M[oe]`so*goth"ic\, n.
   The language of the M[oe]sogoths; -- also called {Gothic}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gothic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gothic
     adj 1: characteristic of the style of type commonly used for
            printing German
     2: of or relating to the language of the ancient Goths; "the
        Gothic Bible translation"
     3: of or relating to the Goths; "Gothic migrations"
     4: as if belonging to the Middle Ages; old-fashioned and
        unenlightened; "a medieval attitude toward dating" [syn: {medieval},
         {mediaeval}]
     5: characterized by gloom and mystery and the grotesque;
        "gothic novels like `Frankenstein'"
     n 1: extinct East Germanic language of the ancient Goths; the
          only surviving record being fragments of a 4th-century
          translation of the Bible by Bishop Ulfilas
     2: a heavy typeface in use from 15th to 18th centuries [syn: {black
        letter}]
     3: a style of architecture developed in northern France that
        spread throughout Europe between the 12th and 16th
        centuries; characterized by slender vertical piers and
        counterbalancing buttresses and by vaulting and pointed
        arches [syn: {Gothic architecture}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
