<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>gout</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gout</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>GOUT, n.  A physician's name for the rheumatism of a rich patient.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gout</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gout \Gout\ (gout), n. [F. goutte a drop, the gout, the disease
   being considered as a defluxion, fr. L. gutta drop.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A drop; a clot or coagulation.
      [1913 Webster]

            On thy blade and dudgeon gouts of blood. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Med.) A constitutional disease, occurring by paroxysms.
      It consists in an inflammation of the fibrous and
      ligamentous parts of the joints, and almost always attacks
      first the great toe, next the smaller joints, after which
      it may attack the greater articulations. It is attended
      with various sympathetic phenomena, particularly in the
      digestive organs. It may also attack internal organs, as
      the stomach, the intestines, etc. It is an inherited
      disease of purine metaboism, which causes an increased
      level of uric acid in the blood, and leads to deposition
      of crystals of sodium urate in cartilage within joints and
      in connective tissue. It can be alleviated by a diet low
      in purines, and is treated by drugs which block formation
      of uric acid. --Dunglison.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. A disease of cornstalks. See {Corn fly}, under {Corn}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Gout stones}. See {Chalkstone}, n., 2.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gout</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gout \Go[^u]t\ (g[=oo]), n. [F., fr. L. gustus taste. See
   {Gusto}.]
   Taste; relish.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>gout</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>gout
     n : a painful inflammation of the big toe and foot caused by
         defects in uric acid metabolism resulting in deposits of
         the acid and its salts in the blood and joints [syn: {gouty
         arthritis}, {urarthritis}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
