<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>graft</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>graft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Graft
   the process of inoculating fruit-trees (Rom. 11:17-24). It is
   peculiarly appropriate to olive-trees. The union thus of
   branches to a stem is used to illustrate the union of true
   believers to the true Church.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>graft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Graft \Graft\, n. [Prob. orig. so called because illegitimate or
   improper profit was looked upon as a graft, or sort of
   excrescence, on a legitimate business undertaking, in
   distinction from its natural proper development.]
   1. Acquisition of money, position, etc., by dishonest or
      unjust means, as by actual theft or by taking advantage of
      a public office or any position of trust or employment to
      obtain fees, perquisites, profits on contracts,
      legislation, pay for work not done or service not
      performed, etc.; illegal or unfair practice for profit or
      personal advantage; also, anything thus gained. [Colloq.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. A ``soft thing'' or ``easy thing;'' a ``snap.'' [Slang]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>graft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Graft \Graft\, n. [OE. graff, F. greffe, originally the same
   word as OF. grafe pencil, L. graphium, Gr. ?, ?, fr. ? to
   write; prob. akin to E. carve. So named from the resemblance
   of a scion or shoot to a pointed pencil. Cf. {Graphic},
   {Grammar.}]
      (a) A small shoot or scion of a tree inserted in another
          tree, the stock of which is to support and nourish it.
          The two unite and become one tree, but the graft
          determines the kind of fruit.
      (b) A branch or portion of a tree growing from such a
          shoot.
      (c) (Surg.) A portion of living tissue used in the
          operation of autoplasty.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>graft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Graft \Graft\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Grafted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Grafting}.] [F. greffer. See {Graft}, n.]
   1. To insert (a graft) in a branch or stem of another tree;
      to propagate by insertion in another stock; also, to
      insert a graft upon. [Formerly written {graff}.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Surg.) To implant a portion of (living flesh or akin) in
      a lesion so as to form an organic union.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To join (one thing) to another as if by grafting, so as to
      bring about a close union.
      [1913 Webster]

            And graft my love immortal on thy fame ! --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Naut.) To cover, as a ring bolt, block strap, splicing,
      etc., with a weaving of small cord or rope-yarns.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>graft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Graft \Graft\, v. i.
   To insert scions from one tree, or kind of tree, etc., into
   another; to practice grafting.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>graft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>graft
     n 1: (surgery) tissue or organ transplanted from a donor to a
          recipient; in some cases the patient can be both donor
          and recipient [syn: {transplant}]
     2: the practice of offering something (usually money) in order
        to gain an illicit advantage [syn: {bribery}]
     3: the act of grafting something onto something else [syn: {grafting}]
     v 1: cause to grow together parts from different plants; "graft
          the cherry tree branch onto the plum tree" [syn: {engraft},
           {ingraft}]
     2: place athe organ of a donor into the body of a recipient
        [syn: {transplant}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
