<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>grand</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>grand</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Grand \Grand\ (gr[a^]nd), a. [Compar. {Grander}
   (gr[a^]nd"[~e]r); superl. {Grandest}.] [OE. grant, grount,
   OF. grant, F. grand, fr. L. grandis; perh. akin to gravis
   heavy, E. grave, a. Cf. {Grandee}.]
   1. Of large size or extent; great; extensive; hence,
      relatively great; greatest; chief; principal; as, a grand
      mountain; a grand army; a grand mistake. ``Our grand foe,
      Satan.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Making so bold . . . to unseal
            Their grand commission.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Great in size, and fine or imposing in appearance or
      impression; illustrious, dignifled, or noble (said of
      persons); majestic, splendid, magnificent, or sublime
      (said of things); as, a grand monarch; a grand lord; a
      grand general; a grand view; a grand conception.
      [1913 Webster]

            They are the highest models of expression, the
            unapproached
            masters of the grand style.           --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Having higher rank or more dignity, size, or importance
      than other persons or things of the same name; as, a grand
      lodge; a grand vizier; a grand piano, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Standing in the second or some more remote degree of
      parentage or descent; -- generalIy used in composition;
      as, grandfather, grandson, grandchild, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            What cause
            Mov'd our grand parents, in that happy state,
            Favor'd of Heaven so highly, to fall off
            From their Creator.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Grand action}, a pianoforte action, used in grand pianos, in
      which special devices are employed to obtain perfect
      action of the hammer in striking and leaving the string.
      

   {Grand Army of the Republic}, an organized voluntary
      association of men who served in the Union army or navy
      during the civil war in the United States. The order has
      chapters, called Posts, throughout the country.

   {Grand paunch}, a glutton or gourmand. [Obs.] --Holland.

   {Grand pensionary}. See under {Pensionary}.

   {Grand piano} (Mus.), a large piano, usually harp-shaped, in
      which the wires or strings are generally triplicated,
      increasing the power, and all the mechanism is introduced
      in the most effective manner, regardless of the size of
      the instrument.

   {Grand relief} (Sculp.), alto relievo.

   {Grand Seignior}. See under {Seignior}.

   {Grand stand}, the principal stand, or erection for
      spectators, at a, race course, etc.

   {Grand vicar} (Eccl.), a principal vicar; an ecclesiastical
      delegate in France.

   {Grand vizier}. See under {Vizier}.

   Syn: Magnificent; sublime; majestic; dignified; elevated;
        stately; august; pompous; lofty; eralted; noble.

   Usage: Grand, Magnificent, Sublime. Grand, in reference to
          objects of taste, is applied to that which expands the
          mind by a sense of vastness and majesty; magnificent
          is applied to anything which is imposing from its
          splendor; sublime describes that which is awful and
          elevating. A cataract is grand; a rich and varied
          landscape is magnificent; an overhanging precipice is
          sublime. ``Grandeur admits of degrees and
          modifications; but magnificence is that which has
          already reached the highest degree of superiority
          naturally belonging to the object in question.''
          --Crabb.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>grand</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>grand
     adj 1: impressive in scale; "an expansive lifestyle"; "in the grand
            manner" [syn: {expansive}]
     2: of or befitting a lord; "heir to a lordly fortune"; "of
        august lineage" [syn: {august}, {lordly}]
     3: impressive in size or scope; "heroic undertakings" [syn: {heroic}]
     n 1: the cardinal number that is the product of 10 and 100 [syn:
          {thousand}, {one thousand}, {1000}, {M}, {K}, {chiliad},
           {G}, {thou}, {yard}]
     2: a piano with the strings on a harp-shaped frame; usually
        supported by 3 legs [syn: {grand piano}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
