<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>grasshopper</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>grasshopper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Grasshopper
   belongs to the class of neuropterous insects called Gryllidae.
   This insect is not unknown in Palestine.
   
     In Judg. 6:5; 7:12; Job 39:30; Jer. 46:23, where the
   Authorized Version has "grasshopper," the Revised Version more
   correctly renders the Hebrew word ('arbeh) by "locust." This is
   the case also in Amos 7:1; Nah. 3:17, where the Hebrew word
   _gob_ is used; and in Lev. 11:22; Num. 13:33; Eccl. 12:5; Isa.
   40:22, where _hagab_ is used. In all these instances the proper
   rendering is probably "locust" (q.v.).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>grasshopper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Grasshopper \Grass"hop`per\, n.
   1. (Zo["o]l.) Any jumping, orthopterous insect, of the
      families {Acridid[ae]} and {Locustid[ae]}, having large
      hind legs adapted for leaping, and chewing mouth parts.
      The species and genera are very numerous and some are very
      destructive to crops. The former family includes the
      Western grasshopper or locust ({Caloptenus spretus}),
      noted for the great extent of its ravages in the region
      beyond the Mississippi. In the Eastern United States the
      red-legged ({Caloptenus femurrubrum} and {C. atlanis}) are
      closely related species, but their ravages are less
      important. They are closely related to the migratory
      locusts of the Old World. See {Locust}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: The meadow or green grasshoppers belong to the
         {Locustid[ae]}. They have long antenn[ae], large
         ovipositors, and stridulating organs at the base of the
         wings in the male. The European great green grasshopper
         ({Locusta viridissima}) belongs to this family. The
         common American green species mostly belong to
         {Xiphidium}, {Orchelimum}, and {Conocephalus}.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. In ordinary square or upright pianos of London make, the
      escapement lever or jack, so made that it can be taken out
      and replaced with the key; -- called also the {hopper.}
      --Grove.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil.) An antipersonnel mine that jumps from the ground to
      body height when activated, and explodes, hurling metal
      fragments over a wide area.
      [PJC]

   4. A mixed alcoholic beverage containing cr[`e]me de menthe,
      light cream, and sometimes cr[`e]me de cacao. The name
      comes from its light green color.
      [PJC]

   {Grasshopper engine}, a steam engine having a working beam
      with its fulcrum at one end, the steam cylinder at the
      other end, and the connecting rod at an intermediate
      point.

   {Grasshopper lobster} (Zo["o]l.) a young lobster. [Local, U.
      S.]

   {Grasshopper warbler} (Zo["o]l.), cricket bird.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>grasshopper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>grasshopper
     n 1: terrestrial plant-eating insect with hind legs adapted for
          leaping [syn: {hopper}]
     2: a cocktail made of creme de menthe and cream (sometimes with
        creme de cacao)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
