<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>greener</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>greener</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Green \Green\ (gr[=e]n), a. [Compar. {Greener} (gr[=e]n"[~e]r);
   superl. {Greenest.}] [OE. grene, AS. gr[=e]ne; akin to D.
   groen, OS. gr[=o]ni, OHG. gruoni, G. gr["u]n, Dan. &amp; Sw.
   gr["o]n, Icel. gr[ae]nn; fr. the root of E. grow. See
   {Grow.}]
   1. Having the color of grass when fresh and growing;
      resembling that color of the solar spectrum which is
      between the yellow and the blue; verdant; emerald.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Having a sickly color; wan.
      [1913 Webster]

            To look so green and pale.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Full of life and vigor; fresh and vigorous; new; recent;
      as, a green manhood; a green wound.
      [1913 Webster]

            As valid against such an old and beneficent
            government as against . . . the greenest usurpation.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Not ripe; immature; not fully grown or ripened; as, green
      fruit, corn, vegetables, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Not roasted; half raw. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We say the meat is green when half roasted. --L.
                                                  Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Immature in age, judgment, or experience; inexperienced;
      young; raw; not trained; awkward; as, green in years or
      judgment.
      [1913 Webster]

            I might be angry with the officious zeal which
            supposes that its green conceptions can instruct my
            gray hairs.                           --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Not seasoned; not dry; containing its natural juices; as,
      green wood, timber, etc. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Politics) Concerned especially with protection of the
      enviroment; -- of political parties and political
      philosophies; as, the European green parties.
      [PJC]

   {Green brier} (Bot.), a thorny climbing shrub ({Emilaz
      rotundifolia}) having a yellowish green stem and thick
      leaves, with small clusters of flowers, common in the
      United States; -- called also {cat brier}.

   {Green con} (Zo["o]l.), the pollock.

   {Green crab} (Zo["o]l.), an edible, shore crab ({Carcinus
      menas}) of Europe and America; -- in New England locally
      named {joe-rocker}.

   {Green crop}, a crop used for food while in a growing or
      unripe state, as distingushed from a grain crop, root
      crop, etc.

   {Green diallage}. (Min.)
      (a) Diallage, a variety of pyroxene.
      (b) Smaragdite.

   {Green dragon} (Bot.), a North American herbaceous plant
      ({Aris[ae]ma Dracontium}), resembling the Indian turnip;
      -- called also {dragon root}.

   {Green earth} (Min.), a variety of glauconite, found in
      cavities in amygdaloid and other eruptive rock, and used
      as a pigment by artists; -- called also {mountain green}.
      

   {Green ebony}.
      (a) A south American tree ({Jacaranda ovalifolia}), having
          a greenish wood, used for rulers, turned and inlaid
          work, and in dyeing.
      (b) The West Indian green ebony. See {Ebony}.

   {Green fire} (Pyrotech.), a composition which burns with a
      green flame. It consists of sulphur and potassium
      chlorate, with some salt of barium (usually the nitrate),
      to which the color of the flame is due.

   {Green fly} (Zo["o]l.), any green species of plant lice or
      aphids, esp. those that infest greenhouse plants.

   {Green gage}, (Bot.) See {Greengage}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Green gland} (Zo["o]l.), one of a pair of large green glands
      in Crustacea, supposed to serve as kidneys. They have
      their outlets at the bases of the larger antenn[ae].

   {Green hand}, a novice. [Colloq.]

   {Green heart} (Bot.), the wood of a lauraceous tree found in
      the West Indies and in South America, used for
      shipbuilding or turnery. The green heart of Jamaica and
      Guiana is the {Nectandra Rodi[oe]i}, that of Martinique is
      the {Colubrina ferruginosa}.

   {Green iron ore} (Min.) dufrenite.

   {Green laver} (Bot.), an edible seaweed ({Ulva latissima});
      -- called also {green sloke}.

   {Green lead ore} (Min.), pyromorphite.

   {Green linnet} (Zo["o]l.), the greenfinch.

   {Green looper} (Zo["o]l.), the cankerworm.

   {Green marble} (Min.), serpentine.

   {Green mineral}, a carbonate of copper, used as a pigment.
      See {Greengill}.

   {Green monkey} (Zo["o]l.) a West African long-tailed monkey
      ({Cercopithecus callitrichus}), very commonly tamed, and
      trained to perform tricks. It was introduced into the West
      Indies early in the last century, and has become very
      abundant there.

   {Green salt of Magnus} (Old Chem.), a dark green crystalline
      salt, consisting of ammonia united with certain chlorides
      of platinum.

   {Green sand} (Founding) molding sand used for a mold while
      slightly damp, and not dried before the cast is made.

   {Green sea} (Naut.), a wave that breaks in a solid mass on a
      vessel's deck.

   {Green sickness} (Med.), chlorosis.

   {Green snake} (Zo["o]l.), one of two harmless American snakes
      ({Cyclophis vernalis}, and {C. [ae]stivus}). They are
      bright green in color.

   {Green turtle} (Zo["o]l.), an edible marine turtle. See
      {Turtle}.

   {Green vitriol}.
      (a) (Chem.) Sulphate of iron; a light green crystalline
          substance, very extensively used in the preparation of
          inks, dyes, mordants, etc.
      (b) (Min.) Same as {copperas}, {melanterite} and {sulphate
          of iron}.

   {Green ware}, articles of pottery molded and shaped, but not
      yet baked.

   {Green woodpecker} (Zo["o]l.), a common European woodpecker
      ({Picus viridis}); -- called also {yaffle}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
