<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>grounds</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>grounds</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Home \Home\, a.
   1. Of or pertaining to one's dwelling or country; domestic;
      not foreign; as home manufactures; home comforts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Close; personal; pointed; as, a home thrust.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Games) In various games, the ultimate point aimed at in a
      progress; goal; as:
      (a) (Baseball) The plate at which the batter stands; same
          as {home base} and {home plate}.
      (b) (Lacrosse) The place of a player in front of an
          opponent's goal; also, the player.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Home base} or {Home plate} (Baseball), the base at which the
      batter stands when batting, and which is the last base to
      be reached in scoring a run.

   {Home farm}, {grounds}, etc., the farm, grounds, etc.,
      adjacent to the residence of the owner.

   {Home lot}, an inclosed plot on which the owner's home
      stands. [U. S.]

   {Home rule}, rule or government of an appendent or dependent
      country, as to all local and internal legislation, by
      means of a governing power vested in the people within the
      country itself, in contradistinction to a government
      established by the dominant country; as, home rule in
      Ireland. Also used adjectively; as, home-rule members of
      Parliament.

   {Home ruler}, one who favors or advocates home rule.

   {Home stretch} (Sport.), that part of a race course between
      the last curve and the winning post.

   {Home thrust}, a well directed or effective thrust; one that
      wounds in a vital part; hence, in controversy, a personal
      attack.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>grounds</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>grounds
     n 1: your basis for belief or disbelief; knowledge on which to
          base belief; "the evidence that smoking causes lung
          cancer is very compelling" [syn: {evidence}]
     2: the enclosed land around a house or other building; "it was
        a small house with almost no yard" [syn: {yard}, {curtilage}]
     3: a tract of land cleared for some special purposes
        (recreation or burial etc.)
     4: a justification for something existing or happening; "he had
        no cause to complain"; "they had good reason to rejoice"
        [syn: {cause}, {reason}]
     5: sediment that has settled at the bottom of a liquid [syn: {dregs},
         {settlings}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
