<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ground</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Grind \Grind\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Ground}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Grinding}.] [AS. grindan; perh. akin to L. frendere to
   gnash, grind. Cf. {Grist}.]
   1. To reduce to powder by friction, as in a mill, or with the
      teeth; to crush into small fragments; to produce as by the
      action of millstones.
      [1913 Webster]

            Take the millstones, and grind meal.  --Is. xivii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To wear down, polish, or sharpen, by friction; to make
      smooth, sharp, or pointed; to whet, as a knife or drill;
      to rub against one another, as teeth, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To oppress by severe exactions; to harass.
      [1913 Webster]

            To grind the subject or defraud the prince.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To study hard for examination; -- commonly used with away;
      as, to grind away at one's studies. [College Slang]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ground \ground\ (ground), n. [OE. ground, grund, AS. grund; akin
   to D. grond, OS., G., Sw., &amp; Dan. grund, Icel. grunnr bottom,
   Goth. grundus (in composition); perh. orig. meaning, dust,
   gravel, and if so perh. akin to E. grind.]
   1. The surface of the earth; the outer crust of the globe, or
      some indefinite portion of it.
      [1913 Webster]

            There was not a man to till the ground. --Gen. ii.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fire ran along upon the ground.   --Ex. ix. 23.
      Hence: A floor or pavement supposed to rest upon the
      earth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any definite portion of the earth's surface; region;
      territory; country. Hence: A territory appropriated to, or
      resorted to, for a particular purpose; the field or place
      of action; as, a hunting or fishing ground; a play ground.
      [1913 Webster]

            From . . . old Euphrates, to the brook that parts
            Egypt from Syrian ground.             --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Land; estate; possession; field; esp. (pl.), the gardens,
      lawns, fields, etc., belonging to a homestead; as, the
      grounds of the estate are well kept.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy next design is on thy neighbor's grounds.
                                                  --Dryden. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The basis on which anything rests; foundation. Hence: The
      foundation of knowledge, belief, or conviction; a premise,
      reason, or datum; ultimate or first principle; cause of
      existence or occurrence; originating force or agency; as,
      the ground of my hope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Paint. &amp; Decorative Art)
      (a) That surface upon which the figures of a composition
          are set, and which relieves them by its plainness,
          being either of one tint or of tints but slightly
          contrasted with one another; as, crimson Bowers on a
          white ground. See {Background}, {Foreground}, and
          {Middle-ground}.
      (b) In sculpture, a flat surface upon which figures are
          raised in relief.
      (c) In point lace, the net of small meshes upon which the
          embroidered pattern is applied; as, Brussels ground.
          See {Brussels lace}, under {Brussels}.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Etching) A gummy composition spread over the surface of a
      metal to be etched, to prevent the acid from eating except
      where an opening is made by the needle.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Arch.) One of the pieces of wood, flush with the
      plastering, to which moldings, etc., are attached; --
      usually in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Grounds are usually put up first and the plastering
         floated flush with them.
         [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mus.)
      (a) A composition in which the bass, consisting of a few
          bars of independent notes, is continually repeated to
          a varying melody.
      (b) The tune on which descants are raised; the plain song.
          --Moore (Encyc.).
          [1913 Webster]

                On that ground I'll build a holy descant.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Elec.) A conducting connection with the earth, whereby
      the earth is made part of an electrical circuit.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. pl. Sediment at the bottom of liquors or liquids; dregs;
       lees; feces; as, coffee grounds.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. The pit of a theater. [Obs.] --B. Jonson.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Ground angling}, angling with a weighted line without a
      float.

   {Ground annual} (Scots Law), an estate created in land by a
      vassal who instead of selling his land outright reserves
      an annual ground rent, which becomes a perpetual charge
      upon the land.

   {Ground ash}. (Bot.) See {Groutweed}.

   {Ground bailiff} (Mining), a superintendent of mines.
      --Simmonds.

   {Ground bait}, bits of bread, boiled barley or worms, etc.,
      thrown into the water to collect the fish, --Wallon.

   {Ground bass} or {Ground base} (Mus.), fundamental base; a
      fundamental base continually repeated to a varied melody.
      

   {Ground beetle} (Zo["o]l.), one of numerous species of
      carnivorous beetles of the family {Carabid[ae]}, living
      mostly in burrows or under stones, etc.

   {Ground chamber}, a room on the ground floor.

   {Ground cherry}. (Bot.)
       (a) A genus ({Physalis}) of herbaceous plants having an
           inflated calyx for a seed pod: esp., the strawberry
           tomato ({Physalis Alkekengi}). See {Alkekengl}.
       (b) A European shrub ({Prunus Cham[ae]cerasus}), with
           small, very acid fruit.

   {Ground cuckoo}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Chaparral cock}.

   {Ground cypress}. (Bot.) See {Lavender cotton}.

   {Ground dove} (Zo["o]l.), one of several small American
      pigeons of the genus {Columbigallina}, esp. {C. passerina}
      of the Southern United States, Mexico, etc. They live
      chiefly on the ground.

   {Ground fish} (Zo["o]l.), any fish which constantly lives on
      the botton of the sea, as the sole, turbot, halibut.

   {Ground floor}, the floor of a house most nearly on a level
      with the ground; -- called also in America, but not in
      England, the {first floor}.

   {Ground form} (Gram.), the stem or basis of a word, to which
      the other parts are added in declension or conjugation. It
      is sometimes, but not always, the same as the root.

   {Ground furze} (Bot.), a low slightly thorny, leguminous
      shrub ({Ononis arvensis}) of Europe and Central Asia,; --
      called also {rest-harrow}.

   {Ground game}, hares, rabbits, etc., as distinguished from
      winged game.

   {Ground hele} (Bot.), a perennial herb ({Veronica
      officinalis}) with small blue flowers, common in Europe
      and America, formerly thought to have curative properties.
      

   {Ground of the heavens} (Astron.), the surface of any part of
      the celestial sphere upon which the stars may be regarded
      as projected.

   {Ground hemlock} (Bot.), the yew ({Taxus baccata} var.
      Canadensisi) of eastern North America, distinguished from
      that of Europe by its low, straggling stems.

   {Ground hog}. (Zo["o]l.)
       (a) The woodchuck or American marmot ({Arctomys monax}).
           See {Woodchuck}.
       (b) The aardvark.

   {Ground hold} (Naut.), ground tackle. [Obs.] --Spenser.

   {Ground ice}, ice formed at the bottom of a body of water
      before it forms on the surface.

   {Ground ivy}. (Bot.) A trailing plant; alehoof. See {Gill}.
      

   {Ground joist}, a joist for a basement or ground floor; a.
      sleeper.

   {Ground lark} (Zo["o]l.), the European pipit. See {Pipit}.

   {Ground laurel} (Bot.). See {Trailing arbutus}, under
      {Arbutus}.

   {Ground line} (Descriptive Geom.), the line of intersection
      of the horizontal and vertical planes of projection.

   {Ground liverwort} (Bot.), a flowerless plant with a broad
      flat forking thallus and the fruit raised on peduncled and
      radiated receptacles ({Marchantia polymorpha}).

   {Ground mail}, in Scotland, the fee paid for interment in a
      churchyard.

   {Ground mass} (Geol.), the fine-grained or glassy base of a
      rock, in which distinct crystals of its constituents are
      embedded.

   {Ground parrakeet} (Zo["o]l.), one of several Australian
      parrakeets, of the genera {Callipsittacus} and
      {Geopsittacus}, which live mainly upon the ground.

   {Ground pearl} (Zo["o]l.), an insect of the family
      {Coccid[ae]} ({Margarodes formicarum}), found in ants'
      nests in the Bahamas, and having a shelly covering. They
      are strung like beads, and made into necklaces by the
      natives.

   {Ground pig} (Zo["o]l.), a large, burrowing, African rodent
      ({Aulacodus Swinderianus}) about two feet long, allied to
      the porcupines but with harsh, bristly hair, and no
      spines; -- called also {ground rat}.

   {Ground pigeon} (Zo["o]l.), one of numerous species of
      pigeons which live largely upon the ground, as the
      tooth-billed pigeon ({Didunculus strigirostris}), of the
      Samoan Islands, and the crowned pigeon, or goura. See
      {Goura}, and {Ground dove} (above).

   {Ground pine}. (Bot.)
       (a) A blue-flowered herb of the genus {Ajuga} ({A.
           Cham[ae]pitys}), formerly included in the genus
           {Teucrium} or germander, and named from its resinous
           smell. --Sir J. Hill.
       (b) A long, creeping, evergreen plant of the genus
           {Lycopodium} ({L. clavatum}); -- called also {club
           moss}.
       (c) A tree-shaped evergreen plant about eight inches in
           height, of the same genus ({L. dendroideum}) found in
           moist, dark woods in the northern part of the United
           States. --Gray.

   {Ground plan} (Arch.), a plan of the ground floor of any
      building, or of any floor, as distinguished from an
      elevation or perpendicular section.

   {Ground plane}, the horizontal plane of projection in
      perspective drawing.

   {Ground plate}.
       (a) (Arch.) One of the chief pieces of framing of a
           building; a timber laid horizontally on or near the
           ground to support the uprights; a ground sill or
           groundsel.
       (b) (Railroads) A bed plate for sleepers or ties; a
           mudsill.
       (c) (Teleg.) A metallic plate buried in the earth to
           conduct the electric current thereto. Connection to
           the pipes of a gas or water main is usual in cities.
           --Knight.

   {Ground plot}, the ground upon which any structure is
      erected; hence, any basis or foundation; also, a ground
      plan.

   {Ground plum} (Bot.), a leguminous plant ({Astragalus
      caryocarpus}) occurring from the Saskatchewan to Texas,
      and having a succulent plum-shaped pod.

   {Ground rat}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Ground pig} (above).

   {Ground rent}, rent paid for the privilege of building on
      another man's land.

   {Ground robin}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Chewink}.

   {Ground room}, a room on the ground floor; a lower room.
      --Tatler.

   {Ground sea}, the West Indian name for a swell of the ocean,
      which occurs in calm weather and without obvious cause,
      breaking on the shore in heavy roaring billows; -- called
      also {rollers}, and in Jamaica, {the North sea}.

   {Ground sill}. See {Ground plate} (a) (above).

   {Ground snake} (Zo["o]l.), a small burrowing American snake
      ({Celuta am[oe]na}). It is salmon colored, and has a blunt
      tail.

   {Ground squirrel}. (Zo["o]l.)
       (a) One of numerous species of burrowing rodents of the
           genera {Tamias} and {Spermophilus}, having cheek
           pouches. The former genus includes the Eastern
           striped squirrel or chipmunk and some allied Western
           species; the latter includes the prairie squirrel or
           striped gopher, the gray gopher, and many allied
           Western species. See {Chipmunk}, and {Gopher}.
       (b) Any species of the African genus {Xerus}, allied to
           {Tamias}.

   {Ground story}. Same as {Ground floor} (above).

   {Ground substance} (Anat.), the intercellular substance, or
      matrix, of tissues.

   {Ground swell}.
       (a) (Bot.) The plant groundsel. [Obs.] --Holland.
       (b) A broad, deep swell or undulation of the ocean,
           caused by a long continued gale, and felt even at a
           remote distance after the gale has ceased.

   {Ground table}. (Arch.) See Earth table, under Earth.

   {Ground tackle} (Naut.), the tackle necessary to secure a
      vessel at anchor. --Totten.

   {Ground thrush} (Zo["o]l.), one of numerous species of
      bright-colored Oriental birds of the family {Pittid[ae]}.
      See {Pitta}.

   {Ground tier}.
       (a) The lowest tier of water casks in a vessel's hold.
           --Totten.
       (b) The lowest line of articles of any kind stowed in a
           vessel's hold.
       (c) The lowest range of boxes in a theater.

   {Ground timbers} (Shipbuilding) the timbers which lie on the
      keel and are bolted to the keelson; floor timbers.
      --Knight.

   {Ground tit}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Ground wren} (below).

   {Ground wheel}, that wheel of a harvester, mowing machine,
      etc., which, rolling on the ground, drives the mechanism.
      

   {Ground wren} (Zo["o]l.), a small California bird ({Cham[ae]a
      fasciata}) allied to the wrens and titmice. It inhabits
      the arid plains. Called also {ground tit}, and {wren tit}.
      

   {To bite the ground}, {To break ground}. See under {Bite},
      {Break}.

   {To come to the ground}, {To fall to the ground}, to come to
      nothing; to fail; to miscarry.

   {To gain ground}.
       (a) To advance; to proceed forward in conflict; as, an
           army in battle gains ground.
       (b) To obtain an advantage; to have some success; as, the
           army gains ground on the enemy.
       (c) To gain credit; to become more prosperous or
           influential.

   {To get ground}, or {To gather ground}, to gain ground. [R.]
      ``Evening mist . . . gathers ground fast.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is no way for duty to prevail, and get ground
            of them, but by bidding higher.       --South.
   {To give ground}, to recede; to yield advantage.
      [1913 Webster]

            These nine . . . began to give me ground. --Shak.
   {To lose ground}, to retire; to retreat; to withdraw from the
      position taken; hence, to lose advantage; to lose credit
      or reputation; to decline. -- {To stand one's ground}, to
      stand firm; to resist attack or encroachment.
      --Atterbury.{To take the ground} to touch bottom or become
      stranded; -- said of a ship.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ground \ground\ (ground), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {grounded}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {grounding}.]
   1. To lay, set, or run, on the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To found; to fix or set, as on a foundation, reason, or
      principle; to furnish a ground for; to fix firmly.
      [1913 Webster]

            Being rooted and grounded in love.    --Eph. iii.
                                                  17.
      [1913 Webster]

            So far from warranting any inference to the
            existence of a God, would, on the contrary, ground
            even an argument to his negation.     --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To instruct in elements or first principles.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Elec.) To connect with the ground so as to make the earth
      a part of an electrical circuit.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Fine Arts) To cover with a ground, as a copper plate for
      etching (see {Ground}, n., 5); or as paper or other
      materials with a uniform tint as a preparation for
      ornament.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To forbid (a pilot) to fly an airplane; -- usually as a
      disciplinary measure, or for reasons of ill health
      sufficient to interfere with performance.
      [PJC]

   7. To forbid (aircraft) to fly; -- usually due to the unsafe
      condition of the aircraft or lack of conformity to safety
      regulations; as, the discovery of a crack in the wing of a
      Trijet caused the whole fleeet to be grounded for
      inspection.
      [PJC]

   8. To temporarily restrict the activities of (a child),
      especially social activity outside the house; -- usually
      for bad or unsatisfactory conduct; as, Johnny was grounded
      for fighting at school and can't go to the movies for two
      weeks.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ground \ground\, v. i.
   To run aground; to strike the bottom and remain fixed; as,
   the ship grounded on the bar.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ground \ground\,
   imp. &amp; p. p. of {Grind}.
   [1913 Webster] {ground cock}, a cock, the plug of which is
      ground into its seat, as distinguished from a compression
      cock. --Knight.{Ground glass}, glass the transparency of
      which has been destroyed by having its surface roughened
      by grinding. -- {Ground joint}, a close joint made by
      grinding together two pieces, as of metal with emery and
      oil, or of glass with fine sand and water.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ground
     See {grind}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>grind
     n 1: an insignificant student who is ridiculed as being affected
          or studying excessively [syn: {swot}, {nerd}, {wonk}, {dweeb}]
     2: hard monotonous routine work [syn: {drudgery}, {plodding}, {donkeywork}]
     3: the act of grinding to a powder or dust [syn: {mill}, {pulverization},
         {pulverisation}]
     v 1: press or grind with a crunching noise [syn: {crunch}, {cranch},
           {craunch}]
     2: make a grating or grinding sound by rubbing together; "grate
        one's teeth in anger" [syn: {grate}]
     3: reduce to small pieces or particles by pounding or abrading;
        "grind the spices in a mortar"; "mash the garlic" [syn: {mash},
         {crunch}, {bray}, {comminute}]
     4: work hard; "She was digging away at her math homework";
        "Lexicographers drudge all day long" [syn: {labor}, {labour},
         {toil}, {fag}, {travail}, {drudge}, {dig}, {moil}]
     5: dance by rotating the pelvis in an erotically suggestive
        way, often while in contact with one's partner such that
        the dancers' legs are interlaced
     [also: {ground}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ground
     adj : broken or pounded into small fragments; used of e.g. ore or
           stone; "paved with crushed bluestone"; "ground glass is
           used as an abrasive" [syn: {crushed}]
     n 1: the solid part of the earth's surface; "the plane turned
          away from the sea and moved back over land"; "the earth
          shook for several minutes"; "he dropped the logs on the
          ground" [syn: {land}, {dry land}, {earth}, {solid ground},
           {terra firma}]
     2: a rational motive for a belief or action; "the reason that
        war was declared"; "the grounds for their declaration"
        [syn: {reason}]
     3: the loose soft material that makes up a large part of the
        land surface; "they dug into the earth outside the church"
        [syn: {earth}]
     4: a relation that provides the foundation for something; "they
        were on a friendly footing"; "he worked on an interim
        basis" [syn: {footing}, {basis}]
     5: a position to be won or defended in battle (or as if in
        battle); "they gained ground step by step"; "they fought
        to regain the lost ground"
     6: the part of a scene (or picture) that lies behind objects in
        the foreground; "he posed her against a background of
        rolling hills" [syn: {background}]
     7: material in the top layer of the surface of the earth in
        which plants can grow (especially with reference to its
        quality or use); "the land had never been plowed"; "good
        agricultural soil" [syn: {land}, {soil}]
     8: a relatively homogeneous percept extending back of the
        figure on which attention is focused [ant: {figure}]
     9: a connection between an electrical device and the earth
        (which is a zero voltage) [syn: {earth}]
     10: (art) the surface (as a wall or canvas) prepared to take the
         paint for a painting
     11: the first or preliminary coat of paint or size applied to a
         surface [syn: {flat coat}, {primer}, {priming}, {primer
         coat}, {priming coat}, {undercoat}]
     v 1: fix firmly and stably; "anchor the lamppost in concrete"
          [syn: {anchor}]
     2: confine or restrict to the ground; "After the accident, they
        grounded the plane and the pilot"
     3: place or put on the ground
     4: instruct someone in the fundamentals of a subject
     5: bring to the ground; "the storm grounded the ship" [syn: {run
        aground}]
     6: hit or reach the ground [syn: {run aground}]
     7: throw to the ground in order to stop play and avoid being
        tackled behind the line of scrimmage
     8: hit a groundball; "he grounded to the second baseman"
     9: hit onto the ground
     10: cover with a primer; apply a primer to [syn: {prime}, {undercoat}]
     11: connect to a ground; "ground the electrical connections for
         safety reasons"
     12: use as a basis for; found on; "base a claim on some
         observation" [syn: {establish}, {base}, {found}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
