<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>guardian</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guardian</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guardian \Guard"i*an\, n. [OF. guardain, gardien, F. gardien,
   LL. guardianus. See {Guard}, v. t., and cf. {Wasden}.]
   1. One who guards, preserves, or secures; one to whom any
      person or thing is committed for protection, security, or
      preservation from injury; a warden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) One who has, or is entitled to, the custody of the
      person or property of an infant, a minor without living
      parents, or a person incapable of managing his own
      affairs.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of the several species of guardians, the first are
            guardians by nature. -- viz., the father and (in
            some cases) the mother of the child.  --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Guardian ad litem}(Law), a guardian appointed by a court of
      justice to conduct a particular suit.

   {Guardians of the poor}, the members of a board appointed or
      elected to care for the relief of the poor within a
      township, or district.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guardian</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guardian \Guard"i*an\ (g[aum]rd"[i^]*an or g[aum]rd"yan; 106),
   a.
   Performing, or appropriate to, the office of a protector; as,
   a guardian care.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Feast of Guardian Angels} (R. C. Ch.) a church festival
      instituted by Pope Paul V., and celebrated on October 2d.
      

   {Guardian angel}.
   (a) The particular spiritual being believed in some branches
       of the Christian church to have guardianship and
       protection of each human being from birth.
   (b) Hence, a protector or defender in general. --O. W.
       Holmes.

   {Guardian spirit}, in the belief of many pagan nations, a
      spirit, often of a deceased relative or friend, that
      presides over the interests of a household, a city, or a
      region.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guardian</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>guardian
     adj : providing protective supervision; watching over or
           safeguarding; "daycare that is educational and not just
           custodial"; "a guardian angel"; "tutelary gods" [syn: {custodial},
            {tutelary}, {tutelar}]
     n : a person who cares for persons or property [syn: {defender},
          {protector}, {shielder}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
