<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>guard</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guard
   (1.) Heb. tabbah (properly a "cook," and in a secondary sense
   "executioner," because this office fell to the lot of the cook
   in Eastern countries), the bodyguard of the kings of Egypt (Gen.
   37:36) and Babylon (2 Kings 25:8; Jer. 40:1; Dan. 2:14).
   
     (2.) Heb. rats, properly a "courier," one whose office was to
   run before the king's chariot (2 Sam. 15:1; 1 Kings 1:5). The
   couriers were also military guards (1 Sam. 22:17; 2 Kings
   10:25). They were probably the same who under David were called
   Pelethites (1 Kings 14:27; 2 Sam. 15:1).
   
     (3.) Heb. mishmereth, one who watches (Neh. 4:22), or a
   watch-station (7:3; 12:9; Job 7:12).
   
     In the New Testament (Mark 6:27) the Authorized Version
   renders the Greek _spekulator_ by "executioner," earlier English
   versions by "hangman," the Revised Version by "soldier of his
   guard." The word properly means a "pikeman" or "halberdier," of
   whom the bodyguard of kings and princes was composed. In Matt.
   27:65, 66; 28:11, the Authorized Version renders the Greek
   _kustodia_ by "watch," and the Revised Version by "guard," the
   Roman guard, which consisted of four soldiers, who were relieved
   every three hours (Acts 12:4). The "captain of the guard"
   mentioned Acts 28:16 was the commander of the Praetorian troops,
   whose duty it was to receive and take charge of all prisoners
   from the provinces.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>guard
     
        &lt;programming&gt; 1. In {functional programming}, a {Boolean}
        expression attached to a function definition specifying when
        (for what arguments) that definition is appropriate.
     
        2. In (parallel) {logic programming}, a Boolean expression
        which is used to select a {clause} from several alternative
        matching clauses.
     
        See {Guarded Horn Clauses}.
     
        3. In {parallel} languages, a {Boolean} expression which
        specifies when an message may be sent or received.
     
        (1995-05-09)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guard \Guard\ (g[aum]rd), v. i.
   To watch by way of caution or defense; to be cautious; to be
   in a state or position of defense or safety; as, careful
   persons guard against mistakes.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guard \Guard\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Guarded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Gurding}.] [OF. guarder, garder, warder, F. garder, fr. OHG.
   wart?n to be on the watch, await, G. marten. See {Ward}, v. &amp;
   n., and cf. {Guard}, n.]
   1. To protect from danger; to secure against surprise,
      attack, or injury; to keep in safety; to defend; to
      shelter; to shield from surprise or attack; to protect by
      attendance; to accompany for protection; to care for.
      [1913 Webster]

            For Heaven still guards the right.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To keep watch over, in order to prevent escape or restrain
      from acts of violence, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To protect the edge of, esp. with an ornamental border;
      hence, to face or ornament with lists, laces, etc.

            The body of your discourse is sometime guarded with
            fragments, and the guards are but slightly basted on
            neither.                              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To fasten by binding; to gird. [Obs.] --B. Jonson.

   Syn: To defend; protect; shield; keep; watch.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guard \Guard\, n. [OF. guarde, F. garde; of German origin; cf.
   OHG. wart, warto, one who watches, warta a watching, Goth.
   wardja watchman. See {Guard}, v. t.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. One who, or that which, guards from injury, danger,
      exposure, or attack; defense; protection.
      [1913 Webster]

            His greatness was no guard to bar heaven's shaft.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A man, or body of men, stationed to protect or control a
      person or position; a watch; a sentinel.
      [1913 Webster]

            The guard which kept the door of the king's house.
                                                  --Kings xiv.
                                                  27.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who has charge of a mail coach or a railway train; a
      conductor. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any fixture or attachment designed to protect or secure
      against injury, soiling, or defacement, theft or loss; as:
      (a) That part of a sword hilt which protects the hand.
      (b) Ornamental lace or hem protecting the edge of a
          garment.
      (c) A chain or cord for fastening a watch to one's person
          or dress.
      (d) A fence or rail to prevent falling from the deck of a
          vessel.
      (e) An extension of the deck of a vessel beyond the hull;
          esp., in side-wheel steam vessels, the framework of
          strong timbers, which curves out on each side beyond
          the paddle wheel, and protects it and the shaft
          against collision.
      (f) A plate of metal, beneath the stock, or the lock
          frame, of a gun or pistol, having a loop, called a
          bow, to protect the trigger.
      (g) (Bookbinding) An interleaved strip at the back, as in
          a scrap book, to guard against its breaking when
          filled.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. A posture of defense in fencing, and in bayonet and saber
      exercise.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An expression or admission intended to secure against
      objections or censure.
      [1913 Webster]

            They have expressed themselves with as few guards
            and restrictions as I.                --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Watch; heed; care; attention; as, to keep guard.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Zo["o]l.) The fibrous sheath which covers the phragmacone
      of the Belemnites.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Guard is often used adjectively or in combination; as,
         guard boat or guardboat; guardroom or guard room; guard
         duty.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Advanced guard}, {Coast guard}, etc. See under {Advanced},
      {Coast}, etc.

   {Grand guard} (Mil.), one of the posts of the second line
      belonging to a system of advance posts of an army.
      --Mahan.

   {Guard boat}.
      (a) A boat appointed to row the rounds among ships of war
          in a harbor, to see that their officers keep a good
          lookout.
      (b) A boat used by harbor authorities to enforce the
          observance of quarantine regulations.

   {Guard cells} (Bot.), the bordering cells of stomates; they
      are crescent-shaped and contain chlorophyll.

   {Guard chamber}, a guardroom.

   {Guard detail} (Mil.), men from a company regiment etc.,
      detailed for guard duty.

   {Guard duty} (Mil.), the duty of watching patrolling, etc.,
      performed by a sentinel or sentinels.

   {Guard lock} (Engin.), a tide lock at the mouth of a dock or
      basin.

   {Guard of honor} (Mil.), a guard appointed to receive or to
      accompany eminent persons.

   {Guard rail} (Railroads), a rail placed on the inside of a
      main rail, on bridges, at switches, etc., as a safeguard
      against derailment.

   {Guard ship}, a war vessel appointed to superintend the
      marine affairs in a harbor, and also, in the English
      service, to receive seamen till they can be distributed
      among their respective ships.

   {Life guard} (Mil.), a body of select troops attending the
      person of a prince or high officer.

   {Off one's guard}, in a careless state; inattentive;
      unsuspicious of danger.

   {On guard}, serving in the capacity of a guard; doing duty as
      a guard or sentinel; watching.

   {On one's guard}, in a watchful state; alert; vigilant.

   {To mount guard} (Mil.), to go on duty as a guard or
      sentinel.

   {To run the guard}, to pass the watch or sentinel without
      leave.

   Syn: Defense; shield; protection; safeguard; convoy; escort;
        care; attention; watch; heed.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>guard
     n 1: a person who keeps watch over something or someone
     2: the person who plays that position on a football team; "the
        left guard was injured on the play"
     3: a device designed to prevent injury [syn: {safety}, {safety
        device}]
     4: a posture of defence in boxing or fencing; "keep your guard
        up"
     5: the person who plays the position of guard on a basketball
        team
     6: a group of men who escort and protect some important person
        [syn: {bodyguard}]
     7: a precautionary measure warding off impending danger or
        damage or injury etc.; "he put an ice pack on the injury
        as a precaution"; "an insurance policy is a good
        safeguard"; "we let our guard down" [syn: {precaution}, {safeguard}]
     8: the duty of serving as a sentry; "he was on guard that
        night" [syn: {guard duty}, {sentry duty}, {sentry go}]
     9: a position on the line of scrimmage; "guards must be good
        blockers"
     10: a position on a basketball team
     v 1: to keep watch over; "there would be men guarding the horses"
     2: watch over or shield from danger or harm; protect; "guard my
        possessions while I'm away" [syn: {ward}]
     3: protect against a challenge or attack; "Hold that position
        behind the trees!"; "Hold the bridge against the enemy's
        attacks" [syn: {defend}, {hold}]
     4: take precautions in order to avoid some unwanted
        consequence; "guard against becoming too friendly with the
        staff"; "guard against infection"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
