<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>guarantee</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guarantee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guarantee \Guar`an*tee"\, n.; pl. {Guarantees}. [For guaranty,
   prob. influenced by words like assignee, lessee, etc. See
   {Guaranty}, and cf. {Warrantee}.]
   1. In law and common usage: A promise to answer for the
      payment of some debt, or the performance of some duty, in
      case of the failure of another person, who is, in the
      first instance, liable to such payment or performance; an
      engagement which secures or insures another against a
      contingency; a warranty; a security. Same as {Guaranty}.
      [1913 Webster]

            His interest seemed to be a guarantee for his zeal.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who binds himself to see an undertaking of another
      performed; a guarantor. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Guarantor is the correct form in this sense.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) The person to whom a guaranty is made; -- the
      correlative of guarantor.

   Syn: {Guarantee}, {Warranty.}

   Usage: A guarantee is an engagement that a certain act will
          be done or not done in future. A warranty is an
          engagement as to the qualities or title of a thing at
          the time of the engagement.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guarantee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Guarantee \Guar"an*tee`\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {guaranteed}; p,
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Guaranteeing}.] [From {Guarantee}, n.]
   In law and common usage: to undertake or engage for the
   payment of (a debt) or the performance of (a duty) by another
   person; to undertake to secure (a possession, right, claim,
   etc.) to another against a specified contingency, or in all
   events; to give a guarantee concerning; to engage, assure, or
   secure as a thing that may be depended on; to warrant; as, to
   guarantee the execution of a treaty.
   [1913 Webster]

         The United States shall guarantee to every State in
         this Union a republican form of government.
                                                  --Constitution
                                                  of the U. S.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>guarantee</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>guarantee
     n 1: a written assurance that some product or service will be
          provided or will meet certain specifications [syn: {warrant},
           {warrantee}, {warranty}]
     2: a pledge that something will happen or that something is
        true; "there is no guarantee that they are not lying"
     3: a collateral agreement to answer for the debt of another in
        case that person defaults [syn: {guaranty}]
     v 1: give surety or assume responsibility; "I vouch for the
          quality of my products" [syn: {vouch}]
     2: make certain of; "This nest egg will ensure a nice
        retirement for us"; "Preparation will guarantee success!"
        [syn: {ensure}, {insure}, {assure}, {secure}]
     3: promise to do or accomplish; "guarantee to free the
        prisoners" [syn: {undertake}]
     4: stand behind and guarantee the quality, accuracy, or
        condition of; "The dealer warrants all the cars he sells";
        "I warrant this information" [syn: {warrant}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
