<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>face</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>face</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Face
   means simply presence, as when it is recorded that Adam and Eve
   hid themselves from the "face [R.V., 'presence'] of the Lord
   God" (Gen. 3:8; comp. Ex. 33:14, 15, where the same Hebrew word
   is rendered "presence"). The "light of God's countenance" is his
   favour (Ps. 44:3; Dan. 9:17). "Face" signifies also anger,
   justice, severity (Gen. 16:6, 8; Ex. 2:15; Ps. 68:1; Rev. 6:16).
   To "provoke God to his face" (Isa. 65:3) is to sin against him
   openly.
   
     The Jews prayed with their faces toward the temple and
   Jerusalem (1 Kings 8:38, 44, 48; Dan. 6:10). To "see God's face"
   is to have access to him and to enjoy his favour (Ps. 17:15;
   27:8). This is the privilege of holy angels (Matt. 18:10; Luke
   1:19). The "face of Jesus Christ" (2 Cor. 4:6) is the office and
   person of Christ, the revealer of the glory of God (John 1:14,
   18).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>face</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Face \Face\ (f[=a]s), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Faced}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Facing}.]
   1. To meet in front; to oppose with firmness; to resist, or
      to meet for the purpose of stopping or opposing; to
      confront; to encounter; as, to face an enemy in the field
      of battle.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll face
            This tempest, and deserve the name of king.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To Confront impudently; to bully.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will neither be facednor braved.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To stand opposite to; to stand with the face or front
      toward; to front upon; as, the apartments of the general
      faced the park; some of the seats on the train faced
      backward.
      [1913 Webster]

            He gained also with his forces that part of Britain
            which faces Ireland.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cover in front, for ornament, protection, etc.; to put
      a facing upon; as, a building faced with marble.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To line near the edge, esp. with a different material; as,
      to face the front of a coat, or the bottom of a dress.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cover with better, or better appearing, material than
      the mass consists of, for purpose of deception, as the
      surface of a box of tea, a barrel of sugar, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mach.) To make the surface of (anything) flat or smooth;
      to dress the face of (a stone, a casting, etc.); esp., in
      turning, to shape or smooth the flat surface of, as
      distinguished from the cylindrical surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To cause to turn or present a face or front, as in a
      particular direction.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To face down}, to put down by bold or impudent opposition.
      ``He faced men down.'' --Prior.

   {To face (a thing) out}, to persist boldly or impudently in
      an assertion or in a line of conduct. ``That thinks with
      oaths to face the matter out.'' --Shak.

   {to face the music} to admit error and accept reprimand or
      punishment as a consequence for having failed or having
      done something wrong; to willingly experience an
      unpleasant situation out of a sense of duty or obligation;
      as, as soon as he broke the window with the football,
      Billy knew he would have to face the music.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>face</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Face \Face\ (f[=a]s), n. [F., from L. facies form, shape, face,
   perh. from facere to make (see {Fact}); or perh. orig.
   meaning appearance, and from a root meaning to shine, and
   akin to E. fancy. Cf. {Facetious}.]
   1. The exterior form or appearance of anything; that part
      which presents itself to the view; especially, the front
      or upper part or surface; that which particularly offers
      itself to the view of a spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

            A mist . . . watered the whole face of the ground.
                                                  --Gen. ii. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lake Leman wooes me with its crystal face. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That part of a body, having several sides, which may be
      seen from one point, or which is presented toward a
      certain direction; one of the bounding planes of a solid;
      as, a cube has six faces.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.)
      (a) The principal dressed surface of a plate, disk, or
          pulley; the principal flat surface of a part or
          object.
      (b) That part of the acting surface of a cog in a cog
          wheel, which projects beyond the pitch line.
      (c) The width of a pulley, or the length of a cog from end
          to end; as, a pulley or cog wheel of ten inches face.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Print.)
      (a) The upper surface, or the character upon the surface,
          of a type, plate, etc.
      (b) The style or cut of a type or font of type.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. Outside appearance; surface show; look; external aspect,
      whether natural, assumed, or acquired.
      [1913 Webster]

            To set a face upon their own malignant design.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            This would produce a new face of things in Europe.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            We wear a face of joy, because
            We have been glad of yore.            --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That part of the head, esp. of man, in which the eyes,
      cheeks, nose, and mouth are situated; visage; countenance.
      [1913 Webster]

            In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread.
                                                  --Gen. iii.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Cast of features; expression of countenance; look; air;
      appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            We set the best faceon it we could.   --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Astrol.) Ten degrees in extent of a sign of the zodiac.
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Maintenance of the countenance free from abashment or
      confusion; confidence; boldness; shamelessness;
      effrontery.
      [1913 Webster]

            This is the man that has the face to charge others
            with false citations.                 --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Presence; sight; front; as in the phrases, before the
       face of, in the immediate presence of; in the face of,
       before, in, or against the front of; as, to fly in the
       face of danger; to the face of, directly to; from the
       face of, from the presence of.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Mode of regard, whether favorable or unfavorable; favor
       or anger; mostly in Scriptural phrases.
       [1913 Webster]

             The Lord make his face to shine upon thee. --Num.
                                                  vi. 25.
       [1913 Webster]

             My face [favor] will I turn also from them. --Ezek.
                                                  vii. 22.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Mining) The end or wall of the tunnel, drift, or
       excavation, at which work is progressing or was last
       done.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Com.) The exact amount expressed on a bill, note, bond,
       or other mercantile paper, without any addition for
       interest or reduction for discount; most commonly called
       {face value}. --McElrath.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Face is used either adjectively or as part of a
         compound; as, face guard or face-guard; face cloth;
         face plan or face-plan; face hammer.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Face ague} (Med.), a form of neuralgia, characterized by
      acute lancinating pains returning at intervals, and by
      twinges in certain parts of the face, producing convulsive
      twitches in the corresponding muscles; -- called also {tic
      douloureux}.

   {Face card}, one of a pack of playing cards on which a human
      face is represented; the king, queen, or jack.

   {Face cloth}, a cloth laid over the face of a corpse.

   {Face guard}, a mask with windows for the eyes, worn by
      workman exposed to great heat, or to flying particles of
      metal, stone, etc., as in glass works, foundries, etc.

   {Face hammer}, a hammer having a flat face.

   {Face joint} (Arch.), a joint in the face of a wall or other
      structure.

   {Face mite} (Zo["o]ll.), a small, elongated mite ({Demdex
      folliculorum}), parasitic in the hair follicles of the
      face.

   {Face mold}, the templet or pattern by which carpenters,
      etc., outline the forms which are to be cut out from
      boards, sheet metal, etc.

   {Face plate}.
       (a) (Turning) A plate attached to the spindle of a lathe,
           to which the work to be turned may be attached.
       (b) A covering plate for an object, to receive wear or
           shock.
       (c) A true plane for testing a dressed surface. --Knight.

   {Face wheel}. (Mach.)
       (a) A crown wheel.
       (b) A wheel whose disk face is adapted for grinding and
           polishing; a lap.

   {face value} the value written on a financial instrument;
      same as {face[13]}. Also used metaphorically, to mean
      apparent value; as, to take his statemnet at its face
      value.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cylinder face} (Steam Engine), the flat part of a steam
      cylinder on which a slide valve moves.

   {Face of an anvil}, its flat upper surface.

   {Face of a bastion} (Fort.), the part between the salient and
      the shoulder angle.

   {Face of coal} (Mining), the principal cleavage plane, at
      right angles to the stratification.

   {Face of a gun}, the surface of metal at the muzzle.

   {Face of a place} (Fort.), the front comprehended between the
      flanked angles of two neighboring bastions. --Wilhelm.

   {Face of a square} (Mil.), one of the sides of a battalion
      when formed in a square.

   {Face of a} {watch, clock, compass, card etc.}, the dial or
      graduated surface on which a pointer indicates the time of
      day, point of the compass, etc.

   {Face to face}.
       (a) In the presence of each other; as, to bring the
           accuser and the accused face to face.
       (b) Without the interposition of any body or substance.
           ``Now we see through a glass darkly; but then face to
           face.'' 1 --Cor. xiii. 12.
       (c) With the faces or finished surfaces turned inward or
           toward one another; vis [`a] vis; -- opposed to {back
           to back}.

   {To fly in the face of}, to defy; to brave; to withstand.

   {To make a face}, to distort the countenance; to make a
      grimace; -- often expressing dislike, annoyance, or
      disagreement. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>face</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Face \Face\, v. i.
   1. To carry a false appearance; to play the hypocrite. ``To
      lie, to face, to forge.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To turn the face; as, to face to the right or left.
      [1913 Webster]

            Face about, man; a soldier, and afraid! --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To present a face or front.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>face</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FACE
     Framed Access Command Environment (Unix, SVR4)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>face</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>face
     n 1: the front of the human head from the forehead to the chin
          and ear to ear; "he washed his face"; "I wish I had seen
          the look on his face when he got the news" [syn: {human
          face}]
     2: the expression on a person's face; "a sad expression"; "a
        look of triumph"; "an angry face" [syn: {expression}, {look},
         {aspect}, {facial expression}]
     3: the general outward appearance of something; "the face of
        the city is changing"
     4: the act of confronting bravely; "he hated facing the facts";
        "he excelled in the face of danger" [syn: {facing}]
     5: the striking or working surface of an implement
     6: a part of a person that is used to refer to a person; "he
        looked out at a roomful of faces"; "when he returned to
        work he met many new faces"
     7: a surface forming part of the outside of an object; "he
        examined all sides of the crystal"; "dew dripped from the
        face of the leaf" [syn: {side}]
     8: the part of an animal corresponding to the human face
     9: the side upon which the use of a thing depends (usually the
        most prominent surface of an object); "he dealt the cards
        face down"
     10: a contorted facial expression; "she made a grimace at the
         prospect" [syn: {grimace}]
     11: a specific size and style of type within a type family [syn:
          {font}, {fount}, {typeface}]
     12: status in the eyes of others; "he lost face"
     13: impudent aggressiveness; "I couldn't believe her boldness";
         "he had the effrontery to question my honesty" [syn: {boldness},
          {nerve}, {brass}, {cheek}]
     14: a vertical surface of a building or cliff
     v 1: deal with (something unpleasant) head on; "You must confront
          your problems"; "He faced the terrible consequences of
          his mistakes" [syn: {confront}, {face up}] [ant: {avoid}]
     2: oppose, as in hostility or a competition; "You must confront
        your opponent"; "Jackson faced Smith in the boxing ring";
        "The two enemies finally confronted each other" [syn: {confront}]
     3: be oriented in a certain direction, often with respect to
        another reference point; be opposite to; "The house looks
        north"; "My backyard look onto the pond"; "The building
        faces the park" [syn: {front}, {look}] [ant: {back}]
     4: be opposite; "the facing page"; "the two sofas face each
        other"
     5: turn so as to face; turn the face in a certain direction;
        "Turn and face your partner now"
     6: present somebody with something, usually to accuse or
        criticize; "We confronted him with the evidence"; "He was
        faced with all the evidence and could no longer deny his
        actions"; "An enormous dilemma faces us" [syn: {confront},
         {present}]
     7: turn so as to expose the face; "face a playing card"
     8: line the edge (of a garment) with a different material;
        "face the lapels of the jacket"
     9: cover the front or surface of; "The building was faced with
        beautiful stones"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
