<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>facing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>facing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Face \Face\ (f[=a]s), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Faced}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Facing}.]
   1. To meet in front; to oppose with firmness; to resist, or
      to meet for the purpose of stopping or opposing; to
      confront; to encounter; as, to face an enemy in the field
      of battle.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll face
            This tempest, and deserve the name of king.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To Confront impudently; to bully.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will neither be facednor braved.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To stand opposite to; to stand with the face or front
      toward; to front upon; as, the apartments of the general
      faced the park; some of the seats on the train faced
      backward.
      [1913 Webster]

            He gained also with his forces that part of Britain
            which faces Ireland.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cover in front, for ornament, protection, etc.; to put
      a facing upon; as, a building faced with marble.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To line near the edge, esp. with a different material; as,
      to face the front of a coat, or the bottom of a dress.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cover with better, or better appearing, material than
      the mass consists of, for purpose of deception, as the
      surface of a box of tea, a barrel of sugar, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mach.) To make the surface of (anything) flat or smooth;
      to dress the face of (a stone, a casting, etc.); esp., in
      turning, to shape or smooth the flat surface of, as
      distinguished from the cylindrical surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To cause to turn or present a face or front, as in a
      particular direction.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To face down}, to put down by bold or impudent opposition.
      ``He faced men down.'' --Prior.

   {To face (a thing) out}, to persist boldly or impudently in
      an assertion or in a line of conduct. ``That thinks with
      oaths to face the matter out.'' --Shak.

   {to face the music} to admit error and accept reprimand or
      punishment as a consequence for having failed or having
      done something wrong; to willingly experience an
      unpleasant situation out of a sense of duty or obligation;
      as, as soon as he broke the window with the football,
      Billy knew he would have to face the music.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>facing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Facing \Fa"cing\, n.
   1. A covering in front, for ornament or other purpose; an
      exterior covering or sheathing; as, the facing of an
      earthen slope, sea wall, etc., to strengthen it or to
      protect or adorn the exposed surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lining placed near the edge of a garment for ornament or
      protection.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.) The finishing of any face of a wall with material
      different from that of which it is chiefly composed, or
      the coating or material so used.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Founding) A powdered substance, as charcoal, bituminous
      coal, etc., applied to the face of a mold, or mixed with
      the sand that forms it, to give a fine smooth surface to
      the casting.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mil.)
      (a) pl. The collar and cuffs of a military coat; --
          commonly of a color different from that of the coat.
      (b) The movement of soldiers by turning on their heels to
          the right, left, or about; -- chiefly in the pl.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Facing brick}, front or pressed brick.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>facing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>facing
     n 1: a lining applied to the edge of a garment for ornamentation
          or strengthening
     2: an ornamental coating to a building [syn: {veneer}]
     3: a protective covering that protects the outside of a
        building [syn: {cladding}]
     4: providing something with a surface of a different material
        [syn: {lining}]
     5: the act of confronting bravely; "he hated facing the facts";
        "he excelled in the face of danger" [syn: {face}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
