<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fact</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fact</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FACT
     
        {Fully Automated Compiling Technique}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fact</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fact
     
        &lt;artificial intelligence, programming&gt; The kind of {clause}
        used in {logic programming} which has no {subgoals} and so is
        always true (always succeeds).  E.g.
     
        	wet(water).
        	male(denis).
     
        This is in contrast to a {rule} which only succeeds if all its
        subgoals do.  Rules usually contain {logic variables}, facts
        rarely do, except for oddities like "equal(X,X).".
     
        (1996-10-20)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fact</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fact \Fact\ (f[a^]kt), n. [L. factum, fr. facere to make or do.
   Cf. {Feat}, {Affair}, {Benefit}, {Defect}, {Fashion}, and
   {-fy}.]
   1. A doing, making, or preparing. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            A project for the fact and vending
            Of a new kind of fucus, paint for ladies. --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An effect produced or achieved; anything done or that
      comes to pass; an act; an event; a circumstance.
      [1913 Webster]

            What might instigate him to this devilish fact, I am
            not able to conjecture.               --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

            He who most excels in fact of arms.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Reality; actuality; truth; as, he, in fact, excelled all
      the rest; the fact is, he was beaten.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The assertion or statement of a thing done or existing;
      sometimes, even when false, improperly put, by a transfer
      of meaning, for the thing done, or supposed to be done; a
      thing supposed or asserted to be done; as, history abounds
      with false facts.
      [1913 Webster]

            I do not grant the fact.              --De Foe.
      [1913 Webster]

            This reasoning is founded upon a fact which is not
            true.                                 --Roger Long.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The term fact has in jurisprudence peculiar uses in
         contrast with law; as, attorney at law, and attorney in
         fact; issue in law, and issue in fact. There is also a
         grand distinction between law and fact with reference
         to the province of the judge and that of the jury, the
         latter generally determining the fact, the former the
         law. --Burrill --Bouvier.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Accessary before the fact}, or {Accessary after the fact}.
      See under {Accessary}.

   {Matter of fact}, an actual occurrence; a verity; used
      adjectively: of or pertaining to facts; prosaic;
      unimaginative; as, a matter-of-fact narration.

   Syn: Act; deed; performance; event; incident; occurrence;
        circumstance.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fact</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fact
     n 1: a piece of information about circumstances that exist or
          events that have occurred; "first you must collect all
          the facts of the case"
     2: a statement or assertion of verified information about
        something that is the case or has happened; "he supported
        his argument with an impressive array of facts"
     3: an event known to have happened or something known to have
        existed; "your fears have no basis in fact"; "how much of
        the story is fact and how much fiction is hard to tell"
     4: a concept whose truth can be proved; "scientific hypotheses
        are not facts"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
