<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>faculty</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>faculty</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Faculty \Fac"ul*ty\, n.; pl. {Faculties}. [F. facult?, L.
   facultas, fr. facilis easy (cf. facul easily), fr. fecere to
   make. See {Fact}, and cf. {Facility}.]
   1. Ability to act or perform, whether inborn or cultivated;
      capacity for any natural function; especially, an original
      mental power or capacity for any of the well-known classes
      of mental activity; psychical or soul capacity; capacity
      for any of the leading kinds of soul activity, as
      knowledge, feeling, volition; intellectual endowment or
      gift; power; as, faculties of the mind or the soul.
      [1913 Webster]

            But know that in the soul
            Are many lesser faculties that serve
            Reason as chief.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            What a piece of work is a man ! how noble in reason
            ! how infinite in faculty !           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Special mental endowment; characteristic knack.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had a ready faculty, indeed, of escaping from any
            topic that agitated his too sensitive and nervous
            temperament.                          --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Power; prerogative or attribute of office. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This Duncan
            Hath borne his faculties so meek.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Privilege or permission, granted by favor or indulgence,
      to do a particular thing; authority; license;
      dispensation.
      [1913 Webster]

            The pope . . . granted him a faculty to set him free
            from his promise.                     --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            It had not only faculty to inspect all bishops'
            dioceses, but to change what laws and statutes they
            should think fit to alter among the colleges.
                                                  --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A body of a men to whom any specific right or privilege is
      granted; formerly, the graduates in any of the four
      departments of a university or college (Philosophy, Law,
      Medicine, or Theology), to whom was granted the right of
      teaching (profitendi or docendi) in the department in
      which they had studied; at present, the members of a
      profession itself; as, the medical faculty; the legal
      faculty, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Amer. Colleges) The body of person to whom are intrusted
      the government and instruction of a college or university,
      or of one of its departments; the president, professors,
      and tutors in a college.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Dean of faculty}. See under {Dean}.

   {Faculty of advocates}. (Scot.) See under {Advocate}.

   Syn: Talent; gift; endowment; dexterity; expertness;
        cleverness; readiness; ability; knack.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>faculty</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>faculty
     n 1: one of the inherent cognitive or perceptual powers of the
          mind [syn: {mental faculty}, {module}]
     2: the body of teachers and administrators at a school; "the
        dean addressed the letter to the entire staff of the
        university" [syn: {staff}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
