<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fan</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fan
   a winnowing shovel by which grain was thrown up against the wind
   that it might be cleansed from broken straw and chaff (Isa.
   30:24; Jer. 15:7; Matt. 3:12). (See {AGRICULTURE}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fan \Fan\ (f[a^]n), n. [AS. fann, fr. L. vannus fan, van for
   winnowing grain; cf. F. van. Cf. {Van} a winnowing machine,
   {Winnow}.]
   1. An instrument used for producing artificial currents of
      air, by the wafting or revolving motion of a broad
      surface; as:
      (a) An instrument for cooling the person, made of
          feathers, paper, silk, etc., and often mounted on
          sticks all turning about the same pivot, so as when
          opened to radiate from the center and assume the
          figure of a section of a circle.
      (b) (Mach.) Any revolving vane or vanes used for producing
          currents of air, in winnowing grain, blowing a fire,
          ventilation, etc., or for checking rapid motion by the
          resistance of the air; a fan blower; a fan wheel.
      (c) An instrument for winnowing grain, by moving which the
          grain is tossed and agitated, and the chaff is
          separated and blown away.
      (d) Something in the form of a fan when spread, as a
          peacock's tail, a window, etc.
      (e) A small vane or sail, used to keep the large sails of
          a smock windmill always in the direction of the wind.
          [1913 Webster]

                Clean provender, which hath been winnowed with
                the shovel and with the fan.      --Is. xxx. 24.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. That which produces effects analogous to those of a fan,
      as in exciting a flame, etc.; that which inflames,
      heightens, or strengthens; as, it served as a fan to the
      flame of his passion.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A quintain; -- from its form. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fan blower}, a wheel with vanes fixed on a rotating shaft
      inclosed in a case or chamber, to create a blast of air
      (fan blast) for forge purposes, or a current for draft and
      ventilation; a fanner.

   {Fan cricket} (Zo["o]l.), a mole cricket.

   {Fan light} (Arch.), a window over a door; -- so called from
      the semicircular form and radiating sash bars of those
      windows which are set in the circular heads of arched
      doorways.

   {Fan shell} (Zo["o]l.), any shell of the family
      {Pectinid[ae]}. See {Scallop}, n., 1.

   {Fan tracery} (Arch.), the decorative tracery on the surface
      of fan vaulting.

   {Fan vaulting} (Arch.), an elaborate system of vaulting, in
      which the ribs diverge somewhat like the rays of a fan, as
      in Henry VII.'s chapel in Westminster Abbey. It is
      peculiar to English Gothic.

   {Fan wheel}, the wheel of a fan blower.

   {Fan window}. Same as {Fan light} (above).

   {electric fan}. a fan having revolving blades for propelling
      air, powered by an electric motor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fan \Fan\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fanned}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Fanning}.] [Cf. OF. vanner, L. vannere. See {Fan}, n., {Van}
   a winnowing machine.]
   1. To move as with a fan.
      [1913 Webster]

            The air . . . fanned with unnumbered plumes.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cool and refresh, by moving the air with a fan; to blow
      the air on the face of with a fan.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To ventilate; to blow on; to affect by air put in motion.
      [1913 Webster]

            Calm as the breath which fans our eastern groves.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To winnow; to separate chaff from, and drive it away by a
      current of air; as, to fan wheat. --Jer. li. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To excite or stir up to activity, as a fan excites a
      flame; to stimulate; as, this conduct fanned the
      excitement of the populace.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fanning machine}, or {Fanning mill}, a machine for
      separating seed from chaff, etc., by a blast of air; a
      fanner.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fan n. Without qualification, indicates a fan of science fiction,
   especially one who goes to {con}s and tends to hang out with other fans.
   Many hackers are fans, so this term has been imported from fannish
   slang; however, unlike much fannish slang it is recognized by most
   non-fannish hackers. Among SF fans the plural is correctly `fen', but
   this usage is not automatic to hackers. "Laura reads the stuff
   occasionally but isn't really a fan."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fan
     n 1: a device for creating a current of air by movement of a
          surface or surfaces
     2: an enthusiastic devotee of sports [syn: {sports fan}]
     3: an ardent follower and admirer [syn: {buff}, {devotee}, {lover}]
     v 1: strike out (a batter), (of a pitcher)
     2: make (an emotion) fiercer; "fan hatred"
     3: agitate the air
     4: separate from chaff; "She stood there winnowing grain all
        day in the field" [syn: {winnow}]
     [also: {fanning}, {fanned}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
