<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fang</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fang \Fang\, n. [From {Fang}, v. t.; cf. AS. fang a taking,
   booty, G. fang.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) The tusk of an animal, by which the prey is
      seized and held or torn; a long pointed tooth; esp., one
      of the usually erectile, venomous teeth of serpents. Also,
      one of the falcers of a spider.
      [1913 Webster]

            Since I am a dog, beware my fangs.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any shoot or other thing by which hold is taken.
      [1913 Webster]

            The protuberant fangs of the yucca.   --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Anat.) The root, or one of the branches of the root, of a
      tooth. See {Tooth}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mining) A niche in the side of an adit or shaft, for an
      air course. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mech.) A projecting tooth or prong, as in a part of a
      lock, or the plate of a belt clamp, or the end of a tool,
      as a chisel, where it enters the handle.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.)
      (a) The valve of a pump box.
      (b) A bend or loop of a rope.
          [1913 Webster]

   {In a fang}, fast entangled.

   {To lose the fang}, said of a pump when the water has gone
      out; hence:

   {To fang a pump}, to supply it with the water necessary to
      make it operate. [Scot.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fang \Fang\ (f[a^]ng), v. t. [OE. fangen, fongen, fon (g orig.
   only in p. p. and imp. tense), AS. f[=o]n; akin to D. vangen,
   OHG. f[=a]han, G. fahen, fangen, Icel. f[=a], Sw. f[*a],
   f[*a]nga, Dan. fange, faae, Goth. fahan, and prob. to E.
   fair, peace, pact. Cf. {Fair}, a.]
   1. To catch; to seize, as with the teeth; to lay hold of; to
      gripe; to clutch. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He's in the law's clutches; you see he's fanged.
                                                  --J. Webster.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To enable to catch or tear; to furnish with fangs.
      ``Chariots fanged with scythes.'' --Philips.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fang
     n 1: a Bantu language spoken in Cameroon
     2: canine tooth of a carnivorous animal; used to seize and tear
        its prey
     3: hollow or grooved tooth of a venomous snake; used to inject
        its poison
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
