<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>faster</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>faster</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fast \Fast\, a. [Compar. {Faster}; superl. {Fastest}.] [OE.,
   firm, strong, not loose, AS. f[ae]st; akin to OS. fast, D.
   vast, OHG. fasti, festi, G. fest, Icel. fastr, Sw. &amp; Dan.
   fast, and perh. to E. fetter. The sense swift comes from the
   idea of keeping close to what is pursued; a Scandinavian use.
   Cf. {Fast}, adv., {Fast}, v., {Avast}.]
   1. Firmly fixed; closely adhering; made firm; not loose,
      unstable, or easily moved; immovable; as, to make fast the
      door.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is an order that keeps things fast. --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Firm against attack; fortified by nature or art;
      impregnable; strong.
      [1913 Webster]

            Outlaws . . . lurking in woods and fast places.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Firm in adherence; steadfast; not easily separated or
      alienated; faithful; as, a fast friend.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Permanent; not liable to fade by exposure to air or by
      washing; durable; lasting; as, fast colors.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Tenacious; retentive. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Roses, damask and red, are fast flowers of their
            smells.                               --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Not easily disturbed or broken; deep; sound.
      [1913 Webster]

            All this while in a most fast sleep.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Moving rapidly; quick in mition; rapid; swift; as, a fast
      horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Given to pleasure seeking; disregardful of restraint;
      reckless; wild; dissipated; dissolute; as, a fast man; a
      fast liver. --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. In such a condition, as to resilience, etc., as to make
      possible unusual rapidity of play or action; as, a fast
      racket, or tennis court; a fast track; a fast billiard
      table, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Fast and loose}, now cohering, now disjoined; inconstant,
      esp. in the phrases to play at fast and loose, to play
      fast and loose, to act with giddy or reckless inconstancy
      or in a tricky manner; to say one thing and do another.
      ``Play fast and loose with faith.'' --Shak.

   {Fast and loose pulleys} (Mach.), two pulleys placed side by
      side on a revolving shaft, which is driven from another
      shaft by a band, and arranged to disengage and re["e]ngage
      the machinery driven thereby. When the machinery is to be
      stopped, the band is transferred from the pulley fixed to
      the shaft to the pulley which revolves freely upon it, and
      vice versa.

   {Hard and fast} (Naut.), so completely aground as to be
      immovable.

   {To make fast} (Naut.), to make secure; to fasten firmly, as
      a vessel, a rope, or a door.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>faster</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Faster \Fast"er\, n.
   One who abstains from food.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>faster</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>faster
     adv : more quickly [syn: {quicker}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
