<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fat</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fat
   (Heb. heleb) denotes the richest part of the animal, or the
   fattest of the flock, in the account of Abel's sacrifice (Gen.
   4:4). It sometimes denotes the best of any production (Gen.
   45:18; Num. 18:12; Ps. 81:16; 147:47). The fat of sacrifices was
   to be burned (Lev. 3:9-11; 4:8; 7:3; 8:25; Num. 18:17. Comp. Ex.
   29:13-22; Lev. 3:3-5).
   
     It is used figuratively for a dull, stupid state of mind (Ps
   17:10).
   
     In Joel 2:24 the word is equivalent to "vat," a vessel. The
   hebrew word here thus rendered is elsewhere rendered "wine-fat"
   and "press-fat" (Hag. 2:16; Isa. 63:2).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FAT
     
        {File Allocation Table}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fat \Fat\, n. [See {Vat}, n.]
   1. A large tub, cistern, or vessel; a vat. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The fats shall overflow with wine and oil. --Joel
                                                  ii. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A measure of quantity, differing for different
      commodities. [Obs.] --Hebert.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fat \Fat\, a. [Compar. {Fatter}; superl. {Fattest}.] [AS.
   f[=ae]tt; akin to D. vet, G. fett, feist, Icel. feitr, Sw.
   fet, Dan. fed, and perh. to Gr. pi^dax spring, fountain,
   pidy`ein to gush forth, pi`wn fat, Skr. pi to swell.]
   1. Abounding with fat; as:
      (a) Fleshy; characterized by fatness; plump; corpulent;
          not lean; as, a fat man; a fat ox.
      (b) Oily; greasy; unctuous; rich; -- said of food.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Exhibiting the qualities of a fat animal; coarse; heavy;
      gross; dull; stupid.
      [1913 Webster]

            Making our western wits fat and mean. --Emerson.
      [1913 Webster]

            Make the heart of this people fat.    --Is. vi. 10.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fertile; productive; as, a fat soil; a fat pasture.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Rich; producing a large income; desirable; as, a fat
      benefice; a fat office; a fat job.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now parson of Troston, a fat living in Suffolk.
                                                  --Carlyle.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Abounding in riches; affluent; fortunate. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Persons grown fat and wealthy by long impostures.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Typog.) Of a character which enables the compositor to
      make large wages; -- said of matter containing blank,
      cuts, or many leads, etc.; as, a fat take; a fat page.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fat lute}, a mixture of pipe clay and oil for filling
      joints.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fat \Fat\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fatted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {atting}.] [OE. fatten, AS. f[=ae]ttian. See {Fat}, a., and
   cf. {Fatten}.]
   To make fat; to fatten; to make plump and fleshy with
   abundant food; as, to fat fowls or sheep.
   [1913 Webster]

         We fat all creatures else to fat us.     --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fat \Fat\, v. i.
   To grow fat, plump, and fleshy.
   [1913 Webster]

         An old ox fats as well, and is as good, as a young one.
                                                  --Mortimer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fat \Fat\, n.
   1. (Physiol. Chem.) An oily liquid or greasy substance making
      up the main bulk of the adipose tissue of animals, and
      widely distributed in the seeds of plants. See {Adipose
      tissue}, under {Adipose}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Animal fats are composed mainly of three distinct fats,
         tristearin, tripalmitin, and triolein, mixed in varying
         proportions. As olein is liquid at ordinary
         temperatures, while the other two fats are solid, it
         follows that the consistency or hardness of fats
         depends upon the relative proportion of the three
         individual fats. During the life of an animal, the fat
         is mainly in a liquid state in the fat cells, owing to
         the solubility of the two solid fats in the more liquid
         olein at the body temperature. Chemically, fats are
         composed of fatty acid, as stearic, palmitic, oleic,
         etc., united with glyceryl. In butter fat, olein and
         palmitin predominate, mixed with another fat
         characteristic of butter, butyrin. In the vegetable
         kingdom many other fats or glycerides are to be found,
         as myristin from nutmegs, a glyceride of lauric acid in
         the fat of the bay tree, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The best or richest productions; the best part; as, to
      live on the fat of the land.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Typog.) Work. containing much blank, or its equivalent,
      and, therefore, profitable to the compositor.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fat acid}. (Chem.) See {Sebacic acid}, under {Sebacic}.

   {Fat series}, {Fatty series} (Chem.), the series of the
      paraffine hydrocarbons and their derivatives; the marsh
      gas or methane series.

   {Natural fats} (Chem.), the group of oily substances of
      natural occurrence, as butter, lard, tallow, etc., as
      distinguished from certain fatlike substance of artificial
      production, as paraffin. Most natural fats are essentially
      mixtures of triglycerides of fatty acids.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FAT
     File Allocation Table (DOS)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fat
     adj 1: having much flesh (especially fat); "he hadn't remembered
            how fat she was" [ant: {thin}]
     2: having a relatively large diameter; "a fat rope"
     3: containing or composed of fat; "fatty food"; "fat tissue"
        [syn: {fatty}] [ant: {nonfat}]
     4: lucrative; "a juicy contract"; "a nice fat job" [syn: {juicy}]
     5: marked by great fruitfulness; "fertile farmland"; "a fat
        land"; "a productive vineyard"; "rich soil" [syn: {fertile},
         {productive}, {rich}]
     6: a chubby body; "the boy had a rounded face and fat cheeks"
        [syn: {rounded}]
     n 1: a soft greasy substance occurring in organic tissue and
          consisting of a mixture of lipids (mostly
          triglycerides); "pizza has too much fat"
     2: a kind of body tissue containing stored fat that serves as a
        source of energy; adipose tissue also cushions and
        insulates vital organs; "fatty tissue protected them from
        the severe cold" [syn: {adipose tissue}, {fatty tissue}]
     3: excess bodily weight; "she found fatness disgusting in
        herself as well as in others" [syn: {fatness}, {blubber},
        {avoirdupois}] [ant: {leanness}]
     v : make fat or plump; "We will plump out that poor starving
         child" [syn: {fatten}, {flesh out}, {fill out}, {plump},
         {plump out}, {fatten out}, {fatten up}]
     [also: {fatting}, {fatted}, {fattest}, {fatter}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
