<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>feature</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>feature</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>feature
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; 1. A good property or behaviour (as of a program).
        Whether it was intended or not is immaterial.
     
        2. An intended property or behaviour (as of a program).
        Whether it is good or not is immaterial (but if bad, it is
        also a {misfeature}).
     
        3. A surprising property or behaviour; in particular, one that
        is purposely inconsistent because it works better that way -
        such an inconsistency is therefore a {feature} and not a
        {bug}.  This kind of feature is sometimes called a {miswart}.
     
        4. A property or behaviour that is gratuitous or unnecessary,
        though perhaps also impressive or cute.  For example, one
        feature of {Common LISP}'s "format" function is the ability to
        print numbers in two different Roman-numeral formats (see
        {bells, whistles, and gongs}).
     
        5. A property or behaviour that was put in to help someone
        else but that happens to be in your way.
     
        6. A bug that has been documented.  To call something a
        feature sometimes means the author of the program did not
        consider the particular case, and that the program responded
        in a way that was unexpected but not strictly incorrect.  A
        standard joke is that a bug can be turned into a {feature}
        simply by documenting it (then theoretically no one can
        complain about it because it's in the manual), or even by
        simply declaring it to be good.  "That's not a bug, that's a
        feature!" is a common catch-phrase.  Apparently there is a
        Volkswagen Beetle in San Francisco whose license plate reads
        "FEATURE".
     
        See also {feetch feetch}, {creeping featurism}, {wart}, {green
        lightning}.
     
        The relationship among bugs, features, misfeatures, warts and
        miswarts might be clarified by the following hypothetical
        exchange between two hackers on an airliner:
     
        A: "This seat doesn't recline."
     
        B: "That's not a bug, that's a feature.  There is an emergency
        exit door built around the window behind you, and the route
        has to be kept clear."
     
        A: "Oh.  Then it's a misfeature; they should have increased
        the spacing between rows here."
     
        B: "Yes.  But if they'd increased spacing in only one section
        it would have been a wart - they would've had to make
        nonstandard-length ceiling panels to fit over the displaced
        seats."
     
        A: "A miswart, actually.  If they increased spacing throughout
        they'd lose several rows and a chunk out of the profit margin.
        So unequal spacing would actually be the Right Thing."
     
        B: "Indeed."
     
        "Undocumented feature" is a common euphemism for a {bug}.
     
        7. An attribute or function of a {class} in {Eiffel}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-10-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>feature</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Feature \Fea"ture\ (?; 135), n. [OE. feture form, shape,
   feature, OF. faiture fashion, make, fr. L. factura a making,
   formation, fr. facere, factum, to make. See {Feat}, {Fact},
   and cf. {Facture}.]
   1. The make, form, or outward appearance of a person; the
      whole turn or style of the body; esp., good appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            What needeth it his feature to descrive? --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cheated of feature by dissembling nature. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The make, cast, or appearance of the human face, and
      especially of any single part of the face; a lineament.
      (pl.) The face, the countenance.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is for homely features to keep home. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The cast or structure of anything, or of any part of a
      thing, as of a landscape, a picture, a treaty, or an
      essay; any marked peculiarity or characteristic; as, one
      of the features of the landscape.
      [1913 Webster]

            And to her service bind each living creature
            Through secret understanding of their feature.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A form; a shape. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            So scented the grim feature, and upturned
            His nostril wide into the murky air.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>feature</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>feature n. 1. [common] A good property or behavior (as of a program).
   Whether it was intended or not is immaterial. 2. [common] An intended
   property or behavior (as of a program). Whether it is good or not is
   immaterial (but if bad, it is also a {misfeature}). 3. A surprising
   property or behavior; in particular, one that is purposely inconsistent
   because it works better that way -- such an inconsistency is therefore a
   {feature} and not a {bug}. This kind of feature is sometimes called a
   {miswart}; see that entry for a classic example. 4. A property or
   behavior that is gratuitous or unnecessary, though perhaps also
   impressive or cute. For example, one feature of Common LISP's `format'
   function is the ability to print numbers in two different Roman-numeral
   formats (see {bells whistles and gongs}). 5. A property or behavior that
   was put in to help someone else but that happens to be in your way. 6.
   [common] A bug that has been documented. To call something a feature
   sometimes means the author of the program did not consider the
   particular case, and that the program responded in a way that was
   unexpected but not strictly incorrect. A standard joke is that a bug can
   be turned into a {feature} simply by documenting it (then theoretically
   no one can complain about it because it's in the manual), or even by
   simply declaring it to be good. "That's not a bug, that's a feature!" is
   a common catchphrase. See also {feetch feetch}, {creeping featurism},
   {wart}, {green lightning}.

   The relationship among bugs, features, misfeatures, warts, and
   miswarts might be clarified by the following hypothetical exchange
   between two hackers on an airliner:

   A: "This seat doesn't recline."

   B: "That's not a bug, that's a feature. There is an emergency exit
   door built around the window behind you, and the route has to be kept
   clear."

   A: "Oh. Then it's a misfeature; they should have increased the spacing
   between rows here."

   B: "Yes. But if they'd increased spacing in only one section it would
   have been a wart -- they would've had to make nonstandard-length ceiling
   panels to fit over the displaced seats."

   A: "A miswart, actually. If they increased spacing throughout they'd
   lose several rows and a chunk out of the profit margin. So unequal
   spacing would actually be the Right Thing."

   B: "Indeed."

   `Undocumented feature' is a common, allegedly humorous euphemism for a
   {bug}. There's a related joke that is sometimes referred to as the
   "one-question geek test". You say to someone "I saw a Volkswagen Beetle
   today with a vanity license plate that read FEATURE". If he/she laughs,
   he/she is a {geek}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>feature</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>feature
     n 1: a prominent aspect of something; "the map showed roads and
          other features"; "generosity is one of his best
          characteristics" [syn: {characteristic}]
     2: the characteristic parts of a person's face: eyes and nose
        and mouth and chin; "an expression of pleasure crossed his
        features"; "his lineaments were very regular" [syn: {lineament}]
     3: the principal (full-length) film in a program at a movie
        theater; "the feature tonight is `Casablanca'" [syn: {feature
        film}]
     4: a special or prominent article in a newspaper or magazine;
        "they ran a feature on retirement planning" [syn: {feature
        article}]
     5: an article of merchandise that is displayed or advertised
        more than other articles
     v 1: have as a feature; "This restaurant features the most famous
          chefs in France" [syn: {have}] [ant: {miss}]
     2: wear or display in an ostentatious or proud manner; "she was
        sporting a new hat" [syn: {sport}, {boast}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
