<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>female</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>female</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FEMALE, n.  One of the opposing, or unfair, sex.

    The Maker, at Creation's birth,
    With living things had stocked the earth.
    From elephants to bats and snails,
    They all were good, for all were males.
    But when the Devil came and saw
    He said:  "By Thine eternal law
    Of growth, maturity, decay,
    These all must quickly pass away
    And leave untenanted the earth
    Unless Thou dost establish birth" --
    Then tucked his head beneath his wing
    To laugh -- he had no sleeve -- the thing
    With deviltry did so accord,
    That he'd suggested to the Lord.
    The Master pondered this advice,
    Then shook and threw the fateful dice
    Wherewith all matters here below
    Are ordered, and observed the throw;
    Then bent His head in awful state,
    Confirming the decree of Fate.
    From every part of earth anew
    The conscious dust consenting flew,
    While rivers from their courses rolled
    To make it plastic for the mould.
    Enough collected (but no more,
    For niggard Nature hoards her store)
    He kneaded it to flexible clay,
    While Nick unseen threw some away.
    And then the various forms He cast,
    Gross organs first and finer last;
    No one at once evolved, but all
    By even touches grew and small
    Degrees advanced, till, shade by shade,
    To match all living things He'd made
    Females, complete in all their parts
    Except (His clay gave out) the hearts.
    "No matter," Satan cried; "with speed
    I'll fetch the very hearts they need" --
    So flew away and soon brought back
    The number needed, in a sack.
    That night earth range with sounds of strife --
    Ten million males each had a wife;
    That night sweet Peace her pinions spread
    O'er Hell -- ten million devils dead!
                                                                  G.J.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>female</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Female \Fe"male\, n. [OE. femel, femal, F. femelle, fr. L.
   femella, dim. of femina woman. See {Feminine}.]
   1. An individual of the sex which conceives and brings forth
      young, or (in a wider sense) which has an ovary and
      produces ova.
      [1913 Webster]

            The male and female of each living thing. --Drayton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) A plant which produces only that kind of
      reproductive organs which are capable of developing into
      fruit after impregnation or fertilization; a pistillate
      plant.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>female</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Female \Fe"male\, a.
   1. Belonging to the sex which conceives and gives birth to
      young, or (in a wider sense) which produces ova; not male.
      [1913 Webster]

            As patient as the female dove
            When that her golden couplets are disclosed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Belonging to an individual of the female sex;
      characteristic of woman; feminine; as, female tenderness.
      ``Female usurpation.'b8 --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            To the generous decision of a female mind, we owe
            the discovery of America.             --Belknap.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) Having pistils and no stamens; pistillate; or, in
      cryptogamous plants, capable of receiving fertilization.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Female rhymes} (Pros.), double rhymes, or rhymes (called in
      French feminine rhymes because they end in e weak, or
      feminine) in which two syllables, an accented and an
      unaccented one, correspond at the end of each line.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A rhyme, in which the final syllables only agree
         (strain, complain) is called a male rhyme; one in which
         the two final syllables of each verse agree, the last
         being short (motion, ocean), is called female. --Brande
         &amp; C.

   {Female screw}, the spiral-threaded cavity into which
      another, or male, screw turns. --Nicholson.

   {Female fern} (Bot.), a common species of fern with large
      decompound fronds ({Asplenium Filixf[ae]mina}), growing in
      many countries; lady fern.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The names male fern and female fern were anciently
         given to two common ferns; but it is now understood
         that neither has any sexual character.

   Syn: {Female}, {Feminine}.

   Usage: We apply female to the sex or individual, as opposed
          to male; also, to the distinctive belongings of women;
          as, female dress, female form, female character, etc.;
          feminine, to things appropriate to, or affected by,
          women; as, feminine studies, employments,
          accomplishments, etc. ``Female applies to sex rather
          than gender, and is a physiological rather than a
          grammatical term. Feminine applies to gender rather
          than sex, and is grammatical rather than
          physiological.'' --Latham.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>female</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>female
     adj 1: being the sex (of plant or animal) that produces
            fertilizable gametes (ova) from which offspring
            develop; "a female heir"; "female holly trees bear the
            berries" [ant: {androgynous}, {male}]
     2: characteristic of or peculiar to a woman; "female
        sensitiveness"; "female suffrage" [syn: {distaff}]
     3: for or composed of women or girls; "the female lead in the
        play"; "a female chorus"
     n 1: an animal that produces gametes (ova) that can be fertilized
          by male gametes (spermatozoa) [ant: {male}]
     2: a person who belongs to the sex that can have babies [syn: {female
        person}] [ant: {male}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
