<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fence</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fence
   (Heb. gader), Num. 22:24 (R.V.). Fences were constructions of
   unmortared stones, to protect gardens, vineyards, sheepfolds,
   etc. From various causes they were apt to bulge out and fall
   (Ps. 62:3). In Ps. 80:12, R.V. (see Isa. 5:5), the psalmist
   says, "Why hast thou broken down her fences?" Serpents delight
   to lurk in the crevices of such fences (Eccl. 10:8; comp. Amos
   5:19).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fence
     
        1. A sequence of one or more distinguished ({out-of-band})
        characters (or other data items), used to delimit a piece of
        data intended to be treated as a unit (the computer-science
        literature calls this a "sentinel").  The NUL (ASCII 0000000)
        character that terminates strings in C is a fence.  {Hex} FF
        is also (though slightly less frequently) used this way.  See
        {zigamorph}.
     
        2. An extra data value inserted in an array or other data
        structure in order to allow some normal test on the array's
        contents also to function as a termination test.  For example,
        a highly optimised routine for finding a value in an array
        might artificially place a copy of the value to be searched
        for after the last slot of the array, thus allowing the main
        search loop to search for the value without having to check at
        each pass whether the end of the array had been reached.
     
        3. [among users of optimising compilers] Any technique,
        usually exploiting knowledge about the compiler, that blocks
        certain optimisations.  Used when explicit mechanisms are not
        available or are overkill.  Typically a hack: "I call a dummy
        procedure there to force a flush of the optimiser's
        register-colouring info" can be expressed by the shorter
        "That's a fence procedure".
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1999-01-08)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fence, WI
  Zip code(s): 54120
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fence \Fence\ (f[e^]ns), n. [Abbrev. from defence.]
   1. That which fends off attack or danger; a defense; a
      protection; a cover; security; shield.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let us be backed with God and with the seas,
            Which he hath given for fence impregnable. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A fence betwixt us and the victor's wrath.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An inclosure about a field or other space, or about any
      object; especially, an inclosing structure of wood, iron,
      or other material, intended to prevent intrusion from
      without or straying from within.
      [1913 Webster]

            Leaps o'er the fence with ease into the fold.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In England a hedge, ditch, or wall, as well as a
         structure of boards, palings, or rails, is called a
         fence.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Locks) A projection on the bolt, which passes through the
      tumbler gates in locking and unlocking.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Self-defense by the use of the sword; the art and practice
      of fencing and sword play; hence, skill in debate and
      repartee. See {Fencing}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Enjoy your dear wit, and gay rhetoric,
            That hath so well been taught her dazzing fence.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of dauntless courage and consummate skill in fence.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A receiver of stolen goods, or a place where they are
      received. [Slang] --Mayhew.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fence month} (Forest Law), the month in which female deer
      are fawning, when hunting is prohibited. --Bullokar.

   {Fence roof}, a covering for defense. ``They fitted their
      shields close to one another in manner of a fence roof.''
      --Holland.

   {Fence time}, the breeding time of fish or game, when they
      should not be killed.

   {Rail fence}, a fence made of rails, sometimes supported by
      posts.

   {Ring fence}, a fence which encircles a large area, or a
      whole estate, within one inclosure.

   {Worm fence}, a zigzag fence composed of rails crossing one
      another at their ends; -- called also {snake fence}, or
      {Virginia rail fence}.

   {To be on the fence}, to be undecided or uncommitted in
      respect to two opposing parties or policies. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fence \Fence\, v. i.
   1. To make a defense; to guard one's self of anything, as
      against an attack; to give protection or security, as by a
      fence.
      [1913 Webster]

            Vice is the more stubborn as well as the more
            dangerous evil, and therefore, in the first place,
            to be fenced against.                 --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To practice the art of attack and defense with the sword
      or with the foil, esp. with the smallsword, using the
      point only.
      [1913 Webster]

            He will fence with his own shadow.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, to fight or dispute in the manner of fencers, that
      is, by thrusting, guarding, parrying, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            They fence and push, and, pushing, loudly roar;
            Their dewlaps and their sides are bat?ed in gore.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            As when a billow, blown against,
            Falls back, the voice with which I fenced
            A little ceased, but recommenced.     --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fence \Fence\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fenced} (f[e^]nst); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Fencing} (f[e^]n"s[i^]ng).]
   1. To fend off danger from; to give security to; to protect;
      to guard.
      [1913 Webster]

            To fence my ear against thy sorceries. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To inclose with a fence or other protection; to secure by
      an inclosure.
      [1913 Webster]

            O thou wall! . . . dive in the earth,
            And fence not Athens.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A sheepcote fenced about with olive trees. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fence the tables} (Scot. Church), to make a solemn
      address to those who present themselves to commune at the
      Lord's supper, on the feelings appropriate to the service,
      in order to hinder, so far as possible, those who are
      unworthy from approaching the table. --McCheyne.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fence n. 1. A sequence of one or more distinguished ({out-of-band})
   characters (or other data items), used to delimit a piece of data
   intended to be treated as a unit (the computer-science literature calls
   this a `sentinel'). The NUL (ASCII 0000000) character that terminates
   strings in C is a fence. Hex FF is also (though slightly less
   frequently) used this way. See {zigamorph}. 2. An extra data value
   inserted in an array or other data structure in order to allow some
   normal test on the array's contents also to function as a termination
   test. For example, a highly optimized routine for finding a value in an
   array might artificially place a copy of the value to be searched for
   after the last slot of the array, thus allowing the main search loop to
   search for the value without having to check at each pass whether the
   end of the array had been reached. 3. [among users of optimizing
   compilers] Any technique, usually exploiting knowledge about the
   compiler, that blocks certain optimizations. Used when explicit
   mechanisms are not available or are overkill. Typically a hack: "I call
   a dummy procedure there to force a flush of the optimizer's
   register-coloring info" can be expressed by the shorter "That's a fence
   procedure".


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fence
     n 1: a barrier that serves to enclose an area [syn: {fencing}]
     2: a dealer in stolen property
     v 1: enclose with a fence; "we fenced in our yard" [syn: {fence
          in}]
     2: receive stolen goods
     3: fight with fencing swords
     4: surround with a wall in order to fortify [syn: {wall}, {palisade},
         {fence in}, {surround}]
     5: have an argument about something [syn: {argue}, {contend}, {debate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
