<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fever</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fever</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fever
   (Deut. 28:22; Matt. 8:14; Mark 1:30; John 4:52; Acts 28:8), a
   burning heat, as the word so rendered denotes, which attends all
   febrile attacks. In all Eastern countries such diseases are very
   common. Peter's wife's mother is said to have suffered from a
   "great fever" (Luke 4:38), an instance of Luke's professional
   exactitude in describing disease. He adopts here the technical
   medical distinction, as in those times fevers were divided into
   the "great" and the "less."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fever</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fever \Fe"ver\ (f[=e]"v[~e]r), n. [OE. fever, fefer, AS. fefer,
   fefor, L. febris: cf. F. fi[`e]vre. Cf. {Febrile}.]
   1. (Med.) A diseased state of the system, marked by increased
      heat, acceleration of the pulse, and a general derangement
      of the functions, including usually, thirst and loss of
      appetite. Many diseases, of which fever is the most
      prominent symptom, are denominated fevers; as, typhoid
      fever; yellow fever.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Remitting fevers subside or abate at intervals;
         intermitting fevers intermit or entirely cease at
         intervals; continued or continual fevers neither remit
         nor intermit.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Excessive excitement of the passions in consequence of
      strong emotion; a condition of great excitement; as, this
      quarrel has set my blood in a fever.
      [1913 Webster]

            An envious fever
            Of pale and bloodless emulation.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            After life's fitful fever he sleeps well. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Brain fever}, {Continued fever}, etc. See under {Brain},
      {Continued}, etc.

   {Fever and ague}, a form of fever recurring in paroxysms
      which are preceded by chills. It is of malarial origin.

   {Fever blister} (Med.), a blister or vesicle often found
      about the mouth in febrile states; a variety of herpes.

   {Fever bush} (Bot.), the wild allspice or spice bush. See
      {Spicewood}.

   {Fever powder}. Same as {Jame's powder}.

   {Fever root} (Bot.), an American herb of the genus
      {Triosteum} ({Triosteum perfoliatum}); -- called also
      {feverwort} and {horse gentian}.

   {Fever sore}, a carious ulcer or necrosis. --Miner.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fever</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fever \Fe"ver\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fevered} (f[=e]"v[~e]rd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Fevering}.]
   To put into a fever; to affect with fever; as, a fevered lip.
   [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         The white hand of a lady fever thee.     --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fever</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fever
     n 1: a rise in the temperature of the body; frequently a symptom
          of infection [syn: {febrility}, {febricity}, {pyrexia},
          {feverishness}]
     2: intense nervous anticipation; "in a fever of resentment"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
