<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fig</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fig</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fig
   First mentioned in Gen. 3:7. The fig-tree is mentioned (Deut.
   8:8) as one of the valuable products of Palestine. It was a sign
   of peace and prosperity (1 Kings 4:25; Micah 4:4; Zech. 3:10).
   Figs were used medicinally (2 Kings 20:7), and pressed together
   and formed into "cakes" as articles of diet (1 Sam. 30:12; Jer.
   24:2).
   
     Our Lord's cursing the fig-tree near Bethany (Mark 11:13) has
   occasioned much perplexity from the circumstance, as mentioned
   by the evangelist, that "the time of figs was not yet." The
   explanation of the words, however, lies in the simple fact that
   the fruit of the fig-tree appears before the leaves, and hence
   that if the tree produced leaves it ought also to have had
   fruit. It ought to have had fruit if it had been true to its
   "pretensions," in showing its leaves at this particular season.
   "This tree, so to speak, vaunted itself to be in advance of all
   the other trees, challenged the passer-by that he should come
   and refresh himself with its fruit. Yet when the Lord accepted
   its challenge and drew near, it proved to be but as the others,
   without fruit as they; for indeed, as the evangelist observes,
   the time of figs had not yet arrived. Its fault, if one may use
   the word, lay in its pretensions, in its making a show to run
   before the rest when it did not so indeed" (Trench, Miracles).
   
     The fig-tree of Palestine (Ficus carica) produces two and
   sometimes three crops of figs in a year, (1) the bikkurah, or
   "early-ripe fig" (Micah 7:1; Isa. 28:4; Hos. 9:10, R.V.), which
   is ripe about the end of June, dropping off as soon as it is
   ripe (Nah. 3:12); (2) the kermus, or "summer fig," then begins
   to be formed, and is ripe about August; and (3) the pag (plural
   "green figs," Cant. 2:13; Gr. olynthos, Rev. 6:13, "the untimely
   fig"), or "winter fig," which ripens in sheltered spots in
   spring.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fig</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fig \Fig\ (f[i^]g), n. [F. figue the fruit of the tree, Pr.
   figa, fr. L. ficus fig tree, fig. Cf. {Fico}.]
   1. (Bot.) A small fruit tree ({Ficus Carica}) with large
      leaves, known from the remotest antiquity. It was probably
      native from Syria westward to the Canary Islands.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The fruit of a fig tree, which is of round or oblong
      shape, and of various colors.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The fruit of a fig tree is really the hollow end of a
         stem, and bears numerous achenia inside the cavity.
         Many species have little, hard, inedible figs, and in
         only a few does the fruit become soft and pulpy. The
         fruit of the cultivated varieties is much prized in its
         fresh state, and also when dried or preserved. See
         {Caprification}.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. A small piece of tobacco. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The value of a fig, practically nothing; a fico; -- used
      in scorn or contempt. ``A fig for Peter.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cochineal fig}. See {Conchineal fig}.

   {Fig dust}, a preparation of fine oatmeal for feeding caged
      birds.

   {Fig faun}, one of a class of rural deities or monsters
      supposed to live on figs. ``Therefore shall dragons dwell
      there with the fig fauns.'' --Jer. i. 39. (Douay version).

   {Fig gnat} (Zo["o]l.), a small fly said to be injurious to
      figs.

   {Fig leaf}, the leaf tree; hence, in allusion to the first
      clothing of Adam and Eve (Genesis iii.7), a covering for a
      thing that ought to be concealed; esp., an inadequate
      covering; a symbol for affected modesty.

   {Fig marigold} (Bot.), the name of several plants of the
      genus {Mesembryanthemum}, some of which are prized for the
      brilliancy and beauty of their flowers.

   {Fig tree} (Bot.), any tree of the genus {Ficus}, but
      especially {F. Carica} which produces the fig of commerce.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fig</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fig \Fig\, n.
   Figure; dress; array. [Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Were they all in full fig, the females with feathers on
         their heads, the males with chapeaux bras? --Prof.
                                                  Wilson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fig</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fig \Fig\, v. t. [See {Fico}, {Fig}, n.]
   1. To insult with a fico, or contemptuous motion. See {Fico}.
      [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            When Pistol lies, do this, and fig me like
            The bragging Spaniard.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put into the head of, as something useless o?
      contemptible. [Obs.] --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fig</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FIG
     Forth Interest Group (org., Forth)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fig</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fig
     n 1: a diagram or picture illustrating textual material; "the
          area covered can be seen from Figure 2" [syn: {figure}]
     2: Mediterranean tree widely cultivated for its edible fruit
        [syn: {common fig}, {common fig tree}, {Ficus carica}]
     3: a Libyan terrorist group organized in 1995 and aligned with
        al-Qaeda; seeks to radicalize the Libyan government;
        attempted to assassinate Qaddafi [syn: {Libyan Islamic
        Fighting Group}, {Al-Jama'a al-Islamiyyah al-Muqatilah
        bi-Libya}, {Libyan Fighting Group}, {Libyan Islamic Group}]
     4: fleshy sweet pear-shaped yellowish or purple multiple fruit
        eaten fresh or preserved or dried
     [also: {figging}, {figged}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
