<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>filing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>filing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>File \File\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Filed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Filing}.]
   1. To set in order; to arrange, or lay away, esp. as papers
      in a methodical manner for preservation and reverence; to
      place on file; to insert in its proper place in an
      arranged body of papers.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would have my several courses and my dishes well
            filed.                                --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring before a court or legislative body by presenting
      proper papers in a regular way; as, to file a petition or
      bill. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) To put upon the files or among the records of a
      court; to note on (a paper) the fact date of its reception
      in court.
      [1913 Webster]

            To file a paper, on the part of a party, is to place
            it in the official custody of the clerk. To file, on
            the part of the clerk, is to indorse upon the paper
            the date of its reception, and retain it in his
            office, subject to inspection by whomsoever it may
            concern.                              --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>filing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Filing \Fil"ing\, n.
   A fragment or particle rubbed off by the act of filing; as,
   iron filings.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>filing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>filing
     n 1: the entering of a legal document into the public record; "he
          filed a complaint"; "he filed his tax return"
     2: a fragment rubbed off by the use of a file
     3: the act of using a file (as in shaping or smoothing an
        object)
     4: preservation and methodical arrangement as of documents and
        papers etc.; "I have some filing to do"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
