<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>filling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>filling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fill \Fill\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Filled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Filling}.] [OE. fillen, fullen, AS. fyllan, fr. full full;
   akin to D. vullen, G. f["u]llen, Icel. fylla, Sw. fylla, Dan.
   fylde, Goth. fulljan. See {Full}, a.]
   1. To make full; to supply with as much as can be held or
      contained; to put or pour into, till no more can be
      received; to occupy the whole capacity of.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rain also filleth the pools.      --Ps. lxxxiv.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jesus saith unto them, Fill the waterpots with
            water. Anf they filled them up to the brim. --John
                                                  ii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To furnish an abudant supply to; to furnish with as mush
      as is desired or desirable; to occupy the whole of; to
      swarm in or overrun.
      [1913 Webster]

            And God blessed them, saying. Be fruitful, and
            multiply, and fill the waters in the seas. --Gen. i.
                                                  22.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Syrians filled the country.       --1 Kings xx.
                                                  27.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fill or supply fully with food; to feed; to satisfy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whence should we have so much bread in the
            wilderness, as to fillso great a multitude? --Matt.
                                                  xv. 33.
      [1913 Webster]

            Things that are sweet and fat are more filling.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To possess and perform the duties of; to officiate in, as
      an incumbent; to occupy; to hold; as, a king fills a
      throne; the president fills the office of chief
      magistrate; the speaker of the House fills the chair.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To supply with an incumbent; as, to fill an office or a
      vacancy. --A. Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.)
      (a) To press and dilate, as a sail; as, the wind filled
          the sails.
      (b) To trim (a yard) so that the wind shall blow on the
          after side of the sails.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. (Civil Engineering) To make an embankment in, or raise the
      level of (a low place), with earth or gravel.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fill in}, to insert; as, he filled in the figures.

   {To fill out}, to extend or enlarge to the desired limit; to
      make complete; as, to fill out a bill.

   {To fill up}, to make quite full; to fill to the brim or
      entirely; to occupy completely; to complete. ``The bliss
      that fills up all the mind.'' --Pope. ``And fill up that
      which is behind of the afflictions of Christ.'' --Col. i.
      24.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>filling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Filling \Fill"ing\, n.
   1. That which is used to fill a cavity or any empty space, or
      to supply a deficiency; as, filling for a cavity in a
      tooth, a depression in a roadbed, the space between
      exterior and interior walls of masonry, the pores of
      open-grained wood, the space between the outer and inner
      planks of a vessel, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The woof in woven fabrics.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Brewing) Prepared wort added to ale to cleanse it.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Back filling}. (Arch.) See under {Back}, a.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>filling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>filling
     n 1: any material that fills a space or container; "there was not
          enough fill for the trench" [syn: {fill}]
     2: flow into something (as a container)
     3: (dentistry) a dental appliance consisting of any of various
        substances (as metal or plastic) inserted into a prepared
        cavity in a tooth; "when he yawned I could see the gold
        fillings in his teeth"; "an informal British term for
        `filling' is `stopping'"
     4: a food mixture used to fill pastry or sandwiches etc.
     5: the yarn woven across the warp yarn in weaving [syn: {woof},
         {weft}, {pick}]
     6: the act of filling something
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
