<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fill</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fill \Fill\, n. [See {Thill}.]
   One of the thills or shafts of a carriage. --Mortimer.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Fill horse}, a thill horse. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fill \Fill\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Filled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Filling}.] [OE. fillen, fullen, AS. fyllan, fr. full full;
   akin to D. vullen, G. f["u]llen, Icel. fylla, Sw. fylla, Dan.
   fylde, Goth. fulljan. See {Full}, a.]
   1. To make full; to supply with as much as can be held or
      contained; to put or pour into, till no more can be
      received; to occupy the whole capacity of.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rain also filleth the pools.      --Ps. lxxxiv.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jesus saith unto them, Fill the waterpots with
            water. Anf they filled them up to the brim. --John
                                                  ii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To furnish an abudant supply to; to furnish with as mush
      as is desired or desirable; to occupy the whole of; to
      swarm in or overrun.
      [1913 Webster]

            And God blessed them, saying. Be fruitful, and
            multiply, and fill the waters in the seas. --Gen. i.
                                                  22.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Syrians filled the country.       --1 Kings xx.
                                                  27.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fill or supply fully with food; to feed; to satisfy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whence should we have so much bread in the
            wilderness, as to fillso great a multitude? --Matt.
                                                  xv. 33.
      [1913 Webster]

            Things that are sweet and fat are more filling.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To possess and perform the duties of; to officiate in, as
      an incumbent; to occupy; to hold; as, a king fills a
      throne; the president fills the office of chief
      magistrate; the speaker of the House fills the chair.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To supply with an incumbent; as, to fill an office or a
      vacancy. --A. Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.)
      (a) To press and dilate, as a sail; as, the wind filled
          the sails.
      (b) To trim (a yard) so that the wind shall blow on the
          after side of the sails.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. (Civil Engineering) To make an embankment in, or raise the
      level of (a low place), with earth or gravel.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fill in}, to insert; as, he filled in the figures.

   {To fill out}, to extend or enlarge to the desired limit; to
      make complete; as, to fill out a bill.

   {To fill up}, to make quite full; to fill to the brim or
      entirely; to occupy completely; to complete. ``The bliss
      that fills up all the mind.'' --Pope. ``And fill up that
      which is behind of the afflictions of Christ.'' --Col. i.
      24.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fill \Fill\, v. i.
   1. To become full; to have the whole capacity occupied; to
      have an abundant supply; to be satiated; as, corn fills
      well in a warm season; the sail fills with the wind.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fill a cup or glass for drinking.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give me some wine; fill full.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To back and fill}. See under {Back}, v. i.

   {To fill up}, to grow or become quite full; as, the channel
      of the river fills up with sand.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fill \Fill\, n. [AS. fyllo. See {Fill}, v. t.]
   1. A full supply, as much as supplies want; as much as gives
      complete satisfaction. ``Ye shall eat your fill.'' --Lev.
      xxv. 19.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll bear thee hence, where I may weep my fill.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which fills; filling; filler; specif., an embankment,
      as in railroad construction, to fill a hollow or ravine;
      also, the place which is to be filled.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fill
     n 1: a quantity sufficient to satisfy; "he ate his fill of
          potatoes"; "she had heard her fill of gossip"
     2: any material that fills a space or container; "there was not
        enough fill for the trench" [syn: {filling}]
     v 1: make full, also in a metaphorical sense; "fill a container";
          "fill the child with pride" [syn: {fill up}, {make full}]
          [ant: {empty}]
     2: become full; "The pool slowly filled with water"; "The
        theater filled up slowly" [syn: {fill up}] [ant: {empty}]
     3: occupy the whole of; "The liquid fills the container" [syn:
        {occupy}]
     4: assume, as of positions or roles; "She took the job as
        director of development" [syn: {take}]
     5: fill or meet a want or need [syn: {meet}, {satisfy}, {fulfill},
         {fulfil}]
     6: appoint someone to (a position or a job)
     7: eat until one is sated; "He filled up on turkey" [syn: {fill
        up}]
     8: fill to satisfaction; "I am sated" [syn: {satiate}, {sate},
        {replete}]
     9: plug with a substance; "fill a cavity"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
