<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>film</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>film</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Film \Film\, v. t.
   1. To cover with a thin skin or pellicle.
      [1913 Webster]

            It will but skin and film the ulcerous place.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. to make a motion picture of (any event or literary work);
      to record with a movie camera; as, to film the
      inauguration ceremony; to film Dostoevsky's War and Peace.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>film</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Film \Film\, n. [AS. film skin, fr. fell skin; akin to fylmen
   membrane, OFries. filmene skin. See {Fell} skin.]
   1. A thin skin; a pellicle; a membranous covering, causing
      opacity.
      [1913 Webster]

            He from thick films shall purge the visual ray.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. hence, any thin layer covering a surface.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. A slender thread, as that of a cobweb.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her whip of cricket's bone, the lash of film.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Photog.) The layer, usually of gelatin or collodion,
      containing the sensitive salts of photographic plates.
      [PJC]

   5. (Photog.) a flexible sheet of celluloid or other plastic
      material to which a light-sensitive layer has been
      applied, used for recording images by the processes of
      photography. It is commonly used in rolls mounted within
      light-proof canisters suitable for simple insertion into
      cameras designed for such canisters. On such rolls,
      varying numbers of photographs may be taken before the
      canister needs to be replaced.
      [PJC]

   6. a motion picture.
      [PJC]

   7. the art of making motion pictures; -- used mostly in the
      phrase the film.
      [PJC]

   8. a thin transparent sheet of plastic, used for wrapping
      objects; as, polyethylene film.
      [PJC]

   {Celluloid film} (Photog.), a thin flexible sheet of
      celluloid, coated with a sensitized emulsion of gelatin,
      and used as a substitute for photographic plates.

   {Cut film} (Photog.), a celluloid film cut into pieces
      suitable for use in a camera.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>film</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>film
     n 1: a form of entertainment that enacts a story by a sequence of
          images giving the illusion of continuous movement; "they
          went to a movie every Saturday night"; "the film was
          shot on location" [syn: {movie}, {picture}, {moving
          picture}, {moving-picture show}, {motion picture}, {motion-picture
          show}, {picture show}, {pic}, {flick}]
     2: a medium that disseminates moving pictures; "theater pieces
        transferred to celluloid"; "this story would be good
        cinema"; "film coverage of sporting events" [syn: {cinema},
         {celluloid}]
     3: a thin coating or layer; "the table was covered with a film
        of dust"
     4: a thin sheet of (usually plastic and usually transparent)
        material used to wrap or cover things [syn: {plastic film}]
     5: photographic material consisting of a base of celluloid
        covered with a photographic emulsion; used to make
        negatives or transparencies [syn: {photographic film}]
     v 1: make a film or photograph of something; "take a scene";
          "shoot a movie" [syn: {shoot}, {take}]
     2: record in film; "The coronation was filmed"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
