<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fin \Fin\ (f[i^]n), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Finned}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Finning}.] [Cf. {Fin} of a fish.]
   To carve or cut up, as a chub.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fin \Fin\, n. [See {Fine}, n.]
   End; conclusion; object. [Obs.] ``She knew eke the fin of his
   intent.'' --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fin \Fin\, n.[OE. finne, fin, AS. finn; akin to D. vin, G. &amp;
   Dan. finne, Sw. fena, L. pinna, penna, a wing, feather. Cf.
   {pen} a feather.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) An organ of a fish, consisting of a membrane
      supported by rays, or little bony or cartilaginous
      ossicles, and serving to balance and propel it in the
      water.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Fishes move through the water chiefly by means of the
         caudal fin or tail, the principal office of the other
         fins being to balance or direct the body, though they
         are also, to a certain extent, employed in producing
         motion.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Zo["o]l.) A membranous, finlike, swimming organ, as in
      pteropod and heteropod mollusks.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A finlike organ or attachment; a part of an object or
      product which protrudes like a fin, as:
      (a) The hand. [Slang]
      (b) (Com.) A blade of whalebone. [Eng.] --McElrath.
      (c) (Mech.) A mark or ridge left on a casting at the
          junction of the parts of a mold.
      (d) (Mech.) The thin sheet of metal squeezed out between
          the collars of the rolls in the process of rolling.
          --Raymond.
      (e) (Mech.) A feather; a spline.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. A finlike appendage, as to submarine boats.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (A["e]ronautics) A fixed stabilizing surface, usually
      vertical, similar in purpose to a bilge keel on a ship.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Apidose fin}. (Zo["o]l.) See under {Adipose}, a.

   {Fin ray} (Anat.), one of the hornlike, cartilaginous, or
      bony, dermal rods which form the skeleton of the fins of
      fishes.

   {Fin whale} (Zo["o]l.), a finback.

   {Paired fins} (Zo["o]l.), the pectoral and ventral fins,
      corresponding to the fore and hind legs of the higher
      animals.

   {Unpaired fins}, or {Median fins} (Zo["o]l.), the dorsal,
      caudal, and anal fins.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fin
     n 1: the cardinal number that is the sum of four and one [syn: {five},
           {5}, {V}, {cinque}, {quint}, {quintet}, {fivesome}, {quintuplet},
           {pentad}, {Phoebe}, {Little Phoebe}]
     2: one of a pair of decorations projecting above the rear
        fenders of an automobile [syn: {tail fin}, {tailfin}]
     3: one of a set of parallel slats in a door or window to admit
        air and reject rain [syn: {louver}, {louvre}]
     4: a shoe for swimming; the paddle-like front is an aid in
        swimming (especially underwater) [syn: {flipper}, {flippers},
         {fins}]
     5: a stabilizer that resembles the fins of a fish
     6: organ of locomotion and balance in fishes and some other
        aquatic animals
     v 1: equip (a car) with fins
     2: propel oneself through the water in a finning motion
     3: show the fins above the water while swimming; "The sharks
        were finning near the surface" [syn: {break water}]
     [also: {finning}, {finned}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
