<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>final</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>final</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Final \Fi"nal\ (f[imac]"nal), a. [F., fr. L. finalis, fr. finis
   boundary, limit, end. See {Finish}.]
   1. Pertaining to the end or conclusion; last; terminating;
      ultimate; as, the final day of a school term.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet despair not of his final pardon.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Conclusive; decisive; as, a final judgment; the battle of
      Waterloo brought the contest to a final issue.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Respecting an end or object to be gained; respecting the
      purpose or ultimate end in view.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Final cause}. See under {Cause}.

   Syn: {Final}, {Conclusive}, {Ultimate}.

   Usage: Final is now appropriated to that which brings with it
          an end; as, a final adjustment; the final judgment,
          etc. Conclusive implies the closing of all discussion,
          negotiation, etc.; as, a conclusive argument or fact;
          a conclusive arrangement. In using ultimate, we have
          always reference to something earlier or proceeding;
          as when we say, a temporary reverse may lead to an
          ultimate triumph. The statements which a man finally
          makes at the close of a negotiation are usually
          conclusive as to his ultimate intentions and designs.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>final</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>final
     adj 1: occurring at or forming an end or termination; "his
            concluding words came as a surprise"; "the final
            chapter"; "the last days of the dinosaurs"; "terminal
            leave" [syn: {concluding}, {last}, {terminal}]
     2: conclusive in a process or progression; "the final answer";
        "a last resort"; "the net result" [syn: {last}, {net}]
     3: not to be altered or undone; "the judge's decision is
        final"; "the arbiter will have the last say" [syn: {last}]
     n 1: the final match between the winners of all previous matches
          in an elimination tournament
     2: an examination administered at the end of an academic term
        [syn: {final examination}, {final exam}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
