<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>finding</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Find \Find\ (f[imac]nd), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Found} (found); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Finding}.] [AS. findan; akin to D. vinden, OS.
   &amp; OHG. findan, G. finden, Dan. finde, icel. &amp; Sw. finna,
   Goth. fin[thorn]an; and perh. to L. petere to seek, Gr.
   pi`ptein to fall, Skr. pat to fall, fly, E. petition.]
   1. To meet with, or light upon, accidentally; to gain the
      first sight or knowledge of, as of something new, or
      unknown; hence, to fall in with, as a person.
      [1913 Webster]

            Searching the window for a flint, I found
            This paper, thus sealed up.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In woods and forests thou art found.  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To learn by experience or trial; to perceive; to
      experience; to discover by the intellect or the feelings;
      to detect; to feel. ``I find you passing gentle.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The torrid zone is now found habitable. --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To come upon by seeking; as, to find something lost.
      (a) To discover by sounding; as, to find bottom.
      (b) To discover by study or experiment direct to an object
          or end; as, water is found to be a compound substance.
      (c) To gain, as the object of desire or effort; as, to
          find leisure; to find means.
      (d) To attain to; to arrive at; to acquire.
          [1913 Webster]

                Seek, and ye shall find.          --Matt. vii.
                                                  7.
          [1913 Webster]

                Every mountain now hath found a tongue. --Byron.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. To provide for; to supply; to furnish; as, to find food
      for workemen; he finds his nephew in money.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wages [pounds]14 and all found.       --London
                                                  Times.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing a day and find yourself.      --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To arrive at, as a conclusion; to determine as true; to
      establish; as, to find a verdict; to find a true bill (of
      indictment) against an accused person.
      [1913 Webster]

            To find his title with some shows of truth. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To find out}, to detect (a thief); to discover (a secret) --
      to solve or unriddle (a parable or enigma); to understand.
      ``Canst thou by searching find out God?'' --Job. xi. 7.
      ``We do hope to find out all your tricks.'' --Milton.

   {To find fault with}, to blame; to censure.

   {To find one's self}, to be; to fare; -- often used in
      speaking of health; as, how do you find yourself this
      morning?
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Finding \Find"ing\, n.
   1. That which is found, come upon, or provided; esp. (pl.),
      that which a journeyman artisan finds or provides for
      himself; as tools, trimmings, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            When a man hath been laboring . . . in the deep
            mines of knowledge, hath furnished out his findings
            in all their equipage.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Support; maintenance; that which is provided for one;
      expence; provision.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) The result of a judicial examination or inquiry,
      especially into some matter of fact; a verdict; as, the
      finding of a jury. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

            After his friends finding and his rent. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>finding
     n 1: the act of determining the properties of something [syn: {determination}]
     2: the decision of a court on issues of fact or law
     3: something that is found; "the findings in the
        gastrointestinal tract indicate that he died several hours
        after dinner"; "an area rich in archaelogical findings"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
