<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>find</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>find</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Find \Find\ (f[imac]nd), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Found} (found); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Finding}.] [AS. findan; akin to D. vinden, OS.
   &amp; OHG. findan, G. finden, Dan. finde, icel. &amp; Sw. finna,
   Goth. fin[thorn]an; and perh. to L. petere to seek, Gr.
   pi`ptein to fall, Skr. pat to fall, fly, E. petition.]
   1. To meet with, or light upon, accidentally; to gain the
      first sight or knowledge of, as of something new, or
      unknown; hence, to fall in with, as a person.
      [1913 Webster]

            Searching the window for a flint, I found
            This paper, thus sealed up.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In woods and forests thou art found.  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To learn by experience or trial; to perceive; to
      experience; to discover by the intellect or the feelings;
      to detect; to feel. ``I find you passing gentle.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The torrid zone is now found habitable. --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To come upon by seeking; as, to find something lost.
      (a) To discover by sounding; as, to find bottom.
      (b) To discover by study or experiment direct to an object
          or end; as, water is found to be a compound substance.
      (c) To gain, as the object of desire or effort; as, to
          find leisure; to find means.
      (d) To attain to; to arrive at; to acquire.
          [1913 Webster]

                Seek, and ye shall find.          --Matt. vii.
                                                  7.
          [1913 Webster]

                Every mountain now hath found a tongue. --Byron.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. To provide for; to supply; to furnish; as, to find food
      for workemen; he finds his nephew in money.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wages [pounds]14 and all found.       --London
                                                  Times.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing a day and find yourself.      --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To arrive at, as a conclusion; to determine as true; to
      establish; as, to find a verdict; to find a true bill (of
      indictment) against an accused person.
      [1913 Webster]

            To find his title with some shows of truth. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To find out}, to detect (a thief); to discover (a secret) --
      to solve or unriddle (a parable or enigma); to understand.
      ``Canst thou by searching find out God?'' --Job. xi. 7.
      ``We do hope to find out all your tricks.'' --Milton.

   {To find fault with}, to blame; to censure.

   {To find one's self}, to be; to fare; -- often used in
      speaking of health; as, how do you find yourself this
      morning?
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>find</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Find \Find\, v. i. (Law)
   To determine an issue of fact, and to declare such a
   determination to a court; as, the jury find for the
   plaintiff. --Burrill.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>find</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Find \Find\, n.
   Anything found; a discovery of anything valuable; especially,
   a deposit, discovered by arch[ae]ologists, of objects of
   prehistoric or unknown origin.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>find</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>find
     n 1: a productive insight [syn: {discovery}, {breakthrough}]
     2: the act of discovering something [syn: {discovery}, {uncovering}]
     v 1: come upon, as if by accident; meet with; "We find this idea
          in Plato"; "I happened upon the most wonderful bakery
          not very far from here"; "She chanced upon an
          interesting book in the bookstore the other day" [syn: {happen},
           {chance}, {bump}, {encounter}]
     2: discover or determine the existence, presence, or fact of;
        "She detected high levels of lead in her drinking water";
        "We found traces of lead in the paint" [syn: {detect}, {observe},
         {discover}, {notice}]
     3: come upon after searching; find the location of something
        that was missed or lost; "Did you find your glasses?"; "I
        cannot find my gloves!" [syn: {regain}] [ant: {lose}]
     4: after a calculation, investigation, experiment, survey, or
        study; "find the product of two numbers"; "The physicist
        who found the elusive particle won the Nobel Prize" [syn:
        {determine}, {find out}, {ascertain}]
     5: come to believe on the basis of emotion, intuitions, or
        indefinite grounds; "I feel that he doesn't like me"; "I
        find him to be obnoxious"; "I found the movie rather
        entertaining" [syn: {feel}]
     6: perceive or be contemporaneous with; "We found Republicans
        winning the offices"; "You'll see a lot of cheating in
        this school"; "I want to see results"; "The 1960 saw the
        rebellion of the younger generation against established
        traditions"; "I want to see results" [syn: {witness}, {see}]
     7: get something or somebody for a specific purpose; "I found
        this gadget that will serve as a bottle opener"; "I got
        hold of these tools to fix our plumbing"; "The chairman
        got hold of a secretary on Friday night to type the urgent
        letter" [syn: {line up}, {get hold}, {come up}]
     8: make a discovery, make a new finding; "Roentgen discovered
        X-rays"; "Physicists believe they found a new elementary
        particle" [syn: {discover}]
     9: make a discovery; "She found that he had lied to her"; "The
        story is false, so far as I can discover" [syn: {discover}]
     10: obtain through effort or management; "She found the time and
         energy to take care of her aging parents"; "We found the
         money to send our sons to college"
     11: decide on and make a declaration about; "find someone
         guilty" [syn: {rule}]
     12: receive a specified treatment (abstract); "These aspects of
         civilization do not find expression or receive an
         interpretation"; "His movie received a good review"; "I
         got nothing but trouble for my good intentions" [syn: {receive},
          {get}, {obtain}, {incur}]
     13: perceive oneself to be in a certain condition or place; "I
         found myself in a difficult situation"; "When he woke up,
         he found himself in a hospital room"
     14: get or find back; recover the use of; "She regained control
         of herself"; "She found her voice and replied quickly"
         [syn: {recover}, {retrieve}, {regain}]
     15: succeed in reaching; arrive at; "The arrrow found its mark"
     16: accept and make use of one's personality, abilities, and
         situation; "My son went to Berkeley to find himself"
         [syn: {find oneself}]
     [also: {found}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
