<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fingerprint</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fingerprint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fingerprint \Fin"ger*print\, n. [Finger + print.]
   1. an impression of the pattern of ridges on the skin of the
      last joint of a person's finger, left on a surface after a
      person has touched the surface.

   Note: Fingerprints left by persons who have committed crimes
         are considered as reliable physical evidence linking an
         individual with a crime, because each person's
         fingerprints are distinctively different from those of
         others, allowing identification of a person with high
         confidence.
         [PJC]

   2. a fingerprint[1] made intentionally in ink on a paper form
      for the purpose of identification of the individual.
      [PJC]

   3. any distinctive pattern of characteristics or properties
      of an object which can serve to identify that object; as,
      the distinctive fingerprint of eugenol in the mass
      spectrum allowed easy recognition of its presence in the
      sample.
      [PJC]

   4. a smudge made by a (dirty) finger. [WordNet sense 3]

   Syn: fingermark.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fingerprint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fingerprint \fin"ger*print\ v. t.
   to take an impression of the fingerprints of (a person); as,
   to fingerprint applicants for a gun permit.
   [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fingerprint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fingerprint
     n 1: biometric identification from a print made by an impression
          of the ridges in the skin of a finger; often used as
          evidence in criminal investigations
     2: a generic term for any identifying characteristic; "that tax
        bill had the senator's fingerprints all over it"
     3: a smudge made by a (dirty) finger [syn: {fingermark}]
     v : take an impression of a person's fingerprints
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
