<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>finger</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>finger
     
        &lt;tool&gt; A {Unix} program that displays information about a
        particular user or all users logged on the system, or a remote
        system.  Finger typically shows full name, last login time,
        idle time, terminal line, and terminal location (where
        applicable).  It may also display a {plan file} left by the
        user (see also {Hacking X for Y}).  Some versions take a "-l"
        (long) argument which yields more information.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2002-10-06)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Finger, TN (city, FIPS 26160)
  Location: 35.35474 N, 88.61548 W
  Population (1990): 279 (120 housing units)
  Area: 3.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 38334
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Finger \Fin"ger\ (f[i^][ng]"g[~e]r), n. [AS. finger; akin to D.
   vinger, OS. &amp; OHG. fingar, G. finger, Icel. fingr, Sw. &amp; Dan.
   finger, Goth. figgrs; of unknown origin; perh. akin to E.
   fang.]
   1. One of the five terminating members of the hand; a digit;
      esp., one of the four extremities of the hand, other than
      the thumb.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything that does the work of a finger; as, the pointer
      of a clock, watch, or other registering machine;
      especially (Mech.) a small projecting rod, wire, or piece,
      which is brought into contact with an object to effect,
      direct, or restrain a motion.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The breadth of a finger, or the fourth part of the hand; a
      measure of nearly an inch; also, the length of finger, a
      measure in domestic use in the United States, of about
      four and a half inches or one eighth of a yard.
      [1913 Webster]

            A piece of steel three fingers thick. --Bp. Wilkins.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Skill in the use of the fingers, as in playing upon a
      musical instrument. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            She has a good finger.                --Busby.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ear finger}, the little finger.

   {Finger alphabet}. See {Dactylology}.

   {Finger bar}, the horizontal bar, carrying slotted spikes, or
      fingers, through which the vibratory knives of mowing and
      reaping machines play.

   {Finger board} (Mus.), the part of a stringed instrument
      against which the fingers press the strings to vary the
      tone; the keyboard of a piano, organ, etc.; manual.

   {Finger bowl} {Finger glass}, a bowl or glass to hold water
      for rinsing the fingers at table.

   {Finger flower} (Bot.), the foxglove.

   {Finger grass} (Bot.), a kind of grass ({Panicum sanguinale})
      with slender radiating spikes; common crab grass. See
      {Crab grass}, under {Crab}.

   {Finger nut}, a fly nut or thumb nut.

   {Finger plate}, a strip of metal, glass, etc., to protect a
      painted or polished door from finger marks.

   {Finger post}, a guide post bearing an index finger.

   {Finger reading}, reading printed in relief so as to be
      sensible to the touch; -- so made for the blind.

   {Finger shell} (Zo["o]l.), a marine shell ({Pholas dactylus})
      resembling a finger in form.

   {Finger sponge} (Zo["o]l.), a sponge having finger-shaped
      lobes, or branches.

   {Finger stall}, a cover or shield for a finger.

   {Finger steel}, a steel instrument for whetting a currier's
      knife.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To burn one's fingers}. See under {Burn}.

   {To have a finger in}, to be concerned in. [Colloq.]

   {To have at one's fingers' ends}, to be thoroughly familiar
      with. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Finger \Fin"ger\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fingered}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Fingering}.]
   1. To touch with the fingers; to handle; to meddle with.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let the papers lie;
            You would be fingering them to anger me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To touch lightly; to toy with.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.)
      (a) To perform on an instrument of music.
      (b) To mark the notes of (a piece of music) so as to guide
          the fingers in playing.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. To take thievishly; to pilfer; to purloin. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To execute, as any delicate work.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Finger \Fin"ger\, v. i. (Mus.)
   To use the fingers in playing on an instrument. --Busby.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>finger [WAITS, via BSD Unix] 1. n. A program that displays information
   about a particular user or all users logged on the system, or a remote
   system. Typically shows full name, last login time, idle time, terminal
   line, and terminal location (where applicable). May also display a {plan
   file} left by the user (see also {Hacking X for Y}). 2. vt. To apply
   finger to a username. 3. vt. By extension, to check a human's current
   state by any means. "Foodp?" "T!" "OK, finger Lisa and see if she's
   idle." 4. Any picture (composed of ASCII characters) depicting `the
   finger'. Originally a humorous component of one's plan file to deter the
   curious fingerer (sense 2), it has entered the arsenal of some
   {flamer}s.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>finger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>finger
     n 1: any of the terminal members of the hand (sometimes excepting
          the thumb); "her fingers were long and thin"
     2: the length of breadth of a finger used as a linear measure
        [syn: {fingerbreadth}, {finger's breadth}, {digit}]
     3: the part of a glove that provides a covering for one of the
        fingers
     v 1: feel or handle with the fingers; "finger the binding of the
          book" [syn: {thumb}]
     2: examine by touch; "Feel this soft cloth!"; "The customer
        fingered the sweater" [syn: {feel}]
     3: search for on the computer; "I fingered my boss and found
        that he is not logged on in the afternoons"
     4: indicate the fingering for the playing of musical scores for
        keyboard instruments
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
