<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fire</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fire
   (1.) For sacred purposes. The sacrifices were consumed by fire
   (Gen. 8:20). The ever-burning fire on the altar was first
   kindled from heaven (Lev. 6:9, 13; 9:24), and afterwards
   rekindled at the dedication of Solomon's temple (2 Chr. 7:1, 3).
   The expressions "fire from heaven" and "fire of the Lord"
   generally denote lightning, but sometimes also the fire of the
   altar was so called (Ex. 29:18; Lev. 1:9; 2:3; 3:5, 9).
   
     Fire for a sacred purpose obtained otherwise than from the
   altar was called "strange fire" (Lev. 10:1, 2; Num. 3:4).
   
     The victims slain for sin offerings were afterwards consumed
   by fire outside the camp (Lev. 4:12, 21; 6:30; 16:27; Heb.
   13:11).
   
     (2.) For domestic purposes, such as baking, cooking, warmth,
   etc. (Jer. 36:22; Mark 14:54; John 18:18). But on Sabbath no
   fire for any domestic purpose was to be kindled (Ex. 35:3; Num.
   15:32-36).
   
     (3.) Punishment of death by fire was inflicted on such as were
   guilty of certain forms of unchastity and incest (Lev. 20:14;
   21:9). The burning of captives in war was not unknown among the
   Jews (2 Sam. 12:31; Jer. 29:22). The bodies of infamous persons
   who were executed were also sometimes burned (Josh. 7:25; 2
   Kings 23:16).
   
     (4.) In war, fire was used in the destruction of cities, as
   Jericho (Josh. 6:24), Ai (8:19), Hazor (11:11), Laish (Judg.
   18:27), etc. The war-chariots of the Canaanites were burnt
   (Josh. 11:6, 9, 13). The Israelites burned the images (2 Kings
   10:26; R.V., "pillars") of the house of Baal. These objects of
   worship seem to have been of the nature of obelisks, and were
   sometimes evidently made of wood.
   
     Torches were sometimes carried by the soldiers in battle
   (Judg. 7:16).
   
     (5.) Figuratively, fire is a symbol of Jehovah's presence and
   the instrument of his power (Ex. 14:19; Num. 11:1, 3; Judg.
   13:20; 1 Kings 18:38; 2 Kings 1:10, 12; 2:11; Isa. 6:4; Ezek.
   1:4; Rev. 1:14, etc.).
   
     God's word is also likened unto fire (Jer. 23:29). It is
   referred to as an emblem of severe trials or misfortunes (Zech.
   12:6; Luke 12:49; 1 Cor. 3:13, 15; 1 Pet. 1:7), and of eternal
   punishment (Matt. 5:22; Mark 9:44; Rev. 14:10; 21:8).
   
     The influence of the Holy Ghost is likened unto fire (Matt.
   3:11). His descent was denoted by the appearance of tongues as
   of fire (Acts 2:3).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Command \Com*mand"\, n.
   1. An authoritative order requiring obedience; a mandate; an
      injunction.
      [1913 Webster]

            Awaiting what command their mighty chief
            Had to impose.                        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The possession or exercise of authority.
      [1913 Webster]

            Command and force may often create, but can never
            cure, an aversion.                    --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Authority; power or right of control; leadership; as, the
      forces under his command.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Power to dominate, command, or overlook by means of
      position; scope of vision; survey.
      [1913 Webster]

            The steepy stand
            Which overlooks the vale with wide command.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Control; power over something; sway; influence; as, to
      have command over one's temper or voice; the fort has
      command of the bridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            He assumed an absolute command over his readers.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A body of troops, or any naval or military force or post,
      or the whole territory under the authority or control of a
      particular officer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Word of command} (Mil.), a word or phrase of definite and
      established meaning, used in directing the movements of
      soldiers; as, {aim}; {fire}; {shoulder arms}, etc.

   Syn: Control; sway; power; authority; rule; dominion;
        sovereignty; mandate; order; injunction; charge; behest.
        See {Direction}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fire \Fire\ (f[imac]r), n. [OE. fir, fyr, fur AS. f[=y]r; akin
   to D. vuur, OS. &amp; OHG. fiur, G. feuer, Icel. f[=y]ri,
   f[=u]rr, Gr. py^r, and perh. to L. purus pure, E. pure Cf.
   {Empyrean}, {Pyre}.]
   1. The evolution of light and heat in the combustion of
      bodies; combustion; state of ignition.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The form of fire exhibited in the combustion of gases
         in an ascending stream or current is called flame.
         Anciently, fire, air, earth, and water were regarded as
         the four elements of which all things are composed.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Fuel in a state of combustion, as on a hearth, or in a
      stove or a furnace.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The burning of a house or town; a conflagration.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything which destroys or affects like fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Ardor of passion, whether love or hate; excessive warmth;
      consuming violence of temper.
      [1913 Webster]

            he had fire in his temper.            --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Liveliness of imagination or fancy; intellectual and moral
      enthusiasm; capacity for ardor and zeal.
      [1913 Webster]

            And bless their critic with a poet's fire. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Splendor; brilliancy; luster; hence, a star.
      [1913 Webster]

            Stars, hide your fires.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            As in a zodiac
            representing the heavenly fires.      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Torture by burning; severe trial or affliction.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The discharge of firearms; firing; as, the troops were
      exposed to a heavy fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Blue fire}, {Red fire}, {Green fire} (Pyrotech.),
      compositions of various combustible substances, as
      sulphur, niter, lampblack, etc., the flames of which are
      colored by various metallic salts, as those of antimony,
      strontium, barium, etc.

   {Fire alarm}
      (a) A signal given on the breaking out of a fire.
      (b) An apparatus for giving such an alarm.

   {Fire annihilator}, a machine, device, or preparation to be
      kept at hand for extinguishing fire by smothering it with
      some incombustible vapor or gas, as carbonic acid.

   {Fire balloon}.
      (a) A balloon raised in the air by the buoyancy of air
          heated by a fire placed in the lower part.
      (b) A balloon sent up at night with fireworks which ignite
          at a regulated height. --Simmonds.

   {Fire bar}, a grate bar.

   {Fire basket}, a portable grate; a cresset. --Knight.

   {Fire beetle}. (Zo["o]l.) See in the Vocabulary.

   {Fire blast}, a disease of plants which causes them to appear
      as if burnt by fire.

   {Fire box}, the chamber of a furnace, steam boiler, etc., for
      the fire.

   {Fire brick}, a refractory brick, capable of sustaining
      intense heat without fusion, usually made of fire clay or
      of siliceous material, with some cementing substance, and
      used for lining fire boxes, etc.

   {Fire brigade}, an organized body of men for extinguished
      fires.

   {Fire bucket}. See under {Bucket}.

   {Fire bug}, an incendiary; one who, from malice or through
      mania, persistently sets fire to property; a pyromaniac.
      [U.S.]

   {Fire clay}. See under {Clay}.

   {Fire company}, a company of men managing an engine in
      extinguishing fires.

   {Fire cross}. See {Fiery cross}. [Obs.] --Milton.

   {Fire damp}. See under {Damp}.

   {Fire dog}. See {Firedog}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Fire drill}.
      (a) A series of evolutions performed by fireman for
          practice.
      (b) An apparatus for producing fire by friction, by
          rapidly twirling a wooden pin in a wooden socket; --
          used by the Hindoos during all historic time, and by
          many savage peoples.

   {Fire eater}.
      (a) A juggler who pretends to eat fire.
      (b) A quarrelsome person who seeks affrays; a hotspur.
          [Colloq.]

   {Fire engine}, a portable forcing pump, usually on wheels,
      for throwing water to extinguish fire.

   {Fire escape}, a contrivance for facilitating escape from
      burning buildings.

   {Fire gilding} (Fine Arts), a mode of gilding with an amalgam
      of gold and quicksilver, the latter metal being driven off
      afterward by heat.

   {Fire gilt} (Fine Arts), gold laid on by the process of fire
      gilding.

   {Fire insurance}, the act or system of insuring against fire;
      also, a contract by which an insurance company undertakes,
      in consideration of the payment of a premium or small
      percentage -- usually made periodically -- to indemnify an
      owner of property from loss by fire during a specified
      period.

   {Fire irons}, utensils for a fireplace or grate, as tongs,
      poker, and shovel.

   {Fire main}, a pipe for water, to be used in putting out
      fire.

   {Fire master}
      (Mil), an artillery officer who formerly supervised the
            composition of fireworks.

   {Fire office}, an office at which to effect insurance against
      fire.

   {Fire opal}, a variety of opal giving firelike reflections.
      

   {Fire ordeal}, an ancient mode of trial, in which the test
      was the ability of the accused to handle or tread upon
      red-hot irons. --Abbot.

   {Fire pan}, a pan for holding or conveying fire, especially
      the receptacle for the priming of a gun.

   {Fire plug}, a plug or hydrant for drawing water from the
      main pipes in a street, building, etc., for extinguishing
      fires.

   {Fire policy}, the writing or instrument expressing the
      contract of insurance against loss by fire.

   {Fire pot}.
      (a) (Mil.) A small earthen pot filled with combustibles,
          formerly used as a missile in war.
      (b) The cast iron vessel which holds the fuel or fire in a
          furnace.
      (c) A crucible.
      (d) A solderer's furnace.

   {Fire raft}, a raft laden with combustibles, used for setting
      fire to an enemy's ships.

   {Fire roll}, a peculiar beat of the drum to summon men to
      their quarters in case of fire.

   {Fire setting} (Mining), the process of softening or cracking
      the working face of a lode, to facilitate excavation, by
      exposing it to the action of fire; -- now generally
      superseded by the use of explosives. --Raymond.

   {Fire ship}, a vessel filled with combustibles, for setting
      fire to an enemy's ships.

   {Fire shovel}, a shovel for taking up coals of fire.

   {Fire stink}, the stench from decomposing iron pyrites,
      caused by the formation of hydrogen sulfide. --Raymond.

   {Fire surface}, the surfaces of a steam boiler which are
      exposed to the direct heat of the fuel and the products of
      combustion; heating surface.

   {Fire swab}, a swab saturated with water, for cooling a gun
      in action and clearing away particles of powder, etc.
      --Farrow.

   {Fire teaser}, in England, the fireman of a steam emgine.

   {Fire water}, a strong alcoholic beverage; -- so called by
      the American Indians.

   {Fire worship}, the worship of fire, which prevails chiefly
      in Persia, among the followers of Zoroaster, called
      Chebers, or Guebers, and among the Parsees of India.

   {Greek fire}. See under {Greek}.

   {On fire}, burning; hence, ardent; passionate; eager;
      zealous.

   {Running fire}, the rapid discharge of firearms in succession
      by a line of troops.

   {St. Anthony's fire}, erysipelas; -- an eruptive fever which
      St. Anthony was supposed to cure miraculously. --Hoblyn.

   {St. Elmo's fire}. See under {Saint Elmo}.

   {To set on fire}, to inflame; to kindle.

   {To take fire}, to begin to burn; to fly into a passion.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fire \Fire\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fired}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Fring}.]
   1. To set on fire; to kindle; as, to fire a house or chimney;
      to fire a pile.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To subject to intense heat; to bake; to burn in a kiln;
      as, to fire pottery.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To inflame; to irritate, as the passions; as, to fire the
      soul with anger, pride, or revenge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Love had fired my mind.               --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To animate; to give life or spirit to; as, to fire the
      genius of a young man.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To feed or serve the fire of; as, to fire a boiler.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To light up as if by fire; to illuminate.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The sun] fires the proud tops of the eastern pines.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cause to explode; as, to fire a torpedo; to disharge;
      as, to fire a rifle, pistol, or cannon; to fire cannon
      balls, rockets, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To drive by fire. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Till my bad angel fire my good one out. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Far.) To cauterize.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. to dismiss from employment, a post, or other job; to
       cause (a person) to cease being an employee; -- of a
       person. The act of firing is usually performed by that
       person's supervisor or employer. ``You can't fire me! I
       quit!''
       [PJC]

   {To fire up},

   1. to light up the fires of, as of an engine; also,
      figuratively, to start up any machine.

   2. to render enthusiastic; -- of people.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fire \Fire\, v. i.
   1. To take fire; to be kindled; to kindle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be irritated or inflamed with passion.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To discharge artillery or firearms; as, they fired on the
      town.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fire up}, to grow irritated or angry. ``He . . . fired
      up, and stood vigorously on his defense.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FIRE
     Flexible Intelligent Routing Engine (3Com)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fire</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fire
     n 1: the event of something burning (often destructive); "they
          lost everything in the fire"
     2: the process of combustion of inflammable materials producing
        heat and light and (often) smoke; "fire was one of our
        ancestors' first discoveries" [syn: {flame}, {flaming}]
     3: the act of firing weapons or artillery at an enemy; "hold
        your fire until you can see the whites of their eyes";
        "they retreated in the face of withering enemy fire" [syn:
         {firing}]
     4: a fireplace in which a fire is burning; "they sat by the
        fire and talked"
     5: intense adverse criticism; "Clinton directed his fire at the
        Republican Party"; "the government has come under attack";
        "don't give me any flak" [syn: {attack}, {flak}, {flack},
        {blast}]
     6: feelings of great warmth and intensity; "he spoke with great
        ardor" [syn: {ardor}, {ardour}, {fervor}, {fervour}, {fervency},
         {fervidness}]
     7: once thought to be one of four elements composing the
        universe (Empedocles)
     8: a severe trial; "he went through fire and damnation"
     v 1: start firing a weapon [syn: {open fire}]
     2: cause to go off; "fire a gun"; "fire a bullet" [syn: {discharge}]
     3: bake in a kiln so as to harden; "fire pottery"
     4: terminate the employment of; "The boss fired his secretary
        today"; "The company terminated 25% of its workers" [syn:
        {give notice}, {can}, {dismiss}, {give the axe}, {send
        away}, {sack}, {force out}, {give the sack}, {terminate}]
        [ant: {hire}]
     5: go off or discharge; "The gun fired" [syn: {discharge}, {go
        off}]
     6: drive out or away by or as if by fire; "The soldiers were
        fired"; "Surrender fires the cold skepticism"
     7: call forth (emotions, feelings, and responses); "arouse
        pity"; "raise a smile"; "evoke sympathy" [syn: {arouse}, {elicit},
         {enkindle}, {kindle}, {evoke}, {raise}, {provoke}]
     8: destroy by fire; "They burned the house and his diaries"
        [syn: {burn}, {burn down}]
     9: provide with fuel; "Oil fires the furnace" [syn: {fuel}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
