<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fishes</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fishes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crawfish \Craw"fish`\ (kr[add]"f[i^]sh`), Crayfish \Cray"fish`\
   (kr[=a]"f[i^]sh`), n.; pl. {-fishes} or {-fish}. [Corrupted
   fr. OE. crevis, creves, OF. crevice, F. ['e]crevisse, fr.
   OHG. krebiz crab, G. krebs. See {Crab}. The ending -fish
   arose from confusion with E. fish.] (Zo["o]l.)
   Any decapod crustacean of the family {Astacid[ae]} (genera
   {Cambarus} and {Cambarus}), resembling the lobster, but
   smaller, and found in fresh waters. Crawfishes are esteemed
   very delicate food both in Europe and America. The North
   American species are numerous and mostly belong to the genus
   {Cambarus}. The blind crawfish of the Mammoth Cave is
   {Cambarus pellucidus}. The common European species is
   {Astacus fluviatilis}.

   Syn: crawdad, crawdaddy.
        [1913 Webster]

   2. tiny lobsterlike crustaceans usually boiled briefly.

   Syn: crawdad, ecrevisse.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   3. a large edible marine crustacean having a spiny carapace
      but lacking the large pincers of true lobsters.

   Syn: spiny lobster, langouste, rock lobster, crayfish, sea
        crawfish.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fishes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fish \Fish\, n.; pl. {Fishes} (f[i^]sh"[e^]z), or collectively,
   {Fish}. [OE. fisch, fisc, fis, AS. fisc; akin to D. visch,
   OS. &amp; OHG. fisk, G. fisch, Icel. fiskr, Sw. &amp; Dan. fisk,
   Goth. fisks, L. piscis, Ir. iasg. Cf. {Piscatorial}. In some
   cases, such as fish joint, fish plate, this word has prob.
   been confused with fish, fr. F. fichea peg.]
   1. A name loosely applied in popular usage to many animals of
      diverse characteristics, living in the water.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Zo["o]l.) An oviparous, vertebrate animal usually having
      fins and a covering scales or plates. It breathes by means
      of gills, and lives almost entirely in the water. See
      {Pisces}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The true fishes include the Teleostei (bony fishes),
         Ganoidei, Dipnoi, and Elasmobranchii or Selachians
         (sharks and skates). Formerly the leptocardia and
         Marsipobranciata were also included, but these are now
         generally regarded as two distinct classes, below the
         fishes.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. The twelfth sign of the zodiac; Pisces.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The flesh of fish, used as food.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.)
      (a) A purchase used to fish the anchor.
      (b) A piece of timber, somewhat in the form of a fish,
          used to strengthen a mast or yard.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Fish is used adjectively or as part of a compound word;
         as, fish line, fish pole, fish spear, fish-bellied.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Age of Fishes}. See under {Age}, n., 8.

   {Fish ball}, fish (usually salted codfish) shared fine, mixed
      with mashed potato, and made into the form of a small,
      round cake. [U.S.]

   {Fish bar}. Same as {Fish plate} (below).

   {Fish beam} (Mech.), a beam one of whose sides (commonly the
      under one) swells out like the belly of a fish. --Francis.

   {Fish crow} (Zo["o]l.), a species of crow ({Corvus
      ossifragus}), found on the Atlantic coast of the United
      States. It feeds largely on fish.

   {Fish culture}, the artifical breeding and rearing of fish;
      pisciculture.

   {Fish davit}. See {Davit}.

   {Fish day}, a day on which fish is eaten; a fast day.

   {Fish duck} (Zo["o]l.), any species of merganser.

   {Fish fall}, the tackle depending from the fish davit, used
      in hauling up the anchor to the gunwale of a ship.

   {Fish garth}, a dam or weir in a river for keeping fish or
      taking them easily.

   {Fish glue}. See {Isinglass}.

   {Fish joint}, a joint formed by a plate or pair of plates
      fastened upon two meeting beams, plates, etc., at their
      junction; -- used largely in connecting the rails of
      railroads.

   {Fish kettle}, a long kettle for boiling fish whole.

   {Fish ladder}, a dam with a series of steps which fish can
      leap in order to ascend falls in a river.

   {Fish line}, or {Fishing line}, a line made of twisted hair,
      silk, etc., used in angling.

   {Fish louse} (Zo["o]l.), any crustacean parasitic on fishes,
      esp. the parasitic Copepoda, belonging to {Caligus},
      {Argulus}, and other related genera. See {Branchiura}.

   {Fish maw} (Zo["o]l.), the stomach of a fish; also, the air
      bladder, or sound.

   {Fish meal}, fish desiccated and ground fine, for use in
      soups, etc.

   {Fish oil}, oil obtained from the bodies of fish and marine
      animals, as whales, seals, sharks, from cods' livers, etc.
      

   {Fish owl} (Zo["o]l.), a fish-eating owl of the Old World
      genera {Scotopelia} and {Ketupa}, esp. a large East Indian
      species ({K. Ceylonensis}).

   {Fish plate}, one of the plates of a fish joint.

   {Fish pot}, a wicker basket, sunk, with a float attached, for
      catching crabs, lobsters, etc.

   {Fish pound}, a net attached to stakes, for entrapping and
      catching fish; a weir. [Local, U.S.] --Bartlett.

   {Fish slice}, a broad knife for dividing fish at table; a
      fish trowel.

   {Fish slide}, an inclined box set in a stream at a small
      fall, or ripple, to catch fish descending the current.
      --Knight.

   {Fish sound}, the air bladder of certain fishes, esp. those
      that are dried and used as food, or in the arts, as for
      the preparation of isinglass.

   {Fish story}, a story which taxes credulity; an extravagant
      or incredible narration. [Colloq. U.S.] --Bartlett.

   {Fish strainer}.
      (a) A metal colander, with handles, for taking fish from a
          boiler.
      (b) A perforated earthenware slab at the bottom of a dish,
          to drain the water from a boiled fish.

   {Fish trowel}, a fish slice.

   {Fish weir} or {Fish wear}, a weir set in a stream, for
      catching fish.

   {Neither fish nor flesh}, {Neither fish nor fowl} (Fig.),
      neither one thing nor the other.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fishes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fish
     n 1: any of various mostly cold-blooded aquatic vertebrates
          usually having scales and breathing through gills; "the
          shark is a large fish"; "in the livingroom there was a
          tank of colorful fish"
     2: the flesh of fish used as food; "in Japan most fish is eaten
        raw"; "after the scare about foot-and-mouth disease a lot
        of people started eating fish instead of meat"; "they have
        a chef who specializes in fish"
     3: (astrology) a person who is born while the sun is in Pisces
        [syn: {Pisces}]
     4: the twelfth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from
        about February 19 to March 20 [syn: {Pisces}, {Pisces the
        Fishes}]
     v 1: seek indirectly; "fish for compliments" [syn: {angle}]
     2: catch or try to catch fish or shellfish; "I like to go
        fishing on weekends"
     [also: {fishes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fishes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fishes
     See {fish}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
