<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fixed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fixed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fix \Fix\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fixed} (f[i^]kst); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Fixing}.] [Cf. F. fixer.]
   1. To make firm, stable, or fast; to set or place
      permanently; to fasten immovably; to establish; to
      implant; to secure; to make definite.
      [1913 Webster]

            An ass's nole I fixed on his head.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, fix thy chair of grace, that all my powers
            May also fix their reverence.         --Herbert.
      [1913 Webster]

            His heart is fixed, trusting in the Lord. --Ps.
                                                  cxii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

            And fix far deeper in his head their stings.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To hold steadily; to direct unwaveringly; to fasten, as
      the eye on an object, the attention on a speaker.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sat fixed in thought the mighty Stagirite. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            One eye on death, and one full fix'd on heaven.
                                                  --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To transfix; to pierce. [Obs.] --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Photog.) To render (an impression) permanent by treating
      with a developer to make it insensible to the action of
      light. --Abney.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To put in order; to arrange; to dispose of; to adjust; to
      set to rights; to set or place in the manner desired or
      most suitable; hence, to repair; as, to fix the clothes;
      to fix the furniture of a room. [Colloq. U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Iron Manuf.) To line the hearth of (a puddling furnace)
      with fettling.

   Syn: To arrange; prepare; adjust; place; establish; settle;
        determine.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fixed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fixed \Fixed\ (f[i^]kst), a.
   1. Securely placed or fastened; settled; established; firm;
      imovable; unalterable.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Chem.) Stable; non-volatile.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fixed air} (Old Chem.), carbonic acid or carbon dioxide; --
      so called by Dr. Black because it can be absorbed or fixed
      by strong bases. See {Carbonic acid}, under {Carbonic}.

   {Fixed alkali} (Old Chem.), a non-volatile base, as soda, or
      potash, in distinction from the volatile alkali ammonia.
      

   {Fixed ammunition} (Mil.), a projectile and powder inclosed
      together in a case ready for loading.

   {Fixed battery} (Mil.), a battery which contains heavy guns
      and mortars intended to remain stationary; --
      distinguished from movable battery.

   {Fixed bodies}, those which can not be volatilized or
      separated by a common menstruum, without great difficulty,
      as gold, platinum, lime, etc.

   {Fixed capital}. See the Note under {Capital}, n., 4.

   {Fixed fact}, a well established fact. [Colloq.]

   {Fixed light}, one which emits constant beams; --
      distinguished from a flashing, revolving, or intermittent
      light.

   {Fixed oils} (Chem.), non-volatile, oily substances, as
      stearine and olein, which leave a permanent greasy stain,
      and which can not be distilled unchanged; -- distinguished
      from volatile or {essential oils}.

   {Fixed pivot} (Mil.), the fixed point about which any line of
      troops wheels.

   {Fixed stars} (Astron.), such stars as always retain nearly
      the same apparent position and distance with respect to
      each other, thus distinguished from planets and comets.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fixed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fixed
     adj 1: (of a number) having a fixed and unchanging value
     2: fixed and unmoving; "with eyes set in a fixed glassy stare";
        "his bearded face already has a set hollow look"- Connor
        Cruise O'Brien; "a face rigid with pain" [syn: {set}, {rigid}]
     3: securely placed or fastened or set; "a fixed piece of wood";
        "a fixed resistor" [ant: {unfixed}]
     4: intent and directed steadily; "had her gaze fastened on the
        stranger"; "a fixed expresson" [syn: {fastened}]
     5: incapable of being changed or moved or undone; e.g. "frozen
        prices"; "living on fixed incomes" [syn: {frozen}]
     6: mended or put in working order; "a reconditioned sewing
        machine"; "a repaired vacuum cleaner"; "the broken lock is
        now fixed" [syn: {reconditioned}, {repaired}]
     7: not increasing as the amount taxed increases [syn: {flat}]
     8: specified in advance; "a given number"; "we will meet at a
        given time and location" [syn: {given(a)}]
     9: directed with intense concentration; "a fixed stare"; "an
        intent gaze" [syn: {intent}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
