<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>flame</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flame</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flame
     
        &lt;messaging&gt; To rant, to speak or write incessantly and/or
        rabidly on some relatively uninteresting subject or with a
        patently ridiculous attitude or with hostility toward a
        particular person or group of people.  "Flame" is used as a
        verb ("Don't flame me for this, but..."), a flame is a single
        flaming message, and "flamage" /flay'm*j/ the content.
     
        Flamage may occur in any medium (e.g. spoken, {electronic
        mail}, {Usenet} news, {World-Wide Web}).  Sometimes a flame
        will be delimited in text by marks such as "&lt;flame
        on&gt;...&lt;flame off&gt;".
     
        The term was probably independently invented at several
        different places.
     
        Mark L. Levinson says, "When I joined the Harvard student
        radio station (WHRB) in 1966, the terms flame and flamer were
        already well established there to refer to impolite ranting
        and to those who performed it.  Communication among the
        students who worked at the station was by means of what today
        you might call a paper-based Usenet group.  Everyone wrote
        comments to one another in a large ledger.  Documentary
        evidence for the early use of flame/flamer is probably still
        there for anyone fanatical enough to research it."
     
        It is reported that "flaming" was in use to mean something
        like "interminably drawn-out semi-serious discussions"
        (late-night bull sessions) at Carleton College during
        1968-1971.
     
        {Usenetter} Marc Ramsey, who was at {WPI} from 1972 to 1976,
        says: "I am 99% certain that the use of "flame" originated at
        WPI.  Those who made a nuisance of themselves insisting that
        they needed to use a {TTY} for "real work" came to be known as
        "flaming asshole lusers".  Other particularly annoying people
        became "flaming asshole ravers", which shortened to "flaming
        ravers", and ultimately "flamers".  I remember someone picking
        up on the Human Torch pun, but I don't think "flame on/off"
        was ever much used at WPI."  See also {asbestos}.
     
        It is possible that the hackish sense of "flame" is much older
        than that.  The poet Chaucer was also what passed for a wizard
        hacker in his time; he wrote a treatise on the astrolabe, the
        most advanced computing device of the day.  In Chaucer's
        "Troilus and Cressida", Cressida laments her inability to
        grasp the proof of a particular mathematical theorem; her
        uncle Pandarus then observes that it's called "the fleminge of
        wrecches."  This phrase seems to have been intended in context
        as "that which puts the wretches to flight" but was probably
        just as ambiguous in Middle English as "the flaming of
        wretches" would be today.  One suspects that Chaucer would
        feel right at home on {Usenet}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2001-03-11)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flame</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flame \Flame\ (fl[=a]m), n. [OE. flame, flaume, flaumbe, OF.
   flame, flambe, F. flamme, fr. L. flamma, fr. flamma, fr.
   flagrare to burn. See {Flagrant}, and cf. {Flamneau},
   {Flamingo}.]
   1. A stream of burning vapor or gas, emitting light and heat;
      darting or streaming fire; a blaze; a fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Burning zeal or passion; elevated and noble enthusiasm;
      glowing imagination; passionate excitement or anger. ``In
      a flame of zeal severe.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where flames refin'd in breasts seraphic glow.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Smit with the love of sister arts we came,
            And met congenial, mingling flame with flame.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Ardor of affection; the passion of love. --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A person beloved; a sweetheart. --Thackeray.

   Syn: Blaze; brightness; ardor. See {Blaze}.
        [1913 Webster]

   {Flame bridge}, a bridge wall. See {Bridge}, n., 5.

   {Flame color}, brilliant orange or yellow. --B. Jonson.

   {Flame engine}, an early name for the gas engine.

   {Flame manometer}, an instrument, invented by Koenig, to
      obtain graphic representation of the action of the human
      vocal organs. See {Manometer}.

   {Flame reaction} (Chem.), a method of testing for the
      presence of certain elements by the characteristic color
      imparted to a flame; as, sodium colors a flame yellow,
      potassium violet, lithium crimson, boracic acid green,
      etc. Cf. {Spectrum analysis}, under {Spectrum}.

   {Flame tree} (Bot.), a tree with showy scarlet flowers, as
      the {Rhododendron arboreum} in India, and the
      {Brachychiton acerifolium} of Australia.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flame</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flame \Flame\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Flamed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Flaming}.] [OE. flamen, flaumben, F. flamber, OF. also,
   flamer. See {Flame}, n.]
   1. To burn with a flame or blaze; to burn as gas emitted from
      bodies in combustion; to blaze.
      [1913 Webster]

            The main blaze of it is past, but a small thing
            would make it flame again.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To burst forth like flame; to break out in violence of
      passion; to be kindled with zeal or ardor.
      [1913 Webster]

            He flamed with indignation.           --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flame</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flame \Flame\, v. t.
   To kindle; to inflame; to excite.
   [1913 Webster]

         And flamed with zeal of vengeance inwardly. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flame</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flame [at MIT, orig. from the phrase `flaming asshole'] 1. vi. To post
   an email message intended to insult and provoke. 2. vi. To speak
   incessantly and/or rabidly on some relatively uninteresting subject or
   with a patently ridiculous attitude. 3. vt. Either of senses 1 or 2,
   directed with hostility at a particular person or people. 4. n. An
   instance of flaming. When a discussion degenerates into useless
   controversy, one might tell the participants "Now you're just flaming"
   or "Stop all that flamage!" to try to get them to cool down (so to
   speak).

   The term may have been independently invented at several different
   places. It has been reported from MIT, Carleton College and RPI (among
   many other places) from as far back as 1969, and from the University of
   Virginia in the early 1960s.

   It is possible that the hackish sense of `flame' is much older than
   that. The poet Chaucer was also what passed for a wizard hacker in his
   time; he wrote a treatise on the astrolabe, the most advanced computing
   device of the day. In Chaucer's "Troilus and Cressida", Cressida laments
   her inability to grasp the proof of a particular mathematical theorem;
   her uncle Pandarus then observes that it's called "the fleminge of
   wrecches." This phrase seems to have been intended in context as "that
   which puts the wretches to flight" but was probably just as ambiguous in
   Middle English as "the flaming of wretches" would be today. One suspects
   that Chaucer would feel right at home on Usenet.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flame</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FLAME
     FLexible API for Module-based Environments (RL, API)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flame</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flame
     n : the process of combustion of inflammable materials producing
         heat and light and (often) smoke; "fire was one of our
         ancestors' first discoveries" [syn: {fire}, {flaming}]
     v 1: shine with a sudden light; "The night sky flared with the
          massive bombardment" [syn: {flare}]
     2: be in flames or aflame; "The sky seemed to flame in the
        Hawaiian sunset"
     3: criticize harshly, on the e-mail
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
