<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>flank</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flank \Flank\, v. i.
   1. To border; to touch. --Bp. Butler.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be posted on the side.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flank \Flank\ (fl[a^][ng]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Flanked}
   (fl[a^][ng]kt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Flanking}.] [Cf. F.
   flanquer. See {Flank}, n., and cf. {Flanker}, v. t.]
   1. To stand at the flank or side of; to border upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Stately colonnades are flanked with trees. --Pitt.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To overlook or command the flank of; to secure or guard
      the flank of; to pass around or turn the flank of; to
      attack, or threaten to attack; the flank of.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flank \Flank\ (fl[a^][ng]k), n. [F. flanc, prob. fr. L. flaccus
   flabby, with n inserted. Cf. {Flaccid}, {Flanch}, {Flange}.]
   1. The fleshy or muscular part of the side of an animal,
      between the ribs and the hip. See Illust. of {Beef}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.)
      (a) The side of an army, or of any division of an army, as
          of a brigade, regiment, or battalion; the extreme
          right or left; as, to attack an enemy in flank is to
          attack him on the side.
          [1913 Webster]

                When to right and left the front

                Divided, and to either flank retired. --Milton.
      (b) (Fort.) That part of a bastion which reaches from the
          curtain to the face, and defends the curtain, the
          flank and face of the opposite bastion; any part of a
          work defending another by a fire along the outside of
          its parapet. See Illust. of {Bastion}.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.) The side of any building. --Brands.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That part of the acting surface of a gear wheel tooth that
      lies within the pitch line.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Flank attack} (Mil.), an attack upon the side of an army or
      body of troops, distinguished from one upon its front or
      rear.

   {Flank company} (Mil.), a certain number of troops drawn up
      on the right or left of a battalion; usually grenadiers,
      light infantry, or riflemen.

   {Flank defense} (Fort.), protection of a work against undue
      exposure to an enemy's direct fire, by means of the fire
      from other works, sweeping the ground in its front.

   {Flank en potence} (Mil.), any part of the right or left wing
      formed at a projecting angle with the line.

   {Flank files}, the first men on the right, and the last on
      the left, of a company, battalion, etc.

   {Flank march}, a march made parallel or obliquely to an
      enemy's position, in order to turn it or to attack him on
      the flank.

   {Flank movement}, a change of march by an army, or portion of
      one, in order to turn one or both wings of the enemy, or
      to take up a new position.

   {Flanks of a frontier}, salient points in a national
      boundary, strengthened to protect the frontier against
      hostile incursion.

   {Flank patrol}, detachments acting independently of the
      column of an army, but patrolling along its flanks, to
      secure it against surprise and to observe the movements of
      the enemy.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flank
     n 1: the side of military or naval formation; "they attacked the
          enemy's right flank" [syn: {wing}]
     2: a subfigure consisting of a side of something
     3: a cut from the fleshy part of an animal's side between the
        ribs and the leg
     4: the side between ribs and hipbone
     v : be located at the sides of something or somebody
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
