<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>flashlight</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flashlight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\ (l[imac]t), n. [OE. light, liht, AS. le['o]ht;
   akin to OS. lioht, D. &amp; G. licht, OHG. lioht, Goth.
   liuha[thorn], Icel. lj[=o]s, L. lux light, lucere to shine,
   Gr. leyko`s white, Skr. ruc to shine. [root]122. Cf. {Lucid},
   {Lunar}, {Luminous}, {Lynx}.]
   1. That agent, force, or action in nature by the operation of
      which upon the organs of sight, objects are rendered
      visible or luminous.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Light was regarded formerly as consisting of material
         particles, or corpuscules, sent off in all directions
         from luminous bodies, and traversing space, in right
         lines, with the known velocity of about 186,300 miles
         per second; but it is now generally understood to
         consist, not in any actual transmission of particles or
         substance, but in the propagation of vibrations or
         undulations in a subtile, elastic medium, or ether,
         assumed to pervade all space, and to be thus set in
         vibratory motion by the action of luminous bodies, as
         the atmosphere is by sonorous bodies. This view of the
         nature of light is known as the undulatory or wave
         theory; the other, advocated by Newton (but long since
         abandoned), as the corpuscular, emission, or Newtonian
         theory. A more recent theory makes light to consist in
         electrical oscillations, and is known as the
         electro-magnetic theory of light.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. That which furnishes, or is a source of, light, as the
      sun, a star, a candle, a lighthouse, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then he called for a light, and sprang in. --Acts
                                                  xvi. 29.
      [1913 Webster]

            And God made two great lights; the greater light to
            rule the day, and the lesser light to rule the
            night.                                --Gen. i. 16.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The time during which the light of the sun is visible;
      day; especially, the dawn of day.
      [1913 Webster]

            The murderer, rising with the light, killeth the
            poor and needy.                       --Job xxiv.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The brightness of the eye or eyes.
      [1913 Webster]

            He seemed to find his way without his eyes;
            For out o'door he went without their helps,
            And, to the last, bended their light on me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The medium through which light is admitted, as a window,
      or window pane; a skylight; in architecture, one of the
      compartments of a window made by a mullion or mullions.
      [1913 Webster]

            There were windows in three rows, and light was
            against light in three ranks.         --I Kings
                                                  vii.4.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Life; existence.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, spring to light, auspicious Babe, be born !
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Open view; a visible state or condition; public
      observation; publicity.
      [1913 Webster]

            The duke yet would have dark deeds darkly answered;
            he would never bring them to light.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. The power of perception by vision.
      [1913 Webster]

            My strength faileth me; as for the light of my eyes,
            it also is gone from me.              --Ps. xxxviii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. That which illumines or makes clear to the mind; mental or
      spiritual illumination; enlightenment; knowledge;
      information.
      [1913 Webster]

            He shall never know
            That I had any light of this from thee. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Prosperity; happiness; joy; felicity.
       [1913 Webster]

             Then shall thy light break forth as the morning,
             and thy health shall spring forth speedily. --Is.
                                                  lviii. 8.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Paint.) The manner in which the light strikes upon a
       picture; that part of a picture which represents those
       objects upon which the light is supposed to fall; the
       more illuminated part of a landscape or other scene; --
       opposed to {shade}. Cf. {Chiaroscuro}.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Appearance due to the particular facts and circumstances
       presented to view; point of view; as, to state things
       fairly and put them in the right light.
       [1913 Webster]

             Frequent consideration of a thing . . . shows it in
             its several lights and various ways of appearance.
                                                  --South.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. One who is conspicuous or noteworthy; a model or example;
       as, the lights of the age or of antiquity.
       [1913 Webster]

             Joan of Arc,
             A light of ancient France.           --Tennyson.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Pyrotech.) A firework made by filling a case with a
       substance which burns brilliantly with a white or colored
       flame; as, a Bengal light.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Light is used figuratively to denote that which
         resembles physical light in any respect, as
         illuminating, benefiting, enlightening, or enlivening
         mankind.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Ancient lights} (Law), {Calcium light}, {Flash light}, etc.
      See under {Ancient}, {Calcium}, etc.

   {Light ball} (Mil.), a ball of combustible materials, used to
      afford light; -- sometimes made so as to be fired from a
      cannon or mortar, or to be carried up by a rocket.

   {Light barrel} (Mil.), an empty power barrel pierced with
      holes and filled with shavings soaked in pitch, used to
      light up a ditch or a breach.

   {Light dues} (Com.), tolls levied on ships navigating certain
      waters, for the maintenance of lighthouses.

   {Light iron}, a candlestick. [Obs.]

   {Light keeper}, a person appointed to take care of a
      lighthouse or light-ship.

   {Light money}, charges laid by government on shipping
      entering a port, for the maintenance of lighthouses and
      light-ships.

   {The light of the countenance}, favor; kindness; smiles.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lord, lift thou up the light of thy countenance upon
            us.                                   --Ps. iv. 6.

   {Northern lights}. See {Aurora borealis}, under {Aurora}.

   {To bring to light}, to cause to be disclosed.

   {To come to light}, to be disclosed.

   {To see the light}, to come into the light; hence, to come
      into the world or into public notice; as, his book never
      saw the light.

   {To stand in one's own light}, to take a position which is
      injurious to one's own interest.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flashlight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flash \Flash\, n.; pl. {Flashes}.
   1. A sudden burst of light; a flood of light instantaneously
      appearing and disappearing; a momentary blaze; as, a flash
      of lightning.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A sudden and brilliant burst, as of wit or genius; a
      momentary brightness or show.
      [1913 Webster]

            The flash and outbreak of a fiery mind. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            No striking sentiment, no flash of fancy. --Wirt.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The time during which a flash is visible; an instant; a
      very brief period.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Persians and Macedonians had it for a flash.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A preparation of capsicum, burnt sugar, etc., for coloring
      and giving a fictitious strength to liquors.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. a lamp for providing intense momentary light to take a
      photograph; as, to take a picture without a flash.

   Syn: flashbulb, photoflash, flash lamp, flashgun.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   6. Same as {flashlight}. [informal]
      [PJC]

   7. (Journalism) A short news item providing recently received
      and usually preliminary information about an event that is
      considered important enough to interrupt normal
      broadcasting or other news delivery services; also called
      a {news flash} or {bulletin}.
      [PJC]

   {Flash light}, or {Flashing light}, a kind of light shown by
      lighthouses, produced by the revolution of reflectors, so
      as to show a flash of light every few seconds, alternating
      with periods of dimness. --Knight.

   {Flash in the pan}, the flashing of the priming in the pan of
      a flintlock musket without discharging the piece; hence,
      sudden, spasmodic effort that accomplishes nothing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flashlight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flashlight \flash"light`\ n.
   a portable battery-powered electric lamp, small enough to be
   held in one hand; -- it is most commonly cylindrical, but
   other forms are also made. It is called in Britain a {torch}

   Syn: torch.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flashlight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flashlight
     n : a small portable battery-powered electric lamp [syn: {torch}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
