<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>flaw</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flaw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flaw \Flaw\ (fl[add]), n. [OE. flai, flaw flake; cf. Sw. flaga
   flaw, crack, breach, flake, D. vlaag gust of wind, Norw.
   flage, flaag, and E. flag a flat stone.]
   1. A crack or breach; a gap or fissure; a defect of
      continuity or cohesion; as, a flaw in a knife or a vase.
      [1913 Webster]

            This heart
            Shall break into a hundered thousand flaws. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A defect; a fault; as, a flaw in reputation; a flaw in a
      will, in a deed, or in a statute.
      [1913 Webster]

            Has not this also its flaws and its dark side?
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sudden burst of noise and disorder; a tumult; uproar; a
      quarrel. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            And deluges of armies from the town
            Came pouring in; I heard the mighty flaw. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A sudden burst or gust of wind of short duration.
      [1913 Webster]

            Snow, and hail, and stormy gust and flaw. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like flaws in summer laying lusty corn. --Tennyson.

   Syn: Blemish; fault; imperfection; spot; speck.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flaw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flaw \Flaw\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Flawed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Flawing}.]
   1. To crack; to make flaws in.
      [1913 Webster]

            The brazen caldrons with the frosts are flawed.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To break; to violate; to make of no effect. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            France hath flawed the league.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flaw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flaw
     n 1: an imperfection in a device or machine; "if there are any
          defects you should send it back to the manufacturer"
          [syn: {defect}, {fault}]
     2: defect or weakness in a person's character; "he had his
        flaws, but he was great nonetheless"
     v : add a flaw or blemish to; make imperfect or defective [syn:
         {blemish}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
