<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fling \Fling\, v. i.
   1. To throw; to wince; to flounce; as, the horse began to
      kick and fling.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cast in the teeth; to utter abusive language; to sneer;
      as, the scold began to flout and fling.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To throw one's self in a violent or hasty manner; to rush
      or spring with violence or haste.
      [1913 Webster]

            And crop-full, out of doors he flings. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            I flung closer to his breast,
            As sword that, after battle, flings to sheath.
                                                  --Mrs.
                                                  Browning.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fling out}, to become ugly and intractable; to utter
      sneers and insinuations.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fling \Fling\ (fl[i^]ng), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Flung}
   (fl[u^]ng); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Flinging}.] [OE. flingen,
   flengen, to rush, hurl; cf. Icel. flengia to whip, ride
   furiously, OSw. flenga to strike, Sw. fl["a]nga to romp, Dan.
   flenge to slash.]
   1. To cast, send, to throw from the hand; to hurl; to dart;
      to emit with violence as if thrown from the hand; as, to
      fing a stone into the pond.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is Fate that flings the dice: and, as she flings,
            Of kings makes peasants, and of peasants kings.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . like Jove, his lighting flung. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            I know thy generous temper well.
            Fling but the appearance of dishonor on it,
            It straight takes fire.               --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To shed forth; to emit; to scatter.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sun begins to fling
            His flaring beams.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every beam new transient colors flings. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To throw; to hurl; to throw off or down; to prostrate;
      hence, to baffle; to defeat; as, to fling a party in
      litigation.
      [1913 Webster]

            His horse started, flung him, and fell upon him.
                                                  --Walpole.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fling about}, to throw on all sides; to scatter.

   {To fling away}, to reject; to discard.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cromwell, I charge thee, fling away ambition.
                                                  --Shak.
      

   {To fling down}.
      (a) To throw to the ground; esp., to throw in defiance, as
          formerly knights cast a glove into the arena as a
          challenge.
          [1913 Webster]

                This question so flung down before the guests, .
                . .
                Was handed over by consent of all
                To me who had not spoken.         --Tennyson.
      (b) To overturn; to demolish; to ruin.

   {To fling in}, to throw in; not to charge in an account; as,
      in settling accounts, one party flings in a small sum, or
      a few days' work.

   {To fling off}, to baffle in the chase; to defeat of prey;
      also, to get rid of. --Addison.

   {To fling open}, to throw open; to open suddenly or with
      violence; as, to fling open a door.

   {To fling out}, to utter; to speak in an abrupt or harsh
      manner; as, to fling out hard words against another.

   {To fling up}, to relinquish; to abandon; as, to fling up a
      design.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fling \Fling\, n.
   1. A cast from the hand; a throw; also, a flounce; a kick;
      as, the fling of a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A severe or contemptuous remark; an expression of
      sarcastic scorn; a gibe; a sarcasm.
      [1913 Webster]

            I, who love to have a fling,
            Both at senate house and king.        --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A kind of dance; as, the Highland fling.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A trifing matter; an object of contempt. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            England were but a fling
            Save for the crooked stick and the gray goose wing.
                                                  --Old Proverb.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. a short period during which one indulges one's wishes,
      whims, or desires in an unrestrained manner.
      [PJC]

   6. a love affair.
      [PJC]

   7. a casual or brief attempt to accomplish something.
      [informal]

   Syn: shot.
        [PJC]

   8. a period during which one tries a new activity; as, he
      took a fling at playing tennis.
      [PJC]

   {To have one's fling}, to enjoy one's self to the full; to
      have a season of dissipation. --J. H. Newman. ``When I was
      as young as you, I had my fling. I led a life of
      pleasure.'' --D. Jerrold.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fling
     n 1: a usually brief attempt; "he took a crack at it"; "I gave it
          a whirl" [syn: {crack}, {go}, {pass}, {whirl}, {offer}]
     2: a brief indulgence of your impulses [syn: {spree}]
     3: the act of flinging
     v 1: throw with force or recklessness; "fling the frisbee"
     2: move in an abrupt or headlong manner; "He flung himself onto
        the sofa"
     3: indulge oneself; "I splurged on a new TV" [syn: {splurge}]
     4: throw or cast away; "Put away your worries" [syn: {discard},
         {toss}, {toss out}, {toss away}, {chuck out}, {cast aside},
         {dispose}, {throw out}, {cast out}, {throw away}, {cast
        away}, {put away}]
     [also: {flung}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
