<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>floating</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>floating</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Floating \Float"ing\, a.
   1. Buoyed upon or in a fluid; a, the floating timbers of a
      wreck; floating motes in the air.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Free or lose from the usual attachment; as, the floating
      ribs in man and some other animals.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not funded; not fixed, invested, or determined; as,
      floating capital; a floating debt.
      [1913 Webster]

            Trade was at an end. Floating capital had been
            withdrawn in great masses from the island.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Floating anchor} (Naut.), a drag or sea anchor; drag sail.
      

   {Floating battery} (Mil.), a battery erected on rafts or the
      hulls of ships, chiefly for the defense of a coast or the
      bombardment of a place.

   {Floating bridge}.
      (a) A bridge consisting of rafts or timber, with a floor
          of plank, supported wholly by the water; a bateau
          bridge. See {Bateau}.
      (b) (Mil.) A kind of double bridge, the upper one
          projecting beyond the lower one, and capable of being
          moved forward by pulleys; -- used for carrying troops
          over narrow moats in attacking the outworks of a fort.
      (c) A kind of ferryboat which is guided and impelled by
          means of chains which are anchored on each side of a
          stream, and pass over wheels on the vessel, the wheels
          being driven by stream power.
      (d) The landing platform of a ferry dock.

   {Floating cartilage} (Med.), a cartilage which moves freely
      in the cavity of a joint, and often interferes with the
      functions of the latter.

   {Floating dam}.
      (a) An anchored dam.
      (b) A caisson used as a gate for a dry dock.

   {Floating derrick}, a derrick on a float for river and harbor
      use, in raising vessels, moving stone for harbor
      improvements, etc.

   {Floating dock}. (Naut.) See under {Dock}.

   {Floating harbor}, a breakwater of cages or booms, anchored
      and fastened together, and used as a protection to ships
      riding at anchor to leeward. --Knight.

   {Floating heart} (Bot.), a small aquatic plant ({Limnanthemum
      lacunosum}) whose heart-shaped leaves float on the water
      of American ponds.

   {Floating island}, a dish for dessert, consisting of custard
      with floating masses of whipped cream or white of eggs.

   {Floating kidney}. (Med.) See {Wandering kidney}, under
      {Wandering}.

   {Floating light}, a light shown at the masthead of a vessel
      moored over sunken rocks, shoals, etc., to warn mariners
      of danger; a light-ship; also, a light erected on a buoy
      or floating stage.

   {Floating liver}. (Med.) See {Wandering liver}, under
      {Wandering}.

   {Floating pier}, a landing stage or pier which rises and
      falls with the tide.

   {Floating ribs} (Anat.), the lower or posterior ribs which
      are not connected with the others in front; in man they
      are the last two pairs.

   {Floating screed} (Plastering), a strip of plastering first
      laid on, to serve as a guide for the thickness of the
      coat.

   {Floating threads} (Weaving), threads which span several
      other threads without being interwoven with them, in a
      woven fabric.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>floating</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Floating \Float"ing\, n.
   1. (Weaving) Floating threads. See {Floating threads}, above.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The second coat of three-coat plastering. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The process of rendering oysters and scallops plump by
      placing them in fresh or brackish water; -- called also
      {fattening}, {plumping}, and {laying out}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>floating</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Float \Float\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Floated}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Floating}.] [OE. flotien, flotten, AS. flotian to float,
   swim, fr. fle['o]tan. See {Float}, n.]
   1. To rest on the surface of any fluid; to swim; to be buoyed
      up.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ark no more now floats, but seems on ground.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Three blustering nights, borne by the southern
            blast,
            I floated.                            --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move quietly or gently on the water, as a raft; to
      drift along; to move or glide without effort or impulse on
      the surface of a fluid, or through the air.
      [1913 Webster]

            They stretch their broad plumes and float upon the
            wind.                                 --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            There seems a floating whisper on the hills.
                                                  --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>floating</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>floating
     adj 1: continually changing especially as from one abode or
            occupation to another; "a drifting double-dealer";
            "the floating population"; "vagrant hippies of the
            sixties" [syn: {aimless}, {drifting}, {vagabond}, {vagrant}]
     2: inclined to move or be moved about; "a floating crap game"
     3: (of a part of the body) not firmly connected; movable or out
        of normal position; "floating ribs are not connected with
        the sternum"; "a floating kidney" [syn: {floating(a)}]
     4: not definitely committed to a party or policy; "floating
        voters" [syn: {floating(a)}]
     5: borne up by or suspended in a liquid; "the ship is still
        floating"; "floating logs"; "floating seaweed"
     n : the act of someone who floats on the water
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
