<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>floor</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>floor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Floor \Floor\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Floored}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Flooring}.]
   1. To cover with a floor; to furnish with a floor; as, to
      floor a house with pine boards.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To strike down or lay level with the floor; to knock down;
      hence, to silence by a conclusive answer or retort; as, to
      floor an opponent.
      [1913 Webster]

            Floored or crushed by him.            --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To finish or make an end of; as, to floor a college
      examination. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I've floored my little-go work.       --T. Hughes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>floor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Floor \Floor\ (fl[=o]r), n. [AS. fl[=o]r; akin to D. vloer, G.
   flur field, floor, entrance hall, Icel. fl[=o]r floor of a
   cow stall, cf. Ir. &amp; Gael. lar floor, ground, earth, W.
   llawr, perh. akin to L. planus level. Cf. {Plain} smooth.]
   1. The bottom or lower part of any room; the part upon which
      we stand and upon which the movables in the room are
      supported.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The structure formed of beams, girders, etc., with proper
      covering, which divides a building horizontally into
      stories. Floor in sense 1 is, then, the upper surface of
      floor in sense 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The surface, or the platform, of a structure on which we
      walk or travel; as, the floor of a bridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A story of a building. See {Story}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Legislative Assemblies)
      (a) The part of the house assigned to the members.
      (b) The right to speak; as, the gentleman from Iowa has
          the floor. [U.S.]
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Instead of he has the floor, the English say, he is in
         possession of the house.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) That part of the bottom of a vessel on each side
      of the keelson which is most nearly horizontal.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining)
      (a) The rock underlying a stratified or nearly horizontal
          deposit.
      (b) A horizontal, flat ore body. --Raymond.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Floor cloth}, a heavy fabric, painted, varnished, or
      saturated, with waterproof material, for covering floors;
      oilcloth.

   {Floor cramp}, an implement for tightening the seams of floor
      boards before nailing them in position.

   {Floor light}, a frame with glass panes in a floor.

   {Floor plan}.
      (a) (Shipbuilding) A longitudinal section, showing a ship
          as divided at the water line.
      (b) (Arch.) A horizontal section, showing the thickness of
          the walls and partitions, arrangement of passages,
          apartments, and openings at the level of any floor of
          a house.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>floor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>floor
     n 1: the inside lower horizontal surface (as of a room or
          hallway); "they needed rugs to cover the bare floors"
          [syn: {flooring}]
     2: structure consisting of a room or set of rooms comprising a
        single level of a multilevel building; "what level is the
        office on?" [syn: {level}, {storey}, {story}]
     3: a lower limit; "the government established a wage floor"
        [syn: {base}]
     4: the ground on which people and animals move about; "the fire
        spared the forest floor"
     5: the bottom surface of any a cave or lake etc.
     6: the occupants of a floor; "the whole floor complained about
        the lack of heat"
     7: the parliamentary right to address an assembly; "the
        chairman granted him the floor"
     8: the legislative hall where members debate and vote and
        conduct other business; "there was a motion from the
        floor"
     9: a large room in a stock exchange where the trading is done;
        "he is a floor trader" [syn: {trading floor}]
     v 1: surprise greatly; knock someone's socks off; "I was floored
          when I heard that I was promoted" [syn: {shock}, {stun},
           {ball over}, {blow out of the water}, {take aback}]
     2: knock down with force; "He decked his opponent" [syn: {deck},
         {coldcock}, {dump}, {knock down}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
