<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>flower</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flower</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flower, WV
  Zip code(s): 26611
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flower</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flower \Flow"er\ (flou"[~e]r), n. [OE. flour, OF. flour, flur,
   flor, F. fleur, fr. L. flos, floris. Cf. {Blossom},
   {Effloresce}, {Floret}, {Florid}, {Florin}, {Flour},
   {Flourish}.]
   1. In the popular sense, the bloom or blossom of a plant; the
      showy portion, usually of a different color, shape, and
      texture from the foliage.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) That part of a plant destined to produce seed, and
      hence including one or both of the sexual organs; an organ
      or combination of the organs of reproduction, whether
      inclosed by a circle of foliar parts or not. A complete
      flower consists of two essential parts, the stamens and
      the pistil, and two floral envelopes, the corolla and
      callyx. In mosses the flowers consist of a few special
      leaves surrounding or subtending organs called archegonia.
      See {Blossom}, and {Corolla}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: If we examine a common flower, such for instance as a
         geranium, we shall find that it consists of: First, an
         outer envelope or calyx, sometimes tubular, sometimes
         consisting of separate leaves called sepals; secondly,
         an inner envelope or corolla, which is generally more
         or less colored, and which, like the calyx, is
         sometimes tubular, sometimes composed of separate
         leaves called petals; thirdly, one or more stamens,
         consisting of a stalk or filament and a head or anther,
         in which the pollen is produced; and fourthly, a
         pistil, which is situated in the center of the flower,
         and consists generally of three principal parts; one or
         more compartments at the base, each containing one or
         more seeds; the stalk or style; and the stigma, which
         in many familiar instances forms a small head, at the
         top of the style or ovary, and to which the pollen must
         find its way in order to fertilize the flower. --Sir J.
         Lubbock.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The fairest, freshest, and choicest part of anything; as,
      the flower of an army, or of a family; the state or time
      of freshness and bloom; as, the flower of life, that is,
      youth.
      [1913 Webster]

            The choice and flower of all things profitable the
            Psalms do more briefly contain.       --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            The flower of the chivalry of all Spain. --Southey.
      [1913 Webster]

            A simple maiden in her flower
            Is worth a hundred coats of arms.     --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Grain pulverized; meal; flour. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The flowers of grains, mixed with water, will make a
            sort of glue.                         --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. (Old Chem.) A substance in the form of a powder,
      especially when condensed from sublimation; as, the
      flowers of sulphur.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A figure of speech; an ornament of style.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. (Print.) Ornamental type used chiefly for borders
      around pages, cards, etc. --W. Savage.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. pl. Menstrual discharges. --Lev. xv. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Animal flower} (Zo["o]l.) See under {Animal}.

   {Cut flowers}, flowers cut from the stalk, as for making a
      bouquet.

   {Flower bed}, a plat in a garden for the cultivation of
      flowers.

   {Flower beetle} (Zo["o]l.), any beetle which feeds upon
      flowers, esp. any one of numerous small species of the
      genus {Meligethes}, family {Nitidulid[ae]}, some of which
      are injurious to crops.

   {Flower bird} (Zo["o]l.), an Australian bird of the genus
      {Anthornis}, allied to the honey eaters.

   {Flower bud}, an unopened flower.

   {Flower clock}, an assemblage of flowers which open and close
      at different hours of the day, thus indicating the time.
      

   {Flower head} (Bot.), a compound flower in which all the
      florets are sessile on their receptacle, as in the case of
      the daisy.

   {Flower pecker} (Zo["o]l.), one of a family ({Dic[ae]id[ae]})
      of small Indian and Australian birds. They resemble
      humming birds in habits.

   {Flower piece}.
      (a) A table ornament made of cut flowers.
      (b) (Fine Arts) A picture of flowers.

   {Flower stalk} (Bot.), the peduncle of a plant, or the stem
      that supports the flower or fructification.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flower</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flower \Flow"er\, v. t.
   To embellish with flowers; to adorn with imitated flowers;
   as, flowered silk.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flower</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flower \Flow"er\ (flou"[~e]r), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Flowered}
   (flou"[~e]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Flowering}.] [From the noun.
   Cf. {Flourish}.]
   1. To blossom; to bloom; to expand the petals, as a plant; to
      produce flowers; as, this plant flowers in June.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To come into the finest or fairest condition.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their lusty and flowering age.        --Robynson
                                                  (More's
                                                  Utopia).
      [1913 Webster]

            When flowered my youthful spring.     --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To froth; to ferment gently, as new beer.
      [1913 Webster]

            That beer did flower a little.        --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To come off as flowers by sublimation. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Observations which have flowered off. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flower</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flower
     n 1: a plant cultivated for its blooms or blossoms
     2: reproductive organ of angiosperm plants especially one
        having showy or colorful parts [syn: {bloom}, {blossom}]
     3: the period of greatest prosperity or productivity [syn: {prime},
         {peak}, {heyday}, {bloom}, {blossom}, {efflorescence}, {flush}]
     v : produce or yield flowers; "The cherry tree bloomed" [syn: {bloom},
          {blossom}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
