<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>flushing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flushing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flushing, MI (city, FIPS 29200)
  Location: 43.06487 N, 83.84164 W
  Population (1990): 8542 (3370 housing units)
  Area: 11.2 sq km (land), 0.1 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 48433
Flushing, NY
  Zip code(s): 11354, 11355, 11358, 11364, 11367, 11371
Flushing, OH (village, FIPS 27552)
  Location: 40.14847 N, 81.06550 W
  Population (1990): 1042 (447 housing units)
  Area: 1.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 43977
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flushing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flashing \Flash"ing\, n.
   1. (Engineering) The creation of an artifical flood by the
      sudden letting in of a body of water; -- called also
      {flushing}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) Pieces of metal, built into the joints of a wall,
      so as to lap over the edge of the gutters or to cover the
      edge of the roofing; also, similar pieces used to cover
      the valleys of roofs of slate, shingles, or the like. By
      extension, the metal covering of ridges and hips of roofs;
      also, in the United States, the protecting of angles and
      breaks in walls of frame houses with waterproof material,
      tarred paper, or the like. Cf. {Filleting}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Glass Making)
      (a) The reheating of an article at the furnace aperture
          during manufacture to restore its plastic condition;
          esp., the reheating of a globe of crown glass to allow
          it to assume a flat shape as it is rotated.
      (b) A mode of covering transparent white glass with a film
          of colored glass. --Knight.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Flashing point} (Chem.), that degree of temperature at which
      a volatile oil gives off vapor in sufficient quantity to
      burn, or flash, on the approach of a flame, used as a test
      of the comparative safety of oils, esp. kerosene; a
      flashing point of 100[deg] F. is regarded as a fairly safe
      standard. The burning point of the oil is usually from ten
      to thirty degree above the flashing point of its vapor.
      Usually called {flash point}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flushing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flush \Flush\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Flushed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Flushing}.] [Cf. OE. fluschen to fly up, penetrate, F. fluz
   a flowing, E. flux, dial. Sw. flossa to blaze, and E. flash;
   perh. influenced by blush. [root]84.]
   1. To flow and spread suddenly; to rush; as, blood flushes
      into the face.
      [1913 Webster]

            The flushing noise of many waters.    --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

            It flushes violently out of the cock. --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To become suddenly suffused, as the cheeks; to turn red;
      to blush.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To snow red; to shine suddenly; to glow.
      [1913 Webster]

            In her cheek, distemper flushing glowed. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To start up suddenly; to take wing as a bird.
      [1913 Webster]

            Flushing from one spray unto another. --W. Browne.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flushing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flushing \Flush"ing\, n.
   1. A heavy, coarse cloth manufactured from shoddy; --
      commonly in the ? [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Weaving) A surface formed of floating threads.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
