<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fly</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FLY-:SPECK:, n.  The prototype of punctuation.  It is observed by
Garvinus that the systems of punctuation in use by the various
literary nations depended originally upon the social habits and
general diet of the flies infesting the several countries.  These
creatures, which have always been distinguished for a neighborly and
companionable familiarity with authors, liberally or niggardly
embellish the manuscripts in process of growth under the pen,
according to their bodily habit, bringing out the sense of the work by
a species of interpretation superior to, and independent of, the
writer's powers.  The "old masters" of literature -- that is to say,
the early writers whose work is so esteemed by later scribes and
critics in the same language -- never punctuated at all, but worked
right along free-handed, without that abruption of the thought which
comes from the use of points.  (We observe the same thing in children
to-day, whose usage in this particular is a striking and beautiful
instance of the law that the infancy of individuals reproduces the
methods and stages of development characterizing the infancy of
races.)  In the work of these primitive scribes all the punctuation is
found, by the modern investigator with his optical instruments and
chemical tests, to have been inserted by the writers' ingenious and
serviceable collaborator, the common house-fly -- _Musca maledicta_. 
In transcribing these ancient MSS, for the purpose of either making
the work their own or preserving what they naturally regard as divine
revelations, later writers reverently and accurately copy whatever
marks they find upon the papyrus or parchment, to the unspeakable
enhancement of the lucidity of the thought and value of the work. 
Writers contemporary with the copyists naturally avail themselves of
the obvious advantages of these marks in their own work, and with such
assistance as the flies of their own household may be willing to
grant, frequently rival and sometimes surpass the older compositions,
in respect at least of punctuation, which is no small glory.  Fully to
understand the important services that flies perform to literature it
is only necessary to lay a page of some popular novelist alongside a
saucer of cream-and-molasses in a sunny room and observe "how the wit
brightens and the style refines" in accurate proportion to the
duration of exposure.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fly
   Heb. zebub, (Eccl. 10:1; Isa. 7:18). This fly was so grievous a
   pest that the Phoenicians invoked against it the aid of their
   god Baal-zebub (q.v.). The prophet Isaiah (7:18) alludes to some
   poisonous fly which was believed to be found on the confines of
   Egypt, and which would be called by the Lord. Poisonous flies
   exist in many parts of Africa, for instance, the different kinds
   of tsetse.
   
     Heb. 'arob, the name given to the insects sent as a plague on
   the land of Egypt (Ex. 8:21-31; Ps. 78:45; 105:31). The LXX.
   render this by a word which means the "dog-fly," the cynomuia.
   The Jewish commentators regarded the Hebrew word here as
   connected with the word _'arab_, which means "mingled;" and they
   accordingly supposed the plague to consist of a mixed multitude
   of animals, beasts, reptiles, and insects. But there is no doubt
   that "the _'arab_" denotes a single definite species. Some
   interpreters regard it as the Blatta orientalis, the cockroach,
   a species of beetle. These insects "inflict very painful bites
   with their jaws; gnaw and destroy clothes, household furniture,
   leather, and articles of every kind, and either consume or
   render unavailable all eatables."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fly \Fly\, n.; pl. {Flies} (fl[imac]z). [OE. flie, flege, AS.
   fl[=y]ge, fle['o]ge, fr. fle['o]gan to fly; akin to D. vlieg,
   OHG. flioga, G. fliege, Icel. &amp; Sw. fluga, Dan. flue. [root]
   84. See {Fly}, v. i.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) Any winged insect; esp., one with transparent wings;
          as, the Spanish fly; firefly; gall fly; dragon fly.
      (b) Any dipterous insect; as, the house fly; flesh fly;
          black fly. See {Diptera}, and Illust. in Append.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A hook dressed in imitation of a fly, -- used for fishing.
      ``The fur-wrought fly.'' --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A familiar spirit; a witch's attendant. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            A trifling fly, none of your great familiars. --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A parasite. [Obs.] --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A kind of light carriage for rapid transit, plying for
      hire and usually drawn by one horse. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The length of an extended flag from its staff; sometimes,
      the length from the ``union'' to the extreme end.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The part of a vane pointing the direction from which the
      wind blows.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Naut.) That part of a compass on which the points are
      marked; the compass card. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mech.)
      (a) Two or more vanes set on a revolving axis, to act as a
          fanner, or to equalize or impede the motion of
          machinery by the resistance of the air, as in the
          striking part of a clock.
      (b) A heavy wheel, or cross arms with weights at the ends
          on a revolving axis, to regulate or equalize the
          motion of machinery by means of its inertia, where the
          power communicated, or the resistance to be overcome,
          is variable, as in the steam engine or the coining
          press. See {Fly wheel} (below).
          [1913 Webster]

   10. (Knitting Machine) The piece hinged to the needle, which
       holds the engaged loop in position while the needle is
       penetrating another loop; a latch. --Knight.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. The pair of arms revolving around the bobbin, in a
       spinning wheel or spinning frame, to twist the yarn.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Weaving) A shuttle driven through the shed by a blow or
       jerk. --Knight.
       [1913 Webster]

   13.
       (a) Formerly, the person who took the printed sheets from
           the press.
       (b) A vibrating frame with fingers, attached to a power
           to a power printing press for doing the same work.
           [1913 Webster]

   14. The outer canvas of a tent with double top, usually drawn
       over the ridgepole, but so extended as to touch the roof
       of the tent at no other place.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. One of the upper screens of a stage in a theater.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. The fore flap of a bootee; also, a lap on trousers,
       overcoats, etc., to conceal a row of buttons.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Baseball) A batted ball that flies to a considerable
       distance, usually high in the air; also, the flight of a
       ball so struck; as, it was caught on the fly. Also called
       {fly ball}. ``a fly deep into right field''
       [1913 Webster +PJC]

   18. (Cotton Manuf.) Waste cotton.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Black fly}, {Cheese fly}, {Dragon fly, etc.} See under
      {Black}, {Cheese}, etc. -- {Fly agaric} (Bot.), a mushroom
      ({Agaricus muscarius}), having a narcotic juice which, in
      sufficient quantities, is poisonous. -- {Fly block}
      (Naut.), a pulley whose position shifts to suit the
      working of the tackle with which it is connected; -- used
      in the hoisting tackle of yards. -- {Fly board} (Printing
      Press), the board on which printed sheets are deposited by
      the fly. -- {Fly book}, a case in the form of a book for
      anglers' flies. --Kingsley.{Fly cap}, a cap with wings,
      formerly worn by women. -- {Fly drill}, a drill having a
      reciprocating motion controlled by a fly wheel, the
      driving power being applied by the hand through a cord
      winding in reverse directions upon the spindle as it
      rotates backward and forward. --Knight.{Fly fishing}, the
      act or art of angling with a bait of natural or artificial
      flies; fishing using a fly[2] as bait. --Walton. -- --
   {Fly fisherman}, one who fishes using natural or artificial
      flies[2] as bait, especially one who fishes exclusively in
      that manner. -- {Fly flap}, an implement for killing
      flies. -- {Fly governor}, a governor for regulating the
      speed of an engine, etc., by the resistance of vanes
      revolving in the air. -- {Fly honeysuckle} (Bot.), a plant
      of the honeysuckle genus ({Lonicera}), having a bushy stem
      and the flowers in pairs, as {L. ciliata} and {L.
      Xylosteum}. -- {Fly hook}, a fishhook supplied with an
      artificial fly. -- {Fly leaf}, an unprinted leaf at the
      beginning or end of a book, circular, programme, etc. --
   {Fly maggot}, a maggot bred from the egg of a fly. --Ray.

   {Fly net}, a screen to exclude insects.

   {Fly nut} (Mach.), a nut with wings; a thumb nut; a finger
      nut.

   {Fly orchis} (Bot.), a plant ({Ophrys muscifera}), whose
      flowers resemble flies.

   {Fly paper}, poisoned or sticky paper for killing flies that
      feed upon or are entangled by it.

   {Fly powder}, an arsenical powder used to poison flies.

   {Fly press}, a screw press for punching, embossing, etc.,
      operated by hand and having a heavy fly.

   {Fly rail}, a bracket which turns out to support the hinged
      leaf of a table.

   {Fly rod}, a light fishing rod used in angling with a fly.

   {Fly sheet}, a small loose advertising sheet; a handbill.

   {Fly snapper} (Zo["o]l.), an American bird ({Phainopepla
      nitens}), allied to the chatterers and shrikes. The male
      is glossy blue-black; the female brownish gray.

   {Fly wheel} (Mach.), a heavy wheel attached to machinery to
      equalize the movement (opposing any sudden acceleration by
      its inertia and any retardation by its momentum), and to
      accumulate or give out energy for a variable or
      intermitting resistance. See {Fly}, n., 9.

   {On the fly} (Baseball), still in the air; -- said of a
      batted ball caught before touching the ground..
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fly \Fly\ (fl[imac]), v. i. [imp. {Flew} (fl[=u]); p. p. {Flown}
   (fl[=o]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Flying}.] [OE. fleen, fleen,
   fleyen, flegen, AS. fle['o]gan; akin to D. vliegen, OHG.
   fliogan, G. fliegen, Icel. flj[=u]ga, Sw. flyga, Dan. flyve,
   Goth. us-flaugjan to cause to fly away, blow about, and perh.
   to L. pluma feather, E. plume. [root]84. Cf. {Fledge},
   {Flight}, {Flock} of animals.]
   1. To move in or pass through the air with wings, as a bird.

   2. To move through the air or before the wind; esp., to pass
      or be driven rapidly through the air by any impulse.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To float, wave, or rise in the air, as sparks or a flag.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man is born unto trouble, as the sparks fly upward.
                                                  --Job v. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To move or pass swiftly; to hasten away; to circulate
      rapidly; as, a ship flies on the deep; a top flies around;
      rumor flies.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fly, envious Time, till thou run out thy race.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The dark waves murmured as the ships flew on.
                                                  --Bryant.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To run from danger; to attempt to escape; to flee; as, an
      enemy or a coward flies. See Note under {Flee}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fly, ere evil intercept thy flight.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whither shall I fly to escape their hands ? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To move suddenly, or with violence; to do an act suddenly
      or swiftly; -- usually with a qualifying word; as, a door
      flies open; a bomb flies apart.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fly about} (Naut.), to change frequently in a short time;
      -- said of the wind.

   {To fly around}, to move about in haste. [Colloq.]

   {To fly at}, to spring toward; to rush on; to attack
      suddenly.

   {To fly in the face of}, to insult; to assail; to set at
      defiance; to oppose with violence; to act in direct
      opposition to; to resist.

   {To fly off}, to separate, or become detached suddenly; to
      revolt.

   {To fly on}, to attack.

   {To fly open}, to open suddenly, or with violence.

   {To fly out}.
      (a) To rush out.
      (b) To burst into a passion; to break out into license.

   {To let fly}.
      (a) To throw or drive with violence; to discharge. ``A man
          lets fly his arrow without taking any aim.''
          --Addison.
      (b) (Naut.) To let go suddenly and entirely; as, to let
          fly the sheets.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fly \Fly\, v. t.
   1. To cause to fly or to float in the air, as a bird, a kite,
      a flag, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            The brave black flag I fly.           --W. S.
                                                  Gilbert.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fly or flee from; to shun; to avoid.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sleep flies the wretch.               --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            To fly the favors of so good a king.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To hunt with a hawk. [Obs.] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To manage (an aircraft) in flight; as, to fly an
      a["e]roplane.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To fly a kite} (Com.), to raise money on commercial notes.
      [Cant or Slang]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fly \Fly\, a.
   Knowing; wide awake; fully understanding another's meaning.
   [Slang] --Dickens.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fly</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fly
     adj : (British informal) not to be deceived or hoodwinked
     n 1: two-winged insects characterized by active flight
     2: flap consisting of a piece of canvas that can be drawn back
        to provide entrance to a tent [syn: {tent-fly}, {rainfly},
         {fly sheet}, {tent flap}]
     3: an opening in a garment that is closed by a zipper or
        buttons concealed by a fold of cloth [syn: {fly front}]
     4: (baseball) a hit that flies up in the air [syn: {fly ball}]
     5: fisherman's lure consisting of a fishhook decorated to look
        like an insect
     v 1: travel through the air; be airborne; "Man cannot fly" [syn:
          {wing}]
     2: move quickly or suddenly; "He flew about the place"
     3: fly a plane [syn: {aviate}, {pilot}]
     4: transport by aeroplane; "We fly flowers from the Caribbean
        to North America"
     5: cause to fly or float; "fly a kite"
     6: be dispersed or disseminated; "Rumors and accusations are
        flying"
     7: change quickly from one emotional state to another; "fly
        into a rage"
     8: pass away rapidly; "Time flies like an arrow"; "Time fleeing
        beneath him" [syn: {fell}, {vanish}]
     9: travel in an airplane; "she is flying to Cincinnati
        tonight"; "Are we driving or flying?"
     10: display in the air or cause to float; "fly a kite"; "All
         nations fly their flags in front of the U.N."
     11: run away quickly; "He threw down his gun and fled" [syn: {flee},
          {take flight}]
     12: travel over (an area of land or sea) in an aircraft;
         "Lindbergh was the first to fly the Atlantic"
     13: hit a fly
     14: decrease rapidly and disappear; "the money vanished in las
         Vegas"; "all my stock assets have vaporized" [syn: {vanish},
          {vaporize}]
     [also: {flown}, {flew}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
