<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>flying</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fly \Fly\ (fl[imac]), v. i. [imp. {Flew} (fl[=u]); p. p. {Flown}
   (fl[=o]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Flying}.] [OE. fleen, fleen,
   fleyen, flegen, AS. fle['o]gan; akin to D. vliegen, OHG.
   fliogan, G. fliegen, Icel. flj[=u]ga, Sw. flyga, Dan. flyve,
   Goth. us-flaugjan to cause to fly away, blow about, and perh.
   to L. pluma feather, E. plume. [root]84. Cf. {Fledge},
   {Flight}, {Flock} of animals.]
   1. To move in or pass through the air with wings, as a bird.

   2. To move through the air or before the wind; esp., to pass
      or be driven rapidly through the air by any impulse.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To float, wave, or rise in the air, as sparks or a flag.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man is born unto trouble, as the sparks fly upward.
                                                  --Job v. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To move or pass swiftly; to hasten away; to circulate
      rapidly; as, a ship flies on the deep; a top flies around;
      rumor flies.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fly, envious Time, till thou run out thy race.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The dark waves murmured as the ships flew on.
                                                  --Bryant.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To run from danger; to attempt to escape; to flee; as, an
      enemy or a coward flies. See Note under {Flee}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fly, ere evil intercept thy flight.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whither shall I fly to escape their hands ? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To move suddenly, or with violence; to do an act suddenly
      or swiftly; -- usually with a qualifying word; as, a door
      flies open; a bomb flies apart.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To fly about} (Naut.), to change frequently in a short time;
      -- said of the wind.

   {To fly around}, to move about in haste. [Colloq.]

   {To fly at}, to spring toward; to rush on; to attack
      suddenly.

   {To fly in the face of}, to insult; to assail; to set at
      defiance; to oppose with violence; to act in direct
      opposition to; to resist.

   {To fly off}, to separate, or become detached suddenly; to
      revolt.

   {To fly on}, to attack.

   {To fly open}, to open suddenly, or with violence.

   {To fly out}.
      (a) To rush out.
      (b) To burst into a passion; to break out into license.

   {To let fly}.
      (a) To throw or drive with violence; to discharge. ``A man
          lets fly his arrow without taking any aim.''
          --Addison.
      (b) (Naut.) To let go suddenly and entirely; as, to let
          fly the sheets.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Flying \Fly"ing\, a. [From {Fly}, v. i.]
   Moving in the air with, or as with, wings; moving lightly or
   rapidly; intended for rapid movement.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Flying army} (Mil.) a body of cavalry and infantry, kept in
      motion, to cover its own garrisons and to keep the enemy
      in continual alarm. --Farrow. 

   {Flying artillery} (Mil.), artillery trained to rapid
      evolutions, -- the men being either mounted or trained to
      spring upon the guns and caissons when they change
      position.

   {Flying bridge}, {Flying camp}. See under {Bridge}, and
      {Camp}.

   {Flying buttress} (Arch.), a contrivance for taking up the
      thrust of a roof or vault which can not be supported by
      ordinary buttresses. It consists of a straight bar of
      masonry, usually sloping, carried on an arch, and a solid
      pier or buttress sufficient to receive the thrust. The
      word is generally applied only to the straight bar with
      supporting arch.

   {Flying colors}, flags unfurled and waving in the air; hence:

   {To come off with flying colors}, to be victorious; to
      succeed thoroughly in an undertaking.

   {Flying doe} (Zo["o]l.), a young female kangaroo.

   {Flying dragon}.
   (a) (Zo["o]l.) See {Dragon}, 6.
   (b) A meteor. See under {Dragon}.

   {Flying Dutchman}.
   (a) A fabled Dutch mariner condemned for his crimes to sail
       the seas till the day of judgment.
   (b) A spectral ship.

   {Flying fish}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Flying fish}, in the
      Vocabulary.

   {Flying fox} (Zo["o]l.), see {Flying fox} in the vocabulary.
      

   {Flying frog} (Zo["o]l.), either of two East Indian tree
      frogs of the genus {Rhacophorus} ({Rhacophorus
      nigrapalmatus} and {Rhacophorus pardalis}), having very
      large and broadly webbed feet, which serve as parachutes,
      and enable it to make very long leaps.

   {Flying gurnard} (Zo["o]l.), a species of gurnard of the
      genus {Cephalacanthus} or {Dactylopterus}, with very large
      pectoral fins, said to be able to fly like the flying
      fish, but not for so great a distance.

   Note: Three species are known; that of the Atlantic is
         {Cephalacanthus volitans}.

   {Flying jib} (Naut.), a sail extended outside of the standing
      jib, on the flying-jib boom.

   {Flying-jib boom} (Naut.), an extension of the jib boom.

   {Flying kites} (Naut.), light sails carried only in fine
      weather.

   {Flying lemur}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Colugo}.

   {Flying level} (Civil Engin.), a reconnoissance level over
      the course of a projected road, canal, etc.

   {Flying lizard}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Dragon}, n. 6.

   {Flying machine}, any apparatus for navigating through the
      air, especially a heavier-than-air machine. -- {Flying
   mouse} (Zo["o]l.), the opossum mouse ({Acrobates
      pygm[ae]us}), a marsupial of Australia. Called also
      {feathertail glider}.

   Note: It has lateral folds of skin, like the flying
         squirrels, and a featherlike tail. -- {Flying party}
      (Mil.), a body of soldiers detailed to hover about an
      enemy. -- {Flying phalanger} (Zo["o]l.), one of several
      species of small marsuupials of the genera {Petaurus} and
      {Belideus}, of Australia and New Guinea, having lateral
      folds like those of the flying squirrels. The sugar
      squirrel ({Belideus sciureus}), and the ariel ({Belideus
      ariel}), are the best known; -- called also {squirrel
      petaurus} and {flying squirrel}. See {Sugar squirrel}. --
   {Flying pinion}, the fly of a clock. -- {Flying sap} (Mil.),
      the rapid construction of trenches (when the enemy's fire
      of case shot precludes the method of simple trenching), by
      means of gabions placed in juxtaposition and filled with
      earth. -- {Flying shot}, a shot fired at a moving object,
      as a bird on the wing. -- {Flying spider}. (Zo["o]l.) See
      {Ballooning spider}. -- {Flying squid} (Zo["o]l.), an
      oceanic squid ({Ommastrephes Bartramii} syn.
      {Sthenoteuthis Bartramii}), abundant in the Gulf Stream,
      which is able to leap out of the water with such force
      that it often falls on the deck of a vessel. -- {Flying
   squirrel} (Zo["o]l.) See {Flying squirrel}, in the
      Vocabulary. -- {Flying start}, a start in a sailing race
      in which the signal is given while the vessels are under
      way. -- {Flying torch} (Mil.), a torch attached to a long
      staff and used for signaling at night.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>flying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>flying
     adj 1: capable of or engaged in flight; "the bat is a flying
            animal"
     2: moving swiftly; "fast-flying planes"; "played the difficult
        passage with flying fingers" [syn: {fast-flying}]
     3: streaming or flapping or spreading wide as if in a current
        of air; "ran quickly, her flaring coat behind her";
        "flying banners"; "flags waving in the breeze" [syn: {aflare},
         {flaring}, {waving}]
     4: designed for swift movement or action; "a flying police
        squad is trained for quick action anywhere in the city"
     5: of or relating to passage through the air especially
        aviation; "a flying time of three hours between cities";
        "unidentified flying objects"
     6: hurried and brief; "paid a flying visit"; "took a flying
        glance at the book"; "a quick inspection"; "a fast visit"
        [syn: {quick}, {fast}]
     7: done swiftly in or as if in the air; used e.g. of a racing
        start in which runners are already in motion as they cross
        the starting line; "a flying start"; "crossed the goal
        line with a flying leap"
     n : an instance of traveling by air; "flying was still an
         exciting adventure for him" [syn: {flight}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
