<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>following</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>following</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Follow \Fol"low\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Followed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Following}.][OE. foluwen, folwen, folgen, AS. folgian,
   fylgean, fylgan; akin to D. volgen, OHG. folg[=e]n, G.
   folgen, Icel. fylgja, Sw. f["o]lja, Dan. f["o]lge, and perh.
   to E. folk.]
   1. To go or come after; to move behind in the same path or
      direction; hence, to go with (a leader, guide, etc.); to
      accompany; to attend.
      [1913 Webster]

            It waves me forth again; I'll follow it. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To endeavor to overtake; to go in pursuit of; to chase; to
      pursue; to prosecute.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will harden the hearts of the Egyptians, and they
            shall follow them.                    --Ex. xiv. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To accept as authority; to adopt the opinions of; to obey;
      to yield to; to take as a rule of action; as, to follow
      good advice.
      [1913 Webster]

            Approve the best, and follow what I approve.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Follow peace with all men.            --Heb. xii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is most agreeable to some men to follow their
            reason; and to others to follow their appetites.
                                                  --J. Edwards.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To copy after; to take as an example.
      [1913 Webster]

            We had rather follow the perfections of them whom we
            like not, than in defects resemble them whom we
            love.                                 --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To succeed in order of time, rank, or office.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To result from, as an effect from a cause, or an inference
      from a premise.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To watch, as a receding object; to keep the eyes fixed
      upon while in motion; to keep the mind upon while in
      progress, as a speech, musical performance, etc.; also, to
      keep up with; to understand the meaning, connection, or
      force of, as of a course of thought or argument.
      [1913 Webster]

            He followed with his eyes the flitting shade.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To walk in, as a road or course; to attend upon closely,
      as a profession or calling.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, had I but followed the arts!       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            O Antony! I have followed thee to this. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Follow board} (Founding), a board on which the pattern and
      the flask lie while the sand is rammed into the flask.
      --Knight.

   {To follow the hounds}, to hunt with dogs.

   {To follow suit} (Card Playing), to play a card of the same
      suit as the leading card; hence, colloquially, to follow
      an example set.

   {To follow up}, to pursue indefatigably.

   Syn: Syn.- To pursue; chase; go after; attend; accompany;
        succeed; imitate; copy; embrace; maintain.

   Usage: - To {Follow}, {Pursue}. To follow (v.t.) denotes
          simply to go after; to pursue denotes to follow with
          earnestness, and with a view to attain some definite
          object; as, a hound pursues the deer. So a person
          follows a companion whom he wishes to overtake on a
          journey; the officers of justice pursue a felon who
          has escaped from prison.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>following</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Following \Fol"low*ing\, n.
   1. One's followers, adherents, or dependents, collectively.
      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Vocation; business; profession.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>following</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Following \Fol"low*ing\, a.
   1. Next after; succeeding; ensuing; as, the assembly was held
      on the following day.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Astron.) (In the field of a telescope) In the direction
      from which stars are apparently moving (in consequence of
      the earth's rotation); as, a small star, north following
      or south following. In the direction toward which stars
      appear to move is called preceding.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The four principal directions in the field of a
         telescope are north, south, following, preceding.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>following</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>following
     adj 1: going or proceeding or coming after in the same direction;
            "the crowd of following cars made the occasion seem
            like a parade"; "tried to outrun the following
            footsteps" [ant: {leading}]
     2: in the desired direction; "a following wind" [syn: {following(a)}]
     3: immediately following in time or order; "the following day";
        "next in line"; "the next president"; "the next item on
        the list" [syn: {next}]
     4: about to be mentioned or specified; "the following items"
        [syn: {following(a)}, {undermentioned}]
     n 1: a group of followers or enthusiasts [syn: {followers}]
     2: the act of pursuing in an effort to overtake or capture;
        "the culprit started to run and the cop took off in
        pursuit" [syn: {pursuit}, {chase}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
