<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>food</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>food</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Food
   Originally the Creator granted the use of the vegetable world
   for food to man (Gen. 1:29), with the exception mentioned
   (2:17). The use of animal food was probably not unknown to the
   antediluvians. There is, however, a distinct law on the subject
   given to Noah after the Deluge (Gen. 9:2-5). Various articles of
   food used in the patriarchal age are mentioned in Gen. 18:6-8;
   25:34; 27:3, 4; 43:11. Regarding the food of the Israelites in
   Egypt, see Ex. 16:3; Num. 11:5. In the wilderness their ordinary
   food was miraculously supplied in the manna. They had also
   quails (Ex. 16:11-13; Num. 11:31).
   
     In the law of Moses there are special regulations as to the
   animals to be used for food (Lev. 11; Deut. 14:3-21). The Jews
   were also forbidden to use as food anything that had been
   consecrated to idols (Ex. 34:15), or animals that had died of
   disease or had been torn by wild beasts (Ex. 22:31; Lev. 22:8).
   (See also for other restrictions Ex. 23:19; 29:13-22; Lev.
   3:4-9; 9:18, 19; 22:8; Deut. 14:21.) But beyond these
   restrictions they had a large grant from God (Deut. 14:26;
   32:13, 14).
   
     Food was prepared for use in various ways. The cereals were
   sometimes eaten without any preparation (Lev. 23:14; Deut.
   23:25; 2 Kings 4:42). Vegetables were cooked by boiling (Gen.
   25:30, 34; 2 Kings 4:38, 39), and thus also other articles of
   food were prepared for use (Gen. 27:4; Prov. 23:3; Ezek. 24:10;
   Luke 24:42; John 21:9). Food was also prepared by roasting (Ex.
   12:8; Lev. 2:14). (See {COOK}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>food</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Food \Food\, v. t.
   To supply with food. [Obs.] --Baret.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>food</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Food \Food\, n. [OE. fode, AS. f[=o]da; akin to Icel.
   f[ae][eth]a, f[ae][eth]i, Sw. f["o]da, Dan. &amp; LG. f["o]de,
   OHG. fatunga, Gr. patei^sthai to eat, and perh. to Skr. p[=a]
   to protect, L. pascere to feed, pasture, pabulum food, E.
   pasture. [root]75. Cf. {Feed}, {Fodder} food, {Foster} to
   cherish.]
   1. What is fed upon; that which goes to support life by being
      received within, and assimilated by, the organism of an
      animal or a plant; nutriment; aliment; especially, what is
      eaten by animals for nourishment.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In a physiological sense, true aliment is to be
         distinguished as that portion of the food which is
         capable of being digested and absorbed into the blood,
         thus furnishing nourishment, in distinction from the
         indigestible matter which passes out through the
         alimentary canal as f[ae]ces.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: Foods are divided into two main groups: nitrogenous, or
         proteid, foods, i.e., those which contain nitrogen, and
         nonnitrogenous, i.e., those which do not contain
         nitrogen. The latter group embraces the fats and
         carbohydrates, which collectively are sometimes termed
         heat producers or respiratory foods, since by oxidation
         in the body they especially subserve the production of
         heat. The proteids, on the other hand, are known as
         plastic foods or tissue formers, since no tissue can be
         formed without them. These latter terms, however, are
         misleading, since proteid foods may also give rise to
         heat both directly and indirectly, and the fats and
         carbohydrates are useful in other ways than in
         producing heat.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything that instructs the intellect, excites the
      feelings, or molds habits of character; that which
      nourishes.
      [1913 Webster]

            This may prove food to my displeasure. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In this moment there is life and food
            For future years.                     --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Food is often used adjectively or in self-explaining
         compounds, as in food fish or food-fish, food supply.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Food vacuole} (Zo["o]l.), one of the spaces in the interior
      of a protozoan in which food is contained, during
      digestion.

   {Food yolk}. (Biol.) See under {Yolk}.

   Syn: Aliment; sustenance; nutriment; feed; fare; victuals;
        provisions; meat.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>food</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Food

Ethnic. Spicy. Oriental, esp. Chinese and most esp. Szechuan, Hunan, and
Mandarin (hackers consider Cantonese vaguely de'classe'). Hackers prefer
the exotic; for example, the Japanese-food fans among them will eat with
gusto such delicacies as fugu (poisonous pufferfish) and whale. Thai food
has experienced flurries of popularity. Where available, high-quality
Jewish delicatessen food is much esteemed. A visible minority of
Southwestern and Pacific Coast hackers prefers Mexican.

For those all-night hacks, pizza and microwaved burritos are big.
Interestingly, though the mainstream culture has tended to think of hackers
as incorrigible junk-food junkies, many have at least mildly health-foodist
attitudes and are fairly discriminating about what they eat. This may be
generational; anecdotal evidence suggests that the stereotype was more on
the mark before the early 1980s.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>food</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>food
     n 1: any substance that can be metabolized by an organism to give
          energy and build tissue [syn: {nutrient}]
     2: any solid substance (as opposed to liquid) that is used as a
        source of nourishment; "food and drink"
     3: anything that provides mental stimulus for thinking [syn: {food
        for thought}, {intellectual nourishment}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
