<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>force</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FORCE, n.

    "Force is but might," the teacher said --
        "That definition's just."
    The boy said naught but through instead,
    Remembering his pounded head:
        "Force is not might but must!"


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Force
     
        A {dBASE} dialect for {MS-DOS}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Force \Force\, v. t. [See {Farce} to stuff.]
   To stuff; to lard; to farce. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Wit larded with malice, and malice forced with wit.
                                                  --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Force \Force\, n. [Of Scand. origin; cf. Icel. fors, foss, Dan.
   fos.]
   A waterfall; a cascade. [Prov. Eng.]
   [1913 Webster]

         To see the falls for force of the river Kent. --T.
                                                  Gray.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Force \Force\, n. [F. force, LL. forcia, fortia, fr. L. fortis
   strong. See {Fort}, n.]
   1. Capacity of exercising an influence or producing an
      effect; strength or energy of body or mind; active power;
      vigor; might; often, an unusual degree of strength or
      energy; especially, power to persuade, or convince, or
      impose obligation; pertinency; validity; special
      signification; as, the force of an appeal, an argument, a
      contract, or a term.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was, in the full force of the words, a good man.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Power exerted against will or consent; compulsory power;
      violence; coercion; as, by force of arms; to take by
      force.
      [1913 Webster]

            Which now they hold by force, and not by right.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Strength or power for war; hence, a body of land or naval
      combatants, with their appurtenances, ready for action; --
      an armament; troops; warlike array; -- often in the
      plural; hence, a body of men prepared for action in other
      ways; as, the laboring force of a plantation; the armed
      forces.
      [1913 Webster]

            Is Lucius general of the forces?      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law)
      (a) Strength or power exercised without law, or contrary
          to law, upon persons or things; violence.
      (b) Validity; efficacy. --Burrill.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Physics) Any action between two bodies which changes, or
      tends to change, their relative condition as to rest or
      motion; or, more generally, which changes, or tends to
      change, any physical relation between them, whether
      mechanical, thermal, chemical, electrical, magnetic, or of
      any other kind; as, the force of gravity; cohesive force;
      centrifugal force.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Animal force} (Physiol.), muscular force or energy.

   {Catabiotic force} [Gr. ? down (intens.) + ? life.] (Biol.),
      the influence exerted by living structures on adjoining
      cells, by which the latter are developed in harmony with
      the primary structures.

   {Centrifugal force}, {Centripetal force}, {Coercive force},
      etc. See under {Centrifugal}, {Centripetal}, etc.

   {Composition of forces}, {Correlation of forces}, etc. See
      under {Composition}, {Correlation}, etc.

   {Force and arms} [trans. of L. vi et armis] (Law), an
      expression in old indictments, signifying violence.

   {In force}, or {Of force}, of unimpaired efficacy; valid; of
      full virtue; not suspended or reversed. ``A testament is
      of force after men are dead.'' --Heb. ix. 17.

   {Metabolic force} (Physiol.), the influence which causes and
      controls the metabolism of the body.

   {No force}, no matter of urgency or consequence; no account;
      hence, to do no force, to make no account of; not to heed.
      [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {Of force}, of necessity; unavoidably; imperatively. ``Good
      reasons must, of force, give place to better.'' --Shak.

   {Plastic force} (Physiol.), the force which presumably acts
      in the growth and repair of the tissues.

   {Vital force} (Physiol.), that force or power which is
      inherent in organization; that form of energy which is the
      cause of the vital phenomena of the body, as distinguished
      from the physical forces generally known.

   Syn: Strength; vigor; might; energy; stress; vehemence;
        violence; compulsion; coaction; constraint; coercion.

   Usage: {Force}, {Strength}. Strength looks rather to power as
          an inward capability or energy. Thus we speak of the
          strength of timber, bodily strength, mental strength,
          strength of emotion, etc. Force, on the other hand,
          looks more to the outward; as, the force of
          gravitation, force of circumstances, force of habit,
          etc. We do, indeed, speak of strength of will and
          force of will; but even here the former may lean
          toward the internal tenacity of purpose, and the
          latter toward the outward expression of it in action.
          But, though the two words do in a few cases touch thus
          closely on each other, there is, on the whole, a
          marked distinction in our use of force and strength.
          ``Force is the name given, in mechanical science, to
          whatever produces, or can produce, motion.'' --Nichol.
          [1913 Webster]

                Thy tears are of no force to mollify
                This flinty man.                  --Heywood.
          [1913 Webster]

                More huge in strength than wise in works he was.
                                                  --Spenser.
          [1913 Webster]

                Adam and first matron Eve
                Had ended now their orisons, and found
                Strength added from above, new hope to spring
                Out of despair.                   --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Force \Force\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Forced}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Forcing}.] [OF. forcier, F. forcer, fr. LL. forciare,
   fortiare. See {Force}, n.]
   1. To constrain to do or to forbear, by the exertion of a
      power not resistible; to compel by physical, moral, or
      intellectual means; to coerce; as, masters force slaves to
      labor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To compel, as by strength of evidence; as, to force
      conviction on the mind.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To do violence to; to overpower, or to compel by violence
      to one's will; especially, to ravish; to violate; to
      commit rape upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            To force their monarch and insult the court.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            I should have forced thee soon wish other arms.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            To force a spotless virgin's chastity. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To obtain, overcome, or win by strength; to take by
      violence or struggle; specifically, to capture by assault;
      to storm, as a fortress; as, to force the castle; to force
      a lock.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To impel, drive, wrest, extort, get, etc., by main
      strength or violence; -- with a following adverb, as
      along, away, from, into, through, out, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            It stuck so fast, so deeply buried lay
            That scarce the victor forced the steel away.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            To force the tyrant from his seat by war. --Sahk.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ethelbert ordered that none should be forced into
            religion.                             --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To put in force; to cause to be executed; to make binding;
      to enforce. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            What can the church force more?       --J. Webster.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To exert to the utmost; to urge; hence, to strain; to urge
      to excessive, unnatural, or untimely action; to produce by
      unnatural effort; as, to force a conceit or metaphor; to
      force a laugh; to force fruits.
      [1913 Webster]

            High on a mounting wave my head I bore,
            Forcing my strength, and gathering to the shore.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Whist) To compel (an adversary or partner) to trump a
      trick by leading a suit of which he has none.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To provide with forces; to re["e]nforce; to strengthen by
      soldiers; to man; to garrison. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To allow the force of; to value; to care for. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

             For me, I force not argument a straw. --Shak.

   Syn: To compel; constrain; oblige; necessitate; coerce;
        drive; press; impel.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Force \Force\, v. i. [Obs. in all the senses.]
   1. To use violence; to make violent effort; to strive; to
      endeavor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Forcing with gifts to win his wanton heart.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make a difficult matter of anything; to labor; to
      hesitate; hence, to force of, to make much account of; to
      regard.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your oath once broke, you force not to forswear.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I force not of such fooleries.        --Camden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be of force, importance, or weight; to matter.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is not sufficient to have attained the name and
            dignity of a shepherd, not forcing how. --Udall.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>force</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>force
     n 1: a unit that is part of some military service; "he sent
          Caesar a force of six thousand men" [syn: {military unit},
           {military force}, {military group}]
     2: one possessing or exercising power or influence or
        authority; "the mysterious presence of an evil power";
        "may the force be with you"; "the forces of evil" [syn: {power}]
     3: (physics) the influence that produces a change in a physical
        quantity; "force equals mass times acceleration"
     4: group of people willing to obey orders; "a public force is
        necessary to give security to the rights of citizens"
        [syn: {personnel}]
     5: a powerful effect or influence; "the force of his eloquence
        easily persuaded them"
     6: an act of aggression (as one against a person who resists);
        "he may accomplish by craft in the long run what he cannot
        do by force and violence in the short one" [syn: {violence}]
     7: physical energy or intensity; "he hit with all the force he
        could muster"; "it was destroyed by the strength of the
        gale"; "a government has not the vitality and forcefulness
        of a living man" [syn: {forcefulness}, {strength}]
     8: a group of people having the power of effective action; "he
        joined forces with a band of adventurers"
     9: (of a law) having legal validity; "the law is still in
        effect" [syn: {effect}]
     v 1: to cause to do through pressure or necessity, by physical,
          moral or intellectual means :"She forced him to take a
          job in the city"; "He squeezed her for information"
          [syn: {coerce}, {hale}, {squeeze}, {pressure}]
     2: urge or force (a person) to an action; constrain or motivate
        [syn: {impel}]
     3: move with force, "He pushed the table into a corner" [syn: {push}]
        [ant: {pull}]
     4: impose or thrust urgently, importunately, or inexorably;
        "She forced her diet fads on him" [syn: {thrust}]
     5: squeeze like a wedge into a tight space; "I squeezed myself
        into the corner" [syn: {wedge}, {squeeze}]
     6: force into or from an action or state, either physically or
        metaphorically; "She rammed her mind into focus"; "He
        drives me mad" [syn: {drive}, {ram}]
     7: do forcibly; exert force; "Don't force it!"
     8: cause to move along the ground by pulling; "draw a wagon";
        "pull a sled" [syn: {pull}, {draw}] [ant: {push}]
     9: take by force; "Storm the fort" [syn: {storm}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
