<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>foreign</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>foreign</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Foreign \For"eign\, a. [OE. forein, F. forain, LL. foraneus, fr.
   L. foras, foris, out of doors, abroad, without; akin to fores
   doors, and E. door. See {Door}, and cf. {Foreclose},
   {Forfeit}, {Forest}, {Forum}.]
   1. Outside; extraneous; separated; alien; as, a foreign
      country; a foreign government. ``Foreign worlds.''
      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not native or belonging to a certain country; born in or
      belonging to another country, nation, sovereignty, or
      locality; as, a foreign language; foreign fruits.
      ``Domestic and foreign writers.'' --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hail, foreign wonder!
            Whom certain these rough shades did never breed.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Remote; distant; strange; not belonging; not connected;
      not pertaining or pertient; not appropriate; not
      harmonious; not agreeable; not congenial; -- with to or
      from; as, foreign to the purpose; foreign to one's nature.
      [1913 Webster]

            This design is not foreign from some people's
            thoughts.                             --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Held at a distance; excluded; exiled. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Kept him a foreign man still; which so grieved him,
            That he ran mad and died.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Foreign attachment} (Law), a process by which the property
      of a foreign or absent debtor is attached for the
      satisfaction of a debt due from him to the plaintiff; an
      attachment of the goods, effects, or credits of a debtor
      in the hands of a third person; -- called in some States
      trustee, in others factorizing, and in others garnishee
      process. --Kent. --Tomlins. --Cowell.

   {Foreign bill}, a bill drawn in one country, and payable in
      another, as distinguished from an inland bill, which is
      one drawn and payable in the same country. In this latter,
      as well as in several other points of view, the different
      States of the United States are foreign to each other. See
      {Exchange}, n., 4. --Kent. --Story.

   {Foreign body} (Med.), a substance occurring in any part of
      the body where it does not belong, and usually introduced
      from without.

   {Foreign office}, that department of the government of Great
      Britain which has charge British interests in foreign
      countries.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Outlandish; alien; exotic; remote; distant; extraneous;
        extrinsic.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>foreign</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>foreign
     adj 1: of concern to or concerning the affairs of other nations
            (other than your own); "foreign trade"; "a foreign
            office" [ant: {domestic}]
     2: relating to or originating in or characteristic of another
        place or part of the world; "foreign nations"; "a foreign
        accent"; "on business in a foreign city" [ant: {native}]
     3: not contained in or deriving from the essential nature of
        something; "an economic theory alien to the spirit of
        capitalism"; "the mysticism so foreign to the French mind
        and temper"; "jealousy is foreign to her nature" [syn: {alien}]
     4: not belonging to that in which it is contained; introduced
        from an outside source; "water free of extraneous matter";
        "foreign particles in milk" [syn: {extraneous}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
