<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fore</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fore</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fore \Fore\ (f[=o]r), a. [See {Fore}, adv.]
   Advanced, as compared with something else; toward the front;
   being or coming first, in time, place, order, or importance;
   preceding; anterior; antecedent; earlier; forward; -- opposed
   to {back} or {behind}; as, the fore part of a garment; the
   fore part of the day; the fore and of a wagon.
   [1913 Webster]

         The free will of the subject is preserved, while it is
         directed by the fore purpose of the state. --Southey.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Fore is much used adjectively or in composition.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Fore bay}, a reservoir or canal between a mill race and a
      water wheel; the discharging end of a pond or mill race.
      

   {Fore body} (Shipbuilding), the part of a ship forward of the
      largest cross-section, distinguished from {middle body}
      and {after body}.

   {Fore boot}, a receptacle in the front of a vehicle, for
      stowing baggage, etc.

   {Fore bow}, the pommel of a saddle. --Knight.

   {Fore cabin}, a cabin in the fore part of a ship, usually
      with inferior accommodations.

   {Fore carriage}.
   (a) The forward part of the running gear of a four-wheeled
       vehicle.
   (b) A small carriage at the front end of a plow beam.

   {Fore course} (Naut.), the lowermost sail on the foremost of
      a square-rigged vessel; the foresail. See Illust. under
      {Sail}.

   {Fore door}. Same as {Front door}.

   {Fore edge}, the front edge of a book or folded sheet, etc.
      

   {Fore elder}, an ancestor. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Fore end}.
   (a) The end which precedes; the earlier, or the nearer, part;
       the beginning.
       [1913 Webster]

             I have . . . paid
             More pious debts to heaven, than in all
             The fore end of my time.             --Shak.
   (b) In firearms, the wooden stock under the barrel, forward
       of the trigger guard, or breech frame.

   {Fore girth}, a girth for the fore part (of a horse, etc.); a
      martingale.

   {Fore hammer}, a sledge hammer, working alternately, or in
      time, with the hand hammer.

   {Fore leg}, one of the front legs of a quadruped, or
      multiped, or of a chair, settee, etc.

   {Fore peak} (Naut.), the angle within a ship's bows; the
      portion of the hold which is farthest forward.

   {Fore piece}, a front piece, as the flap in the fore part of
      a sidesaddle, to guard the rider's dress.

   {Fore plane}, a carpenter's plane, in size and use between a
      jack plane and a smoothing plane. --Knight.

   {Fore reading}, previous perusal. [Obs.] --Hales.

   {Fore rent}, in Scotland, rent payable before a crop is
      gathered.

   {Fore sheets} (Naut.), the forward portion of a rowboat; the
      space beyond the front thwart. See {Stern sheets}.

   {Fore shore}.
   (a) A bank in advance of a sea wall, to break the force of
       the surf.
   (b) The seaward projecting, slightly inclined portion of a
       breakwater. --Knight.
   (c) The part of the shore between high and low water marks.
       

   {Fore sight}, that one of the two sights of a gun which is
      near the muzzle.

   {Fore tackle} (Naut.), the tackle on the foremast of a ship.
      

   {Fore topmast}. (Naut.) See {Fore-topmast}, in the
      Vocabulary.

   {Fore wind}, a favorable wind. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Sailed on smooth seas, by fore winds borne.
                                                  --Sandys.

   {Fore world}, the antediluvian world. [R.] --Southey.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fore</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fore \Fore\ (f[=o]r), n. [AS. f[=o]r, fr. faran to go. See
   {Fare}, v. i.]
   Journey; way; method of proceeding. [Obs.] ``Follow him and
   his fore.'' --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fore</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fore \Fore\, adv. [AS. fore, adv. &amp; prep., another form of for.
   See {For}, and cf. {Former}, {Foremost}.]
   1. In the part that precedes or goes first; -- opposed to
      aft, after, back, behind, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Formerly; previously; afore. [Obs. or Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The eyes, fore duteous, now converted are. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) In or towards the bows of a ship.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fore and aft} (Naut.), from stem to stern; lengthwise of the
      vessel; -- in distinction from athwart. --R. H. Dana, Jr.

   {Fore-and-aft rigged} (Naut.), not rigged with square sails
      attached to yards, but with sails bent to gaffs or set on
      stays in the midship line of the vessel. See {Schooner},
      {Sloop}, {Cutter}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fore</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fore \Fore\, n.
   The front; hence, that which is in front; the future.
   [1913 Webster]

   {At the fore} (Naut.), at the fore royal masthead; -- said of
      a flag, so raised as a signal for sailing, etc.

   {To the fore}.
   (a) In advance; to the front; to a prominent position; in
       plain sight; in readiness for use.
   (b) In existence; alive; not worn out, lost, or spent, as
       money, etc. [Irish] ``While I am to the fore.'' --W.
       Collins. ``How many captains in the regiment had two
       thousand pounds to the fore?'' --Thackeray.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fore</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fore \Fore\, prep.
   Before; -- sometimes written 'fore as if a contraction of
   afore or before. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fore</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fore
     adj 1: situated at or toward the bow of a vessel [syn: {fore(a)}]
            [ant: {aft(a)}]
     2: located anteriorly [syn: {fore(a)}, {front(a)}]
     n : front part of a vessel or aircraft; "he pointed the bow of
         the boat toward the finish line" [syn: {bow}, {prow}, {stem}]
     adv : near or toward the bow of a ship or cockpit of a plane; "the
           captain went fore (or forward) to check the
           instruments" [syn: {forward}] [ant: {aft}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
