<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>format</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>format</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Format \For`mat"\ (f[-o]r`m[.a]" or f[-o]r`m[aum]t"), n. [F. or
   G. Cf. {Formation}.]
   1. (Print.) The shape and size of a book or other printed
      publication; hence, its external form. [WordNet sense 2]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

            The older manuscripts had been written in a much
            larger format than that found convenient for
            university work.                      --G. H.
                                                  Putnam.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

            One might, indeed, protest that the format is a
            little too luxurious.                 --Nature.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. (Print.) the arrangement of the parts of a printed page,
      such as text and graphics; as, text flowing around an
      illustration provides a more pleasing format; multiple
      columns are a more common format for large pages.
      [PJC]

   3. (Computers) The pattern of organization of information in
      an electronic storage medium, such as the number and size
      of records, or the size, spacing, or separation symbols
      for fields in a record. A computer file, for example, may
      be in fixed-length format, in which each field or record
      occupies the same number of bytes, or in variable-length
      format, in which the lengths of fields or records varies.
      The number of formats are unlimited, being specifiable at
      will by programmers or in some cases by the users of
      programs. [WordNet sense 1]

   Syn: data format.
        [PJC]

   4. Hence, The general organization, form, or plan for
      anything, such as an organized social, political, or
      entertainment event.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>format</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>format \format\ v. t.
   to set into a specific format; -- of printed matter or data
   recorded on a data soorage medium.

   Syn: arrange.
        [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>format</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>format
     n 1: the organization of information according to preset
          specifications (usually for computer processing) [syn: {formatting},
           {data format}, {data formatting}]
     2: the general appearance of a publication
     v 1: set (printed matter) into a specific format; "Format this
          letter so it can be printed out" [syn: {arrange}]
     2: determine the arrangement of (data) for storage and display
        (in computer science)
     3: divide (a disk) into marked sectors so that it may store
        data; "Please format this disk before entering data!"
        [syn: {initialize}, {initialise}]
     [also: {formatting}, {formatted}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
