<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>form</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>form</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FORM
     
        &lt;mathematics, tool&gt; A system written by Jos Vermaseren
        &lt;t68@nikhefh.nikhef.nl&gt; in 1989 for fast handling of very
        large-scale {symbolic mathematics} problems.  FORM is a
        descendant of {Schoonschip} and is available for many
        {personal computer}s and {workstation}s.
     
        {(ftp://acm.princeton.edu/)}, {(ftp://nikhefh.nikhef.nl/)}.
     
        Mailing list: &lt;form@can.nl&gt;.
     
        (1995-04-12)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>form</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Form \Form\ (f[=o]rm; in senses 8 &amp; 9, often f[=o]rm in
   England), n. [OE. &amp; F. forme, fr. L. forma; cf. Skr.
   dhariman. Cf. {Firm}.]
   1. The shape and structure of anything, as distinguished from
      the material of which it is composed; particular
      disposition or arrangement of matter, giving it
      individuality or distinctive character; configuration;
      figure; external appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            The form of his visage was changed.   --Dan. iii.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

            And woven close close, both matter, form, and style.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Constitution; mode of construction, organization, etc.;
      system; as, a republican form of government.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Established method of expression or practice; fixed way of
      proceeding; conventional or stated scheme; formula; as, a
      form of prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those whom form of laws
            Condemned to die.                     --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Show without substance; empty, outside appearance; vain,
      trivial, or conventional ceremony; conventionality;
      formality; as, a matter of mere form.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though well we may not pass upon his life
            Without the form of justice.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Orderly arrangement; shapeliness; also, comeliness;
      elegance; beauty.
      [1913 Webster]

            The earth was without form and void.  --Gen. i. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hath no form nor comeliness.       --Is. liii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A shape; an image; a phantom.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. That by which shape is given or determined; mold; pattern;
      model.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A long seat; a bench; hence, a rank of students in a
      school; a class; also, a class or rank in society.
      ``Ladies of a high form.'' --Bp. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The seat or bed of a hare.
      [1913 Webster]

            As in a form sitteth a weary hare.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Print.) The type or other matter from which an
       impression is to be taken, arranged and secured in a
       chase.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Fine Arts) The boundary line of a material object. In
       (painting), more generally, the human body.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Gram.) The particular shape or structure of a word or
       part of speech; as, participial forms; verbal forms.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Crystallog.) The combination of planes included under a
       general crystallographic symbol. It is not necessarily a
       closed solid.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Metaph.) That assemblage or disposition of qualities
       which makes a conception, or that internal constitution
       which makes an existing thing to be what it is; -- called
       essential or substantial form, and contradistinguished
       from matter; hence, active or formative nature; law of
       being or activity; subjectively viewed, an idea;
       objectively, a law.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. Mode of acting or manifestation to the senses, or the
       intellect; as, water assumes the form of ice or snow. In
       modern usage, the elements of a conception furnished by
       the mind's own activity, as contrasted with its object or
       condition, which is called the matter; subjectively, a
       mode of apprehension or belief conceived as dependent on
       the constitution of the mind; objectively, universal and
       necessary accompaniments or elements of every object
       known or thought of.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. (Biol.) The peculiar characteristics of an organism as a
       type of others; also, the structure of the parts of an
       animal or plant.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Good form} or {Bad form}, the general appearance, condition
      or action, originally of horses, afterwards of persons;
      as, the members of a boat crew are said to be in good form
      when they pull together uniformly. The phrases are further
      used colloquially in description of conduct or manners in
      society; as, it is not good form to smoke in the presence
      of a lady.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>form</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-form \-form\ [See {Form}, n.]
   A suffix used to denote in the form or shape of, resembling,
   etc.; as, valiform; oviform.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>form</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Form \Form\ (f[^o]rm), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Formed} (f[^o]rmd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Forming}.] [F. former, L. formare, fr.
   forma. See {Form}, n.]
   1. To give form or shape to; to frame; to construct; to make;
      to fashion.
      [1913 Webster]

            God formed man of the dust of the ground. --Gen. ii.
                                                  7.
      [1913 Webster]

            The thought that labors in my forming brain. --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give a particular shape to; to shape, mold, or fashion
      into a certain state or condition; to arrange; to adjust;
      also, to model by instruction and discipline; to mold by
      influence, etc.; to train.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is education forms the common mind. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus formed for speed, he challenges the wind.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To go to make up; to act as constituent of; to be the
      essential or constitutive elements of; to answer for; to
      make the shape of; -- said of that out of which anything
      is formed or constituted, in whole or in part.
      [1913 Webster]

            The diplomatic politicians . . . who formed by far
            the majority.                         --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To provide with a form, as a hare. See {Form}, n., 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            The melancholy hare is formed in brakes and briers.
                                                  --Drayton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Gram.) To derive by grammatical rules, as by adding the
      proper suffixes and affixes.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Elec.) To treat (plates) so as to bring them to fit
      condition for introduction into a storage battery, causing
      one plate to be composed more or less of spongy lead, and
      the other of lead peroxide. This was formerly done by
      repeated slow alternations of the charging current, but
      now the plates or grids are coated or filled, one with a
      paste of red lead and the other with litharge, introduced
      into the cell, and formed by a direct charging current.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>form</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Form \Form\, v. i.
   1. To take a form, definite shape, or arrangement; as, the
      infantry should form in column.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To run to a form, as a hare. --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To form on} (Mil.), to form a lengthened line with reference
      to (any given object) as a basis.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>form</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>form
     n 1: the phonological or orthographic sound or appearance of a
          word that can be used to describe or identify something;
          "the inflected forms of a word can be represented by a
          stem and a list of inflections to be attached" [syn: {word
          form}, {signifier}, {descriptor}]
     2: a category of things distinguished by some common
        characteristic or quality; "sculpture is a form of art";
        "what kinds of desserts are there?" [syn: {kind}, {sort},
        {variety}]
     3: a perceptual structure; "the composition presents problems
        for students of musical form"; "a visual pattern must
        include not only objects but the spaces between them"
        [syn: {shape}, {pattern}]
     4: any spatial attributes (especially as defined by outline);
        "he could barely make out their shapes through the smoke"
        [syn: {shape}, {configuration}, {contour}, {conformation}]
     5: alternative names for the body of a human being; "Leonardo
        studied the human body"; "he has a strong physique"; "the
        spirit is willing but the flesh is weak" [syn: {human body},
         {physical body}, {material body}, {soma}, {build}, {figure},
         {physique}, {anatomy}, {shape}, {bod}, {chassis}, {frame},
         {flesh}]
     6: the spatial arrangement of something as distinct from its
        substance; "geometry is the mathematical science of shape"
        [syn: {shape}]
     7: the visual appearance of something or someone; "the delicate
        cast of his features" [syn: {shape}, {cast}]
     8: (physical chemistry) a distinct state of matter in a system;
        matter that is identical in chemical composition and
        physical state and separated from other material by the
        phase boundary; "the reaction occurs in the liquid phase
        of the system" [syn: {phase}]
     9: a printed document with spaces in which to write; "he filled
        out his tax form"
     10: (biology) a group of organisms within a species that differ
         in trivial ways from similar groups; "a new strain of
         microorganisms" [syn: {variant}, {strain}, {var.}]
     11: an arrangement of the elements in a composition or
         discourse; "the essay was in the form of a dialogue"; "he
         first sketches the plot in outline form"
     12: a particular mode in which something is manifested; "his
         resentment took the form of extreme hostility"
     13: a body of students who are taught together; "early morning
         classes are always sleepy" [syn: {class}, {grade}]
     14: an ability to perform well; "he was at the top of his form";
         "the team was off form last night"
     15: a life-size dummy used to display clothes [syn: {mannequin},
          {manikin}, {mannikin}, {manakin}]
     16: a mold for setting concrete; "they built elaborate forms for
         pouring the foundation"
     v 1: to compose or represent:"This wall forms the background of
          the stage setting"; "The branches made a roof"; "This
          makes a fine introduction" [syn: {constitute}, {make}]
     2: create (as an entity); "social groups form everywhere";
        "They formed a company" [syn: {organize}, {organise}]
     3: develop into a distinctive entity; "our plans began to take
        shape" [syn: {take form}, {take shape}, {spring}]
     4: give a shape or form to; "shape the dough" [syn: {shape}]
     5: make something, usually for a specific function; "She molded
        the riceballs carefully"; "Form cylinders from the dough";
        "shape a figure"; "Work the metal into a sword" [syn: {shape},
         {work}, {mold}, {mould}, {forge}]
     6: establish or impress firmly in the mind; "We imprint our
        ideas onto our children" [syn: {imprint}]
     7: give shape to; "form the clay into a head" [ant: {deform}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
