<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>forming</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>forming</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Forming \Form"ing\, n.
   The act or process of giving form or shape to anything; as,
   in shipbuilding, the exact shaping of partially shaped
   timbers.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>forming</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Form \Form\ (f[^o]rm), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Formed} (f[^o]rmd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Forming}.] [F. former, L. formare, fr.
   forma. See {Form}, n.]
   1. To give form or shape to; to frame; to construct; to make;
      to fashion.
      [1913 Webster]

            God formed man of the dust of the ground. --Gen. ii.
                                                  7.
      [1913 Webster]

            The thought that labors in my forming brain. --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give a particular shape to; to shape, mold, or fashion
      into a certain state or condition; to arrange; to adjust;
      also, to model by instruction and discipline; to mold by
      influence, etc.; to train.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is education forms the common mind. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus formed for speed, he challenges the wind.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To go to make up; to act as constituent of; to be the
      essential or constitutive elements of; to answer for; to
      make the shape of; -- said of that out of which anything
      is formed or constituted, in whole or in part.
      [1913 Webster]

            The diplomatic politicians . . . who formed by far
            the majority.                         --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To provide with a form, as a hare. See {Form}, n., 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            The melancholy hare is formed in brakes and briers.
                                                  --Drayton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Gram.) To derive by grammatical rules, as by adding the
      proper suffixes and affixes.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Elec.) To treat (plates) so as to bring them to fit
      condition for introduction into a storage battery, causing
      one plate to be composed more or less of spongy lead, and
      the other of lead peroxide. This was formerly done by
      repeated slow alternations of the charging current, but
      now the plates or grids are coated or filled, one with a
      paste of red lead and the other with litharge, introduced
      into the cell, and formed by a direct charging current.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
