<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fortune</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fortune</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fortune \For"tune\ (f[^o]r"t[-u]n; 135), n. [F. fortune, L.
   fortuna; akin to fors, fortis, chance, prob. fr. ferre to
   bear, bring. See {Bear} to support, and cf. {Fortuitous}.]
   1. The arrival of something in a sudden or unexpected manner;
      chance; accident; luck; hap; also, the personified or
      deified power regarded as determining human success,
      apportioning happiness and unhappiness, and distributing
      arbitrarily or fortuitously the lots of life.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is more by fortune, lady, than by merit. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            O Fortune, Fortune, all men call thee fickle.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which befalls or is to befall one; lot in life, or
      event in any particular undertaking; fate; destiny; as, to
      tell one's fortune.
      [1913 Webster]

            You, who men's fortunes in their faces read.
                                                  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which comes as the result of an undertaking or of a
      course of action; good or ill success; especially,
      favorable issue; happy event; success; prosperity as
      reached partly by chance and partly by effort.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our equal crimes shall equal fortune give. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is a tide in the affairs of men,
            Which, taken at the flood, leads on to fortune.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            His father dying, he was driven to seek his fortune.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Wealth; large possessions; large estate; riches; as, a
      gentleman of fortune.

   Syn: Chance; accident; luck; fate.
        [1913 Webster]

   {Fortune book}, a book supposed to reveal future events to
      those who consult it. --Crashaw.

   {Fortune hunter}, one who seeks to acquire wealth by
      marriage.

   {Fortune teller}, one who professes to tell future events in
      the life of another.

   {Fortune telling}, the practice or art of professing to
      reveal future events in the life of another.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fortune</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fortune \For"tune\, v. t. [OF. fortuner, L. fortunare. See
   {Fortune}, n.]
   1. To make fortunate; to give either good or bad fortune to.
      [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To provide with a fortune. --Richardson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To presage; to tell the fortune of. [Obs.] --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fortune</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fortune \For"tune\, v. i.
   To fall out; to happen.
   [1913 Webster]

         It fortuned the same night that a Christian, serving a
         Turk in the camp, secretely gave the watchmen warning.
                                                  --Knolles.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fortune</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fortune
     n 1: an unknown and unpredictable phenomenon that causes an event
          to result one way rather than another; "bad luck caused
          his downfall"; "we ran into each other by pure chance"
          [syn: {luck}, {chance}, {hazard}]
     2: a large amount of wealth or prosperity
     3: an unknown and unpredictable phenomenon that leads to a
        favorable outcome; "it was my good luck to be there";
        "they say luck is a lady"; "it was as if fortune guided
        his hand" [syn: {luck}]
     4: your overall circumstances or condition in life (including
        everything that happens to you); "whatever my fortune may
        be"; "deserved a better fate"; "has a happy lot"; "the
        luck of the Irish"; "a victim of circumstances"; "success
        that was her portion" [syn: {destiny}, {fate}, {luck}, {lot},
         {circumstances}, {portion}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
