<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fountain</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fountain
   (Heb. 'ain; i.e., "eye" of the water desert), a natural source
   of living water. Palestine was a "land of brooks of water, of
   fountains, and depths that spring out of valleys and hills"
   (Deut. 8:7; 11:11).
   
     These fountains, bright sparkling "eyes" of the desert, are
   remarkable for their abundance and their beauty, especially on
   the west of Jordan. All the perennial rivers and streams of the
   country are supplied from fountains, and depend comparatively
   little on surface water. "Palestine is a country of mountains
   and hills, and it abounds in fountains of water. The murmur of
   these waters is heard in every dell, and the luxuriant foliage
   which surrounds them is seen in every plain." Besides its
   rain-water, its cisterns and fountains, Jerusalem had also an
   abundant supply of water in the magnificent reservoir called
   "Solomon's Pools" (q.v.), at the head of the Urtas valley,
   whence it was conveyed to the city by subterrean channels some
   10 miles in length. These have all been long ago destroyed, so
   that no water from the "Pools" now reaches Jerusalem. Only one
   fountain has been discovered at Jerusalem, the so-called
   "Virgins's Fountains," in the valley of Kidron; and only one
   well (Heb. beer), the Bir Eyub, also in the valley of Kidron,
   south of the King's Gardens, which has been dug through the
   solid rock. The inhabitants of Jerusalem are now mainly
   dependent on the winter rains, which they store in cisterns.
   (See {WELL}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fountain, CO (city, FIPS 27865)
  Location: 38.66689 N, 104.69329 W
  Population (1990): 9984 (3789 housing units)
  Area: 36.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 80817
Fountain, FL
  Zip code(s): 32438
Fountain, MI (village, FIPS 29940)
  Location: 44.04778 N, 86.17949 W
  Population (1990): 165 (79 housing units)
  Area: 2.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 49410
Fountain, MN (city, FIPS 22094)
  Location: 43.74073 N, 92.13400 W
  Population (1990): 327 (132 housing units)
  Area: 2.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 55935
Fountain, NC (town, FIPS 24440)
  Location: 35.67414 N, 77.63708 W
  Population (1990): 445 (216 housing units)
  Area: 1.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 27829
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fountain \Foun"tain\ (foun"t[i^]n), n. [F. fontaine, LL.
   fontana, fr. L. fons, fontis. See 2d {Fount}.]
   1. A spring of water issuing from the earth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An artificially produced jet or stream of water; also, the
      structure or works in which such a jet or stream rises or
      flows; a basin built and constantly supplied with pure
      water for drinking and other useful purposes, or for
      ornament.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A reservoir or chamber to contain a liquid which can be
      conducted or drawn off as needed for use; as, the ink
      fountain in a printing press, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The source from which anything proceeds, or from which
      anything is supplied continuously; origin; source.
      [1913 Webster]

            Judea, the fountain of the gospel.    --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            Author of all being,
            Fountain of light, thyself invisible. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Air fountain}. See under {Air}.

   {Fountain heead}, primary source; original; first principle.
      --Young.

   {Fountain inkstand}, an inkstand having a continual supply of
      ink, as from elevated reservoir.

   {Fountain lamp}, a lamp fed with oil from an elevated
      reservoir.

   {Fountain pen}, a pen with a reservoir in the handle which
      furnishes a supply of ink.

   {Fountain pump}.
      (a) A structure for a fountain, having the form of a pump.
      (b) A portable garden pump which throws a jet, for
          watering plants, etc.

   {Fountain shell} (Zo["o]l.), the large West Indian conch
      shell ({Strombus gigas}).

   {Fountain of youth}, a mythical fountain whose waters were
      fabled to have the property of renewing youth.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fountain
     n 1: a structure from which an artificially produced jet of water
          arises
     2: a natural flow of ground water [syn: {spring}, {outflow}, {outpouring},
         {natural spring}]
     3: an artificially produced flow of water [syn: {jet}]
     4: a plumbing fixture that provides a flow of water [syn: {fount}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
