<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fox</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fox
   (Heb. shu'al, a name derived from its digging or burrowing under
   ground), the Vulpes thaleb, or Syrian fox, the only species of
   this animal indigenous to Palestine. It burrows, is silent and
   solitary in its habits, is destructive to vineyards, being a
   plunderer of ripe grapes (Cant. 2:15). The Vulpes Niloticus, or
   Egyptian dog-fox, and the Vulpes vulgaris, or common fox, are
   also found in Palestine.
   
     The proverbial cunning of the fox is alluded to in Ezek. 13:4,
   and in Luke 13:32, where our Lord calls Herod "that fox." In
   Judg. 15:4, 5, the reference is in all probability to the
   jackal. The Hebrew word _shu'al_ through the Persian _schagal_
   becomes our jackal (Canis aureus), so that the word may bear
   that signification here. The reasons for preferring the
   rendering "jackal" are (1) that it is more easily caught than
   the fox; (2) that the fox is shy and suspicious, and flies
   mankind, while the jackal does not; and (3) that foxes are
   difficult, jackals comparatively easy, to treat in the way here
   described. Jackals hunt in large numbers, and are still very
   numerous in Southern Palestine.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fox, AK (CDP, FIPS 26870)
  Location: 64.96074 N, 147.62126 W
  Population (1990): 275 (154 housing units)
  Area: 45.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Fox, AR
  Zip code(s): 72051
Fox, OR
  Zip code(s): 97831
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fox \Fox\ (f[o^]ks), n.; pl. {Foxes}. [AS. fox; akin to D. vos,
   G. fuchs, OHG. fuhs, foha, Goth. fa['u]h[=o], Icel. f[=o]a
   fox, fox fraud; of unknown origin, cf. Skr. puccha tail. Cf.
   {Vixen}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) A carnivorous animal of the genus {Vulpes},
      family {Canid[ae]}, of many species. The European fox ({V.
      vulgaris} or {V. vulpes}), the American red fox ({V.
      fulvus}), the American gray fox ({V. Virginianus}), and
      the arctic, white, or blue, fox ({V. lagopus}) are
      well-known species.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The black or silver-gray fox is a variety of the
         American red fox, producing a fur of great value; the
         cross-gray and woods-gray foxes are other varieties of
         the same species, of less value. The common foxes of
         Europe and America are very similar; both are
         celebrated for their craftiness. They feed on wild
         birds, poultry, and various small animals.
         [1913 Webster]

               Subtle as the fox for prey.        --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Zo["o]l.) The European dragonet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) The fox shark or thrasher shark; -- called also
      {sea fox}. See {Thrasher shark}, under {Shark}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A sly, cunning fellow. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We call a crafty and cruel man a fox. --Beattie.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) Rope yarn twisted together, and rubbed with tar;
      -- used for seizings or mats.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A sword; -- so called from the stamp of a fox on the
      blade, or perhaps of a wolf taken for a fox. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou diest on point of fox.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. (Ethnol.) A tribe of Indians which, with the Sacs,
      formerly occupied the region about Green Bay, Wisconsin;
      -- called also {Outagamies}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fox and geese}.
      (a) A boy's game, in which one boy tries to catch others
          as they run one goal to another.
      (b) A game with sixteen checkers, or some substitute for
          them, one of which is called the fox, and the rest the
          geese; the fox, whose first position is in the middle
          of the board, endeavors to break through the line of
          the geese, and the geese to pen up the fox.

   {Fox bat} (Zo["o]l.), a large fruit bat of the genus
      {Pteropus}, of many species, inhabiting Asia, Africa, and
      the East Indies, esp. {P. medius} of India. Some of the
      species are more than four feet across the outspread
      wings. See {Fruit bat}.

   {Fox bolt}, a bolt having a split end to receive a fox wedge.
      

   {Fox brush} (Zo["o]l.), the tail of a fox.

   {Fox evil}, a disease in which the hair falls off; alopecy.
      

   {Fox grape} (Bot.), the name of two species of American
      grapes. The northern fox grape ({Vitis Labrusca}) is the
      origin of the varieties called {Isabella}, {Concord},
      {Hartford}, etc., and the southern fox grape ({Vitis
      vulpina}) has produced the {Scuppernong}, and probably the
      {Catawba}.

   {Fox hunter}.
      (a) One who pursues foxes with hounds.
      (b) A horse ridden in a fox chase.

   {Fox shark} (Zo["o]l.), the thrasher shark. See {Thrasher
      shark}, under {Thrasher}.

   {Fox sleep}, pretended sleep.

   {Fox sparrow} (Zo["o]l.), a large American sparrow
      ({Passerella iliaca}); -- so called on account of its
      reddish color.

   {Fox squirrel} (Zo["o]l.), a large North American squirrel
      ({Sciurus niger}, or {S. cinereus}). In the Southern
      States the black variety prevails; farther north the
      fulvous and gray variety, called the {cat squirrel}, is
      more common.

   {Fox terrier} (Zo["o]l.), one of a peculiar breed of
      terriers, used in hunting to drive foxes from their holes,
      and for other purposes. There are rough- and smooth-haired
      varieties.

   {Fox trot}, a pace like that which is adopted for a few
      steps, by a horse, when passing from a walk into a trot,
      or a trot into a walk.

   {Fox wedge} (Mach. &amp; Carpentry), a wedge for expanding the
      split end of a bolt, cotter, dowel, tenon, or other piece,
      to fasten the end in a hole or mortise and prevent
      withdrawal. The wedge abuts on the bottom of the hole and
      the piece is driven down upon it. Fastening by fox wedges
      is called foxtail wedging.

   {Fox wolf} (Zo["o]l.), one of several South American wild
      dogs, belonging to the genus {Canis}. They have long,
      bushy tails like a fox.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fox \Fox\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Foxed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Foxing}.] [See {Fox}, n., cf. Icel. fox imposture.]
   1. To intoxicate; to stupefy with drink.
      [1913 Webster]

            I drank . . . so much wine that I was almost foxed.
                                                  --Pepys.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make sour, as beer, by causing it to ferment.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To repair the feet of, as of boots, with new front upper
      leather, or to piece the upper fronts of.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fox \Fox\, v. i.
   To turn sour; -- said of beer, etc., when it sours in
   fermenting.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dragonet \Drag"on*et\, n.
   1. A little dragon. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Zo["o]l.) A small British marine fish
      ({Callionymuslyra}); -- called also {yellow sculpin},
      {fox}, and {gowdie}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FOX
     Field Operational X.500
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fox</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fox
     n 1: alert carnivorous mammal with pointed muzzle and ears and a
          bushy tail; most are predators that do not hunt in packs
     2: a shifty deceptive person [syn: {dodger}, {slyboots}]
     3: the gray or reddish-brown fur of a fox
     4: English statesman who supported American independence and
        the French Revolution (1749-1806) [syn: {Charles James Fox}]
     5: English religious leader who founded the Society of Friends
        (1624-1691) [syn: {George Fox}]
     6: a member of an Algonquian people formerly living west of
        Lake Michigan along the Fox River
     7: the Algonquian language of the Fox people
     v 1: deceive somebody; "We tricked the teacher into thinking that
          class would be cancelled next week" [syn: {trick}, {fob},
           {pull a fast one on}, {play a trick on}]
     2: be confusing or perplexing to; cause to be unable to think
        clearly; "These questions confuse even the experts"; "This
        question completely threw me"; "This question befuddled
        even the teacher" [syn: {confuse}, {throw}, {befuddle}, {fuddle},
         {bedevil}, {confound}, {discombobulate}]
     3: become discolored with, or as if with, mildew spots
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
