<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fracture</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fracture</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fracture \Frac"ture\ (?; 135), n. [L. fractura, fr. frangere,
   fractum, to break: cf. F. fracture. See {Fraction}.]
   1. The act of breaking or snapping asunder; rupture; breach.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Surg.) The breaking of a bone.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Min.) The texture of a freshly broken surface; as, a
      compact fracture; an even, hackly, or conchoidal fracture.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Comminuted fracture} (Surg.), a fracture in which the bone
      is broken into several parts.

   {Complicated fracture} (Surg.), a fracture of the bone
      combined with the lesion of some artery, nervous trunk, or
      joint.

   {Compound fracture} (Surg.), a fracture in which there is an
      open wound from the surface down to the fracture.

   {Simple fracture} (Surg.), a fracture in which the bone only
      is ruptured. It does not communicate with the surface by
      an open wound.

   Syn: {Fracture}, {Rupture}.

   Usage: These words denote different kinds of breaking,
          according to the objects to which they are applied.
          Fracture is applied to hard substances; as, the
          fracture of a bone. Rupture is oftener applied to soft
          substances; as, the rupture of a blood vessel. It is
          also used figuratively. ``To be an enemy and once to
          have been a friend, does it not embitter the
          rupture?'' --South.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fracture</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fracture \Frac"ture\ (?; 135), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fractured}
   (#; 135); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.. {Fracturing}.] [Cf. F. fracturer.]
   To cause a fracture or fractures in; to break; to burst
   asunder; to crack; to separate the continuous parts of; as,
   to fracture a bone; to fracture the skull.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fracture</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fracture
     n 1: breaking of hard tissue such as bone; "it was a nasty
          fracture"; "the break seems to have been caused by a
          fall" [syn: {break}]
     2: (geology) a crack in the earth's crust resulting from the
        displacement of one side with respect to the other; "they
        built it right over a geological fault" [syn: {fault}, {geological
        fault}, {shift}, {break}]
     3: the act of cracking something [syn: {crack}, {cracking}]
     v 1: violate or abuse; "This writer really fractures the
          language"
     2: interrupt, break, or destroy; "fracture the balance of
        power"
     3: break into pieces; "The pothole fractured a bolt on the
        axle"
     4: become fractured; "The tibia fractured from the blow of the
        iron pipe"
     5: break (a bone); "She broke her clavicle"
     6: fracture a bone of; "I broke my foot while playing hockey"
        [syn: {break}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
