<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fraction</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fraction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fraction \Frac"tion\, n. [F. fraction, L. fractio a breaking,
   fr. frangere, fractum, to break. See {Break}.]
   1. The act of breaking, or state of being broken, especially
      by violence. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Neither can the natural body of Christ be subject to
            any fraction or breaking up.          --Foxe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A portion; a fragment.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some niggard fractions of an hour.    --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arith. or Alg.) One or more aliquot parts of a unit or
      whole number; an expression for a definite portion of a
      unit or magnitude.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Common fraction}, or {Vulgar fraction}, a fraction in which
      the number of equal parts into which the integer is
      supposed to be divided is indicated by figures or letters,
      called the denominator, written below a line, over which
      is the numerator, indicating the number of these parts
      included in the fraction; as 1/2, one half, 2/5, two
      fifths.

   {Complex fraction}, a fraction having a fraction or mixed
      number in the numerator or denominator, or in both.
      --Davies &amp; Peck.

   {Compound fraction}, a fraction of a fraction; two or more
      fractions connected by of.

   {Continued fraction}, {Decimal fraction}, {Partial fraction},
      etc. See under {Continued}, {Decimal}, {Partial}, etc.

   {Improper fraction}, a fraction in which the numerator is
      greater than the denominator.

   {Proper fraction}, a fraction in which the numerator is less
      than the denominator.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fraction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fraction \Frac"tion\, v. t. (Chem.)
   To separate by means of, or to subject to, fractional
   distillation or crystallization; to fractionate; --
   frequently used with out; as, to fraction out a certain grade
   of oil from pretroleum.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fraction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Angle \An"gle\ ([a^][ng]"g'l), n. [F. angle, L. angulus angle,
   corner; akin to uncus hook, Gr. 'agky`los bent, crooked,
   angular, 'a`gkos a bend or hollow, AS. angel hook, fish-hook,
   G. angel, and F. anchor.]
   1. The inclosed space near the point where two lines meet; a
      corner; a nook.
      [1913 Webster]

            Into the utmost angle of the world.   --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            To search the tenderest angles of the heart.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geom.)
      (a) The figure made by. two lines which meet.
      (b) The difference of direction of two lines. In the lines
          meet, the point of meeting is the vertex of the angle.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. A projecting or sharp corner; an angular fragment.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though but an angle reached him of the stone.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Astrol.) A name given to four of the twelve astrological
      ``houses.'' [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [AS. angel.] A fishhook; tackle for catching fish,
      consisting of a line, hook, and bait, with or without a
      rod.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give me mine angle: we 'll to the river there.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A fisher next his trembling angle bears. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Acute angle}, one less than a right angle, or less than
      90[deg].

   {Adjacent} or {Contiguous angles}, such as have one leg
      common to both angles.

   {Alternate angles}. See {Alternate}.

   {Angle bar}.
      (a) (Carp.) An upright bar at the angle where two faces of
          a polygonal or bay window meet. --Knight.
      (b) (Mach.) Same as {Angle iron}.

   {Angle bead} (Arch.), a bead worked on or fixed to the angle
      of any architectural work, esp. for protecting an angle of
      a wall.

   {Angle brace}, {Angle tie} (Carp.), a brace across an
      interior angle of a wooden frame, forming the hypothenuse
      and securing the two side pieces together. --Knight.

   {Angle iron} (Mach.), a rolled bar or plate of iron having
      one or more angles, used for forming the corners, or
      connecting or sustaining the sides of an iron structure to
      which it is riveted.

   {Angle leaf} (Arch.), a detail in the form of a leaf, more or
      less conventionalized, used to decorate and sometimes to
      strengthen an angle.

   {Angle meter}, an instrument for measuring angles, esp. for
      ascertaining the dip of strata.

   {Angle shaft} (Arch.), an enriched angle bead, often having a
      capital or base, or both.

   {Curvilineal angle}, one formed by two curved lines.

   {External angles}, angles formed by the sides of any
      right-lined figure, when the sides are produced or
      lengthened.

   {Facial angle}. See under {Facial}.

   {Internal angles}, those which are within any right-lined
      figure.

   {Mixtilineal angle}, one formed by a right line with a curved
      line.

   {Oblique angle}, one acute or obtuse, in opposition to a
      right angle.

   {Obtuse angle}, one greater than a right angle, or more than
      90[deg].

   {Optic angle}. See under {Optic}.

   {Rectilineal} or {Right-lined angle}, one formed by two right
      lines.

   {Right angle}, one formed by a right line falling on another
      perpendicularly, or an angle of 90[deg] (measured by a
      quarter circle).

   {Solid angle}, the figure formed by the meeting of three or
      more plane angles at one point.

   {Spherical angle}, one made by the meeting of two arcs of
      great circles, which mutually cut one another on the
      surface of a globe or sphere.

   {Visual angle}, the angle formed by two rays of light, or two
      straight lines drawn from the extreme points of an object
      to the center of the eye.

   {For Angles of commutation}, {draught}, {incidence},
   {reflection}, {refraction}, {position}, {repose}, {fraction},
      see {Commutation}, {Draught}, {Incidence}, {Reflection},
      {Refraction}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fraction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fraction
     n 1: a component of a mixture that has been separated by a
          fractional process
     2: a small part or item forming a piece of a whole
     3: the quotient of two rational numbers
     v : perform a division; "Can you divide 49 by seven?" [syn: {divide}]
         [ant: {multiply}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
