<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>framed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>framed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Frame \Frame\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Framed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Framing}.] [OE. framen, fremen, to execute, build, AS.
   fremman to further, perform, effect, fr. fram strong,
   valiant; akin to E. foremost, and prob. to AS. fram from,
   Icel. fremja, frama, to further, framr forward, G. fromm
   worthy, excellent, pious. See {Foremost}, {From}, and cf.
   {Furnish}.]
   1. (Arch. &amp; Engin.) To construct by fitting and uniting the
      several parts of the skeleton of any structure;
      specifically, in woodwork, to put together by cutting
      parts of one member to fit parts of another. See
      {Dovetail}, {Halve}, v. t., {Miter}, {Tenon}, {Tooth},
      {Tusk}, {Scarf}, and {Splice}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To originate; to plan; to devise; to contrive; to compose;
      in a bad sense, to invent or fabricate, as something
      false.
      [1913 Webster]

            How many excellent reasonings are framed in the mind
            of a man of wisdom and study in a length of years.
                                                  --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fit to something else, or for some specific end; to
      adjust; to regulate; to shape; to conform.
      [1913 Webster]

            And frame my face to all occasions.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            We may in some measure frame our minds for the
            reception of happiness.               --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The human mind is framed to be influenced. --I.
                                                  Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cause; to bring about; to produce. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Fear frames disorder, and disorder wounds. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To support. [Obs. &amp; R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            That on a staff his feeble steps did frame.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To provide with a frame, as a picture.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. to manufacture false evidence against (an innocent
      person), so as to make the person appear guilty of a
      crime. The act of framing a person is often referred to as
      a {frame-up}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>framed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>framed \framed\ adj.
   provided with a frame; as, there were framed snapshots of
   family and friends on her desk. Opposite of {unframed}.
   [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>framed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>framed
     adj : provided with a frame; "there were framed snapshots of
           family and friends on her desk" [ant: {unframed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
