<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>free</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>free</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>free
     
        See {free software}, {free variable}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>free</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Free \Free\ (fr[=e]), a. [Compar. {Freer} (-[~e]r); superl.
   {Freest} (-[e^]st).] [OE. fre, freo, AS. fre['o], fr[=i];
   akin to D. vrij, OS. &amp; OHG. fr[=i], G. frei, Icel. fr[=i],
   Sw. &amp; Dan. fri, Goth. freis, and also to Skr. prija beloved,
   dear, fr. pr[=i] to love, Goth. frij[=o]n. Cf. {Affray},
   {Belfry}, {Friday}, {Friend}, {Frith} inclosure.]
   1. Exempt from subjection to the will of others; not under
      restraint, control, or compulsion; able to follow one's
      own impulses, desires, or inclinations; determining one's
      own course of action; not dependent; at liberty.
      [1913 Webster]

            That which has the power, or not the power, to
            operate, is that alone which is or is not free.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not under an arbitrary or despotic government; subject
      only to fixed laws regularly and fairly administered, and
      defended by them from encroachments upon natural or
      acquired rights; enjoying political liberty.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Liberated, by arriving at a certain age, from the control
      of parents, guardian, or master.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Not confined or imprisoned; released from arrest;
      liberated; at liberty to go.
      [1913 Webster]

            Set an unhappy prisoner free.         --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Not subjected to the laws of physical necessity; capable
      of voluntary activity; endowed with moral liberty; -- said
      of the will.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not free, what proof could they have given sincere
            Of true allegiance, constant faith, or love.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Clear of offense or crime; guiltless; innocent.
      [1913 Webster]

            My hands are guilty, but my heart is free. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Unconstrained by timidity or distrust; unreserved;
      ingenuous; frank; familiar; communicative.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was free only with a few.          --Milward.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Unrestrained; immoderate; lavish; licentious; -- used in a
      bad sense.
      [1913 Webster]

            The critics have been very free in their censures.
                                                  --Felton.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man may live a free life as to wine or women.
                                                  --Shelley.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Not close or parsimonious; liberal; open-handed; lavish;
      as, free with his money.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Exempt; clear; released; liberated; not encumbered or
       troubled with; as, free from pain; free from a burden; --
       followed by from, or, rarely, by of.
       [1913 Webster]

             Princes declaring themselves free from the
             obligations of their treaties.       --Bp. Burnet.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Characteristic of one acting without restraint; charming;
       easy.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Ready; eager; acting without spurring or whipping;
       spirited; as, a free horse.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Invested with a particular freedom or franchise; enjoying
       certain immunities or privileges; admitted to special
       rights; -- followed by of.
       [1913 Webster]

             He therefore makes all birds, of every sect,
             Free of his farm.                    --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Thrown open, or made accessible, to all; to be enjoyed
       without limitations; unrestricted; not obstructed,
       engrossed, or appropriated; open; -- said of a thing to
       be possessed or enjoyed; as, a free school.
       [1913 Webster]

             Why, sir, I pray, are not the streets as free
             For me as for you?                   --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. Not gained by importunity or purchase; gratuitous;
       spontaneous; as, free admission; a free gift.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. Not arbitrary or despotic; assuring liberty; defending
       individual rights against encroachment by any person or
       class; instituted by a free people; -- said of a
       government, institutions, etc.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (O. Eng. Law) Certain or honorable; the opposite of
       {base}; as, free service; free socage. --Burrill.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. (Law) Privileged or individual; the opposite of common;
       as, a free fishery; a free warren. --Burrill.
       [1913 Webster]

   19. Not united or combined with anything else; separated;
       dissevered; unattached; at liberty to escape; as, free
       carbonic acid gas; free cells.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Free agency}, the capacity or power of choosing or acting
      freely, or without necessity or constraint upon the will.
      

   {Free bench} (Eng. Law), a widow's right in the copyhold
      lands of her husband, corresponding to dower in freeholds.
      

   {Free board} (Naut.), a vessel's side between water line and
      gunwale.

   {Free bond} (Chem.), an unsaturated or unemployed unit, or
      bond, of affinity or valence, of an atom or radical.

   {Free-borough men} (O.Eng. Law). See {Friborg}.

   {Free chapel} (Eccles.), a chapel not subject to the
      jurisdiction of the ordinary, having been founded by the
      king or by a subject specially authorized. [Eng.]
      --Bouvier.

   {Free charge} (Elec.), a charge of electricity in the free or
      statical condition; free electricity.

   {Free church}.
       (a) A church whose sittings are for all and without
           charge.
       (b) An ecclesiastical body that left the Church of
           Scotland, in 1843, to be free from control by the
           government in spiritual matters.

   {Free city}, or {Free town}, a city or town independent in
      its government and franchises, as formerly those of the
      Hanseatic league.

   {Free cost}, freedom from charges or expenses. --South.

   {Free and easy}, unconventional; unrestrained; regardless of
      formalities. [Colloq.] ``Sal and her free and easy ways.''
      --W. Black.

   {Free goods}, goods admitted into a country free of duty.

   {Free labor}, the labor of freemen, as distinguished from
      that of slaves.

   {Free port}. (Com.)
       (a) A port where goods may be received and shipped free
           of custom duty.
       (b) A port where goods of all kinds are received from
           ships of all nations at equal rates of duty.

   {Free public house}, in England, a tavern not belonging to a
      brewer, so that the landlord is free to brew his own beer
      or purchase where he chooses. --Simmonds.

   {Free school}.
       (a) A school to which pupils are admitted without
           discrimination and on an equal footing.
       (b) A school supported by general taxation, by
           endowmants, etc., where pupils pay nothing for
           tuition; a public school.

   {Free services} (O.Eng. Law), such feudal services as were
      not unbecoming the character of a soldier or a freemen to
      perform; as, to serve under his lord in war, to pay a sum
      of money, etc. --Burrill.

   {Free ships}, ships of neutral nations, which in time of war
      are free from capture even though carrying enemy's goods.
      

   {Free socage} (O.Eng. Law), a feudal tenure held by certain
      services which, though honorable, were not military.
      --Abbott.

   {Free States}, those of the United States before the Civil
      War, in which slavery had ceased to exist, or had never
      existed.

   {Free stuff} (Carp.), timber free from knots; clear stuff.

   {Free thought}, that which is thought independently of the
      authority of others.

   {Free trade}, commerce unrestricted by duties or tariff
      regulations.

   {Free trader}, one who believes in free trade.

   {To make free with}, to take liberties with; to help one's
      self to. [Colloq.]

   {To sail free} (Naut.), to sail with the yards not braced in
      as sharp as when sailing closehauled, or close to the
      wind.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>free</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Free \Free\, adv.
   1. Freely; willingly. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I as free forgive you
            As I would be forgiven.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Without charge; as, children admitted free.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>free</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Free \Free\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Freed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Freeing}.] [OE. freen, freoien, AS. fre['o]gan. See {Free},
   a.]
   1. To make free; to set at liberty; to rid of that which
      confines, limits, embarrasses, oppresses, etc.; to
      release; to disengage; to clear; -- followed by from, and
      sometimes by off; as, to free a captive or a slave; to be
      freed of these inconveniences. --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our land is from the rage of tigers freed. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Arise, . . . free thy people from their yoke.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To remove, as something that confines or bars; to relieve
      from the constraint of.
      [1913 Webster]

            This master key
            Frees every lock, and leads us to his person.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To frank. [Obs.] --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>free</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>free
     adj 1: able to act at will; not hampered; not under compulsion or
            restraint; "free enterprise"; "a free port"; "a free
            country"; "I have an hour free"; "free will"; "free of
            racism"; "feel free to stay as long as you wish"; "a
            free choice" [ant: {unfree}]
     2: unconstrained or not chemically bound in a molecule or not
        fixed and capable of relatively unrestricted motion; "free
        expansion"; "free oxygen"; "a free electron" [ant: {bound}]
     3: costing nothing; "complimentary tickets" [syn: {complimentary},
         {costless}, {gratis(p)}, {gratuitous}]
     4: not occupied or in use; "a free locker"; "a free lane"
     5: not fixed in position; "the detached shutter fell on him";
        "he pulled his arm free and ran" [syn: {detached}]
     6: not held in servitude; "after the Civil War he was a free
        man" [ant: {slave(a)}]
     7: not taken up by scheduled activities; "a free hour between
        classes"; "spare time on my hands" [syn: {spare}]
     8: not literal; "a loose interpretation of what she had been
        told"; "a free translation of the poem" [syn: {loose}, {liberal}]
     n : people who are free; "the home of the free and the brave"
         [syn: {free people}]
     adv : without restraint; "cows in India are running loose" [syn: {loose}]
     v 1: grant freedom to; free from confinement [syn: {liberate}, {release},
           {unloose}, {unloosen}, {loose}] [ant: {confine}]
     2: relieve from; "Rid the the house of pests" [syn: {rid}, {disembarrass}]
     3: remove or force out from a position; "The dentist dislodged
        the piece of food that had been stuck under my gums"; "He
        finally could free the legs of the earthquake victim who
        was buried in the rubble" [syn: {dislodge}] [ant: {lodge}]
     4: grant relief or an exemption from a rule or requirement to;
        "She exempted me from the exam" [syn: {exempt}, {relieve}]
        [ant: {enforce}]
     5: make (information) available publication; "release the list
        with the names of the prisoners" [syn: {release}]
     6: free from obligations or duties [syn: {discharge}]
     7: free or remove obstruction from; "free a path across the
        cluttered floor" [syn: {disengage}] [ant: {obstruct}]
     8: let off the hook; "I absolve you from this responsibility"
        [syn: {absolve}, {justify}] [ant: {blame}]
     9: part with a possession or right; "I am relinquishing my
        bedroom to the long-term house guest"; "resign a claim to
        the throne" [syn: {release}, {relinquish}, {resign}, {give
        up}]
     10: make (assets) available; "release the holdings in the
         dictator's bank account" [syn: {unblock}, {unfreeze}, {release}]
         [ant: {freeze}, {freeze}]
     [also: {freest}, {freer}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
