<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>frog</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>frog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FROG, n.  A reptile with edible legs.  The first mention of frogs in
profane literature is in Homer's narrative of the war between them and
the mice.  Skeptical persons have doubted Homer's authorship of the
work, but the learned, ingenious and industrious Dr. Schliemann has
set the question forever at rest by uncovering the bones of the slain
frogs.  One of the forms of moral suasion by which Pharaoh was
besought to favor the Israelities was a plague of frogs, but Pharaoh,
who liked them _fricasees_, remarked, with truly oriental stoicism,
that he could stand it as long as the frogs and the Jews could; so the
programme was changed.  The frog is a diligent songster, having a good
voice but no ear.  The libretto of his favorite opera, as written by
Aristophanes, is brief, simple and effective -- "brekekex-koax"; the
music is apparently by that eminent composer, Richard Wagner.  Horses
have a frog in each hoof -- a thoughtful provision of nature, enabling
them to shine in a hurdle race.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>frog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Frog
   (Heb. tsepharde'a, meaning a "marsh-leaper"). This reptile is
   mentioned in the Old Testament only in connection with one of
   the plagues which fell on the land of Egypt (Ex. 8:2-14; Ps.
   78:45; 105:30).
   
     In the New Testament this word occurs only in Rev. 16:13,
   where it is referred to as a symbol of uncleanness. The only
   species of frog existing in Palestine is the green frog (Rana
   esculenta), the well-known edible frog of the Continent.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>frog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Frog \Frog\ (fr[o^]g), n. [AS. froggu, frocga a frog (in
   sensel); akin to D. vorsch, OHG. frosk, G. frosch, Icel.
   froskr, fraukr, Sw. &amp; Dan. fr["o].]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) An amphibious animal of the genus {Rana} and
      related genera, of many species. Frogs swim rapidly, and
      take long leaps on land. Many of the species utter loud
      notes in the springtime.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The edible frog of Europe ({Rana esculenta}) is
         extensively used as food; the American bullfrog ({R.
         Catesbiana}) is remarkable for its great size and loud
         voice.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. [Perh. akin to E. fork, cf. frush frog of a horse.]
      (Anat.) The triangular prominence of the hoof, in the
      middle of the sole of the foot of the horse, and other
      animals; the fourchette.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Railroads) A supporting plate having raised ribs that
      form continuations of the rails, to guide the wheels where
      one track branches from another or crosses it.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. [Cf. fraco of wool or silk, L. floccus, E. frock.] An
      oblong cloak button, covered with netted thread, and
      fastening into a loop instead of a button hole.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The loop of the scabbard of a bayonet or sword.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cross frog} (Railroads), a frog adapted for tracks that
      cross at right angles.

   {Frog cheese}, a popular name for a large puffball.

   {Frog eater}, one who eats frogs; -- a term of contempt
      applied to a Frenchman by the vulgar class of English.

   {Frog fly}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Frog} hopper.

   {Frog hopper} (Zo["o]l.), a small, leaping, hemipterous
      insect living on plants. The larv[ae] are inclosed in a
      frothy liquid called {cuckoo spit} or {frog spit}.

   {Frog lily} (Bot.), the yellow water lily ({Nuphar}).

   {Frog spit} (Zo["o]l.), the frothy exudation of the {frog
      hopper}; -- called also {frog spittle}. See {Cuckoo spit},
      under {Cuckoo}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>frog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Frog \Frog\, v. t.
   To ornament or fasten (a coat, etc.) with trogs. See {Frog},
   n., 4.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>frog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>frog alt. `phrog' 1. interj. Term of disgust (we seem to have a lot of
   them). 2. Used as a name for just about anything. See {foo}. 3. n. Of
   things, a crock. 4. n. Of people, somewhere in between a turkey and a
   toad. 5. `froggy': adj. Similar to {bagbiting}, but milder. "This froggy
   program is taking forever to run!"


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>frog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>frog
     n 1: any of various tailless stout-bodied amphibians with long
          hind limbs for leaping; semiaquatic and terrestrial
          species [syn: {toad}, {toad frog}, {anuran}, {batrachian},
           {salientian}]
     2: a person of French descent [syn: {Gaul}]
     3: a decorative loop of braid or cord [syn: {frogs}]
     [also: {frogging}, {frogged}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
