<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>front</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>front</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Front \Front\ (fr[u^]nt), n. [F. frant forehead, L. frons,
   frontis; perh. akin to E. brow.]
   1. The forehead or brow, the part of the face above the eyes;
      sometimes, also, the whole face.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bless'd with his father's front, his mother's
            tongue.                               --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Grim-visaged war hath smoothed his wrinkled front.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            His front yet threatens, and his frowns command.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The forehead, countenance, or personal presence, as
      expressive of character or temper, and especially, of
      boldness of disposition, sometimes of impudence; seeming;
      as, a bold front; a hardened front; hence, an attitude and
      demeanor intended to represent one's feelings, even if not
      actually felt; as, to put on a good front.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            With smiling fronts encountering.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inhabitants showed a bold front.  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The part or surface of anything which seems to look out,
      or to be directed forward; the fore or forward part; the
      foremost rank; the van; -- the opposite to back or rear;
      as, the front of a house; the front of an army.
      [1913 Webster]

            Had he his hurts before?
            Ay, on the front.                     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A position directly before the face of a person, or before
      the foremost part of a thing; as, in front of un person,
      of the troops, or of a house.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The most conspicuous part.
      [1913 Webster]

            The very head and front of my offending. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That which covers the foremost part of the head: a front
      piece of false hair worn by women.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like any plain Miss Smith's, who wears s front.
                                                  --Mrs.
                                                  Browning.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The beginning. ``Summer's front.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Fort.) All the works along one side of the polygon
      inclosing the site which is fortified.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Phon.) The middle of the upper part of the tongue, -- the
      part of the tongue which is more or less raised toward the
      palate in the pronunciation of certain sounds, as the
      vowel i in machine, e in bed, and consonant y in you. See
      Guide to Pronunciation, [sect]10.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. The call boy whose turn it is to answer the call, which
       is often the word ``front,'' used as an exclamation.
       [Hotel Cant]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Bastioned front} (Mil.), a curtain connerting two half
      bastions.

   {Front door}, the door in the front wall of a building,
      usually the principal entrance.

   {Front of fortification}, the works constructed upon any one
      side of a polygon. --Farrow.

   {Front of operations}, all that part of the field of
      operations in front of the successive positions occupied
      by the army as it moves forward. --Farrow.

   {To come to the front}, to attain prominence or leadership.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>front</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Front \Front\, v. t.
   To have or turn the face or front in any direction; as, the
   house fronts toward the east.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>front</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Front \Front\, a.
   Of or relating to the front or forward part; having a
   position in front; foremost; as, a front view.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>front</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Front \Front\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Fronted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Fronting}.]
   1. To oppose face to face; to oppose directly; to meet in a
      hostile manner.
      [1913 Webster]

            You four shall front them in the narrow lane.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To appear before; to meet.
      [1913 Webster]

            [Enid] daily fronted him
            In some fresh splendor.               --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To face toward; to have the front toward; to confront; as,
      the house fronts the street.
      [1913 Webster]

            And then suddenly front the changed reality. --J.
                                                  Morley.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To stand opposed or opposite to, or over against as, his
      house fronts the church.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To adorn in front; to supply a front to; as, to front a
      house with marble; to front a head with laurel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yonder walls, that pertly front your town. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>front</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>front
     adj 1: relating to or located in the front; "the front lines"; "the
            front porch" [syn: {front(a)}] [ant: {back(a)}]
     2: located anteriorly [syn: {fore(a)}, {front(a)}]
     n 1: the immediate proximity of someone or something; "she
          blushed in his presence"; "he sensed the presence of
          danger"; "he was well behaved in front of company" [syn:
           {presence}]
     2: the side that is forward or prominent [syn: {front end}, {forepart}]
        [ant: {rear}]
     3: the side that is seen or that goes first [ant: {rear}]
     4: a sphere of activity involving effort; "the Japanese were
        active last week on the diplomatic front"; "they advertise
        on many different fronts"
     5: the line along which opposing armies face each other [syn: {battlefront},
         {front line}]
     6: a group of people with a common ideology who try together to
        achieve certain general goals; "he was a charter member of
        the movement"; "politicians have to respect a mass
        movement"; "he led the national liberation front" [syn: {movement},
         {social movement}]
     7: (meteorology) the atmospheric phenomenon created at the
        boundary between two different air masses
     8: a person used as a cover for some questionable activity
        [syn: {front man}, {figurehead}, {nominal head}, {straw
        man}, {strawman}]
     9: the outward appearance of a person; "he put up a bold front"
     10: the part of something that is nearest to the normal viewer;
         "he walked to the front of the stage" [ant: {back}]
     v 1: be oriented in a certain direction, often with respect to
          another reference point; be opposite to; "The house
          looks north"; "My backyard look onto the pond"; "The
          building faces the park" [syn: {look}, {face}] [ant: {back}]
     2: confront bodily; "breast the storm" [syn: {breast}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
