<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>functional</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>functional</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>functional
     
        1. Working correctly.
     
        2. Pertaining to {functional programming}.
     
        3. {higher-order function}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>functional</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Functional \Func"tion*al\ (f[u^][ng]k"sh[u^]n*al), a.
   1. Pertaining to, or connected with, a function or duty;
      official.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Pathology, Physiol.) Pertaining to the function of an
      organ or part, or to the functions in general; involving
      or affecting function rather than physiology; as,
      functional deafness; a functional disease. See {functional
      disease}, below. [WordNet sense 2]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Designed for or capable of a particular function or use;
      as, a style of writing in which every word is functional;
      functional architecture. [WordNet sense 1]
      [WordNet 1.6]

   4. Fit or ready for use or service; useable; in working
      order; as, the toaster was still functional even after
      being dropped; the lawnmower is a bit rusty but still
      functional. Antonym of {out of order} and {nonfunctional}.
      [WordNet sense 4 &amp; 6]

   Syn: usable, useable, in working order(predicate), operable,
        operational, running(prenominal), operative.
        [WordNet 1.6]

   5. Designed to emphasize practical utility rather than
      artistic or aesthetic purposes; as, functional education
      selects knowledge that is concrete and usable rather than
      abstract and theoretical; functional architecture; an
      amateurish device, crude but functional.
      [WordNet 1.6]

   {Functional disease} (Med.), a disease of which the symptoms
      cannot be referred to any appreciable lesion or change of
      structure; the derangement of an organ arising from a
      cause, often unknown, external to itself opposed to
      {organic disease}, in which the organ itself is affected.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>functional</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>functional
     adj 1: designed for or capable of a particular function or use; "a
            style of writing in which every word is functional";
            "functional architecture" [ant: {nonfunctional}]
     2: involving or affecting function rather than physiology;
        "functional deafness" [ant: {organic}]
     3: relating to or based on function especially as opposed to
        structure; "the problem now is not a constitutional one;
        it is a functional one"; "delegates elected on a
        functional rather than a geographical basis"
     4: fit or ready for use or service; "the toaster was still
        functional even after being dropped"; "the lawnmower is a
        bit rusty but still usable"; "an operational aircraft";
        "the dishwasher is now in working order" [syn: {usable}, {useable},
         {in working order(p)}, {operable}, {operational}]
     5: designed for or adapted to a function or use; "functional
        education selects knowledge that is concrete and usable
        rather than abstract and theoretical"; "functional
        architecture"
     6: (of e.g. a machine) performing or capable of performing; "in
        running (or working) order"; "a functional set of brakes"
        [syn: {running(a)}, {operative}, {working(a)}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
