<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>function</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>function</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>function
     
        1. &lt;mathematics&gt; (Or "map", "mapping") If D and C are sets
        (the domain and codomain) then a function f from D to C,
        normally written "f : D -&gt; C" is a subset of D x C such that:
     
        1. For each d in D there exists some c in C such that (d,c) is
        an element of f.  I.e. the function is defined for every
        element of D.
     
        2. For each d in D, c1 and c2 in C, if both (d,c1) and (d,c2)
        are elements of f then c1 = c2.  I.e. the function is uniquely
        defined for every element of D.
     
        See also {image}, {inverse}, {partial function}.
     
        2. &lt;programming&gt; Computing usage derives from the mathematical
        term but is much less strict.  In programming (except in
        {functional programming}), a function may return different
        values each time it is called with the same argument values
        and may have {side effects}.
     
        A {procedure} is a function which returns no value but has
        only {side-effects}.  The {C} language, for example, has no
        procedures, only functions.  {ANSI C} even defines a {type},
        {void}, for the result of a function that has no result.
     
        (1996-09-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>function</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fluent \Flu"ent\, n.
   1. A current of water; a stream. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [Cf. F. fluente.] (Math.) A variable quantity, considered
      as increasing or diminishing; -- called, in the modern
      calculus, the {function} or {integral}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>function</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Function \Func"tion\, n. [L. functio, fr. fungi to perform,
   execute, akin to Skr. bhuj to enjoy, have the use of: cf. F.
   fonction. Cf. {Defunct}.]
   1. The act of executing or performing any duty, office, or
      calling; performance. ``In the function of his public
      calling.'' --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Physiol.) The appropriate action of any special organ or
      part of an animal or vegetable organism; as, the function
      of the heart or the limbs; the function of leaves, sap,
      roots, etc.; life is the sum of the functions of the
      various organs and parts of the body.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The natural or assigned action of any power or faculty, as
      of the soul, or of the intellect; the exertion of an
      energy of some determinate kind.
      [1913 Webster]

            As the mind opens, and its functions spread. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The course of action which peculiarly pertains to any
      public officer in church or state; the activity
      appropriate to any business or profession.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tradesmen . . . going about their functions. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The malady which made him incapable of performing
            his
            regal functions.                      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) A quantity so connected with another quantity,
      that if any alteration be made in the latter there will be
      a consequent alteration in the former. Each quantity is
      said to be a function of the other. Thus, the
      circumference of a circle is a function of the diameter.
      If x be a symbol to which different numerical values can
      be assigned, such expressions as x^{2}, 3^{x}, Log. x, and
      Sin. x, are all functions of x.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Eccl.) A religious ceremony, esp. one particularly
      impressive and elaborate.

            Every solemn `function' performed with the
            requirements of the liturgy.          --Card.
                                                  Wiseman.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. A public or social ceremony or gathering; a festivity or
      entertainment, esp. one somewhat formal.

            This function, which is our chief social event. --W.
                                                  D. Howells.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Algebraic function}, a quantity whose connection with the
      variable is expressed by an equation that involves only
      the algebraic operations of addition, subtraction,
      multiplication, division, raising to a given power, and
      extracting a given root; -- opposed to transcendental
      function.

   {Arbitrary function}. See under {Arbitrary}.

   {Calculus of functions}. See under {Calculus}.

   {Carnot's function} (Thermo-dynamics), a relation between the
      amount of heat given off by a source of heat, and the work
      which can be done by it. It is approximately equal to the
      mechanical equivalent of the thermal unit divided by the
      number expressing the temperature in degrees of the air
      thermometer, reckoned from its zero of expansion.

   {Circular functions}. See {Inverse trigonometrical functions}
      (below). -- Continuous function, a quantity that has no
      interruption in the continuity of its real values, as the
      variable changes between any specified limits.

   {Discontinuous function}. See under {Discontinuous}.

   {Elliptic functions}, a large and important class of
      functions, so called because one of the forms expresses
      the relation of the arc of an ellipse to the straight
      lines connected therewith.

   {Explicit function}, a quantity directly expressed in terms
      of the independently varying quantity; thus, in the
      equations y = 6x^{2}, y = 10 -x^{3}, the quantity y is an
      explicit function of x.

   {Implicit function}, a quantity whose relation to the
      variable is expressed indirectly by an equation; thus, y
      in the equation x^{2} + y^{2} = 100 is an implicit
      function of x.

   {Inverse trigonometrical functions}, or {Circular functions},
      the lengths of arcs relative to the sines, tangents, etc.
      Thus, AB is the arc whose sine is BD, and (if the length
      of BD is x) is written sin ^{-1}x, and so of the other
      lines. See {Trigonometrical function} (below). Other
      transcendental functions are the exponential functions,
      the elliptic functions, the gamma functions, the theta
      functions, etc.

   {One-valued function}, a quantity that has one, and only one,
      value for each value of the variable. -- {Transcendental
   functions}, a quantity whose connection with the variable
      cannot be expressed by algebraic operations; thus, y in
      the equation y = 10^{x} is a transcendental function of x.
      See {Algebraic function} (above). -- {Trigonometrical
   function}, a quantity whose relation to the variable is the
      same as that of a certain straight line drawn in a circle
      whose radius is unity, to the length of a corresponding
      are of the circle. Let AB be an arc in a circle, whose
      radius OA is unity let AC be a quadrant, and let OC, DB,
      and AF be drawnpependicular to OA, and EB and CG parallel
      to OA, and let OB be produced to G and F. E Then BD is the
      sine of the arc AB; OD or EB is the cosine, AF is the
      tangent, CG is the cotangent, OF is the secant OG is the
      cosecant, AD is the versed sine, and CE is the coversed
      sine of the are AB. If the length of AB be represented by
      x (OA being unity) then the lengths of Functions. these
      lines (OA being unity) are the trigonometrical functions
      of x, and are written sin x, cos x, tan x (or tang x), cot
      x, sec x, cosec x, versin x, coversin x. These quantities
      are also considered as functions of the angle BOA.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>function</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Function \Func"tion\ (f[u^][ng]k"sh[u^]n), Functionate
\Func"tion*ate\, v. i.
   To execute or perform a function; to transact one's regular
   or appointed business.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>function</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>function
     n 1: a mathematical relation such that each element of one set is
          associated with at least one element of another set
          [syn: {mathematical function}]
     2: what something is used for; "the function of an auger is to
        bore holes"; "ballet is beautiful but what use is it?"
        [syn: {purpose}, {role}, {use}]
     3: the actions and activities assigned to or required or
        expected of a person or group; "the function of a
        teacher"; "the government must do its part"; "play its
        role" [syn: {office}, {part}, {role}]
     4: a relation such that one thing is dependent on another;
        "height is a function of age"; "price is a function of
        supply and demand"
     5: a formal or official social gathering or ceremony; "it was a
        black-tie function"
     6: a vaguely specified social event; "the party was quite an
        affair"; "an occasion arranged to honor the president"; "a
        seemingly endless round of social functions" [syn: {affair},
         {occasion}, {social occasion}, {social function}]
     7: a set sequence of steps, part of larger computer program
        [syn: {routine}, {subroutine}, {subprogram}, {procedure}]
     v 1: perform as expected when applied; "The washing machine won't
          go unless it's plugged in"; "Does this old car still run
          well?"; "This old radio doesn't work anymore" [syn: {work},
           {operate}, {go}, {run}] [ant: {malfunction}]
     2: serve a purpose, role, or function; "The tree stump serves
        as a table"; "The female students served as a control
        group"; "This table would serve very well"; "His freedom
        served him well"; "The table functions as a desk" [syn: {serve}]
     3: perform duties attached to a particular office or place or
        function; "His wife officiated as his private secretary"
        [syn: {officiate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
