<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>funky</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>funky</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>funky
     
        Said of something that functions, but in a slightly strange,
        {kluge}y way.  It does the job and would be difficult to
        change, so its obvious non-optimality is left alone.  Often
        used to describe interfaces.  The more bugs something has that
        nobody has bothered to fix because workarounds are easier, the
        funkier it is.  {TECO} and {UUCP} are funky.  The {Intel}
        {i860}'s exception handling is extraordinarily funky.  Most
        standards acquire funkiness as they age.  "The new mailer is
        installed, but is still somewhat funky; if it bounces your
        mail for no reason, try resubmitting it."  "This {UART} is
        pretty funky.  The data ready line is active-high in interrupt
        mode and active-low in {DMA} mode."
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>funky</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Funky \Funk"y\ (f[u^][ng]k"[y^]), a.
   Pertaining to, or characterized by, great fear, or funking;
   having great fear. [Colloq. Eng.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>funky</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Funky \Funk"y\ (f[u^][ng]k"[y^]), n.
   having an earthy, unsophisticated style or feeling; in
   (Music), earthy and seemingly unsophisticated, having
   elements of black American blues and gospel. See 2nd {funk},
   n.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>funky</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>funky adj. Said of something that functions, but in a slightly strange,
   klugey way. It does the job and would be difficult to change, so its
   obvious non-optimality is left alone. Often used to describe interfaces.
   The more bugs something has that nobody has bothered to fix because
   workarounds are easier, the funkier it is. {TECO} and UUCP are funky.
   The Intel i860's exception handling is extraordinarily funky. Most
   standards acquire funkiness as they age. "The new mailer is installed,
   but is still somewhat funky; if it bounces your mail for no reason, try
   resubmitting it." "This UART is pretty funky. The data ready line is
   active-high in interrupt mode and active-low in DMA mode."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>funky</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>funky
     adj 1: offensively malodorous; "a putrid smell" [syn: {fetid}, {foetid},
             {foul}, {foul-smelling}, {noisome}, {smelly}, {putrid},
             {stinking}]
     2: (of jazz) having the soulful feeling of early blues [syn: {low-down}]
     3: in a state of cowardly fright
     [also: {funkiest}, {funkier}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
