<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fur</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fur \Fur\ (f[^u]r), n. [OE. furre, OF. forre, fuerre, sheath,
   case, of German origin; cf. OHG. fuotar lining, case, G.
   futter; akin to Icel. f[=o][eth]r lining, Goth. f[=o]dr,
   scabbard; cf. Skr. p[=a]tra vessel, dish. The German and
   Icel. words also have the sense, fodder, but this was
   probably a different word originally. Cf. {Fodder} food,
   {Fother}, v. t., {Forel}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The short, fine, soft hair of certain animals, growing
      thick on the skin, and distinguished from the hair, which
      is longer and coarser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The skins of certain wild animals with the fur; peltry;
      as, a cargo of furs.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Strips of dressed skins with fur, used on garments for
      warmth or for ornament.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. pl. Articles of clothing made of fur; as, a set of furs
      for a lady (a collar, tippet, or cape, muff, etc.).
      [1913 Webster]

            Wrapped up in my furs.                --Lady M. W.
                                                  Montagu.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Any coating considered as resembling fur; as:
      (a) A coat of morbid matter collected on the tongue in
          persons affected with fever.
      (b) The soft, downy covering on the skin of a peach.
      (c) The deposit formed on the interior of boilers and
          other vessels by hard water.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Her.) One of several patterns or diapers used as
      tinctures. There are nine in all, or, according to some
      writers, only six. --See Tincture.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fur \Fur\, a.
   Of or pertaining to furs; bearing or made of fur; as, a fur
   cap; the fur trade.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Fur seal} (Zo["o]l.) one of several species of seals of the
      genera {Callorhinus} and {Arclocephalus}, inhabiting the
      North Pacific and the Antarctic oceans. They have a coat
      of fine and soft fur which is highly prized. The northern
      fur seal ({Callorhinus ursinus}) breeds in vast numbers on
      the Prybilov Islands, off the coast of Alaska; -- called
      also {sea bear}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fur \Fur\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Furred}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Furring}.]
   1. To line, face, or cover with fur; as, furred robes. ``You
      fur your gloves with reason.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover with morbid matter, as the tongue.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.) To nail small strips of board or larger scantling
      upon, in order to make a level surface for lathing or
      boarding, or to provide for a space or interval back of
      the plastered or boarded surface, as inside an outer wall,
      by way of protection against damp. --Gwill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fur</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fur
     n 1: the dressed hairy coat of a mammal [syn: {pelt}]
     2: dense coat of fine silky hairs on mammals (e.g., cat or seal
        or weasel)
     3: a garment made of fur
     [also: {furring}, {furred}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
