<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>furnace</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>furnace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Furnace
   (1.) Chald. attun, a large furnace with a wide open mouth, at
   the top of which materials were cast in (Dan. 3:22, 23; comp.
   Jer. 29:22). This furnace would be in constant requisition, for
   the Babylonians disposed of their dead by cremation, as did also
   the Accadians who invaded Mesopotamia.
   
     (2.) Heb. kibshan, a smelting furnace (Gen. 19:28), also a
   lime-kiln (Isa. 33:12; Amos 2:1).
   
     (3.) Heb. kur, a refining furnace (Prov. 17:3; 27:21; Ezek.
   22:18).
   
     (4.) Heb. alil, a crucible; only used in Ps. 12:6.
   
     (5.) Heb. tannur, oven for baking bread (Gen. 15:17; Isa.
   31:9; Neh. 3:11). It was a large pot, narrowing towards the top.
   When it was heated by a fire made within, the dough was spread
   over the heated surface, and thus was baked. "A smoking furnace
   and a burning lamp" (Gen. 15:17), the symbol of the presence of
   the Almighty, passed between the divided pieces of Abraham's
   sacrifice in ratification of the covenant God made with him.
   (See {OVEN}.)
   
     (6.) Gr. kamnos, a furnace, kiln, or oven (Matt. 13:42, 50;
   Rev. 1:15; 9:2).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>furnace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Furnace \Fur"nace\, n. [OE. fornais, forneis, OF. fornaise, F.
   fournaise, from L. fornax; akin to furnus oven, and prob. to
   E. forceps.]
   1. An inclosed place in which heat is produced by the
      combustion of fuel, as for reducing ores or melting
      metals, for warming a house, for baking pottery, etc.; as,
      an iron furnace; a hot-air furnace; a glass furnace; a
      boiler furnace, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Furnaces are classified as wind or air. furnaces when
         the fire is urged only by the natural draught; as blast
         furnaces, when the fire is urged by the injection
         artificially of a forcible current of air; and as
         reverberatory furnaces, when the flame, in passing to
         the chimney, is thrown down by a low arched roof upon
         the materials operated upon.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A place or time of punishment, affiction, or great trial;
      severe experience or discipline. --Deut. iv. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bustamente furnace}, a shaft furnace for roasting
      quicksilver ores.

   {Furnace bridge}, Same as {Bridge wall}. See {Bridge}, n., 5.
      

   {Furnace cadmiam} or {Furnace cadmia}, the oxide of zinc
      which accumulates in the chimneys of furnaces smelting
      zinciferous ores. --Raymond.

   {Furnace hoist} (Iron Manuf.), a lift for raising ore, coal,
      etc., to the mouth of a blast furnace.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>furnace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Furnace \Fur"nace\, n.
   1. To throw out, or exhale, as from a furnace; also, to put
      into a furnace. [Obs. or R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He furnaces
            The thick sighs from him.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>furnace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hydrocarbon \Hy`dro*car"bon\, n. [Hydro-, 2 + carbon.] (Chem.)
   A compound containing only hydrogen and carbon, as methane,
   benzene, etc.; also, by extension, any of their derivatives.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Hydrocarbon burner}, {furnace}, {stove}, a burner, furnace,
      or stove with which liquid fuel, as petroleum, is used.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>furnace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>furnace
     n : an enclosed chamber in which heat is produced to heat
         buildings, destroy refuse, smelt or refine ores, etc.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
