<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>fusion</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fusion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>FUSION
     
        Software package supplied by Network Research Corporation
        claiming to connect various different configurations of LAN.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fusion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fusion
     
        &lt;programming&gt; A {program transformation} where a {composition}
        of two functions is replaced by in-lining them and combining
        their bodies.  E.g.
     
        	f x = g (h x)	==&gt;	f x = g (2 * x)
        	g x = x + 1		f x = 2 * x + 1
        	h x = 2 * x
     
        This has the beneficial effect of reducing the number of
        function calls.  It can be especially useful where the
        intermediate result is a large data structure which can be
        eliminated.
     
        See also {vertical loop combination}.
     
        (1994-12-05)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fusion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fusion \Fu"sion\, n. [L. fusio, fr. fundere, fusum to pour,
   melt: cf. F. fusion. See {Fuse}, v. t., aud cf, {Foison}.]
   1. The act or operation of melting or rendering fluid by
      heat; the act of melting together; as, the fusion of
      metals.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being melted or dissolved by heat; a state of
      fluidity or flowing in consequence of heat; as, metals in
      fusion.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The union or blending together of things, as, melted
      together.
      [1913 Webster]

            The universal fusion of races, languages, and
            customs . . .
            had produced a corresponding fusion of creeds. --C.
                                                  Kingsley.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Watery fusion} (Chem.) the melting of certain crystals by
      heat in their own water of crystallization.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Biol.) The union, or binding together, of adjacent parts
      or tissues.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>fusion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>fusion
     n 1: an occurrence that involves the production of a union [syn:
          {merger}, {unification}]
     2: a nuclear reaction in which nuclei combine to form more
        massive nuclei with the simultaneous release of energy
        [syn: {nuclear fusion}, {nuclear fusion reaction}]
     3: the state of being combined into one body [syn: {coalition}]
     4: the merging of adjacent sounds or syllables or words
     5: the combining of images from the two eyes to form a single
        visual percept [syn: {optical fusion}]
     6: correction of an unstable part of the spine by joining two
        or more vertebrae; usually done surgically but sometimes
        done by traction or immobilization [syn: {spinal fusion}]
     7: the act of fusing (or melting) together
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
