<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>quarantine</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>quarantine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Quarantine \Quar"an*tine\, n. [F. quarantaine, OF. quaranteine,
   fr. F. quarante forty, L. quadraginta, akin to quattuor four,
   and E. four: cf. It. quarantina, quarentine. See {Four}, and
   cf. {Quadragesima}.]
   1. A space of forty days; -- used of Lent.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically, the term, originally of forty days, during
      which a ship arriving in port, and suspected of being
      infected a malignant contagious disease, is obliged to
      forbear all intercourse with the shore; hence, such
      restraint or inhibition of intercourse; also, the place
      where infected or prohibited vessels are stationed.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Quarantine is now applied also to any forced stoppage
         of travel or communication on account of malignant
         contagious disease, on land as well as by sea.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Eng. Law) The period of forty days during which the widow
      had the privilege of remaining in the mansion house of
      which her husband died seized.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Quarantine flag}, a yellow flag hoisted at the fore of a
      vessel or hung from a building, to give warning of an
      infectious disease; -- called also the {yellow jack}, and
      {yellow flag}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>quarantine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Quarantine \Quar`an*tine"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Quarantined};
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Quarantining}.]
   To compel to remain at a distance, or in a given place,
   without intercourse, when suspected of having contagious
   disease; to put under, or in, quarantine.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>quarantine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>quarantine
     n 1: enforced isolation of patients suffering from a contagious
          disease in order to prevent the spread of disease
     2: isolation to prevent the spread of infectious disease
     v : place into enforced isolation, as for medical reasons; "My
         dog was quarantined before he could live in England"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
