<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>question</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>question</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Question \Ques"tion\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Questioned}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Questioning}.] [Cf. F. questionner. See {Question},
   n.]
   1. To ask questions; to inquire.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that questioneth much shall learn much. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To argue; to converse; to dispute. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I pray you, think you question with the Jew. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>question</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Question \Ques"tion\, v. t.
   1. To inquire of by asking questions; to examine by
      interrogatories; as, to question a witness.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To doubt of; to be uncertain of; to query.
      [1913 Webster]

            And most we question what we most desire. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To raise a question about; to call in question; to make
      objection to. ``But have power and right to question thy
      bold entrance on this place.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To talk to; to converse with.
      [1913 Webster]

            With many holiday and lady terms he questioned me.
                                                  -- Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To ask; interrogate; catechise; doubt; controvert;
        dispute.

   Usage: Question, Inquire, Interrogate. To inquire is merely
          to ask for information, and implies no authority in
          the one who asks. To interrogate is to put repeated
          questions in a formal or systematic fashion to elicit
          some particular fact or facts. To question has a wider
          sense than to interrogate, and often implies an
          attitude of distrust or opposition on the part of the
          questioner.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>question</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Question \Ques"tion\, n. [F., fr. L. quaestio, fr. quaerere,
   quaesitum, to seek for, ask, inquire. See {Quest}, n.]
   1. The act of asking; interrogation; inquiry; as, to examine
      by question and answer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Discussion; debate; hence, objection; dispute; doubt; as,
      the story is true beyond question; he obeyed without
      question.
      [1913 Webster]

            There arose a question between some of John's
            disciples and the Jews about purifying. -- John iii.
                                                  25.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is to be to question, whether it be lawful for
            Christian princes to make an invasive war simply for
            the propagation of the faith.         -- Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Examination with reference to a decisive result;
      investigation; specifically, a judicial or official
      investigation; also, examination under torture.
      --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that was in question for the robbery. Shak.
            The Scottish privy council had power to put state
            prisoners to the question.            --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is asked; inquiry; interrogatory; query.
      [1913 Webster]

            But this question asked
            Puts me in doubt. Lives there who loves his pain ?
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, a subject of investigation, examination, or debate;
      theme of inquiry; matter to be inquired into; as, a
      delicate or doubtful question.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Talk; conversation; speech; speech. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In question}, in debate; in the course of examination or
      discussion; as, the matter or point in question.

   {Leading question}. See under {Leading}.

   {Out of question}, unquestionably. ``Out of question, 't is
      Maria's hand.'' --Shak.

   {Out of the question}. See under {Out}.

   {Past question}, beyond question; certainly; undoubtedly;
      unquestionably.

   {Previous question}, a question put to a parliamentary
      assembly upon the motion of a member, in order to
      ascertain whether it is the will of the body to vote at
      once, without further debate, on the subject under
      consideration.

   Note: The form of the question is: ``Shall the main question
         be now put?'' If the vote is in the affirmative, the
         matter before the body must be voted upon as it then
         stands, without further general debate or the
         submission of new amendments. In the House of
         Representatives of the United States, and generally in
         America, a negative decision operates to keep the
         business before the body as if the motion had not been
         made; but in the English Parliament, it operates to
         postpone consideration for the day, and until the
         subject may be again introduced. In American practice,
         the object of the motion is to hasten action, and it is
         made by a friend of the measure. In English practice,
         the object is to get rid of the subject for the time
         being, and the motion is made with a purpose of voting
         against it. --Cushing.

   {To beg the question}. See under {Beg}.

   {To the question}, to the point in dispute; to the real
      matter under debate.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Point; topic; subject.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>question</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>question
     n 1: an instance of questioning; "there was a question about my
          training"; "we made inquiries of all those who were
          present" [syn: {inquiry}, {enquiry}, {query}, {interrogation}]
          [ant: {answer}]
     2: the subject matter at issue; "the question of disease merits
        serious discussion"; "under the head of minor Roman poets"
        [syn: {head}]
     3: a sentence of inquiry that asks for a reply; "he asked a
        direct question"; "he had trouble phrasing his
        interrogations" [syn: {interrogation}, {interrogative}, {interrogative
        sentence}]
     4: uncertainty about the truth or factuality of existence of
        something; "the dubiousness of his claim"; "there is no
        question about the validity of the enterprise" [syn: {doubt},
         {dubiousness}, {doubtfulness}]
     5: a formal proposal for action made to a deliberative assembly
        for discussion and vote; "he made a motion to adjourn";
        "she called for the question" [syn: {motion}]
     6: an informal reference to a marriage proposal; "he was ready
        to pop the question"
     v 1: challenge the accuracy, probity, or propriety of; "We must
          question your judgment in this matter" [syn: {oppugn}, {call
          into question}]
     2: pose a series of questions to; "The suspect was questioned
        by the police"; "We questioned the survivor about the
        details of the explosion" [syn: {interrogate}]
     3: pose a question [syn: {query}]
     4: conduct an interview in television, newspaper, and radio
        reporting [syn: {interview}]
     5: place in doubt or express doubtful speculation; "I wonder
        whether this was the right thing to do"; "she wondered
        whether it would snow tonight" [syn: {wonder}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
