<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ultimate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ultimate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ultimate \Ul"ti*mate\, a. [LL. ultimatus last, extreme, fr. L.
   ultimare to come to an end, fr. ultimus the farthest, last,
   superl. from the same source as ulterior. See {Ulterior}, and
   cf. {Ultimatum}.]
   1. Farthest; most remote in space or time; extreme; last;
      final.
      [1913 Webster]

            My harbor, and my ultimate repose.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many actions apt to procure fame are not conductive
            to this our ultimate happiness.       --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Last in a train of progression or consequences; tended
      toward by all that precedes; arrived at, as the last
      result; final.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those ultimate truths and those universal laws of
            thought which we can not rationally contradict.
                                                  --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Incapable of further analysis; incapable of further
      division or separation; constituent; elemental; as, an
      ultimate constituent of matter.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ultimate analysis} (Chem.), organic analysis. See under
      {Organic}.

   {Ultimate belief}. See under {Belief}.

   {Ultimate ratio} (Math.), the limiting value of a ratio, or
      that toward which a series tends, and which it does not
      pass.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Final; conclusive. See {Final}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ultimate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ultimate \Ul"ti*mate\, v. t. &amp; i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Ultimated}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Ultimating}.]
   1. To come or bring to an end; to eventuate; to end. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To come or bring into use or practice. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ultimate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Analysis \A*nal"y*sis\, n.; pl. {Analyses}. [Gr. ?, fr. ? to
   unloose, to dissolve, to resolve into its elements; ? up + ?
   to loose. See {Loose}.]
   1. A resolution of anything, whether an object of the senses
      or of the intellect, into its constituent or original
      elements; an examination of the component parts of a
      subject, each separately, as the words which compose a
      sentence, the tones of a tune, or the simple propositions
      which enter into an argument. It is opposed to
      {synthesis}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Chem.) The separation of a compound substance, by
      chemical processes, into its constituents, with a view to
      ascertain either (a) what elements it contains, or (b) how
      much of each element is present. The former is called
      {qualitative}, and the latter {quantitative analysis}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Logic) The tracing of things to their source, and the
      resolving of knowledge into its original principles.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Math.) The resolving of problems by reducing the
      conditions that are in them to equations.
      [1913 Webster]

   5.
      (a) A syllabus, or table of the principal heads of a
          discourse, disposed in their natural order.
      (b) A brief, methodical illustration of the principles of
          a science. In this sense it is nearly synonymous with
          synopsis.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Nat. Hist.) The process of ascertaining the name of a
      species, or its place in a system of classification, by
      means of an analytical table or key.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ultimate}, {Proximate}, {Qualitative}, {Quantitative}, and
   {Volumetric analysis}. (Chem.) See under {Ultimate},
      {Proximate}, {Qualitative}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ultimate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ultimate
     adj 1: furthest or highest in degree or order; utmost or extreme;
            "the ultimate achievement"; "the ultimate question";
            "man's ultimate destiny"; "the ultimate insult";
            "one's ultimate goal in life" [ant: {proximate}]
     2: being the last or concluding element of a series; "the
        ultimate sonata of that opus"; "a distinction between the
        verb and noun senses of `conflict' is that in the verb the
        stress is on the ultimate (or last) syllable"
     3: being the ultimate or elemental constituents of anything;
        "the elemental stuff of...out of which the many forms of
        life have been molded"- Jack London; "the ultimate
        ingredients of matter"; "his proposal is elegantly simple"
        [syn: {elemental}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
