<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>understanding</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>understanding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>UNDERSTANDING, n.  A cerebral secretion that enables one having it to
know a house from a horse by the roof on the house.  Its nature and
laws have been exhaustively expounded by Locke, who rode a house, and
Kant, who lived in a horse.

    His understanding was so keen
    That all things which he'd felt, heard, seen,
    He could interpret without fail
    If he was in or out of jail.
    He wrote at Inspiration's call
    Deep disquisitions on them all,
    Then, pent at last in an asylum,
    Performed the service to compile 'em.
    So great a writer, all men swore,
    They never had not read before.
                                                       Jorrock Wormley


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>understanding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Understand \Un`der*stand"\ ([u^]n`d[~e]r*st[a^]nd"), v. t. [imp.
   &amp; p. p. {Understood} (([u^]n`d[~e]r*st[oo^]d"),), and Archaic
   {Understanded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Understanding}.] [OE.
   understanden, AS. understandan, literally, to stand under;
   cf. AS. forstandan to understand, G. verstehen. The
   development of sense is not clear. See {Under}, and {Stand}.]
   1. To have just and adequate ideas of; to apprehended the
      meaning or intention of; to have knowledge of; to
      comprehend; to know; as, to understand a problem in
      Euclid; to understand a proposition or a declaration; the
      court understands the advocate or his argument; to
      understand the sacred oracles; to understand a nod or a
      wink.
      [1913 Webster]

            Speaketh [i. e., speak thou] so plain at this time,
            I you pray,
            That we may understande what ye say.  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I understand not what you mean by this. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Understood not all was but a show.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            A tongue not understanded of the people. --Bk. of
                                                  Com. Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be apprised, or have information, of; to learn; to be
      informed of; to hear; as, I understand that Congress has
      passed the bill.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To recognize or hold as being or signifying; to suppose to
      mean; to interpret; to explain.
      [1913 Webster]

            The most learned interpreters understood the words
            of sin, and not of Abel.              --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To mean without expressing; to imply tacitly; to take for
      granted; to assume.
      [1913 Webster]

            War, then, war,
            Open or understood, must be resolved. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To stand under; to support. [Jocose &amp; R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To give one to understand}, to cause one to know.

   {To make one's self understood}, to make one's meaning clear.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>understanding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Understanding \Un`der*stand"ing\ ([u^]n`d[~e]r*st[a^]nd"[i^]ng),
   a.
   Knowing; intelligent; skillful; as, he is an understanding
   man.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>understanding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Understanding \Un`der*stand"ing\, n.
   1. The act of one who understands a thing, in any sense of
      the verb; knowledge; discernment; comprehension;
      interpretation; explanation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An agreement of opinion or feeling; adjustment of
      differences; harmony; anything mutually understood or
      agreed upon; as, to come to an understanding with another.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hoped the loyalty of his subjects would concur
            with him in the preserving of a good understanding
            between him and his people.           --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The power to understand; the intellectual faculty; the
      intelligence; the rational powers collectively conceived
      an designated; the higher capacities of the intellect; the
      power to distinguish truth from falsehood, and to adapt
      means to ends.
      [1913 Webster]

            But there is a spirit in man; and the inspiration of
            the Almighty giveth them understanding. --Job xxxii.
                                                  8.
      [1913 Webster]

            The power of perception is that which we call the
            understanding. Perception, which we make the act of
            the understanding, is of three sorts: 1. The
            perception of ideas in our mind; 2. The perception
            of the signification of signs; 3. The perception of
            the connection or repugnancy, agreement or
            disagreement, that there is between any of our
            ideas. All these are attributed to the
            understanding, or perceptive power, though it be the
            two latter only that use allows us to say we
            understand.                           --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            In its wider acceptation, understanding is the
            entire power of perceiving an conceiving, exclusive
            of the sensibility: the power of dealing with the
            impressions of sense, and composing them into
            wholes, according to a law of unity; and in its most
            comprehensive meaning it includes even simple
            apprehension.                         --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically, the discursive faculty; the faculty of
      knowing by the medium or use of general conceptions or
      relations. In this sense it is contrasted with, and
      distinguished from, the reason.
      [1913 Webster]

            I use the term understanding, not for the noetic
            faculty, intellect proper, or place of principles,
            but for the dianoetic or discursive faculty in its
            widest signification, for the faculty of relations
            or comparisons; and thus in the meaning in which
            ``verstand'' is now employed by the Germans. --Sir
                                                  W. Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Sense; intelligence; perception. See {Sense}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>understanding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>understanding
     adj : characterized by understanding based on comprehension and
           discernment and empathy; "an understanding friend"
     n 1: the cognitive condition of someone who understands; "he has
          virtually no understanding of social cause and effect"
          [syn: {apprehension}, {discernment}, {savvy}]
     2: the statement (oral or written) of an exchange of promises;
        "they had an agreement that they would not interfere in
        each other's business"; "there was an understanding
        between management and the workers" [syn: {agreement}]
     3: an inclination to support or be loyal to or to agree with an
        opinion; "his sympathies were always with the underdog";
        "I knew I could count on his understanding" [syn: {sympathy}]
     4: the capacity for rational thought or inference or
        discrimination; "we are told that man is endowed with
        reason and capable of distinguishing good from evil" [syn:
         {reason}, {intellect}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
