<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>underground</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>underground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Under \Un"der\, prep. [AS. under, prep. &amp; adv.; akin to OFries.
   under, OS. undar, D. onder, G. unter, OHG. untar, Icel.
   undir, Sw. &amp; Dan. under, Goth. undar, L. infra below,
   inferior lower, Skr. adhas below. [root]201. Cf. {Inferior}.]
   1. Below or lower, in place or position, with the idea of
      being covered; lower than; beneath; -- opposed to over;
      as, he stood under a tree; the carriage is under cover; a
      cellar extends under the whole house.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fruit put in bottles, and the bottles let down into
            wells under water, will keep long.    --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Be gathered now, ye waters under heaven,
            Into one place.                       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, in many figurative uses which may be classified as
      follows; 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) Denoting relation to some thing or person that is
          superior, weighs upon, oppresses, bows down, governs,
          directs, influences powerfully, or the like, in a
          relation of subjection, subordination, obligation,
          liability, or the like; as, to travel under a heavy
          load; to live under extreme oppression; to have
          fortitude under the evils of life; to have patience
          under pain, or under misfortunes; to behave like a
          Christian under reproaches and injuries; under the
          pains and penalties of the law; the condition under
          which one enters upon an office; under the necessity
          of obeying the laws; under vows of chastity.
          [1913 Webster]

                Both Jews and Gentiles . . . are all under sin.
                                                  --Rom. iii. 9.
          [1913 Webster]

                That led the embattled seraphim to war
                Under thy conduct.                --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                Who have their provand
                Only for bearing burdens, and sore blows
                For sinking under them.           --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) Denoting relation to something that exceeds in rank or
          degree, in number, size, weight, age, or the like; in
          a relation of the less to the greater, of inferiority,
          or of falling short.
          [1913 Webster]

                Three sons he dying left under age. --Spenser.
          [1913 Webster]

                Medicines take effect sometimes under, and
                sometimes above, the natural proportion of their
                virtue.                           --Hooker.
          [1913 Webster]

                There are several hundred parishes in England
                under twenty pounds a year.       --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]

                It was too great an honor for any man under a
                duke.                             --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Hence, it sometimes means at, with, or for, less than;
         as, he would not sell the horse under sixty dollars.
         [1913 Webster]

               Several young men could never leave the pulpit
               under half a dozen conceits.       --Swift.
         [1913 Webster]
      (c) Denoting relation to something that comprehends or
          includes, that represents or designates, that
          furnishes a cover, pretext, pretense, or the like; as,
          he betrayed him under the guise of friendship;
          Morpheus is represented under the figure of a boy
          asleep.
          [1913 Webster]

                A crew who, under names of old renown . . .
                abused
                Fanatic Egypt.                    --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                Mr. Duke may be mentioned under the double
                capacity of a poet and a divine.  --Felton.
          [1913 Webster]

                Under this head may come in the several contests
                and wars betwixt popes and the secular princes.
                                                  --C. Leslie.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) Less specifically, denoting the relation of being
          subject, of undergoing regard, treatment, or the like;
          as, a bill under discussion.
          [1913 Webster]

                Abject and lost, lay these, covering the flood,
                Under amazement of their hideous change.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Under arms}. (Mil.)
      (a) Drawn up fully armed and equipped.
      (b) Enrolled for military service; as, the state has a
          million men under arms.

   {Under canvas}.
      (a) (Naut.) Moved or propelled by sails; -- said of any
          vessel with her sail set, but especially of a steamer
          using her sails only, as distinguished from one under
          steam. Under steam and canvas signifies that a vessel
          is using both means of propulsion.
      (b) (Mil.) Provided with, or sheltered in, tents.

   {Under fire}, exposed to an enemy's fire; taking part in a
      battle or general engagement.

   {Under foot}. See under {Foot}, n.

   {Under ground}, below the surface of the ground.

   {Under one's signature}, with one's signature or name
      subscribed; attested or confirmed by one's signature. Cf.
      the second Note under {Over}, prep.

   {Under sail}. (Naut.)
      (a) With anchor up, and under the influence of sails;
          moved by sails; in motion.
      (b) With sails set, though the anchor is down.
      (c) Same as {Under canvas}
      (a), above. --Totten.

   {Under sentence}, having had one's sentence pronounced.

   {Under the breath}, with low voice; very softly.

   {Under the lee} (Naut.), to the leeward; as, under the lee of
      the land.

   {Under the rose}. See under {Rose}, n.

   {Under water}, below the surface of the water.

   {Under way}, or {Under weigh} (Naut.), in a condition to make
      progress; having started.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>underground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Subway \Sub"way`\, n.
   1. An underground way or gallery; especially, a passage under
      a street, in which water mains, gas mains, telegraph
      wires, etc., are conducted.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An underground railroad, usually having trains powered by
      electricity provided by an electric line running through
      the underground tunnel. It is usually confined to the
      center portion of cities; -- called also {tube}, and in
      Britain, {underground}. In certain other countries (as in
      France or Russia) it is called the {metro}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>underground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Underground \Un"der*ground`\, adv.
   Beneath the surface of the earth.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>underground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Underground \Un"der*ground`\, n.
   1. The place or space beneath the surface of the ground;
      subterranean space.
      [1913 Webster]

            A spirit raised from depth of underground. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. a subway or subway system, especially in the United
      Kingdom. [chiefly British]
      [PJC]

   3. a secret organization opposed to the prevailing
      government; as, the French underground during the Nazi
      occupation.
      [PJC]

   4. a group or movement holding unorthodox views in an
      environment where conventional ideas dominate, as in
      artistic circles.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>underground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Underground \Un"der*ground`\, a.
   1. Being below the surface of the ground; as, an underground
      story or apartment.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Done or occurring out of sight; secret. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Underground railroad} or {Underground railway}. See under
      {Railroad}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>underground</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>underground
     adj 1: under the level of the ground; "belowground storage areas";
            "underground caverns" [syn: {belowground}]
     2: conducted with or marked by hidden aims or methods;
        "clandestine intelligence operations"; "cloak-and-dagger
        activities behind enemy lines"; "hole-and-corner
        intrigue"; "secret missions"; "a secret agent"; "secret
        sales of arms"; "surreptitious mobilization of troops";
        "an undercover investigation"; "underground resistance"
        [syn: {clandestine}, {cloak-and-dagger}, {hole-and-corner(a)},
         {hugger-mugger}, {hush-hush}, {on the quiet(p)}, {secret},
         {surreptitious}, {undercover}]
     3: used of independent armed resistance forces; "guerrilla
        warfare"; "partisan forces" [syn: {guerrilla(a)}, {guerilla(a)},
         {irregular}]
     n 1: a secret group organized to overthrow a government or
          occupation force [syn: {resistance}]
     2: electric underground railway [syn: {metro}, {subway}, {tube}]
     adv 1: in or into hiding or secret operation; "the organization was
            driven underground"
     2: beneath the surface of the earth; "water flowing
        underground"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
