<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>upgrade</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>upgrade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>upgrade
     
        1. A new or better version of some {hardware} or {software}.
     
        Often used in {marketroid}-speak to mean "{bug fix}".
     
        2. The act of developing or installing a new version.
     
        (1995-03-14)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>upgrade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Grade \Grade\ (gr[=a]d), n. [F. grade, L. gradus step, pace,
   grade, from gradi to step, go. Cf. {Congress}, {Degree},
   {Gradus}.]
   1. A step or degree in any series, rank, quality, order;
      relative position or standing; as, grades of military
      rank; crimes of every grade; grades of flour.
      [1913 Webster]

            They also appointed and removed, at their own
            pleasure,
            teachers of every grade.              --Buckle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. In a railroad or highway:
      (a) The rate of ascent or descent; gradient; deviation
          from a level surface to an inclined plane; -- usually
          stated as so many feet per mile, or as one foot rise
          or fall in so many of horizontal distance; as, a heavy
          grade; a grade of twenty feet per mile, or of 1 in
          264.
      (b) A graded ascending, descending, or level portion of a
          road; a gradient.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Stock Breeding) The result of crossing a native stock
      with some better breed. If the crossbreed have more than
      three fourths of the better blood, it is called high
      grade.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At grade}, on the same level; -- said of the crossing of a
      railroad with another railroad or a highway, when they are
      on the same level at the point of crossing.

   {Down grade}, a descent, as on a graded railroad.

   {Up grade}, an ascent, as on a graded railroad.

   {Equating for grades}. See under {Equate}.

   {Grade crossing}, a crossing at grade.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>upgrade</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>upgrade
     n 1: an upward slope or grade (as in a road); "the car couldn't
          make it up the rise" [syn: {ascent}, {acclivity}, {rise},
           {raise}, {climb}] [ant: {descent}]
     2: software that provides better performance than an earlier
        version did
     3: a reservation that is upgraded; "I got an upgrade to first
        class when coach class was full"
     4: the property possessed by a slope or surface that rises
        [syn: {rise}, {rising slope}]
     5: hardware that provides better performance than an earlier
        version did
     6: the act of improving something (especially machinery) by
        raising it to a higher grade (as by adding or replacing
        components); "the power plant received a new upgrade"
     v 1: rate higher; raise in value or esteem [ant: {downgrade}]
     2: to improve, especially something that was old or outdated;
        "I've upgraded my computer so I can run better software";
        "The company upgraded their personnel"
     3: give a promotion to or assign to a higher position; "John
        was kicked upstairs when a replacement was hired"; "Women
        tend not to advance in the major law firms"; "I got
        promoted after many years of hard work" [syn: {promote}, {advance},
         {kick upstairs}, {raise}, {elevate}] [ant: {demote}]
     4: get better travel conditions; "I upgraded to First Class
        when Coach Class was overbooked"
     5: give better travel conditions to; "The airline upgraded me
        when I arrived late and Coach Class was full"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
