<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>urn</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>urn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>URN
     
        {Uniform Resource Name} (previously Uniform/Universal Resource
        Number).
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>urn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Urn \Urn\, v. t.
   To inclose in, or as in, an urn; to inurn.
   [1913 Webster]

         When horror universal shall descend,
         And heaven's dark concave urn all human race. --Young.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>urn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Urn \Urn\, n. [OE. urne, L. urna; perhaps fr. urere to burn, and
   sop called as being made of burnt clay (cf. {East}): cf. F.
   urne.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A vessel of various forms, usually a vase furnished with a
      foot or pedestal, employed for different purposes, as for
      holding liquids, for ornamental uses, for preserving the
      ashes of the dead after cremation, and anciently for
      holding lots to be drawn.
      [1913 Webster]

            A rustic, digging in the ground by Padua, found an
            urn, or earthen pot, in which there was another urn.
                                                  --Bp. Wilkins.
      [1913 Webster]

            His scattered limbs with my dead body burn,
            And once more join us in the pious urn. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: Any place of burial; the grave.
      [1913 Webster]

            Or lay these bones in an unworthy urn,
            Tombless, with no remembrance over them. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Rom. Antiq.) A measure of capacity for liquids,
      containing about three gallons and a haft, wine measure.
      It was haft the amphora, and four times the congius.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bot.) A hollow body shaped like an urn, in which the
      spores of mosses are contained; a spore case; a theca.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A tea urn. See under {Tea}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Urn mosses} (Bot.), the order of true mosses; -- so called
      because the capsules of many kinds are urn-shaped.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>urn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>URN
     Uniform Resource Name (WWW, RFC 1737)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>urn</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>urn
     n 1: a large vase that usually has a pedestal or feet
     2: a large pot for making coffee or tea
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
