<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>use</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>use</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>USE
     
        An early system on the {IBM 1103} or 1103A.
     
        [Listed in CACM 2(5):16 (May 1959)].
     
        (1994-11-11)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>use</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Use \Use\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Used}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Using}.]
   [OE. usen, F. user to use, use up, wear out, LL. usare to
   use, from L. uti, p. p. usus, to use, OL. oeti, oesus; of
   uncertain origin. Cf. {Utility}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To make use of; to convert to one's service; to avail
      one's self of; to employ; to put a purpose; as, to use a
      plow; to use a chair; to use time; to use flour for food;
      to use water for irrigation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Launcelot Gobbo, use your legs.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some other means I have which may be used. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To behave toward; to act with regard to; to treat; as, to
      use a beast cruelly. ``I will use him well.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            How wouldst thou use me now?          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cato has used me ill.                 --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To practice customarily; to make a practice of; as, to use
      diligence in business.
      [1913 Webster]

            Use hospitality one to another.       --1 Pet. iv.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To accustom; to habituate; to render familiar by practice;
      to inure; -- employed chiefly in the passive participle;
      as, men used to cold and hunger; soldiers used to
      hardships and danger.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am so used in the fire to blow.     --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou with thy compeers,
            Used to the yoke, draw'st his triumphant wheels.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To use one's self}, to behave. [Obs.] ``Pray, forgive me, if
      I have used myself unmannerly.'' --Shak.

   {To use up}.
      (a) To consume or exhaust by using; to leave nothing of;
          as, to use up the supplies.
      (b) To exhaust; to tire out; to leave no capacity of force
          or use in; to overthrow; as, he was used up by
          fatigue. [Colloq.]
          [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Employ.

   Usage: {Use}, {Employ}. We use a thing, or make use of it,
          when we derive from it some enjoyment or service. We
          employ it when we turn that service into a particular
          channel. We use words to express our general meaning;
          we employ certain technical terms in reference to a
          given subject. To make use of, implies passivity in
          the thing; as, to make use of a pen; and hence there
          is often a material difference between the two words
          when applied to persons. To speak of ``making use of
          another'' generally implies a degrading idea, as if we
          had used him as a tool; while employ has no such
          sense. A confidential friend is employed to negotiate;
          an inferior agent is made use of on an intrigue.
          [1913 Webster]

                I would, my son, that thou wouldst use the power
                Which thy discretion gives thee, to control
                And manage all.                   --Cowper.
          [1913 Webster]

                To study nature will thy time employ:
                Knowledge and innocence are perfect joy.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>use</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Use \Use\, v. i.
   1. To be wont or accustomed; to be in the habit or practice;
      as, he used to ride daily; -- now disused in the present
      tense, perhaps because of the similarity in sound, between
      ``use to,'' and ``used to.''
      [1913 Webster]

            They use to place him that shall be their captain on
            a stone.                              --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fears use to be represented in an imaginary.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus we use to say, it is the room that smokes, when
            indeed it is the fire in the room.    --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now Moses used to take the tent and to pitch it
            without the camp.                     --Ex. xxxiii.
                                                  7 (Rev. Ver.)
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be accustomed to go; to frequent; to inhabit; to dwell;
      -- sometimes followed by of. [Obs.] ``Where never foot did
      use.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            He useth every day to a merchant's house. --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye valleys low, where the mild whispers use
            Of shades, and wanton winds, and gushing brooks.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>use</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Use \Use\, n. [OE. us use, usage, L. usus, from uti, p. p. usus,
   to use. See {Use}, v. t.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of employing anything, or of applying it to one's
      service; the state of being so employed or applied;
      application; employment; conversion to some purpose; as,
      the use of a pen in writing; his machines are in general
      use.
      [1913 Webster]

            Books can never teach the use of books. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            This Davy serves you for good uses.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            When he framed
            All things to man's delightful use.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Occasion or need to employ; necessity; as, to have no
      further use for a book. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Yielding of service; advantage derived; capability of
      being used; usefulness; utility.
      [1913 Webster]

            God made two great lights, great for their use
            To man.                               --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is use alone that sanctifies expense. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Continued or repeated practice; customary employment;
      usage; custom; manner; habit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let later age that noble use envy.    --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            How weary, stale, flat and unprofitable,
            Seem to me all the uses of this world! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Common occurrence; ordinary experience. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            O C[ae]sar! these things are beyond all use. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Eccl.) The special form of ritual adopted for use in any
      diocese; as, the Sarum, or Canterbury, use; the Hereford
      use; the York use; the Roman use; etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            From henceforth all the whole realm shall have but
            one use.                              --Pref. to
                                                  Book of Common
                                                  Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The premium paid for the possession and employment of
      borrowed money; interest; usury. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou art more obliged to pay duty and tribute, use
            and principal, to him.                --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. [In this sense probably a corruption of OF. oes, fr. L.
      opus need, business, employment, work. Cf. {Operate}.]
      (Law) The benefit or profit of lands and tenements. Use
      imports a trust and confidence reposed in a man for the
      holding of lands. He to whose use or benefit the trust is
      intended shall enjoy the profits. An estate is granted and
      limited to A for the use of B.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Forging) A stab of iron welded to the side of a forging,
      as a shaft, near the end, and afterward drawn down, by
      hammering, so as to lengthen the forging.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Contingent use}, or {Springing use} (Law), a use to come
      into operation on a future uncertain event.

   {In use}.
      (a) In employment; in customary practice observance.
      (b) In heat; -- said especially of mares. --J. H. Walsh.

   {Of no use}, useless; of no advantage.

   {Of use}, useful; of advantage; profitable.

   {Out of use}, not in employment.

   {Resulting use} (Law), a use, which, being limited by the
      deed, expires or can not vest, and results or returns to
      him who raised it, after such expiration.

   {Secondary use}, or {Shifting use}, a use which, though
      executed, may change from one to another by circumstances.
      --Blackstone.

   {Statute of uses} (Eng. Law), the stat. 27 Henry VIII., cap.
      10, which transfers uses into possession, or which unites
      the use and possession.

   {To make use of}, {To put to use}, to employ; to derive
      service from; to use.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>use</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>use
     n 1: the act of using; "he warned against the use of narcotic
          drugs"; "skilled in the utilization of computers" [syn:
          {usage}, {utilization}, {utilisation}, {employment}, {exercise}]
     2: a particular service; "he put his knowledge to good use";
        "patrons have their uses"
     3: what something is used for; "the function of an auger is to
        bore holes"; "ballet is beautiful but what use is it?"
        [syn: {function}, {purpose}, {role}]
     4: (economics) the utilization of economic goods to satisfy
        needs or in manufacturing; "the consumption of energy has
        increased steadily" [syn: {consumption}, {economic
        consumption}, {usance}, {use of goods and services}]
     5: a pattern of behavior acquired through frequent repetition;
        "she had a habit twirling the ends of her hair"; "long use
        had hardened him to it" [syn: {habit}, {wont}]
     6: (law) the exercise of the legal right to enjoy the benefits
        of owning property; "we were given the use of his boat"
        [syn: {enjoyment}]
     7: exerting shrewd or devious influence especially for one's
        own advantage; "his manipulation of his friends was
        scandalous" [syn: {manipulation}]
     v 1: put into service; make work or employ (something) for a
          particular purpose or for its inherent or natural
          purpose; "use your head!"; "we only use Spanish at
          home"; "I can't make use of this tool"; "Apply a
          magnetic field here"; "This thinking was applied to many
          projects"; "How do you utilize this tool?"; "I apply
          this rule to get good results"; "use the plastic bags to
          store the food"; "He doesn't know how to use a computer"
          [syn: {utilize}, {utilise}, {apply}, {employ}]
     2: take or consume (regularly or habitually); "She uses drugs
        rarely" [syn: {habituate}]
     3: seek or achieve an end by using to one's advantage; "She
        uses her influential friends to get jobs"; "The
        president's wife used her good connections"
     4: use up, consume fully; "The legislature expended its time on
        school questions" [syn: {expend}]
     5: avail oneself to; "apply a principle"; "practice a
        religion"; "use care when going down the stairs"; "use
        your common sense"; "practice non-violent resistance"
        [syn: {practice}, {apply}]
     6: habitually do something (use only in the past tense); "She
        used to call her mother every week but now she calls only
        occasionally"; "I used to get sick when I ate in that
        dining hall"; "They used to vacation in the Bahamas"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
