<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>user</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>user</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>user
     
        1. &lt;person&gt; Someone doing "real work" with the computer, using
        it as a means rather than an end.  Someone who pays to use a
        computer.  A programmer who will believe anything you tell
        him.  One who asks silly questions without thinking for two
        seconds or looking in the documentation.  Someone who uses a
        program, however skillfully, without getting into the
        internals of the program.  One who reports {bug}s instead of
        just fixing them.  See also {luser}, {real user}.
     
        Users are looked down on by {hackers} to some extent because
        they don't understand the full ramifications of the system in
        all its glory.  The term is relative: a skilled hacker may be
        a user with respect to some program he himself does not hack.
        A LISP hacker might be one who maintains LISP or one who uses
        LISP (but with the skill of a hacker).  A LISP user is one who
        uses LISP, whether skillfully or not.  Thus there is some
        overlap between the two terms; the subtle distinctions must be
        resolved by context.
     
        2. &lt;jargon&gt; Any person, organisation, process, device,
        program, {protocol}, or system which uses a service provided
        by others.
     
        The term "{client}" (as in "{client-server}" systems) is
        rather more specific, usually implying two processes
        communicating via some protocol.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1996-04-28)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>user</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>User \Us"er\, n.
   1. One who uses. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) Enjoyment of property; use. --Mozley &amp; W.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>user</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>user n. 1. Someone doing `real work' with the computer, using it as a
   means rather than an end. Someone who pays to use a computer. See {real
   user}. 2. A programmer who will believe anything you tell him. One who
   asks silly questions. [GLS observes: This is slightly unfair. It is true
   that users ask questions (of necessity). Sometimes they are thoughtful
   or deep. Very often they are annoying or downright stupid, apparently
   because the user failed to think for two seconds or look in the
   documentation before bothering the maintainer.] See {luser}. 3. Someone
   who uses a program from the outside, however skillfully, without getting
   into the internals of the program. One who reports bugs instead of just
   going ahead and fixing them.

   The general theory behind this term is that there are two classes of
   people who work with a program: there are implementors (hackers) and
   {luser}s. The users are looked down on by hackers to some extent because
   they don't understand the full ramifications of the system in all its
   glory. (The few users who do are known as `real winners'.) The term is a
   relative one: a skilled hacker may be a user with respect to some
   program he himself does not hack. A LISP hacker might be one who
   maintains LISP or one who uses LISP (but with the skill of a hacker). A
   LISP user is one who uses LISP, whether skillfully or not. Thus there is
   some overlap between the two terms; the subtle distinctions must be
   resolved by context.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>user</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>user
     n 1: a person who makes use of a thing; someone who uses or
          employs something
     2: a person who uses something or someone selfishly or
        unethically [syn: {exploiter}]
     3: a person who takes drugs [syn: {drug user}, {substance
        abuser}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
