<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>utility</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>utility</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Utility \U*til"i*ty\, n. [OE. utilite, F. utilit['e], L.
   utilitas, fr. utilis useful. See {Utile}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The quality or state of being useful; usefulness;
      production of good; profitableness to some valuable end;
      as, the utility of manure upon land; the utility of the
      sciences; the utility of medicines.
      [1913 Webster]

            The utility of the enterprises was, however, so
            great and obvious that all opposition proved
            useless.                              --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Polit. Econ.) Adaptation to satisfy the desires or wants;
      intrinsic value. See Note under {Value}, 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Value in use is utility, and nothing else, and in
            political economy should be called by that name and
            no other.                             --F. A.
                                                  Walker.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Happiness; the greatest good, or happiness, of the
      greatest number, -- the foundation of utilitarianism. --J.
      S. Mill.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Usefulness; advantageous; benefit; profit; avail;
        service.

   Usage: {Utility}, {Usefulness}. Usefulness has an Anglo-Saxon
          prefix, utility is Latin; and hence the former is used
          chiefly of things in the concrete, while the latter is
          employed more in a general and abstract sense. Thus,
          we speak of the utility of an invention, and the
          usefulness of the thing invented; of the utility of an
          institution, and the usefulness of an individual. So
          beauty and utility (not usefulness) are brought into
          comparison. Still, the words are often used
          interchangeably.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>utility</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>utility
     adj 1: used of beef; usable but inferior [syn: {utility(a)}, {utility-grade}]
     2: capable of substituting in any of several positions on a
        team; "a utility infielder" [syn: {utility(a)}, {substitute(a)}]
     n 1: a company that performs a public service; subject to
          government regulation [syn: {public utility}, {public-service
          corporation}]
     2: the quality of being of practical use [syn: {usefulness}]
        [ant: {inutility}, {inutility}]
     3: the service provided by a utility company; "the cost of
        utilities never decreases"
     4: (economics) a measure that is to be maximized in any
        situation involving choice
     5: (computer science) a program designed for general support of
        the processes of a computer; "a computer system provides
        utility programs to perform the tasks needed by most
        users" [syn: {utility program}, {service program}]
     6: a facility composed of one or more pieces of equipment
        connected to or part of a structure and designed to
        provide a service such as heat or electricity or water or
        sewage disposal; "the price of the house included all
        utilities"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
