<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>jack</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jack, AL
  Zip code(s): 36346
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jack \Jack\ (j[a^]k), n. [F. Jacques James, L. Jacobus, Gr. ?,
   Heb. Ya 'aq[=o]b Jacob; prop., seizing by the heel; hence, a
   supplanter. Cf. {Jacobite}, {Jockey}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A familiar nickname of, or substitute for, John.
      [1913 Webster]

            You are John Rugby, and you are Jack Rugby. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An impertinent or silly fellow; a simpleton; a boor; a
      clown; also, a servant; a rustic. ``Jack fool.''
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Since every Jack became a gentleman,
            There 's many a gentle person made a Jack. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A popular colloquial name for a sailor; -- called also
      {Jack tar}, and {Jack afloat}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A mechanical contrivance, an auxiliary machine, or a
      subordinate part of a machine, rendering convenient
      service, and often supplying the place of a boy or
      attendant who was commonly called Jack; as:
      (a) A device to pull off boots.
      (b) A sawhorse or sawbuck.
      (c) A machine or contrivance for turning a spit; a smoke
          jack, or kitchen jack.
      (b) (Mining) A wooden wedge for separating rocks rent by
          blasting.
      (e) (Knitting Machine) A lever for depressing the sinkers
          which push the loops down on the needles.
      (f) (Warping Machine) A grating to separate and guide the
          threads; a heck box.
      (g) (Spinning) A machine for twisting the sliver as it
          leaves the carding machine.
      (h) A compact, portable machine for planing metal.
      (i) A machine for slicking or pebbling leather.
      (k) A system of gearing driven by a horse power, for
          multiplying speed.
      (l) A hood or other device placed over a chimney or vent
          pipe, to prevent a back draught.
      (m) In the harpsichord, an intermediate piece
          communicating the action of the key to the quill; --
          called also {hopper}.
      (n) In hunting, the pan or frame holding the fuel of the
          torch used to attract game at night; also, the light
          itself. --C. Hallock.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. A portable machine variously constructed, for exerting
      great pressure, or lifting or moving a heavy body such as
      an automobile through a small distance. It consists of a
      lever, screw, rack and pinion, hydraulic press, or any
      simple combination of mechanical powers, working in a
      compact pedestal or support and operated by a lever,
      crank, capstan bar, etc. The name is often given to a
      jackscrew, which is a kind of jack.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The small bowl used as a mark in the game of bowls.
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like an uninstructed bowler who thinks to attain the
            jack by delivering his bowl straight forward upon
            it.                                   --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The male of certain animals, as of the ass.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A young pike; a pickerel.
      (b) The jurel.
      (c) A large, California rock fish ({Sebastodes
          paucispinus}); -- called also {boccaccio}, and
          {m['e]rou}.
      (d) The wall-eyed pike.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. A drinking measure holding half a pint; also, one holding
      a quarter of a pint. [Prov. Eng.] --Halliwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Naut.)
       (a) A flag, containing only the union, without the fly,
           usually hoisted on a jack staff at the bowsprit cap;
           -- called also {union jack}. The American jack is a
           small blue flag, with a star for each State.
       (b) A bar of iron athwart ships at a topgallant masthead,
           to support a royal mast, and give spread to the royal
           shrouds; -- called also {jack crosstree}. --R. H.
           Dana, Jr.
           [1913 Webster]

   11. The knave of a suit of playing cards.

   12. (pl.) A game played with small (metallic, with
       tetrahedrally oriented spikes) objects (the jacks(1950+),
       formerly jackstones) that are tossed, caught, picked up,
       and arranged on a horizontal surface in various patterns;
       in the modern American game, the movements are
       accompanied by tossing or bouncing a rubber ball on the
       horizontal surface supporting the jacks. same as
       {jackstones}.
       [PJC]

   13. Money. [slang]
       [PJC]

   14. Apple jack.
       [PJC]

   15. Brandy.
       [PJC]

   Note: Jack is used adjectively in various senses. It
         sometimes designates something cut short or diminished
         in size; as, a jack timber; a jack rafter; a jack arch,
         etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Jack arch}, an arch of the thickness of one brick.

   {Jack back} (Brewing &amp; Malt Vinegar Manuf.), a cistern which
      receives the wort. See under 1st {Back}.

   {Jack block} (Naut.), a block fixed in the topgallant or
      royal rigging, used for raising and lowering light masts
      and spars.

   {Jack boots}, boots reaching above the knee; -- worn in the
      17 century by soldiers; afterwards by fishermen, etc.

   {Jack crosstree}. (Naut.) See 10, b, above.

   {Jack curlew} (Zo["o]l.), the whimbrel.

   {Jack frame}. (Cotton Spinning) See 4
       (g), above.

   {Jack Frost}, frost or cold weather personified as a
      mischievous person.

   {Jack hare}, a male hare. --Cowper.

   {Jack lamp}, a lamp for still hunting and camp use. See def.
      4
       (n.), above.

   {Jack plane}, a joiner's plane used for coarse work.

   {Jack post}, one of the posts which support the crank shaft
      of a deep-well-boring apparatus.

   {Jack pot} (Poker Playing), the name given to the stakes,
      contributions to which are made by each player
      successively, till such a hand is turned as shall take the
      ``pot,'' which is the sum total of all the bets. See also
      {jackpot}.

   {Jack rabbit} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of large
      American hares, having very large ears and long legs. The
      California species ({Lepus Californicus}), and that of
      Texas and New Mexico ({Lepus callotis}), have the tail
      black above, and the ears black at the tip. They do not
      become white in winter. The more northern prairie hare
      ({Lepus campestris}) has the upper side of the tail white,
      and in winter its fur becomes nearly white.

   {Jack rafter} (Arch.), in England, one of the shorter rafters
      used in constructing a hip or valley roof; in the United
      States, any secondary roof timber, as the common rafters
      resting on purlins in a trussed roof; also, one of the
      pieces simulating extended rafters, used under the eaves
      in some styles of building.

   {Jack salmon} (Zo["o]l.), the wall-eyed pike, or glasseye.

   {Jack sauce}, an impudent fellow. [Colloq. &amp; Obs.]

   {Jack shaft} (Mach.), the first intermediate shaft, in a
      factory or mill, which receives power, through belts or
      gearing, from a prime mover, and transmits it, by the same
      means, to other intermediate shafts or to a line shaft.

   {Jack sinker} (Knitting Mach.), a thin iron plate operated by
      the jack to depress the loop of thread between two
      needles.

   {Jack snipe}. (Zo["o]l.) See in the Vocabulary.

   {Jack staff} (Naut.), a staff fixed on the bowsprit cap, upon
      which the jack is hoisted.

   {Jack timber} (Arch.), any timber, as a rafter, rib, or
      studding, which, being intercepted, is shorter than the
      others.

   {Jack towel}, a towel hung on a roller for common use.

   {Jack truss} (Arch.), in a hip roof, a minor truss used where
      the roof has not its full section.

   {Jack tree}. (Bot.) See 1st {Jack}, n.

   {Jack yard} (Naut.), a short spar to extend a topsail beyond
      the gaff.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Blue jack}, blue vitriol; sulphate of copper.

   {Hydraulic jack}, a jack used for lifting, pulling, or
      forcing, consisting of a compact portable hydrostatic
      press, with its pump and a reservoir containing a supply
      of liquid, as oil.

   {Jack-at-a-pinch}.
       (a) One called upon to take the place of another in an
           emergency.
       (b) An itinerant parson who conducts an occasional
           service for a fee.

   {Jack-at-all-trades}, one who can turn his hand to any kind
      of work.

   {Jack-by-the-hedge} (Bot.), a plant of the genus {Erysimum}
      ({Erysimum alliaria}, or {Alliaria officinalis}), which
      grows under hedges. It bears a white flower and has a
      taste not unlike garlic. Called also, in England,
      {sauce-alone}. --Eng. Cyc.

   {Jack-in-office}, an insolent fellow in authority. --Wolcott.

   {Jack-in-the-bush} (Bot.), a tropical shrub with red fruit
      ({Cordia Cylindrostachya}).

   {Jack-in-the-green}, a chimney sweep inclosed in a framework
      of boughs, carried in Mayday processions.

   {Jack-of-the-buttery} (Bot.), the stonecrop ({Sedum acre}).
      

   {Jack-of-the-clock}, a figure, usually of a man, on old
      clocks, which struck the time on the bell.

   {Jack-on-both-sides}, one who is or tries to be neutral.

   {Jack-out-of-office}, one who has been in office and is
      turned out. --Shak.

   {Jack the Giant Killer}, the hero of a well-known nursery
      story.

   {Yellow Jack} (Naut.), the yellow fever; also, the quarantine
      flag. See {Yellow flag}, under {Flag}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jack \Jack\ (j[a^]k), n. [Pg. jaca, Malayalam, tsjaka.] (Bot.)
   A large tree, the {Artocarpus integrifolia}, common in the
   East Indies, closely allied to the breadfruit, from which it
   differs in having its leaves entire. The fruit is of great
   size, weighing from thirty to forty pounds, and through its
   soft fibrous matter are scattered the seeds, which are
   roasted and eaten. The wood is of a yellow color, fine grain,
   and rather heavy, and is much used in cabinetwork. It is also
   used for dyeing a brilliant yellow. [Written also {jak}.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jack \Jack\, n. [F. jaque, jacque, perh. from the proper name
   Jacques. Cf. {Jacquerie}.]
   A coarse and cheap medi[ae]val coat of defense, esp. one made
   of leather.
   [1913 Webster]

         Their horsemen are with jacks for most part clad. --Sir
                                                  J. Harrington.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jack \Jack\, n. [Named from its resemblance to a jack boot.]
   A pitcher or can of waxed leather; -- called also {black
   jack}. [Obs.] --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jack \Jack\, v. i.
   To hunt game at night by means of a jack. See 2d {Jack}, n.,
   4, n.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jack \Jack\, v. t.
   To move or lift, as a house, by means of a jack or jacks. See
   2d {Jack}, n., 5.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jurel \Ju"rel\, n. (Zo["o]l.)
   A yellow carangoid fish of the Atlantic and Gulf coasts
   ({Caranx chrysos}), most abundant southward, where it is
   valued as a food fish; -- called also {hardtail}, {horse
   crevall['e]}, {jack}, {buffalo jack}, {skipjack}, {yellow
   mackerel}, and sometimes, improperly, {horse mackerel}. Other
   species of {Caranx} (as {Caranx fallax}) are also sometimes
   called jurel.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pike \Pike\, n. [F. pique; perhaps of Celtic origin; cf. W. pig
   a prick, a point, beak, Arm. pik pick. But cf. also L. picus
   woodpecker (see {Pie} magpie), and E. spike. Cf. {Pick}, n. &amp;
   v., {Peak}, {Pique}.]
   1. (Mil.) A foot soldier's weapon, consisting of a long
      wooden shaft or staff, with a pointed steel head. It is
      now superseded by the bayonet.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A pointed head or spike; esp., one in the center of a
      shield or target. --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A hayfork. [Obs. or Prov. Eng.] --Tusser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A pick. [Prov. Eng.] --Wright. Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A pointed or peaked hill. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A large haycock. [Prov. Eng.] --Halliwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A turnpike; a toll bar. --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Zo["o]l.) sing. &amp; pl. A large fresh-water fish ({Esox
      lucius}), found in Europe and America, highly valued as a
      food fish; -- called also {pickerel}, {gedd}, {luce}, and
      {jack}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Blue pike, grass pike, green pike, wall-eyed pike, and
         yellow pike, are names, not of true pike, but of the
         wall-eye. See {Wall-eye}.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Gar pike}. See under {Gar}.

   {Pike perch} (Zo["o]l.), any fresh-water fish of the genus
      {Stizostedion} (formerly {Lucioperca}). See {Wall-eye},
      and {Sauger}.

   {Pike pole}, a long pole with a pike in one end, used in
      directing floating logs.

   {Pike whale} (Zo["o]l.), a finback whale of the North
      Atlantic ({Bal[ae]noptera rostrata}), having an elongated
      snout; -- called also {piked whale}.

   {Sand pike} (Zo["o]l.), the lizard fish.

   {Sea pike} (Zo["o]l.), the garfish
      (a) .
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jack</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>jack
     n 1: a small worthless amount; "you don't know jack" [syn: {diddly-squat},
           {diddlysquat}, {diddly-shit}, {diddlyshit}, {diddly}, {diddley},
           {squat}, {shit}]
     2: a man who serves as a sailor [syn: {mariner}, {seaman}, {tar},
         {Jack-tar}, {old salt}, {seafarer}, {gob}, {sea dog}]
     3: someone who works with their hands; someone engaged in
        manual labor [syn: {laborer}, {manual laborer}, {labourer}]
     4: immense East Indian fruit resembling breadfruit of; its
        seeds are commonly roasted [syn: {jackfruit}, {jak}]
     5: an electrical device consisting of a connector socket
        designed for the insertion of a plug
     6: game equipment consisting of one of several small objects
        picked up while bouncing a ball in the game of jacks
     7: small flag indicating a ship's nationality
     8: one of four face cards in a deck bearing a picture of a
        young prince [syn: {knave}]
     9: tool for exerting pressure or lifting
     10: any of several fast-swimming predacious fishes of tropical
         to warm-temperate seas
     11: male donkey [syn: {jackass}]
     v 1: lift with a special device; "jack up the car so you can
          change the tire" [syn: {jack up}]
     2: hunt with a jacklight [syn: {jacklight}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
