<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>james</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>james</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>James
   (1.) The son of Zebedee and Salome; an elder brother of John the
   apostle. He was one of the twelve. He was by trade a fisherman,
   in partnership with Peter (Matt. 20:20; 27:56). With John and
   Peter he was present at the transfiguration (Matt. 17:1; Mark
   9:2), at the raising of Jairus's daughter (Mark 5:37-43), and in
   the garden with our Lord (14:33). Because, probably, of their
   boldness and energy, he and John were called Boanerges, i.e.,
   "sons of thunder." He was the first martyr among the apostles,
   having been beheaded by King Herod Agrippa (Acts 12:1, 2), A.D.
   44. (Comp. Matt. 4:21; 20:20-23).
   
     (2.) The son of Alphaeus, or Cleopas, "the brother" or near
   kinsman or cousin of our Lord (Gal. 1:18, 19), called James "the
   Less," or "the Little," probably because he was of low stature.
   He is mentioned along with the other apostles (Matt. 10:3; Mark
   3:18; Luke 6:15). He had a separate interview with our Lord
   after his resurrection (1 Cor. 15:7), and is mentioned as one of
   the apostles of the circumcision (Acts 1:13). He appears to have
   occupied the position of head of the Church at Jerusalem, where
   he presided at the council held to consider the case of the
   Gentiles (Acts 12:17; 15:13-29: 21:18-24). This James was the
   author of the epistle which bears his name.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>james</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>James \James\ prop. n.
   1. William James, an American psychologist and philosopher
      (1842-1910). He was the brother of Henry James.

   Syn: William James.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. Henry James, an American novelist and critic, born 1843,
      died 1916. He was the brother of William James.

   Syn: Henry James.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   3. Saint James the Apostle, a disciple of Jesus; brother of
      John; author of The Epistle of James in the New Testament.

   Syn: Saint James, St. James, Saint James the Apostle.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   4. The James River, a tributary of the Missouri River.

   Syn: James River.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>james</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>James, same as Jacob

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>james</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>James
     n 1: United States outlaw who fought as a Confederate soldier and
          later led a band of outlaws that robbed trains and banks
          in the West until he was murdered by a member of his own
          gang (1847-1882) [syn: {Jesse James}]
     2: United States pragmatic philosopher and psychologist
        (1842-1910) [syn: {William James}]
     3: writer who was born in the United States but lived in
        England (1843-1916) [syn: {Henry James}]
     4: (New Testament) disciple of Jesus; brother of John; author
        of the Epistle of James in the New Testament [syn: {Saint
        James}, {St. James}, {Saint James the Apostle}, {St. James
        the Apostle}]
     5: a river in Virginia that flows east into Chesapeake Bay at
        Hampton Roads [syn: {James River}]
     6: a river that rises in North Dakota and flows southward
        across South Dakota to the Missouri [syn: {James River}]
     7: a New Testament book attributed to Saint James the Apostle
        [syn: {Epistle of James}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
