<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>java</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>java</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Java
     
        &lt;World-Wide Web, language&gt; (After the Indonesian island, a
        source of {programming fluid}) A simple, {object-oriented},
        {distributed}, {interpreted}, robust, secure,
        {architecture-neutral}, {portable}, {multithreaded}, dynamic,
        buzzword-compliant, general-purpose programming language
        developed by {Sun Microsystems} in 1995(?).  Java supports
        programming for the {Internet} in the form of
        {platform}-independent Java "applets".
     
        Java is similar to {C++} without {operator overloading}
        (though it does have {method} overloading), without {multiple
        inheritance}, and extensive automatic {coercions}.  It has
        automatic {garbage collection}.
     
        Java programs can run stand-alone on small computers.  The
        {interpreter} and {class} support take about 40 kilobytes;
        adding the standard libraries and {thread} support
        (essentially a self-contained {microkernel}) adds an
        additional 175Kb.
     
        Java extends {C++}'s {object-oriented} facilities with those
        of {Objective C} for {dynamic method resolution}.
     
        Java has an extensive library of routines for {TCP/IP}
        {protocols} like {HTTP} and {FTP}.  Java applications can
        access objects across the {Internet} via {URL}s as easily as
        on the local {file system}.
     
        The Java compiler and {linker} both enforce {strong type
        checking} - procedures must be explicitly typed.  Java
        supports the creation of {virus}-free, tamper-free systems
        with {authentication} based on {public-key encryption}.
     
        The Java compiler generates an {architecture-neutral} {object
        file} executable on any processor supporting the Java {run-time
        system}.  The object code consists of {bytecode} instructions
        designed to be both easy to interpret on any machine and
        easily translated into {native} {machine code} at load time.
     
        The Java libraries provide portable interfaces.  For example,
        there is an abstract Window class and implementations of it
        for {Unix}, {Microsoft Windows} and the {Macintosh}.  The
        run-time system is written in {POSIX}-compliant {ANSI C}.  Java
        applets can be executed as attachments in {World-Wide Web}
        documents using either Sun's {HotJava} browser or {Netscape
        Navigator} version 2.0.
     
        {Home (http://java.sun.com/)}.
     
        {Usenet} newsgroup: {news:comp.lang.java}.
     
        E-mail: &lt;java@java.sun.com&gt;.
     
        (1995-12-06)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>java</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Java, SD (city, FIPS 32460)
  Location: 45.50358 N, 99.88423 W
  Population (1990): 161 (125 housing units)
  Area: 1.2 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 57452
Java, VA
  Zip code(s): 24565
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>java</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Java \Ja"va\ (j[aum]"v[.a]), n.
   1. One of the islands of the Malay Archipelago belonging to
      the Netherlands.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Java coffee, a kind of coffee brought from Java.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Computers) [all capitals] an object-oriented computer
      programming language, derived largely from {C++}, used
      widely for design and display of web pages on the
      world-wide web. It is an interpreted language, and has
      been suggested as a platform-independent code to allow
      execution of the same progam under multiple operating
      systems without recompiling. The language is still (1997)
      under active development, and is evolving.
      [GG + PJC]

   {Java cat} (Zo["o]l.), the musang.

   {Java sparrow} (Zo["o]l.), a species of finch ({Padda
      oryzivora}), native of Java, but very commonly kept as a
      cage bird; -- called also {ricebird}, and {paddy bird}. In
      the male the upper parts are glaucous gray, the head and
      tail black, the under parts delicate rose, and the cheeks
      white. The bill is large and red. A white variety is also
      kept as a cage bird.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>java</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>higher programming language \higher programming language\ n.
   (Computers)
   a computer programming language with an instruction set
   allowing one instruction to code for several assembly
   language instructions.

   Note: The aggregation of several assembly-language
         instructions into one instruction allows much greater
         efficiency in writing computer programs. Most programs
         are now written in some higher programming language,
         such as {BASIC}, {FORTRAN}, {COBOL}, {C}, {C++}, or
         {JAVA}.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>java</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Java An object-oriented language originally developed at Sun by James
   Gosling (and known by the name "Oak") with the intention of being the
   successor to {C++} (the project was however originally sold to Sun as an
   embedded language for use in set-top boxes). After the great Internet
   explosion of 1993-1994, Java was hacked into a byte-interpreted language
   and became the focus of a relentless hype campaign by Sun, which touted
   it as the new language of choice for distributed applications.

   Java is indeed a stronger and cleaner design than C++ and has been
   embraced by many in the hacker community - but it has been a
   considerable source of frustration to many others, for reasons ranging
   from uneven support on different Web browser platforms, performance
   issues, and some notorious deficiencies in some of the standard toolkits
   (AWT in particular). {Microsoft}'s determined attempts to corrupt the
   language (which it rightly sees as a threat to its OS monopoly) have not
   helped. As of 2001, these issues are still in the process of being
   resolved.

   Despite many attractive features and a good design, it is difficult to
   find people willing to praise Java who have tried to implement a
   complex, real-world system with it (but to be fair it is early days yet,
   and no other language has ever been forced to spend its childhood under
   the limelight the way Java has). On the other hand, Java has already
   been a big {win} in academic circles, where it has taken the place of
   {Pascal} as the preferred tool for teaching the basics of good
   programming to the next generation of hackers.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>java</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Java
     n 1: an island in Indonesia south of Borneo; one of the world's
          most densely populated regions
     2: a beverage consisting of an infusion of ground coffee beans;
        "he ordered a cup of coffee" [syn: {coffee}]
     3: a simple platform-independent object-oriented programming
        language used for writing applets that are downloaded from
        the World Wide Web by a client and run on the client's
        machine
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
