<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>jesus</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jesus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jesus
   (1.) Joshua, the son of Nun (Acts 7:45; Heb. 4:8; R.V.,
   "Joshua").
   
     (2.) A Jewish Christian surnamed Justus (Col. 4:11).
   
     Je'sus, the proper, as Christ is the official, name of our
   Lord. To distinguish him from others so called, he is spoken of
   as "Jesus of Nazareth" (John 18:7), and "Jesus the son of
   Joseph" (John 6:42).
   
     This is the Greek form of the Hebrew name Joshua, which was
   originally Hoshea (Num. 13:8, 16), but changed by Moses into
   Jehoshua (Num. 13:16; 1 Chr. 7:27), or Joshua. After the Exile
   it assumed the form Jeshua, whence the Greek form Jesus. It was
   given to our Lord to denote the object of his mission, to save
   (Matt. 1:21).
   
     The life of Jesus on earth may be divided into two great
   periods, (1) that of his private life, till he was about thirty
   years of age; and (2) that of his public life, which lasted
   about three years.
   
     In the "fulness of time" he was born at Bethlehem, in the
   reign of the emperor Augustus, of Mary, who was betrothed to
   Joseph, a carpenter (Matt. 1:1; Luke 3:23; comp. John 7:42). His
   birth was announced to the shepherds (Luke 2:8-20). Wise men
   from the east came to Bethlehem to see him who was born "King of
   the Jews," bringing gifts with them (Matt. 2:1-12). Herod's
   cruel jealousy led to Joseph's flight into Egypt with Mary and
   the infant Jesus, where they tarried till the death of this king
   (Matt. 2:13-23), when they returned and settled in Nazareth, in
   Lower Galilee (2:23; comp. Luke 4:16; John 1:46, etc.). At the
   age of twelve years he went up to Jerusalem to the Passover with
   his parents. There, in the temple, "in the midst of the
   doctors," all that heard him were "astonished at his
   understanding and answers" (Luke 2:41, etc.).
   
     Eighteen years pass, of which we have no record beyond this,
   that he returned to Nazareth and "increased in wisdom and
   stature, and in favour with God and man" (Luke 2:52).
   
     He entered on his public ministry when he was about thirty
   years of age. It is generally reckoned to have extended to about
   three years. "Each of these years had peculiar features of its
   own. (1.) The first year may be called the year of obscurity,
   both because the records of it which we possess are very scanty,
   and because he seems during it to have been only slowly emerging
   into public notice. It was spent for the most part in Judea.
   (2.) The second year was the year of public favour, during which
   the country had become thoroughly aware of him; his activity was
   incessant, and his frame rang through the length and breadth of
   the land. It was almost wholly passed in Galilee. (3.) The third
   was the year of opposition, when the public favour ebbed away.
   His enemies multiplied and assailed him with more and more
   pertinacity, and at last he fell a victim to their hatred. The
   first six months of this final year were passed in Galilee, and
   the last six in other parts of the land.", Stalker's Life of
   Jesus Christ, p. 45.
   
     The only reliable sources of information regarding the life of
   Christ on earth are the Gospels, which present in historical
   detail the words and the work of Christ in so many different
   aspects. (See {CHIRST}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jesus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jesus \Je"sus\ (j[=e]"z[u^]s), prop. n. [L. Jesus, Gr. ?, from
   Heb. Y[=e]sh[=u]a'; Y[=a]h Jehovah + h[=o]sh[imac]a' to
   help.]
   The {Savior}; the name of the Son of God as announced by the
   angel to his parents; the personal name of Our Lord, in
   distinction from Christ, his official appellation. --Luke i.
   31.
   [1913 Webster]

         Thou shalt call his name Jesus; for he shall save his
         people from their sins.                  --Matt. i. 21.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The form Jesu is often used, esp. in the vocative.
         [1913 Webster]

               Jesu, do thou my soul receive.     --Keble.
         [1913 Webster]

   {The Society of Jesus}. The Roman Catholic order whose
      members are called Jesuits. See {Jesuit}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jesus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jesus, savior; deliverer

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jesus</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jesus
     n : a teacher and prophet born in Bethlehem and active in
         Nazareth; his life and sermons form the basis for
         Christianity (circa 4 BC - AD 29) [syn: {Jesus of
         Nazareth}, {the Nazarene}, {Jesus Christ}, {Christ}, {Savior},
          {Saviour}, {Good Shepherd}, {Redeemer}, {Deliverer}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
