<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>job</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Job
   persecuted, an Arabian patriarch who resided in the land of Uz
   (q.v.). While living in the midst of great prosperity, he was
   suddenly overwhelmed by a series of sore trials that fell upon
   him. Amid all his sufferings he maintained his integrity. Once
   more God visited him with the rich tokens of his goodness and
   even greater prosperity than he had enjoyed before. He survived
   the period of trial for one hundred and forty years, and died in
   a good old age, an example to succeeding generations of
   integrity (Ezek. 14:14, 20) and of submissive patience under the
   sorest calamities (James 5:11). His history, so far as it is
   known, is recorded in his book.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>job
     
        &lt;operating system&gt; All the activities involved in completing
        any project on a computer from start to finish.  A job may
        involve several processes and several programs.
     
        This term is rather old fashioned and harks back to the days
        of {batch} processing where a user would submit his job as a
        deck of {punched card}s which would typically include {source
        code} interspersed with {job control language} instructions to
        guide the various phases of the job such as compilation,
        linking, execution and printing.
     
        (1995-05-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Job, KY
  Zip code(s): 41224
Job, WV
  Zip code(s): 26296
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Job \Job\ (j[o^]b), n. [Prov. E. job, gob, n., a small piece of
   wood, v., to stab, strike; cf. E. gob, gobbet; perh.
   influenced by E. chop to cut off, to mince. See {Gob}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A sudden thrust or stab; a jab.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A piece of chance or occasional work; any definite work
      undertaken in gross for a fixed price; as, he did the job
      for a thousand dollars.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A public transaction done for private profit; something
      performed ostensibly as a part of official duty, but
      really for private gain; a corrupt official business.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any affair or event which affects one, whether fortunately
      or unfortunately. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A situation or opportunity of work; as, he lost his job.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A task, or the execution of a task; as, Michelangelo did a
      great job on the David statue.
      [PJC]

   7. (Computers) A task or coordinated set of tasks for a
      multitasking computer, submitted for processing as a
      single unit, usually for execution in background. See {job
      control language}.
      [PJC]

   Note: Job is used adjectively to signify doing jobs, used for
         jobs, or let on hire to do jobs; as, job printer; job
         master; job horse; job wagon, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {By the job}, at a stipulated sum for the work, or for each
      piece of work done; -- distinguished from {time work}; as,
      the house was built by the job.

   {Job lot}, a quantity of goods, usually miscellaneous, sold
      out of the regular course of trade, at a certain price for
      the whole; as, these articles were included in a job lot.
      

   {Job master}, one who lest out horses and carriages for hire,
      as for family use. [Eng.]

   {Job printer}, one who does miscellaneous printing, esp.
      circulars, cards, billheads, etc.

   {Odd job}, miscellaneous work of a petty kind; occasional
      work, of various kinds, or for various people.

   {to do a job on}, to harm badly or destroy. [slang]

   {on the job}, alert; performing a responsibility well.
      [slang]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Job \Job\ (j[o^]b), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Jobbed} (j[o^]bd); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Jobbing}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To strike or stab with a pointed instrument. --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To thrust in, as a pointed instrument. --Moxon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To do or cause to be done by separate portions or lots; to
      sublet (work); as, to job a contract.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Com.) To buy and sell, as a broker; to purchase of
      importers or manufacturers for the purpose of selling to
      retailers; as, to job goods.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To hire or let by the job or for a period of service; as,
      to job a carriage. --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Job \Job\, v. i.
   1. To do chance work for hire; to work by the piece; to do
      petty work.
      [1913 Webster]

            Authors of all work, to job for the season. --Moore.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To seek private gain under pretense of public service; to
      turn public matters to private advantage.
      [1913 Webster]

            And judges job, and bishops bite the town. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To carry on the business of a jobber in merchandise or
      stocks.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Job \Job\ (j[=o]b), n.
   The hero of the book of that name in the Old Testament; the
   prototypical patient man.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Job's comforter}.
   (a) A false friend; a tactless or malicious person who, under
       pretense of sympathy, insinuates rebukes.
   (b) A boil. [Colloq.]

   {Job's news}, bad news. --Carlyle.

   {Job's tears} (Bot.), a kind of grass ({Coix Lacryma}), with
      hard, shining, pearly grains.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Job, he that weeps or cries

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>job</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>job
     n 1: the principal activity in your life that you do to earn
          money; "he's not in my line of business" [syn: {occupation},
           {business}, {line of work}, {line}]
     2: a specific piece of work required to be done as a duty or
        for a specific fee; "estimates of the city's loss on that
        job ranged as high as a million dollars"; "the job of
        repairing the engine took several hours"; "the endless
        task of classifying the samples"; "the farmer's morning
        chores" [syn: {task}, {chore}]
     3: the performance of a piece of work; "she did an outstanding
        job as Ophelia"; "he gave it up as a bad job"
     4: the responsibility to do something; "it is their job to
        print the truth"
     5: a workplace; as in the expression "on the job";
     6: an object worked on; a result produced by working; "he held
        the job in his left hand and worked on it with his right"
     7: a state of difficulty that needs to be resolved; "she and
        her husband are having problems"; "it is always a job to
        contact him"; "urban problems such as traffic congestion
        and smog" [syn: {problem}]
     8: a damaging piece of work; "dry rot did the job of destroying
        the barn"; "the barber did a real job on my hair"
     9: a crime (especially a robbery); "the gang pulled off a bank
        job in St. Louis" [syn: {caper}]
     10: a Jewish hero in the Old Testament who maintained his faith
         in God in spite of afflictions that tested him
     11: any long-suffering person who withstands affliction without
         despairing
     12: (computer science) a program application that may consist of
         several steps but is a single logical unit
     13: a book in the Old Testament containing Job's pleas to God
         about his afflictions and God's reply [syn: {Book of Job}]
     v 1: profit privately from public office and official business
     2: arranged for contracted work to be done by others [syn: {subcontract},
         {farm out}]
     3: work occasionally; "As a student I jobbed during the
        semester breaks"
     4: invest at a risk; "I bought this house not because I want to
        live in it but to sell it later at a good price, so I am
        speculating" [syn: {speculate}]
     [also: {jobbing}, {jobbed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
