<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>john</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>john</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>John
   (1.) One who, with Annas and Caiaphas, sat in judgment on the
   apostles Peter and John (Acts 4:6). He was of the kindred of the
   high priest; otherwise unknown.
   
     (2.) The Hebrew name of Mark (q.v.). He is designated by this
   name in the acts of the Apostles (12:12, 25; 13:5, 13; 15:37).
   
     (3.) THE APOSTLE, brother of James the "Greater" (Matt. 4:21;
   10:2; Mark 1:19; 3:17; 10:35). He was one, probably the younger,
   of the sons of Zebedee (Matt. 4:21) and Salome (Matt. 27:56;
   comp. Mark 15:40), and was born at Bethsaida. His father was
   apparently a man of some wealth (comp. Mark 1:20; Luke 5:3; John
   19:27). He was doubtless trained in all that constituted the
   ordinary education of Jewish youth. When he grew up he followed
   the occupation of a fisherman on the Lake of Galilee. When John
   the Baptist began his ministry in the wilderness of Judea, John,
   with many others, gathered round him, and was deeply influenced
   by his teaching. There he heard the announcement, "Behold the
   Lamb of God," and forthwith, on the invitation of Jesus, became
   a disciple and ranked among his followers (John 1:36, 37) for a
   time. He and his brother then returned to their former
   avocation, for how long is uncertain. Jesus again called them
   (Matt. 4: 21; Luke 5:1-11), and now they left all and
   permanently attached themselves to the company of his disciples.
   He became one of the innermost circle (Mark 5:37; Matt. 17:1;
   26:37; Mark 13:3). He was the disciple whom Jesus loved. In zeal
   and intensity of character he was a "Boanerges" (Mark 3:17).
   This spirit once and again broke out (Matt. 20:20-24; Mark
   10:35-41; Luke 9:49, 54). At the betrayal he and Peter follow
   Christ afar off, while the others betake themselves to hasty
   flight (John 18:15). At the trial he follows Christ into the
   council chamber, and thence to the praetorium (18:16, 19, 28)
   and to the place of crucifixion (19:26, 27). To him and Peter,
   Mary first conveys tidings of the resurrection (20:2), and they
   are the first to go and see what her strange words mean. After
   the resurrection he and Peter again return to the Sea of
   Galilee, where the Lord reveals himself to them (21:1, 7). We
   find Peter and John frequently after this together (Acts 3:1;
   4:13). John remained apparently in Jerusalem as the leader of
   the church there (Acts 15:6; Gal. 2:9). His subsequent history
   is unrecorded. He was not there, however, at the time of Paul's
   last visit (Acts 21:15-40). He appears to have retired to
   Ephesus, but at what time is unknown. The seven churches of Asia
   were the objects of his special care (Rev. 1:11). He suffered
   under persecution, and was banished to Patmos (1:9); whence he
   again returned to Ephesus, where he died, probably about A.D.
   98, having outlived all or nearly all the friends and companions
   even of his maturer years. There are many interesting traditions
   regarding John during his residence at Ephesus, but these cannot
   claim the character of historical truth.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>john</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>John \John\ (j[o^]n), n. [See {Johannes}.]
   A proper name of a man.
   [1913 Webster]

   {John-apple}, a sort of apple ripe about St. John's Day. Same
      as {Apple-john}.

   {John Bull}, an ideal personification of the typical
      characteristics of an Englishman, or of the English
      people.

   {John Bullism}, English character. --W. Irving.

   {John Doe} (Law), the name formerly given to the fictitious
      plaintiff in an action of ejectment. --Mozley &amp; W.

   {John Doree}, {John Dory}. [John (or F. jaune yellow) +
      Doree, Dory.] (Zo["o]l.) An oval, compressed, European
      food fish ({Zeus faber}). Its color is yellow and olive,
      with golden, silvery, and blue reflections. It has a round
      dark spot on each side. Called also {dory}, {doree}, and
      {St. Peter's fish}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>john</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>John, the grace or mercy of the Lord

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>john</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>john
     n 1: a room equipped with toilet facilities [syn: {toilet}, {lavatory},
           {lav}, {can}, {privy}, {bathroom}]
     2: youngest son of Henry II; King of England from 1199 to 1216;
        succeeded to the throne on the death of his brother
        Richard I; lost his French possessions; in 1215 John was
        compelled by the barons to sign the Magna Carta
        (1167-1216) [syn: {King John}, {John Lackland}]
     3: (New Testament) disciple of Jesus; traditionally said to be
        the author of the 4th Gospel and three epistles and the
        book of Revelation [syn: {Saint John}, {St. John}, {Saint
        John the Apostle}, {St. John the Apostle}, {John the
        Evangelist}, {John the Divine}]
     4: a prostitute's customer [syn: {whoremaster}, {whoremonger}]
     5: the last of the four Gospels in the New Testament [syn: {Gospel
        According to John}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
