<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>joined</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joined</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Join \Join\ (join), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Joined} (joind); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Joining}.] [OE. joinen, joignen, F. joindre, fr. L.
   jungere to yoke, bind together, join; akin to jugum yoke. See
   {Yoke}, and cf. {Conjugal}, {Junction}, {Junta}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To bring together, literally or figuratively; to place in
      contact; to connect; to couple; to unite; to combine; to
      associate; to add; to append.
      [1913 Webster]

            Woe unto them that join house to house. --Is. v. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

            Held up his left hand, which did flame and burn
            Like twenty torches joined.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy tuneful voice with numbers join.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To associate one's self to; to be or become connected
      with; to league one's self with; to unite with; as, to
      join a party; to join the church.
      [1913 Webster]

            We jointly now to join no other head. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To unite in marriage.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that joineth his virgin in matrimony. --Wyclif.
      [1913 Webster]

            What, therefore, God hath joined together, let not
            man put asunder.                      --Matt. xix.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To enjoin upon; to command. [Obs. &amp; R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They join them penance, as they call it. --Tyndale.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To accept, or engage in, as a contest; as, to join
      encounter, battle, issue. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To meet with and accompany; as, we joined them at the
      restaurant.
      [PJC]

   7. To combine with (another person) in performing some
      activity; as, join me in welcoming our new president.
      [PJC]

   {To join battle}, {To join issue}. See under {Battle},
      {Issue}.

   Syn: To add; annex; unite; connect; combine; consociate;
        couple; link; append. See {Add}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joined</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>joined \joined\ adj.
   1. married. {unmarried}

   Syn: united.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. connected by a link, as railway cars or trailer trucks.

   Syn: coupled, linked.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   3. connected by or sharing a wall with another building.
      [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joined</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>joined
     adj 1: of or relating to two people who are married to each other
            [syn: {united}]
     2: connected by a link, as railway cars or trailer trucks [syn:
         {coupled}, {linked}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
