<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>joint</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Joint \Joint\ (joint), n. [F. joint, fr. joindre, p. p. joint.
   See {Join}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The place or part where two things or parts are joined or
      united; the union of two or more smooth or even surfaces
      admitting of a close-fitting or junction; junction; as, a
      joint between two pieces of timber; a joint in a pipe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A joining of two things or parts so as to admit of motion;
      an articulation, whether movable or not; a hinge; as, the
      knee joint; a node or joint of a stem; a ball and socket
      joint. See {Articulation}.
      [1913 Webster]

            A scaly gauntlet now, with joints of steel,
            Must glove this hand.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To tear thee joint by joint.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The part or space included between two joints, knots,
      nodes, or articulations; as, a joint of cane or of a grass
      stem; a joint of the leg.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any one of the large pieces of meat, as cut into portions
      by the butcher for roasting.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Geol.) A plane of fracture, or divisional plane, of a
      rock transverse to the stratification.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Arch.) The space between the adjacent surfaces of two
      bodies joined and held together, as by means of cement,
      mortar, etc.; as, a thin joint.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The means whereby the meeting surfaces of pieces in a
      structure are secured together.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. [{Jag} a notch.] A projecting or retreating part in
      something; any irregularity of line or surface, as in a
      wall. [Now Chiefly U. S.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Theaters) A narrow piece of scenery used to join together
      two flats or wings of an interior setting.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. a disreputable establishment, or a place of low resort,
       as for smoking opium; -- also used for a commercial
       establishment, implying a less than impeccable
       reputation, but often in jest; as, talking about a
       high-class joint is an oxymoron. [Slang]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   11. a marijuana cigarette. [Slang]
       [PJC]

   12. prison; -- used with ``the''. [Slang] `` he spent five
       years in the joint.''
       [PJC]

   {Coursing joint} (Masonry), the mortar joint between two
      courses of bricks or stones.

   {Fish joint}, {Miter joint}, {Universal joint}, etc. See
      under {Fish}, {Miter}, etc.

   {Joint bolt}, a bolt for fastening two pieces, as of wood,
      one endwise to the other, having a nut embedded in one of
      the pieces.

   {Joint chair} (Railroad), the chair that supports the ends of
      abutting rails.

   {Joint coupling}, a universal joint for coupling shafting.
      See under {Universal}.

   {Joint hinge}, a hinge having long leaves; a strap hinge.

   {Joint splice}, a re["e]nforce at a joint, to sustain the
      parts in their true relation.

   {Joint stool}.
       (a) A stool consisting of jointed parts; a folding stool.
           --Shak.
       (b) A block for supporting the end of a piece at a joint;
           a joint chair.

   {Out of joint}, out of place; dislocated, as when the head of
      a bone slips from its socket; hence, not working well
      together; disordered. ``The time is out of joint.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Joint \Joint\ (joint), a. [F., p. p. of joindre. See {Join}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Joined; united; combined; concerted; as, joint action.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Involving the united activity of two or more; done or
      produced by two or more working together.
      [1913 Webster]

            I read this joint effusion twice over. --T. Hook.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. United, joined, or sharing with another or with others;
      not solitary in interest or action; holding in common with
      an associate, or with associates; acting together; as,
      joint heir; joint creditor; a joint bank account; joint
      debtor, etc. ``Joint tenants of the world.'' --Donne.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Shared by, or affecting two or more; held in common; as,
      joint property; a joint bond.
      [1913 Webster]

            A joint burden laid upon us all.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Joint committee} (Parliamentary Practice), a committee
      composed of members of the two houses of a legislative
      body, for the appointment of which concurrent resolutions
      of the two houses are necessary. --Cushing.

   {Joint meeting}, or {Joint session}, the meeting or session
      of two distinct bodies as one; as, a joint meeting of
      committees representing different corporations; a joint
      session of both branches of a State legislature to chose a
      United States senator. ``Such joint meeting shall not be
      dissolved until the electoral votes are all counted and
      the result declared.'' --Joint Rules of Congress, U. S.

   {Joint resolution} (Parliamentary Practice), a resolution
      adopted concurrently by the two branches of a legislative
      body. ``By the constitution of the United States and the
      rules of the two houses, no absolute distinction is made
      between bills and joint resolutions.'' --Barclay (Digest).

   {Joint rule} (Parliamentary Practice), a rule of proceeding
      adopted by the concurrent action of both branches of a
      legislative assembly. ``Resolved, by the House of
      Representatives (the Senate concurring), that the
      sixteenth and seventeenth joint rules be suspended for the
      remainder of the session.'' --Journal H. of R., U. S.

   {Joint and several} (Law), a phrase signifying that the debt,
      credit, obligation, etc., to which it is applied is held
      in such a way that the parties in interest are engaged
      both together and individually thus a joint and several
      debt is one for which all the debtors may be sued together
      or either of them individually; used especially in the
      phrase joint and several liability.

   {Joint stock}, stock held in company.

   {Joint-stock company} (Law), a species of partnership,
      consisting generally of a large number of members, having
      a capital divided, or agreed to be divided, into shares,
      the shares owned by any member being usually transferable
      without the consent of the rest.

   {Joint tenancy} (Law), a tenure by two or more persons of
      estate by unity of interest, title, time, and possession,
      under which the survivor takes the whole. --Blackstone.

   {Joint tenant} (Law), one who holds an estate by joint
      tenancy. Contrassted with {tenant in common}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Joint \Joint\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Jointed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Jointing}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To unite by a joint or joints; to fit together; to prepare
      so as to fit together; as, to joint boards.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pierced through the yielding planks of jointed wood.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To join; to connect; to unite; to combine.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jointing their force 'gainst C[ae]sar. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To provide with a joint or joints; to articulate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fingers are jointed together for motion. --Ray.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To separate the joints; of; to divide at the joint or
      joints; to disjoint; to cut up into joints, as meat. ``He
      joints the neck.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Quartering, jointing, seething, and roasting.
                                                  --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Joint \Joint\, v. i.
   To fit as if by joints; to coalesce as joints do; as, the
   stones joint, neatly.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joint</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>joint
     adj 1: united or combined; "a joint session of Congress"; "joint
            owners" [ant: {separate}]
     2: affecting or involving two or more; "joint income-tax
        return"; "joint ownership"
     3: involving both houses of a legislature; "a joint session of
        Congress"
     n 1: (anatomy) the point of connection between two bones or
          elements of a skeleton (especially if the articulation
          allows motion) [syn: {articulation}, {articulatio}]
     2: a disreputable place of entertainment
     3: the shape or manner in which things come together and a
        connection is made [syn: {articulation}, {join}, {juncture},
         {junction}]
     4: a piece of meat roasted or for roasting and of a size for
        slicing into more than one portion [syn: {roast}]
     5: junction by which parts or objects are joined together
     6: marijuana leaves rolled into a cigarette for smoking [syn: {marijuana
        cigarette}, {reefer}, {stick}, {spliff}]
     v 1: fit as if by joints; "The boards fit neatly"
     2: provide with a joint; "the carpenter jointed two pieces of
        wood" [syn: {articulate}]
     3: fasten with a joint
     4: separate (meat) at the joint
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
