<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>joker</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Joker \Jok"er\, n.
   1. One who makes jokes or jests.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Card Playing) See {Best bower}, under 2d {Bower}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Card Playing) An extra card usually included in a deck of
      playing cards, having the same design as the others on the
      back, but on the face having a picture of a jester. It is
      not included in the deck used in most games, but in
      certain games may be included and then takes on a special
      value, such as the highest-valued card, or a wild card.
      [PJC]

   4. A clause placed in a document, such as a contract or a
      piece of legislation, not itself appearing significant,
      but in a subtle way substantially changing the effect of
      the document.
      [PJC]

   5. Hence: Any fact or condition which is unknown or not
      apparent, which reverses an apparently advantageous
      position; a kicker.
      [PJC]

   6. A person; a fellow; a chap; -- usually used in a mildly
      disparaging sense; as, who's the joker who left the ice
      cream on the table?.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bower \Bow"er\ (bou"[~e]r), n. [G. bauer a peasant. So called
   from the figure sometimes used for the knave in cards. See
   {Boor}.]
   One of the two highest cards in the pack commonly used in the
   game of euchre.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Right bower}, the knave of the trump suit, the highest card
      (except the ``Joker'') in the game.

   {Left bower}, the knave of the other suit of the same color
      as the trump, being the next to the right bower in value.
      

   {Best bower} or {Joker}, in some forms of euchre and some
      other games, an extra card sometimes added to the pack,
      which takes precedence of all others as the highest card.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>joker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>joker
     n 1: a person who enjoys telling or playing jokes [syn: {jokester}]
     2: a person who does something thoughtless or annoying; "some
        joker is blocking the driveway" [syn: {turkey}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
