<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>jonathan</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jonathan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jonathan
   whom Jehovah gave, the name of fifteen or more persons that are
   mentioned in Scripture. The chief of these are, (1.) A Levite
   descended from Gershom (Judg. 18:30). His history is recorded in
   17:7-13 and 18:30. The Rabbins changed this name into Manasseh
   "to screen the memory of the great lawgiver from the stain of
   having so unworthy an apostate among his near descendants." He
   became priest of the idol image at Dan, and this office
   continued in his family till the Captivity.
   
     (2.) The eldest son of king Saul, and the bosom friend of
   David. He is first mentioned when he was about thirty years of
   age, some time after his father's accession to the throne (1
   Sam. 13:2). Like his father, he was a man of great strength and
   activity (2 Sam. 1:23), and excelled in archery and slinging (1
   Chr. 12:2;2 Sam. 1:22). The affection that evidently subsisted
   between him and his father was interrupted by the growth of
   Saul's insanity. At length, "in fierce anger," he left his
   father's presence and cast in his lot with the cause of David (1
   Sam. 20:34). After an eventful career, interwoven to a great
   extent with that of David, he fell, along with his father and
   his two brothers, on the fatal field of Gilboa (1 Sam. 31:2, 8).
   He was first buried at Jabesh-gilead, but his remains were
   afterwards removed with those of his father to Zelah, in
   Benjamin (2 Sam. 21:12-14). His death was the occasion of
   David's famous elegy of "the Song of the Bow" (2 Sam. 1:17-27).
   He left one son five years old, Merib-baal, or Mephibosheth (2
   Sam. 4:4; comp. 1 Chr. 8:34).
   
     (3.) Son of the high priest Abiathar, and one who adhered to
   David at the time of Absalom's rebellion (2 Sam. 15:27, 36). He
   is the last descendant of Eli of whom there is any record.
   
     (4.) Son of Shammah, and David's nephew, and also one of his
   chief warriors (2 Sam. 21:21). He slew a giant in Gath.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jonathan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jonathan, given of God

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jonathan</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Jonathan
     n : red late-ripening apple; primarily eaten raw
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
