<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>journal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>journal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Journal \Jour"nal\, a. [F., fr. L. diurnalis diurnal, fr.
   diurnus belonging to the day, fr. dies day. See {Diurnal}.]
   Daily; diurnal. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Whiles from their journal labors they did rest.
                                                  --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>journal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Journal \Jour"nal\, n. [F. journal. See {Journal}, a.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A diary; an account of daily transactions and events.
      Specifically:
      (a) (Bookkeeping) A book of accounts, in which is entered
          a condensed and grouped statement of the daily
          transactions.
      (b) (Naut.) A daily register of the ship's course and
          distance, the winds, weather, incidents of the voyage,
          etc.
      (c) (Legislature) The record of daily proceedings, kept by
          the clerk.
      (d) A newspaper published daily; by extension, a weekly
          newspaper or any periodical publication, giving an
          account of passing events, the proceedings and memoirs
          of societies, etc.; a periodical; a magazine.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. That which has occurred in a day; a day's work or travel;
      a day's journey. [Obs. &amp; R.] --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.) That portion of a rotating piece, as a shaft,
      axle, spindle, etc., which turns in a bearing or box. See
      Illust. of {Axle box}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Journal box}, or {Journal bearing} (Mach.) the carrier of a
      journal; the box in which the journal of a shaft, axle, or
      pin turns.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>journal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>journal
     n 1: a daily written record of (usually personal) experiences and
          observations [syn: {diary}]
     2: a periodical dedicated to a particular subject; "he reads
        the medical journals"
     3: a ledger in which transactions have been recorded as they
        occurred [syn: {daybook}]
     4: a record book as a physical object
     5: the part of the axle contained by a bearing
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
