<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>jpeg</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jpeg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>JPEG
     
        {Joint Photographic Experts Group}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jpeg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compression \Com*pres"sion\, n. [L. compressio: cf. F.
   compression.]
   1. The act of compressing, or state of being compressed.
      ``Compression of thought.'' --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Computers) reduction of the space required for storage
      (of binary data) by an algorithm which converts the data
      to a smaller number of bits while preserving the
      information content. The act of compressing [3].

   Note: Compression may be {lossless compression}, in which all
         of the information in the original data is preserved,
         and the original data may be recovered in form
         identical to its original form; or {lossy compression},
         in which some of the information in the original data
         is lost, and decompression results in a data form
         slightly different from the original. {Lossy
         compression} is used, for example, to compress audio or
         video recordings, and sometimes images, where the
         slight differences in the original data and the data
         recovered after {lossy compression} may be
         imperceptable to the human eye or ear. The {JPEG}
         format is produced by a {lossy compression} algorithm.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jpeg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>JPEG \JPEG\ n. [Acronym from Joint Picture Experts Group.]
   (Computers)
   A standardized format for storing graphic data in binary
   computer files, allowing over 16 million different colors. It
   allows for lossy compression, i. e. the compression of data
   into a form which re-expands into an image close, but not
   identical to the original image. Files stored in this format
   usually carry the extension jpg or jpeg. Compare {GIF}.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>jpeg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>JPEG
     Joint Photographics Expert Group (org., JTC1, RFC 1521, JPEG)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
