<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>judgment</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>judgment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Judgment \Judg"ment\, n. [OE. jugement, F. jugement, LL.
   judicamentum, fr. L. judicare. See {Judge}, v. i.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of judging; the operation of the mind, involving
      comparison and discrimination, by which a knowledge of the
      values and relations of things, whether of moral
      qualities, intellectual concepts, logical propositions, or
      material facts, is obtained; as, by careful judgment he
      avoided the peril; by a series of wrong judgments he
      forfeited confidence.
      [1913 Webster]

            I oughte deme, of skilful jugement,
            That in the salte sea my wife is deed. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The power or faculty of performing such operations (see
      1); esp., when unqualified, the faculty of judging or
      deciding rightly, justly, or wisely; good sense; as, a man
      of judgment; a politician without judgment.
      [1913 Webster]

            He shall judge thy people with righteousness and thy
            poor with judgment.                   --Ps. lxxii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hernia. I would my father look'd but with my eyes.
            Theseus. Rather your eyes must with his judgment
            look.                                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The conclusion or result of judging; an opinion; a
      decision.
      [1913 Webster]

            She in my judgment was as fair as you. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who first his judgment asked, and then a place.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The act of determining, as in courts of law, what is
      conformable to law and justice; also, the determination,
      decision, or sentence of a court, or of a judge; the
      mandate or sentence of God as the judge of all.
      [1913 Webster]

            In judgments between rich and poor, consider not
            what the poor man needs, but what is his own. --Jer.
                                                  Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Most heartily I do beseech the court
            To give the judgment.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Philos.)
      (a) That act of the mind by which two notions or ideas
          which are apprehended as distinct are compared for the
          purpose of ascertaining their agreement or
          disagreement. See 1. The comparison may be threefold:
          (1) Of individual objects forming a concept. (2) Of
          concepts giving what is technically called a judgment.
          (3) Of two judgments giving an inference. Judgments
          have been further classed as analytic, synthetic, and
          identical.
      (b) That power or faculty by which knowledge dependent
          upon comparison and discrimination is acquired. See 2.
          [1913 Webster]

                A judgment is the mental act by which one thing
                is affirmed or denied of another. --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
          [1913 Webster]

                The power by which we are enabled to perceive
                what is true or false, probable or improbable,
                is called by logicians the faculty of judgment.
                                                  --Stewart.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. A calamity regarded as sent by God, by way of recompense
      for wrong committed; a providential punishment.
      ``Judgments are prepared for scorners.'' --Prov. xix. 29.
      ``This judgment of the heavens that makes us tremble.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Theol.) The final award; the last sentence.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Judgment, abridgment, acknowledgment, and lodgment are
         in England sometimes written, judgement, abridgement,
         acknowledgement, and lodgement.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: Judgment is used adjectively in many self-explaining
         combinations; as, judgment hour; judgment throne.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Judgment day} (Theol.), the last day, or period when final
      judgment will be pronounced on the subjects of God's moral
      government.

   {Judgment debt} (Law), a debt secured to the creditor by a
      judge's order.

   {Judgment hall}, a hall where courts are held.

   {Judgment seat}, the seat or bench on which judges sit in
      court; hence, a court; a tribunal. ``We shall all stand
      before the judgment seat of Christ.'' --Rom. xiv. 10.

   {Judgment summons} (Law), a proceeding by a judgment creditor
      against a judgment debtor upon an unsatisfied judgment.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Arrest of judgment}. (Law) See under {Arrest}, n.

   {Judgment of God}, a term formerly applied to extraordinary
      trials of secret crimes, as by arms and single combat, by
      ordeal, etc.; it being imagined that God would work
      miracles to vindicate innocence. See under {Ordeal}.

   Syn: Discernment; decision; determination; award; estimate;
        criticism; taste; discrimination; penetration; sagacity;
        intelligence; understanding. See {Taste}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>judgment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>judgment
     n 1: an opinion formed by judging something; "he was reluctant to
          make his judgment known"; "she changed her mind" [syn: {judgement},
           {mind}]
     2: the act of judging or assessing a person or situation or
        event; "they criticized my judgment of the contestants"
        [syn: {judgement}, {assessment}]
     3: (law) the determination by a court of competent jurisdiction
        on matters submitted to it [syn: {judgement}, {judicial
        decision}]
     4: the cognitive process of reaching a decision or drawing
        conclusions [syn: {judgement}, {judging}]
     5: the legal document stating the reasons for a judicial
        decision; "opinions are usually written by a single judge"
        [syn: {opinion}, {legal opinion}, {judgement}]
     6: the capacity to assess situations or circumstances shrewdly
        and to draw sound conclusions [syn: {judgement}, {sound
        judgment}, {sound judgement}, {perspicacity}]
     7: ability to make good judgments [syn: {sagacity}, {sagaciousness},
         {judgement}, {discernment}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
