<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>juggle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>juggle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Juggle \Jug"gle\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Juggled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Juggling}.] [OE. juglen; cf. OF. jogler, jugler, F. jongler.
   See {Juggler}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To play tricks by sleight of hand; to cause amusement and
      sport by tricks of skill; to conjure; especially, to
      maintian several objects in the air at one time by tossing
      them up with one hand, catching them with the other hand,
      and passing them from the catching to the tossing hand.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. To practice artifice or imposture.
      [1913 Webster]

            Be these juggling fiends no more believed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>juggle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Juggle \Jug"gle\, v. t.
   1. To deceive by trick or artifice.
      [1913 Webster]

            Is't possible the spells of France should juggle
            Men into such strange mysteries?      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To maintain (several objects) in continuous motion in the
      air at one time by tossing them up with one hand, catching
      them with the other hand, and passing them from the
      catching to the tossing hand; variations on this basic
      motion are also used. Also used figuratively: see senses 3
      and 4.
      [PJC]

   3. To alter (financial records) secretly for the purpose of
      theft or deception; as, to juggle the accounts. [Colloq.]
      [PJC]

   4. To arrange the performance two tasks or responsibilities
      at alternate times, so as to be able to do both; as, to
      juggle the responsibilities of a job and a mother
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>juggle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Juggle \Jug"gle\, n.
   1. A trick by sleight of hand.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An imposture; a deception. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            A juggle of state to cozen the people. --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A block of timber cut to a length, either in the round or
      split. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>juggle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>juggle
     n 1: the act of rearranging things to give a misleading
          impression [syn: {juggling}]
     2: throwing and catching several objects simultaneously [syn: {juggling}]
     v 1: influence by slyness [syn: {beguile}, {hoodwink}]
     2: manipulate by or as if by moving around components; "juggle
        an account so as to hide a deficit"
     3: deal with simultaneously; "She had to juggle her job and her
        children"
     4: throw, catch, and keep in the air several things
        simultaneously
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
