<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>habit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>habit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>HABIT, n.  A shackle for the free.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>habit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Habit \Hab"it\ (h[a^]b"[i^]t) n. [OE. habit, abit, F. habit, fr.
   L. habitus state, appearance, dress, fr. habere to have, be
   in a condition; prob. akin to E. have. See {Have}, and cf.
   {Able}, {Binnacle}, {Debt}, {Due}, {Exhibit}, {Malady.}]
   1. The usual condition or state of a person or thing, either
      natural or acquired, regarded as something had, possessed,
      and firmly retained; as, a religious habit; his habit is
      morose; elms have a spreading habit; esp., physical
      temperament or constitution; as, a full habit of body.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Biol.) The general appearance and manner of life of a
      living organism. Specifically, the tendency of a plant or
      animal to grow in a certain way; as, the deciduous habit
      of certain trees.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. Fixed or established custom; ordinary course of conduct;
      practice; usage; hence, prominently, the involuntary
      tendency or aptitude to perform certain actions which is
      acquired by their frequent repetition; as, habit is second
      nature; also, peculiar ways of acting; characteristic
      forms of behavior.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man of very shy, retired habits.    --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Outward appearance; attire; dress; hence, a garment; esp.,
      a closely fitting garment or dress worn by ladies; as, a
      riding habit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Costly thy habit as thy purse can buy. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            There are, among the statues, several of Venus, in
            different habits.                     --Addison.

   5. Hence: The distinctive clothing worn commonly by nuns or
      monks; as, in the late 1900's many orders of nuns
      discarded their habits and began to dress as ordinary lay
      women.
      [PJC]

   Syn: Practice; mode; manner; way; custom; fashion.

   Usage: {Habit}, {Custom}. Habit is a disposition or tendency
          leading us to do easily, naturally, and with growing
          certainty, what we do often; custom is external, being
          habitual use or the frequent repetition of the same
          act. The two operate reciprocally on each other. The
          custom of giving produces a habit of liberality;
          habits of devotion promote the custom of going to
          church. Custom also supposes an act of the will,
          selecting given modes of procedure; habit is a law of
          our being, a kind of ``second nature'' which grows up
          within us.
          [1913 Webster]

                How use doth breed a habit in a man! --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                He who reigns . . . upheld by old repute,
                Consent, or custom                --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>habit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Habit \Hab"it\ (h[a^]b"[i^]t), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Habited}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Habiting}.] [OE. habiten to dwell, F. habiter,
   fr. L. habitare to have frequently, to dwell, intens. fr.
   habere to have. See {Habit}, n.]
   1. To inhabit. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            In thilke places as they [birds] habiten. --Rom. of
                                                  R.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To dress; to clothe; to array.
      [1913 Webster]

            They habited themselves like those rural deities.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To accustom; to habituate. [Obs.]           --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>habit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>habit
     n 1: an established custom; "it was their habit to dine at 7
          every evening" [syn: {wont}]
     2: a pattern of behavior acquired through frequent repetition;
        "she had a habit twirling the ends of her hair"; "long use
        had hardened him to it" [syn: {use}, {wont}]
     3: (religion) a distinctive attire (as the costume of a
        religious order)
     4: excessive use of drugs [syn: {substance abuse}, {drug abuse}]
     v : put a habit on
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
