<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>halftime</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>halftime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Half \Half\ (h[aum]f), a. [AS. healf, half, half; as a noun,
   half, side, part; akin to OS., OFries., &amp; D. half, G. halb,
   Sw. half, Dan. halv, Icel. h[=a]lfr, Goth. halbs. Cf.
   {Halve}, {Behalf}.]
   1. Consisting of a moiety, or half; as, a half bushel; a half
      hour; a half dollar; a half view.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The adjective and noun are often united to form a
         compound.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Consisting of some indefinite portion resembling a half;
      approximately a half, whether more or less; partial;
      imperfect; as, a half dream; half knowledge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Assumed from thence a half consent.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Half ape} (Zo["o]l.), a lemur.

   {Half back}. (Football) See under 2d {Back}.

   {Half bent}, the first notch, for the sear point to enter, in
      the tumbler of a gunlock; the halfcock notch.

   {Half binding}, a style of bookbinding in which only the back
      and corners are in leather.

   {Half boarder}, one who boards in part; specifically, a
      scholar at a boarding school who takes dinner only.

   {Half-breadth plan} (Shipbuilding), a horizontal plan of one
      half a vessel, divided lengthwise, showing the lines.

   {Half cadence} (Mus.), a cadence on the dominant.

   {Half cap}, a slight salute with the cap. [Obs.] --Shak.

   {At half cock}, the position of the cock of a gun when
      retained by the first notch.

   {Half hitch}, a sailor's knot in a rope; half of a clove
      hitch.

   {Half hose}, short stockings; socks.

   {Half measure}, an imperfect or weak line of action.

   {Half note} (Mus.), a minim, one half of a semibreve.

   {Half pay}, half of the wages or salary; reduced pay; as, an
      officer on half pay.

   {Half price}, half the ordinary price; or a price much
      reduced.

   {Half round}.
      (a) (Arch.) A molding of semicircular section.
      (b) (Mech.) Having one side flat and the other rounded; --
          said of a file.

   {Half shift} (Mus.), a position of the hand, between the open
      position and the first shift, in playing on the violin and
      kindred instruments. See {Shift}.

   {Half step} (Mus.), a semitone; the smallest difference of
      pitch or interval, used in music.

   {Half tide}, the time or state of the tide equally distant
      from ebb and flood.

   {Half time}, half the ordinary time for work or attendance;
      as, the half-time system.

   {Half tint} (Fine Arts), a middle or intermediate tint, as in
      drawing or painting. See {Demitint}.

   {Half truth}, a statement only partially true, or which gives
      only a part of the truth. --Mrs. Browning.

   {Half year}, the space of six months; one term of a school
      when there are two terms in a year.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>halftime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>halftime \half"time`\ n.
   an intermission between the first and second half of a game,
   especially a football game. Also used attributively, as the
   halftime entertainment
   [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>halftime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>half-time
     adj : involving half the standard or customary time for an
           activity; "he had two years of half-time training"
     adv : for less than the standard number of hours; "he works
           part-time" [syn: {part-time}] [ant: {full-time}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>halftime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>halftime
     n : an intermission between the first and second half of a game
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
