<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hall</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hall
   (Gr. aule, Luke 22:55; R.V., "court"), the open court or
   quadrangle belonging to the high priest's house. In Matt. 26:69
   and Mark 14:66 this word is incorrectly rendered "palace" in the
   Authorized Version, but correctly "court" in the Revised
   Version. In John 10:1,16 it means a "sheep-fold." In Matt. 27:27
   and Mark 15:16 (A.V., "common hall;" R.V., "palace") it refers
   to the proetorium or residence of the Roman governor at
   Jerusalem. The "porch" in Matt. 26:71 is the entrance-hall or
   passage leading into the central court, which is open to the
   sky.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hall, MT
  Zip code(s): 59837
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hall \Hall\ (h[add]l), n. [OE. halle, hal, AS. heal, heall; akin
   to D. hal, OS. &amp; OHG. halla, G. halle, Icel. h["o]ll, and
   prob. from a root meaning, to hide, conceal, cover. See
   {Hell}, {Helmet}.]
   1. A building or room of considerable size and stateliness,
      used for public purposes; as, Westminster Hall, in London.
      [1913 Webster]

   2.
      (a) The chief room in a castle or manor house, and in
          early times the only public room, serving as the place
          of gathering for the lord's family with the retainers
          and servants, also for cooking and eating. It was
          often contrasted with the {bower}, which was the
          private or sleeping apartment.
          [1913 Webster]

                Full sooty was her bower and eke her hall.
                                                  --Chaucer.
          Hence, as the entrance from outside was directly into
          the hall:
      (b) A vestibule, entrance room, etc., in the more
          elaborated buildings of later times. Hence:
      (c) Any corridor or passage in a building.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. A name given to many manor houses because the magistrate's
      court was held in the hall of his mansion; a chief mansion
      house. --Cowell.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A college in an English university (at Oxford, an
      unendowed college).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The apartment in which English university students dine in
      common; hence, the dinner itself; as, hall is at six
      o'clock.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Cleared passageway in a crowd; -- formerly an exclamation.
      [Obs.] ``A hall! a hall!'' --B. Jonson.

   Syn: Entry; court; passage. See {Vestibule}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hall
     n 1: an interior passage or corridor onto which rooms open; "the
          elevators were at the end of the hall" [syn: {hallway}]
     2: a large entrance or reception room or area [syn: {anteroom},
         {antechamber}, {entrance hall}, {foyer}, {lobby}, {vestibule}]
     3: a large room for gatherings or entertainment; "lecture
        hall"; "pool hall"
     4: a college or university building containing living quarters
        for students [syn: {dormitory}, {dorm}, {residence hall},
        {student residence}]
     5: the large room of a manor or castle [syn: {manor hall}]
     6: English writer whose novel about a lesbian relationship was
        banned in Britain for many years (1883-1943) [syn: {Radclyffe
        Hall}, {Marguerite Radclyffe Hall}]
     7: United States child psychologist whose theories of child
        psychology strongly influenced educational psychology
        (1844-1924) [syn: {G. Stanley Hall}, {Granville Stanley
        Hall}]
     8: United States chemist who developed an economical method of
        producing aluminum from bauxite (1863-1914) [syn: {Charles
        Martin Hall}]
     9: United States explorer who led three expeditions to the
        Arctic (1821-1871) [syn: {Charles Francis Hall}]
     10: United States astronomer who discovered Phobos and Deimos
         (the two satellites of Mars) (1829-1907) [syn: {Asaph
         Hall}]
     11: a large and imposing house [syn: {mansion}, {mansion house},
          {manse}, {residence}]
     12: a large building used by a college or university for
         teaching or research; "halls of learning"
     13: a large building for meetings or entertainment
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
