<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>handle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>handle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>handle
     
        1. &lt;jargon&gt; (From Citizen's Band amateur radio slang) An
        electronic pseudonym or "nom de guerre" intended to conceal
        the user's true identity.  Network and BBS handles function as
        the same sort of simultaneous concealment and display one
        finds on CB.
     
        Use of grandiose handles is characteristic of {cracker}s,
        {weenie}s, {spod}s, and other lower forms of network life;
        true hackers travel on their own reputations rather than
        invented legendry.
     
        Compare {nick}.
     
        2. &lt;programming&gt; (Macintosh) A pointer to a pointer to
        dynamically-allocated memory.  The extra level of indirection
        allows on-the-fly memory compaction (to cut down on
        {fragmentation}) or garbage collection of unused resources,
        with minimal impact on the (possibly multiple) parts of the
        larger program containing references to the allocated memory.
     
        Compare {snap} (to snap a handle would defeat its purpose).
        See also {aliasing bug}, {dangling pointer}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-02-28)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>handle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Handle \Han"dle\ (h[a^]n"d'l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Handled}
   (-d'ld); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Handling} (-dl[i^]ng).] [OE.
   handlen, AS. handlian; akin to D. handelen to trade, G.
   handeln. See {Hand}.]
   1. To touch; to feel with the hand; to use or hold with the
      hand.
      [1913 Webster]

            Handle me, and see; for a spirit hath not flesh.
                                                  --Luke xxiv.
                                                  39.
      [1913 Webster]

            About his altar, handling holy things. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To manage in using, as a spade or a musket; to wield;
      often, to manage skillfully.
      [1913 Webster]

            That fellow handles his bow like a crowkeeper.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To accustom to the hand; to work upon, or take care of,
      with the hands.
      [1913 Webster]

            The hardness of the winters forces the breeders to
            house and handle their colts six months every year.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To receive and transfer; to have pass through one's hands;
      hence, to buy and sell; as, a merchant handles a variety
      of goods, or a large stock.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To deal with; to make a business of.
      [1913 Webster]

            They that handle the law knew me not. --Jer. ii. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To treat; to use, well or ill.
      [1913 Webster]

            How wert thou handled being prisoner? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To manage; to control; to practice skill upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            You shall see how I will handle her.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To use or manage in writing or speaking; to treat, as a
      theme, an argument, or an objection.
      [1913 Webster]

            We will handle what persons are apt to envy others.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To handle without gloves}. See under {Glove}. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>handle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Handle \Han"dle\ (h[a^]n"d'l), v. i.
   To use the hands.
   [1913 Webster]

         They have hands, but they handle not.    --Ps. cxv. 7.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>handle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Handle \Han"dle\, n. [AS. handle. See {Hand}.]
   1. That part of vessels, instruments, etc., which is held in
      the hand when used or moved, as the haft of a sword, the
      knob of a door, the bail of a kettle, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That of which use is made; the instrument for effecting a
      purpose; a tool. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To give a handle}, to furnish an occasion or means.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>handle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>handle n. 1. [from CB slang] An electronic pseudonym; a `nom de guerre'
   intended to conceal the user's true identity. Network and BBS handles
   function as the same sort of simultaneous concealment and display one
   finds on Citizen's Band radio, from which the term was adopted. Use of
   grandiose handles is characteristic of {warez d00dz}, {cracker}s,
   {weenie}s, {spod}s, and other lower forms of network life; true hackers
   travel on their own reputations rather than invented legendry. Compare
   {nick}, {screen name}. 2. A {magic cookie}, often in the form of a
   numeric index into some array somewhere, through which you can
   manipulate an object like a file or window. The form `file handle' is
   especially common. 3. [Mac] A pointer to a pointer to
   dynamically-allocated memory; the extra level of indirection allows
   on-the-fly memory compaction (to cut down on fragmentation) or aging out
   of unused resources, with minimal impact on the (possibly multiple)
   parts of the larger program containing references to the allocated
   memory. Compare {snap} (to snap a handle would defeat its purpose); see
   also {aliasing bug}, {dangling pointer}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>handle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>handle
     n : the appendage to an object that is designed to be held in
         order to use or move it; "he grabbed the hammer by the
         handle"; "it was an old briefcase but it still had a good
         grip" [syn: {grip}, {handgrip}, {hold}]
     v 1: be in charge of, act on, or dispose of; "I can deal with
          this crew of workers"; "This blender can't handle nuts";
          "She managed her parents' affairs after they got too
          old" [syn: {manage}, {deal}, {care}]
     2: interact in a certain way; "Do right by her"; "Treat him
        with caution, please"; "Handle the press reporters gently"
        [syn: {treat}, {do by}]
     3: deal with verbally or in some form of artistic expression;
        "This book deals with incest"; "The course covered all of
        Western Civilization"; "The new book treats the history of
        China" [syn: {cover}, {treat}, {plow}, {deal}, {address}]
     4: touch, lift, or hold with the hands; "Don't handle the
        merchandise" [syn: {palm}]
     5: handle effectively; "The burglar wielded an axe" [syn: {wield}]
     6: show and train; "The prize-winning poodle was handled by
        Mrs. Priscilla Prescott"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
