<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hanging</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hanging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hanging
   (as a punishment), a mark of infamy inflicted on the dead bodies
   of criminals (Deut. 21:23) rather than our modern mode of
   punishment. Criminals were first strangled and then hanged (Nu.
   25:4; Deut. 21:22). (See 2 Sam. 21:6 for the practice of the
   Gibeonites.)
   
     Hanging (as a curtain). (1.) Heb. masak, (a) before the
   entrance to the court of the tabernacle (Ex. 35:17); (b) before
   the door of the tabernacle (26:36, 37); (c) before the entrance
   to the most holy place, called "the veil of the covering"
   (35:12; 39:34), as the word properly means.
   
     (2.) Heb. kelaim, tapestry covering the walls of the
   tabernacle (Ex. 27:9; 35:17; Num. 3:26) to the half of the
   height of the wall (Ex. 27:18; comp. 26:16). These hangings were
   fastened to pillars.
   
     (3.) Heb. bottim (2 Kings 23:7), "hangings for the grove"
   (R.V., "for the Asherah"); marg., instead of "hangings," has
   "tents" or "houses." Such curtained structures for idolatrous
   worship are also alluded to in Ezek. 16:16.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hanging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hang \Hang\ (h[a^]ng), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hanged} (h[a^]ngd)
   or {Hung} (h[u^]ng); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Hanging}.

   Usage: The use of hanged is preferable to that of hung, when
          reference is had to death or execution by suspension,
          and it is also more common.] [OE. hangen, hongien, v.
          t. &amp; i., AS. hangian, v. i., fr. h[=o]n, v. t. (imp.
          heng, p. p. hongen); akin to OS. hang[=o]n, v. i., D.
          hangen, v. t. &amp; i., G. hangen, v. i, h["a]ngen, v. t.,
          Icel. hanga, v. i., Goth. h[=a]han, v. t. (imp.
          ha['i]hah), h[=a]han, v. i. (imp. hahaida), and perh.
          to L. cunctari to delay. [root]37. ]
   1. To suspend; to fasten to some elevated point without
      support from below; -- often used with up or out; as, to
      hang a coat on a hook; to hang up a sign; to hang out a
      banner.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fasten in a manner which will allow of free motion upon
      the point or points of suspension; -- said of a pendulum,
      a swing, a door, gate, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fit properly, as at a proper angle (a part of an
      implement that is swung in using), as a scythe to its
      snath, or an ax to its helve. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To put to death by suspending by the neck; -- a form of
      capital punishment; as, to hang a murderer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cover, decorate, or furnish by hanging pictures,
      trophies, drapery, and the like, or by covering with paper
      hangings; -- said of a wall, a room, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hung be the heavens with black.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And hung thy holy roofs with savage spoils.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To paste, as paper hangings, on the walls of a room.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To hold or bear in a suspended or inclined manner or
      position instead of erect; to droop; as, he hung his head
      in shame.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cowslips wan that hang the pensive head. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To prevent from reaching a decision, esp. by refusing to
      join in a verdict that must be unanimous; as, one
      obstinate juror can hang a jury.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To hang down}, to let fall below the proper position; to
      bend down; to decline; as, to hang down the head, or,
      elliptically, to hang the head.

   {To hang fire} (Mil.), to be slow in communicating fire
      through the vent to the charge; as, the gun hangs fire;
      hence, to hesitate, to hold back as if in suspense.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hanging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hanging \Hang"ing\, n.
   1. The act of suspending anything; the state of being
      suspended.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Death by suspension; execution by a halter.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is hung as lining or drapery for the walls of a
      room, as tapestry, paper, etc., or to cover or drape a
      door or window; -- used chiefly in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now purple hangings clothe the palace walls.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hanging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hanging \Hang"ing\, a.
   1. Requiring, deserving, or foreboding death by the halter.
      ``What a hanging face!'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Suspended from above; pendent; as, hanging shelves.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Adapted for sustaining a hanging object; as, the hanging
      post of a gate, the post which holds the hinges.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Hanging compass}, a compass suspended so that the card may
      be read from beneath.

   {Hanging garden}, a garden sustained at an artificial
      elevation by any means, as by the terraces at Babylon.

   {Hanging indentation}. See under {Indentation}.

   {Hanging rail} (Arch.), that rail of a door or casement to
      which hinges are attached.

   {Hanging side} (Mining), the overhanging side of an inclined
      or hading vein.

   {Hanging sleeves}.
      (a) Strips of the same stuff as the gown, hanging down the
          back from the shoulders.
      (b) Loose, flowing sleeves.

   {Hanging stile}. (Arch.)
      (a) That stile of a door to which hinges are secured.
      (b) That upright of a window frame to which casements are
          hinged, or in which the pulleys for sash windows are
          fastened.

   {Hanging wall} (Mining), the upper wall of inclined vein, or
      that which hangs over the miner's head when working in the
      vein.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hanging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hanging
     n 1: decoration that is hung (as a tapestry) on a wall or over a
          window; "the cold castle walls were covered with
          hangings" [syn: {wall hanging}]
     2: a form of capital punishment; victim is suspended by the
        neck from a gallows or gibbet until dead; "in those days
        the hanging of criminals was a public entertainment"
     3: the act of suspending something (hanging it from above so it
        moves freely); "there was a small ceremony for the hanging
        of the portrait" [syn: {suspension}, {dangling}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
