<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hang</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hang
     
        1. To wait for an event that will never occur.  "The system is
        hanging because it can't read from the crashed drive".  See
        {wedged}, {hung}.
     
        2. To wait for some event to occur; to hang around until
        something happens.  "The program displays a menu and then
        hangs until you type a character."  Compare {block}.
     
        3. To attach a peripheral device, especially in the
        construction "hang off": "We're going to hang another tape
        drive off the file server."  Implies a device attached with
        cables, rather than something that is strictly inside the
        machine's chassis.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hang \Hang\, v. i.
   1. To be suspended or fastened to some elevated point without
      support from below; to dangle; to float; to rest; to
      remain; to stay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be fastened in such a manner as to allow of free motion
      on the point or points of suspension.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To die or be put to death by suspension from the neck.
      [R.] ``Sir Balaam hangs.'' --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To hold for support; to depend; to cling; -- usually with
      on or upon; as, this question hangs on a single point.
      ``Two infants hanging on her neck.'' --Peacham.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To be, or be like, a suspended weight.
      [1913 Webster]

            Life hangs upon me, and becomes a burden. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To hover; to impend; to appear threateningly; -- usually
      with over; as, evils hang over the country.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To lean or incline; to incline downward.
      [1913 Webster]

            To decide which way hung the victory. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            His neck obliquely o'er his shoulder hung. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To slope down; as, hanging grounds.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To be undetermined or uncertain; to be in suspense; to
      linger; to be delayed.
      [1913 Webster]

            A noble stroke he lifted high,
            Which hung not, but so swift with tempest fell
            On the proud crest of Satan.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Cricket, Tennis, etc.) Of a ball: To rebound
       unexpectedly or unusually slowly, due to backward spin on
       the ball or imperfections of ground.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. (Baseball) to fail to curve, break, or drop as intended;
       -- said of pitches, such as curve balls or sliders.
       [PJC]

   12. (Computers) to cease to operate normally and remain
       suspended in some state without performing useful work;
       -- said of computer programs, computers, or individual
       processes within a program; as, when using Windows 3.1,
       my system would hang and need rebooting several times a
       day.

   Note: this situation could be caused by bugs within an
         operating system or within a program, or
         incompatibility between programs or between programs
         and the hardware.
         [PJC]

   {To hang around}, to loiter idly about.

   {To hang back}, to hesitate; to falter; to be reluctant. ``If
      any one among you hangs back.'' --Jowett (Thucyd.).

   {To hang by the eyelids}.
       (a) To hang by a very slight hold or tenure.
       (b) To be in an unfinished condition; to be left
           incomplete.

   {To hang in doubt}, to be in suspense.

   {To hang on} (with the emphasis on the preposition), to keep
      hold; to hold fast; to stick; to be persistent, as a
      disease.

   {To hang on the lips} {To hang on the words}, etc., to be
      charmed by eloquence.

   {To hang out}.
       (a) To be hung out so as to be displayed; to project.
       (b) To be unyielding; as, the juryman hangs out against
           an agreement; to hold out. [Colloq.]
       (c) to loiter or lounge around a particular place; as,
           teenageers tend to hang out at the mall these days.
           

   {To hang over}.
       (a) To project at the top.
       (b) To impend over.

   {To hang to}, to cling.

   {To hang together}.
       (a) To remain united; to stand by one another. ``We are
           all of a piece; we hang together.'' --Dryden.
       (b) To be self-consistent; as, the story does not hang
           together. [Colloq.]

   {To hang upon}.
       (a) To regard with passionate affection.
       (b) (Mil.) To hover around; as, to hang upon the flanks
           of a retreating enemy.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hang \Hang\ (h[a^]ng), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hanged} (h[a^]ngd)
   or {Hung} (h[u^]ng); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Hanging}.

   Usage: The use of hanged is preferable to that of hung, when
          reference is had to death or execution by suspension,
          and it is also more common.] [OE. hangen, hongien, v.
          t. &amp; i., AS. hangian, v. i., fr. h[=o]n, v. t. (imp.
          heng, p. p. hongen); akin to OS. hang[=o]n, v. i., D.
          hangen, v. t. &amp; i., G. hangen, v. i, h["a]ngen, v. t.,
          Icel. hanga, v. i., Goth. h[=a]han, v. t. (imp.
          ha['i]hah), h[=a]han, v. i. (imp. hahaida), and perh.
          to L. cunctari to delay. [root]37. ]
   1. To suspend; to fasten to some elevated point without
      support from below; -- often used with up or out; as, to
      hang a coat on a hook; to hang up a sign; to hang out a
      banner.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fasten in a manner which will allow of free motion upon
      the point or points of suspension; -- said of a pendulum,
      a swing, a door, gate, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fit properly, as at a proper angle (a part of an
      implement that is swung in using), as a scythe to its
      snath, or an ax to its helve. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To put to death by suspending by the neck; -- a form of
      capital punishment; as, to hang a murderer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cover, decorate, or furnish by hanging pictures,
      trophies, drapery, and the like, or by covering with paper
      hangings; -- said of a wall, a room, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hung be the heavens with black.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And hung thy holy roofs with savage spoils.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To paste, as paper hangings, on the walls of a room.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To hold or bear in a suspended or inclined manner or
      position instead of erect; to droop; as, he hung his head
      in shame.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cowslips wan that hang the pensive head. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To prevent from reaching a decision, esp. by refusing to
      join in a verdict that must be unanimous; as, one
      obstinate juror can hang a jury.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To hang down}, to let fall below the proper position; to
      bend down; to decline; as, to hang down the head, or,
      elliptically, to hang the head.

   {To hang fire} (Mil.), to be slow in communicating fire
      through the vent to the charge; as, the gun hangs fire;
      hence, to hesitate, to hold back as if in suspense.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hang \Hang\, n.
   1. The manner in which one part or thing hangs upon, or is
      connected with, another; as, the hang of a scythe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Connection; arrangement; plan; as, the hang of a
      discourse. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A sharp or steep declivity or slope. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {To get the hang of}, to learn the method or arrangement of;
      hence, to become accustomed to. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hang v. 1. [very common] To wait for an event that will never occur.
   "The system is hanging because it can't read from the crashed drive".
   See {wedged}, {hung}. 2. To wait for some event to occur; to hang around
   until something happens. "The program displays a menu and then hangs
   until you type a character." Compare {block}. 3. To attach a peripheral
   device, esp. in the construction `hang off': "We're going to hang
   another tape drive off the file server." Implies a device attached with
   cables, rather than something that is strictly inside the machine's
   chassis.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hang</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hang
     n 1: a special way of doing something; "he had a bent for it";
          "he had a special knack for getting into trouble"; "he
          couldn't get the hang of it" [syn: {bent}, {knack}]
     2: the way a garment hangs; "he adjusted the hang of his coat"
     3: a gymnastic exercise performed on the rings or horizontal
        bar or parallel bars when the gymnast's weight is
        supported by the arms
     v 1: be suspended or hanging; "The flag hung on the wall"
     2: cause to be hanging or suspended; "Hang that picture on the
        wall" [syn: {hang up}]
     3: kill by hanging; "The murdered was hanged on Friday" [syn: {string
        up}]
     4: let drop or droop; "Hang one's head in shame"
     5: fall or flow in a certain way; "This dress hangs well"; "Her
        long black hair flowed down her back" [syn: {fall}, {flow}]
     6: be menacing, burdensome, or oppressive; "This worry hangs on
        my mind"; "The cloud of suspicion hangs over her"
     7: give heed (to); "The children in the audience attended the
        recital quietly"; "She hung on his every word"; "They
        attended to everything he said" [syn: {attend}, {advert},
        {pay heed}, {give ear}]
     8: be suspended or poised; "Heavy fog hung over the valley"
     9: hold on tightly or tenaciously; "hang on to your father's
        hands"; "The child clung to his mother's apron" [syn: {cling}]
     10: be exhibited; "Picasso hangs in this new wing of the museum"
     11: prevent from reaching a verdict, of a jury
     12: decorate or furnish with something suspended; "Hang
         wallpaper"
     13: be placed in position as by a hinge; "This cabinet door
         doesn't hang right!"
     14: place in position as by a hinge so as to allow free movement
         in one direction; "hang a door"
     15: of meat, in order to get a gamey taste; "hang the venison
         for a few days"
     [also: {hung}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
