<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hannah</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hannah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hannah
   favour, grace, one of the wives of Elkanah the Levite, and the
   mother of Samuel (1 Sam. 1; 2). Her home was at
   Ramathaim-zophim, whence she was wont every year to go to
   Shiloh, where the tabernacle had been pitched by Joshua, to
   attend the offering of sacrifices there according to the law
   (Ex. 23:15; 34:18; Deut. 16:16), probably at the feast of the
   Passover (comp. Ex. 13:10). On occasion of one of these "yearly"
   visits, being grieved by reason of Peninnah's conduct toward
   her, she went forth alone, and kneeling before the Lord at the
   sanctuary she prayed inaudibly. Eli the high priest, who sat at
   the entrance to the holy place, observed her, and
   misunderstanding her character he harshly condemned her conduct
   (1 Sam. 1:14-16). After hearing her explanation he retracted his
   injurious charge and said to her, "Go in peace: and the God of
   Israel grant thee thy petition." Perhaps the story of the wife
   of Manoah was not unknown to her. Thereafter Elkanah and his
   family retired to their quiet home, and there, before another
   Passover, Hannah gave birth to a son, whom, in grateful memory
   of the Lord's goodness, she called Samuel, i.e., "heard of God."
   After the child was weaned (probably in his third year) she
   brought him to Shiloh into the house of the Lord, and said to
   Eli the aged priest, "Oh my lord, I am the woman that stood by
   thee here, praying unto the Lord. For this child I prayed; and
   the Lord hath given me my petition which I asked of him:
   therefore I also have granted him to the Lord; as long as he
   liveth he is granted to the Lord" (1 Sam. 1:27, 28, R.V.). Her
   gladness of heart then found vent in that remarkable prophetic
   song (2:1-10; comp. Luke 1:46-55) which contains the first
   designation of the Messiah under that name (1 Sam. 2:10,
   "Annointed" = "Messiah"). And so Samuel and his parents parted.
   He was left at Shiloh to minister "before the Lord." And each
   year, when they came up to Shiloh, Hannah brought to her absent
   child "a little coat" (Heb. meil, a term used to denote the
   "robe" of the ephod worn by the high priest, Ex. 28:31), a
   priestly robe, a long upper tunic (1 Chr. 15:27), in which to
   minister in the tabernacle (1 Sam. 2:19; 15:27; Job 2:12). "And
   the child Samuel grew before the Lord." After Samuel, Hannah had
   three sons and two daughters.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hannah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hannah, ND (city, FIPS 35060)
  Location: 48.97311 N, 98.69024 W
  Population (1990): 49 (49 housing units)
  Area: 0.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 58239
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hannah</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hannah, gracious; merciful; he that gives

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
