<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>happily</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>happily</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>happily
     
        Of software, used to emphasise that a program is unaware of
        some important fact about its environment, either because it
        has been fooled into believing a lie, or because it doesn't
        care.  The sense of "happy" here is not that of elation, but
        rather that of blissful ignorance.  "The program continues to
        run, happily unaware that its output is going to /dev/null."
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>happily</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Happily \Hap"pi*ly\ (h[a^]p"p[i^]*l[y^]), adv. [From {Happy}.]
   1. By chance; peradventure; haply. [Obs.] --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. By good fortune; fortunately; luckily.
      [1913 Webster]

            Preferred by conquest, happily o'erthrown. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. In a happy manner or state; in happy circumstances; as, he
      lived happily with his wife.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. With address or dexterity; gracefully; felicitously; in a
      manner to insure success; with success.
      [1913 Webster]

            Formed by thy converse, happily to steer
            From grave to gay, from lively to severe. --Pope.

   Syn: Fortunately; luckily; successfully; prosperously;
        contentedly; dexterously; felicitously.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>happily</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>happily adv. Of software, used to emphasize that a program is unaware
   of some important fact about its environment, either because it has been
   fooled into believing a lie, or because it doesn't care. The sense of
   `happy' here is not that of elation, but rather that of blissful
   ignorance. "The program continues to run, happily unaware that its
   output is going to /dev/null." Also used to suggest that a program or
   device would really rather be doing something destructive, and is being
   given an opportunity to do so. "If you enter an O here instead of a
   zero, the program will happily erase all your data." Neverheless, use of
   this term implies a basically benign attitude towards the program: It
   didn't mean any harm, it was just eager to do its job. We'd like to be
   angry at it but we shouldn't, we should try to understand it instead.
   The adjective "cheerfully" is often used in exactly the same way.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>happily</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>happily
     adv 1: in a joyous manner; "they shouted happily" [syn: {merrily},
            {mirthfully}, {gayly}, {blithely}, {jubilantly}, {with
            happiness}] [ant: {unhappily}]
     2: in an unexpectedly lucky way; "happily he was not injured"
        [ant: {sadly}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
