<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>happiness</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>happiness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>HAPPINESS, n.  An agreeable sensation arising from contemplating the
misery of another.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>happiness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Happiness \Hap"pi*ness\, n. [From {Happy}.]
   1. Good luck; good fortune; prosperity.
      [1913 Webster]

            All happiness bechance to thee in Milan! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An agreeable feeling or condition of the soul arising from
      good fortune or propitious happening of any kind; the
      possession of those circumstances or that state of being
      which is attended with enjoyment; the state of being
      happy; contentment; joyful satisfaction; felicity;
      blessedness.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Fortuitous elegance; unstudied grace; -- used especially
      of language.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some beauties yet no precepts can declare,
            For there's a happiness, as well as care. --Pope.

   Syn: {Happiness}, {Felicity}, {Blessedness}, {Bliss}.

   Usage: Happiness is generic, and is applied to almost every
          kind of enjoyment except that of the animal appetites;
          felicity is a more formal word, and is used more
          sparingly in the same general sense, but with elevated
          associations; blessedness is applied to the most
          refined enjoyment arising from the purest social,
          benevolent, and religious affections; bliss denotes
          still more exalted delight, and is applied more
          appropriately to the joy anticipated in heaven.
          [1913 Webster]

                O happiness! our being's end and aim! --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]

                Others in virtue place felicity,
                But virtue joined with riches and long life;
                In corporal pleasures he, and careless ease.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                His overthrow heaped happiness upon him;
                For then, and not till then, he felt himself,
                And found the blessedness of being little.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>happiness</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>happiness
     n 1: state of well-being characterized by emotions ranging from
          contentment to intense joy [syn: {felicity}] [ant: {unhappiness}]
     2: emotions experienced when in a state of well-being [ant: {sadness}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
