<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hardware</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hardware</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hardware
     
        &lt;hardware&gt; The physical, touchable, material parts of a
        computer or other system.  The term is used to distinguish
        these fixed parts of a system from the more changable
        {software} or {data} components which it executes, stores, or
        carries.
     
        Computer hardware typically consists chiefly of electronic
        devices ({CPU}, {memory}, {display}) with some
        electromechanical parts (keyboard, {printer}, {disk drives},
        {tape drives}, loudspeakers) for input, output, and storage,
        though completely non-electronic (mechanical,
        electromechanical, hydraulic, biological) computers have also
        been conceived of and built.
     
        See also {firmware}, {wetware}.
     
        (1997-01-23)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hardware</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hardware \Hard"ware`\ (h[aum]rd"w[^a]r`), n.
   1. Ware made of metal, as cutlery, kitchen utensils, and the
      like; ironmongery.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any of the physical objects used in carrying out an
      activity, in contrast to the knowledge, skill, or theory
      required to perform the activity; mostly used
      collectively.
      [PJC]

   3. Specifically: (Computers) The sum of all the physical
      objects, such as the electrical, mechanical, and
      electronic devices which comprise a computer system; as,
      the typical PC hardware suite consists of a mainboard and
      a number of peripherals such as hard drives and speakers,
      connected by adapter cards, but the input and output from
      users occurs mostly through the keyboard and monitor;
      contrasted with {software}, the programs executed by the
      computer.
      [PJC]

   4. Specifically: (Military) The weapons, transport, and other
      physical objects used in conducting a war.
      [PJC]

   5. (Slang) Weapons, especially handguns, carried on the
      person; as, check your hardware at the door before
      entering.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hardware</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hardware
     n 1: major items of military weaponry (as tanks or missile)
     2: instrumentalities (tools or implements) made of metal [syn:
        {ironware}]
     3: (computer science) the mechanical, magnetic, electronic, and
        electrical components making up a computer system [syn: {computer
        hardware}] [ant: {software}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
