<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>harmony</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>harmony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Harmony, IN (town, FIPS 31486)
  Location: 39.53402 N, 87.07342 W
  Population (1990): 645 (269 housing units)
  Area: 2.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Harmony, MN (city, FIPS 27188)
  Location: 43.55530 N, 92.00938 W
  Population (1990): 1081 (486 housing units)
  Area: 2.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 55939
Harmony, NC (town, FIPS 29640)
  Location: 35.95840 N, 80.77280 W
  Population (1990): 431 (195 housing units)
  Area: 3.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 28634
Harmony, PA (borough, FIPS 32688)
  Location: 40.80126 N, 80.12516 W
  Population (1990): 1054 (432 housing units)
  Area: 1.0 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 16037
Harmony, WV
  Zip code(s): 25246
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>harmony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Harmony \Har"mo*ny\ (h[aum]r"m[-o]*n[y^]), n.; pl. {Harmonies}
   (-n[i^]z). [F. harmonie, L. harmonia, Gr. "armoni`a joint,
   proportion, concord, fr. "armo`s a fitting or joining. See
   {Article}.]
   1. The just adaptation of parts to each other, in any system
      or combination of things, or in things intended to form a
      connected whole; such an agreement between the different
      parts of a design or composition as to produce unity of
      effect; as, the harmony of the universe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Concord or agreement in facts, opinions, manners,
      interests, etc.; good correspondence; peace and
      friendship; as, good citizens live in harmony.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A literary work which brings together or arranges
      systematically parallel passages of historians respecting
      the same events, and shows their agreement or consistency;
      as, a harmony of the Gospels.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mus.)
      (a) A succession of chords according to the rules of
          progression and modulation.
      (b) The science which treats of their construction and
          progression.
          [1913 Webster]

                Ten thousand harps, that tuned
                Angelic harmonies.                --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Anat.) See {Harmonic suture}, under {Harmonic}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Close harmony}, {Dispersed harmony}, etc. See under {Close},
      {Dispersed}, etc.

   {Harmony of the spheres}. See {Music of the spheres}, under
      {Music}.

   Syn: {Harmony}, {Melody}.

   Usage: Harmony results from the concord of two or more
          strains or sounds which differ in pitch and quality.
          Melody denotes the pleasing alternation and variety of
          musical and measured sounds, as they succeed each
          other in a single verse or strain.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>harmony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Harmonic \Har*mon"ic\ (h[aum]r*m[o^]n"[i^]k), Harmonical
\Har*mon"ic*al\ (-[i^]*kal), a. [L. harmonicus, Gr. "armoniko`s;
   cf. F. harmonique. See {Harmony}.]
   1. Concordant; musical; consonant; as, harmonic sounds.
      [1913 Webster]

            Harmonic twang! of leather, horn, and brass. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mus.) Relating to harmony, -- as melodic relates to
      melody; harmonious; esp., relating to the accessory sounds
      or overtones which accompany the predominant and apparent
      single tone of any string or sonorous body.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Math.) Having relations or properties bearing some
      resemblance to those of musical consonances; -- said of
      certain numbers, ratios, proportions, points, lines,
      motions, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Harmonic interval} (Mus.), the distance between two notes of
      a chord, or two consonant notes.

   {Harmonical mean} (Arith. &amp; Alg.), certain relations of
      numbers and quantities, which bear an analogy to musical
      consonances.

   {Harmonic motion}, the motion of the point A, of the foot of
      the perpendicular PA, when P moves uniformly in the
      circumference of a circle, and PA is drawn perpendicularly
      upon a fixed diameter of the circle. This is simple
      harmonic motion. The combinations, in any way, of two or
      more simple harmonic motions, make other kinds of harmonic
      motion. The motion of the pendulum bob of a clock is
      approximately simple harmonic motion.

   {Harmonic proportion}. See under {Proportion}.

   {Harmonic series} or {Harmonic progression}. See under
      {Progression}.

   {Spherical harmonic analysis}, a mathematical method,
      sometimes referred to as that of {Laplace's Coefficients},
      which has for its object the expression of an arbitrary,
      periodic function of two independent variables, in the
      proper form for a large class of physical problems,
      involving arbitrary data, over a spherical surface, and
      the deduction of solutions for every point of space. The
      functions employed in this method are called spherical
      harmonic functions. --Thomson &amp; Tait.

   {Harmonic suture} (Anat.), an articulation by simple
      apposition of comparatively smooth surfaces or edges, as
      between the two superior maxillary bones in man; -- called
      also {harmonia}, and {harmony}.

   {Harmonic triad} (Mus.), the chord of a note with its third
      and fifth; the common chord.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>harmony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Thorough bass \Thor"ough bass`\ (Mus.)
   The representation of chords by figures placed under the
   base; figured bass; basso continuo; -- sometimes used as
   synonymous with {harmony}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>harmony</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>harmony
     n 1: compatibility in opinion and action [syn: {harmoniousness}]
     2: the structure of music with respect to the composition and
        progression of chords [syn: {musical harmony}]
     3: a harmonious state of things in general and of their
        properties (as of colors and sounds); congruity of parts
        with one another and with the whole [syn: {concord}, {concordance}]
     4: agreement of opinions [syn: {concord}, {concordance}]
     5: an agreeable sound property [ant: {dissonance}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
