<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hast</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hast</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hast \Hast\ (h[a^]st),
   2d pers. sing. pres. of {Have}, contr. of {havest}. [Archaic]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hast</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Have \Have\ (h[a^]v), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Had} (h[a^]d); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Having}. Indic. present, I {have}, thou {hast}, he
   {has}; we, ye, they {have}.] [OE. haven, habben, AS. habben
   (imperf. h[ae]fde, p. p. geh[ae]fd); akin to OS. hebbian, D.
   hebben, OFries. hebba, OHG. hab[=e]n, G. haben, Icel. hafa,
   Sw. hafva, Dan. have, Goth. haban, and prob. to L. habere,
   whence F. avoir. Cf. {Able}, {Avoirdupois}, {Binnacle},
   {Habit}.]
   1. To hold in possession or control; to own; as, he has a
      farm.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To possess, as something which appertains to, is connected
      with, or affects, one.
      [1913 Webster]

            The earth hath bubbles, as the water has. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had a fever late.                  --Keats.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To accept possession of; to take or accept.
      [1913 Webster]

            Break thy mind to me in broken English; wilt thou
            have me?                              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To get possession of; to obtain; to get. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cause or procure to be; to effect; to exact; to desire;
      to require.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had the church accurately described to me. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wouldst thou have me turn traitor also? --Ld.
                                                  Lytton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To bear, as young; as, she has just had a child.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To hold, regard, or esteem.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of them shall I be had in honor.      --2 Sam. vi.
                                                  22.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To cause or force to go; to take. ``The stars have us to
      bed.'' --Herbert. ``Have out all men from me.'' --2 Sam.
      xiii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To take or hold (one's self); to proceed promptly; -- used
      reflexively, often with ellipsis of the pronoun; as, to
      have after one; to have at one or at a thing, i. e., to
      aim at one or at a thing; to attack; to have with a
      companion. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To be under necessity or obligation; to be compelled;
       followed by an infinitive.
       [1913 Webster]

             Science has, and will long have, to be a divider
             and a separatist.                    --M. Arnold.
       [1913 Webster]

             The laws of philology have to be established by
             external comparison and induction.   --Earle.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To understand.
       [1913 Webster]

             You have me, have you not?           --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To put in an awkward position; to have the advantage of;
       as, that is where he had him. [Slang]
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Have, as an auxiliary verb, is used with the past
         participle to form preterit tenses; as, I have loved; I
         shall have eaten. Originally it was used only with the
         participle of transitive verbs, and denoted the
         possession of the object in the state indicated by the
         participle; as, I have conquered him, I have or hold
         him in a conquered state; but it has long since lost
         this independent significance, and is used with the
         participles both of transitive and intransitive verbs
         as a device for expressing past time. Had is used,
         especially in poetry, for would have or should have.
         [1913 Webster]

               Myself for such a face had boldly died.
                                                  --Tennyson.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To have a care}, to take care; to be on one's guard.

   {To have (a man) out}, to engage (one) in a duel.

   {To have done} (with). See under {Do}, v. i.

   {To have it out}, to speak freely; to bring an affair to a
      conclusion.

   {To have on}, to wear.

   {To have to do with}. See under Do, v. t.

   Syn: To possess; to own. See {Possess}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
