<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hawk</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk
   (Heb. netz, a word expressive of strong and rapid flight, and
   hence appropriate to the hawk). It is an unclean bird (Lev.
   11:16; Deut. 14:15). It is common in Syria and surrounding
   countries. The Hebrew word includes various species of
   Falconidae, with special reference perhaps to the kestrel (Falco
   tinnunculus), the hobby (Hypotriorchis subbuteo), and the lesser
   kestrel (Tin, Cenchris). The kestrel remains all the year in
   Palestine, but some ten or twelve other species are all migrants
   from the south. Of those summer visitors to Palestine special
   mention may be made of the Falco sacer and the Falco lanarius.
   (See NIGHT-{HAWK}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk \Hawk\, v. t.
   To raise by hawking, as phlegm.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk \Hawk\, n. [W. hoch.]
   An effort to force up phlegm from the throat, accompanied
   with noise.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk \Hawk\, v. t. [Akin to D. hauker a hawker, G. h["o]ken,
   h["o]cken, to higgle, to retail, h["o]ke, h["o]ker, a
   higgler, huckster. See {Huckster}.]
   To offer for sale by outcry in the street; to carry
   (merchandise) about from place to place for sale; to peddle;
   as, to hawk goods or pamphlets.
   [1913 Webster]

         His works were hawked in every street.   --Swift.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk \Hawk\, n. (Masonry)
   A small board, with a handle on the under side, to hold
   mortar.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Hawk boy}, an attendant on a plasterer to supply him with
      mortar.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk \Hawk\ (h[add]k), n. [OE. hauk (prob. fr. Icel.), havek,
   AS. hafoc, heafoc; akin to D. havik, OHG. habuh, G. habicht,
   Icel. haukr, Sw. h["o]k, Dan. h["o]g, prob. from the root of
   E. heave.] (Zo["o]l.)
   One of numerous species and genera of rapacious birds of the
   family {Falconid[ae]}. They differ from the true falcons in
   lacking the prominent tooth and notch of the bill, and in
   having shorter and less pointed wings. Many are of large size
   and grade into the eagles. Some, as the goshawk, were
   formerly trained like falcons. In a more general sense the
   word is not infrequently applied, also, to true falcons, as
   the sparrow hawk, pigeon hawk, duck hawk, and prairie hawk.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Among the common American species are the red-tailed
         hawk ({Buteo borealis}); the red-shouldered ({Buteo
         lineatus}); the broad-winged ({Buteo Pennsylvanicus});
         the rough-legged ({Archibuteo lagopus}); the
         sharp-shinned ({Accipiter fuscus}). See {Fishhawk},
         {Goshawk}, {Marsh hawk}, under {Marsh}, {Night hawk},
         under {Night}.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Bee hawk} (Zo["o]l.), the honey buzzard.

   {Eagle hawk}. See under {Eagle}.

   {Hawk eagle} (Zo["o]l.), an Asiatic bird of the genus
      {Spiz[ae]tus}, or {Limn[ae]tus}, intermediate between the
      hawks and eagles. There are several species.

   {Hawk fly} (Zo["o]l.), a voracious fly of the family
      {Asilid[ae]}. See {Hornet fly}, under {Hornet}.

   {Hawk moth}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Hawk moth}, in the Vocabulary.
      

   {Hawk owl}. (Zo["o]l.)
   (a) A northern owl ({Surnia ulula}) of Europe and America. It
       flies by day, and in some respects resembles the hawks.
   (b) An owl of India ({Ninox scutellatus}).

   {Hawk's bill} (Horology), the pawl for the rack, in the
      striking mechanism of a clock.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk \Hawk\ (h[add]k), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hawked} (h[add]kt);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Hawking}.]
   1. To catch, or attempt to catch, birds by means of hawks
      trained for the purpose, and let loose on the prey; to
      practice falconry.
      [1913 Webster]

            A falconer Henry is, when Emma hawks. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make an attack while on the wing; to soar and strike
      like a hawk; -- generally with at; as, to hawk at flies.
      --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            A falcon, towering in her pride of place,
            Was by a mousing owl hawked at and killed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hawk \Hawk\, v. i. [W. hochi.]
   To clear the throat with an audible sound by forcing an
   expiratory current of air through the narrow passage between
   the depressed soft palate and the root of the tongue, thus
   aiding in the removal of foreign substances.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hawk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hawk
     n 1: diurnal bird of prey typically having short rounded wings
          and a long tail
     2: an advocate of an aggressive policy on foreign relations
        [syn: {war hawk}] [ant: {dove}]
     3: a square board with a handle underneath; used by masons to
        hold or carry mortar [syn: {mortarboard}]
     v 1: sell or offer for sale from place to place [syn: {peddle}, {monger},
           {huckster}, {vend}, {pitch}]
     2: hunt with hawks; "the Arabs like to hawk in the desert"
     3: clear mucus or food from one's throat; "he cleared his
        throat before he started to speak" [syn: {clear the throat}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
