<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hearing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hearing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hearing \Hear"ing\, n.
   1. The act or power of perceiving sound; perception of sound;
      the faculty or sense by which sound is perceived; as, my
      hearing is good.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have heard of thee by the hearing of the ear.
                                                  --Job xlii. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Hearing in a special sensation, produced by stimulation
         of the auditory nerve; the stimulus (waves of sound)
         acting not directly on the nerve, but through the
         medium of the endolymph on the delicate epithelium
         cells, constituting the peripheral terminations of the
         nerve. See {Ear}.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Attention to what is delivered; opportunity to be heard;
      audience; as, I could not obtain a hearing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A listening to facts and evidence, for the sake of
      adjudication; a session of a court for considering proofs
      and determining issues.
      [1913 Webster]

            His last offenses to us
            Shall have judicious hearing.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Another hearing before some other court. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Hearing, as applied to equity cases, means the same
         thing that the word trial does at law. --Abbot.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. Extent within which sound may be heard; sound; earshot.
      ``She's not within hearing.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            They laid him by the pleasant shore,
            And in the hearing of the wave.       --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hearing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hear \Hear\ (h[=e]r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Heard} (h[~e]rd); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Hearing}.] [OE. heren, AS,. hi['e]ran,
   h[=y]ran, h[=e]ran; akin to OS. h[=o]rian, OFries. hera,
   hora, D. hooren, OHG. h[=o]ren, G. h["o]ren, Icel. heyra, Sw.
   h["o]ra, Dan. hore, Goth. hausjan, and perh. to Gr.
   'akoy`ein, E. acoustic. Cf. {Hark}, {Hearken}.]
   1. To perceive by the ear; to apprehend or take cognizance of
      by the ear; as, to hear sounds; to hear a voice; to hear
      one call.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lay thine ear close to the ground, and list if thou
            canst hear the tread of travelers.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had been heard to utter an ominous growl.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give audience or attention to; to listen to; to heed;
      to accept the doctrines or advice of; to obey; to examine;
      to try in a judicial court; as, to hear a recitation; to
      hear a class; the case will be heard to-morrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To attend, or be present at, as hearer or worshiper; as,
      to hear a concert; to hear Mass.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To give attention to as a teacher or judge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy matters are good and right, but there is no man
            deputed of the king to hear thee.     --2 Sam. xv.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

            I beseech your honor to hear me one single word.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To accede to the demand or wishes of; to listen to and
      answer favorably; to favor.
      [1913 Webster]

            I love the Lord, because he hath heard my voice.
                                                  --Ps. cxvi. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            They think that they shall be heard for their much
            speaking.                             --Matt. vi. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Hear him}. See Remark, under {Hear}, v. i.

   {To hear a bird sing}, to receive private communication.
      [Colloq.] --Shak.

   {To hear say}, to hear one say; to learn by common report; to
      receive by rumor. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hearing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hearing
     adj : able to perceive sound [syn: {hearing(a)}] [ant: {deaf}]
     n 1: (law) a proceeding (usually by a court) where evidence is
          taken for the purpose of determining an issue of fact
          and reaching a decision based on that evidence
     2: an opportunity to state your case and be heard; "they
        condemned him without a hearing"; "he saw that he had lost
        his audience" [syn: {audience}]
     3: the range within which a voice can be heard; "the children
        were told to stay within earshot" [syn: {earshot}, {earreach}]
     4: the act of hearing attentively; "you can learn a lot by just
        listening"; "they make good music--you should give them a
        hearing" [syn: {listening}]
     5: a session (of a committee or grand jury) in which witnesses
        are called and testimony is taken; "the investigative
        committee will hold hearings in Chicago"
     6: the ability to hear; the auditory faculty; "his hearing was
        impaired" [syn: {audition}, {auditory sense}, {sense of
        hearing}, {auditory modality}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
