<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>heartbeat</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heartbeat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>heartbeat
     
        1. &lt;networking&gt; The signal emitted by a Level 2 Ethernet
        transceiver at the end of every {packet} to show that the
        collision-detection circuit is still connected.
     
        2. A periodic synchronisation signal used by software or
        hardware, such as a {bus} clock or a periodic {interrupt}.
     
        3. The "natural" oscillation frequency of a computer's clock
        crystal, before frequency division down to the machine's clock
        rate.
     
        4. A signal emitted at regular intervals by software to
        demonstrate that it is still alive.  Sometimes hardware is
        designed to reboot the machine if it stops hearing a
        heartbeat.  See also {breath-of-life packet}, {watchdog}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1996-03-12)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heartbeat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>heartbeat \heartbeat\ n.
   the audible and palpable rhythmic contraction and expansion
   of the arteries with each beat of the heart; as, he listened
   to her heartbeat with a stethoscope.

   Syn: pulse, pulsation, beat.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   {in a heartbeat} immediately.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heartbeat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>heartbeat n. 1. The signal emitted by a Level 2 Ethernet transceiver at
   the end of every packet to show that the collision-detection circuit is
   still connected. 2. A periodic synchronization signal used by software
   or hardware, such as a bus clock or a periodic interrupt. 3. The
   `natural' oscillation frequency of a computer's clock crystal, before
   frequency division down to the machine's clock rate. 4. A signal emitted
   at regular intervals by software to demonstrate that it is still alive.
   Sometimes hardware is designed to reboot the machine if it stops hearing
   a heartbeat. See also {breath-of-life packet}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heartbeat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>heartbeat
     n 1: the rhythmic contraction and expansion of the arteries with
          each beat of the heart; "he could feel the beat of her
          heart" [syn: {pulse}, {pulsation}, {beat}]
     2: a very short time (as the time it takes the eye blink or the
        heart to beat); "if I had the chance I'd do it in a flash"
        [syn: {blink of an eye}, {flash}, {instant}, {jiffy}, {split
        second}, {trice}, {twinkling}, {wink}, {New York minute}]
     3: an animating or vital unifying force; "New York is the
        commercial heartbeat of America"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
