<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>heaving</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heaving</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Heave \Heave\ (h[=e]v), v. t. [imp. {Heaved} (h[=e]vd), or
   {Hove} (h[=o]v); p. p. {Heaved}, {Hove}, formerly {Hoven}
   (h[=o]"v'n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Heaving}.] [OE. heven, hebben,
   AS. hebban; akin to OS. hebbian, D. heffen, OHG. heffan,
   hevan, G. heben, Icel. hefja, Sw. h[aum]fva, Dan. h[ae]ve,
   Goth. hafjan, L. capere to take, seize; cf. Gr. kw`ph handle.
   Cf. {Accept}, {Behoof}, {Capacious}, {Forceps}, {Haft},
   {Receipt}.]
   1. To cause to move upward or onward by a lifting effort; to
      lift; to raise; to hoist; -- often with up; as, the wave
      heaved the boat on land.
      [1913 Webster]

            One heaved ahigh, to be hurled down below. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Heave, as now used, implies that the thing raised is
         heavy or hard to move; but formerly it was used in a
         less restricted sense.
         [1913 Webster]

               Here a little child I stand,
               Heaving up my either hand.         --Herrick.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To throw; to cast; -- obsolete, provincial, or colloquial,
      except in certain nautical phrases; as, to heave the lead;
      to heave the log.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To force from, or into, any position; to cause to move;
      also, to throw off; -- mostly used in certain nautical
      phrases; as, to heave the ship ahead.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To raise or force from the breast; to utter with effort;
      as, to heave a sigh.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wretched animal heaved forth such groans.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cause to swell or rise, as the breast or bosom.
      [1913 Webster]

            The glittering, finny swarms
            That heave our friths, and crowd upon our shores.
                                                  --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To heave a cable short} (Naut.), to haul in cable till the
      ship is almost perpendicularly above the anchor.

   {To heave a ship ahead} (Naut.), to warp her ahead when not
      under sail, as by means of cables.

   {To heave a ship down} (Naut.), to throw or lay her down on
      one side; to careen her.

   {To heave a ship to} (Naut.), to bring the ship's head to the
      wind, and stop her motion.

   {To heave about} (Naut.), to put about suddenly.

   {To heave in} (Naut.), to shorten (cable).

   {To heave in stays} (Naut.), to put a vessel on the other
      tack.

   {To heave out a sail} (Naut.), to unfurl it.

   {To heave taut} (Naut.), to turn a capstan, etc., till the
      rope becomes strained. See {Taut}, and {Tight}.

   {To heave the lead} (Naut.), to take soundings with lead and
      line.

   {To heave the log}. (Naut.) See {Log}.

   {To heave up anchor} (Naut.), to raise it from the bottom of
      the sea or elsewhere.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heaving</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Heaving \Heav"ing\, n.
   A lifting or rising; a swell; a panting or deep sighing.
   --Addison. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heaving</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>heaving
     adj : rising and falling alternately as in waves; "the heaving
           waves in the storm-tossed sea"; "the exhausted dog's
           heaving chest"
     n 1: an upward movement (especially a rhythmical rising and
          falling); "the heaving of waves on a rough sea" [syn: {heave}]
     2: breathing heavily (as after exertion) [syn: {panting}]
     3: the act of lifting something with great effort [syn: {heave}]
     4: throwing something heavy (with great effort); "he gave it a
        mighty heave"; "he was not good at heaving passes" [syn: {heave}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
