<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>heel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Heel \Heel\ (h[=e]l), v. i. [OE. helden to lean, incline, AS.
   heldan, hyldan; akin to Icel. halla, Dan. helde, Sw. h["a]lla
   to tilt, pour, and perh. to E. hill.] (Naut.)
   To lean or tip to one side, as a ship; as, the ship heels
   aport; the boat heeled over when the squall struck it.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Heeling error} (Naut.), a deviation of the compass caused by
      the heeling of an iron vessel to one side or the other.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Heel \Heel\, n. [OE. hele, heele, AS. h[=e]la, perh. for
   h[=o]hila, fr. AS. h[=o]h heel (cf. {Hough}); but cf. D.
   hiel, OFries. heila, h[=e]la, Icel. h[ae]ll, Dan. h[ae]l, Sw.
   h["a]l, and L. calx. [root]12. Cf. {Inculcate}.]
   1. The hinder part of the foot; sometimes, the whole foot; --
      in man or quadrupeds.
      [1913 Webster]

            He [the stag] calls to mind his strength and then
            his speed,
            His winged heels and then his armed head. --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The hinder part of any covering for the foot, as of a
      shoe, sock, etc.; specif., a solid part projecting
      downward from the hinder part of the sole of a boot or
      shoe.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The latter or remaining part of anything; the closing or
      concluding part. ``The heel of a hunt.'' --A. Trollope.
      ``The heel of the white loaf.'' --Sir W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything regarded as like a human heel in shape; a
      protuberance; a knob.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The part of a thing corresponding in position to the human
      heel; the lower part, or part on which a thing rests;
      especially:
      (a) (Naut.) The after end of a ship's keel.
      (b) (Naut.) The lower end of a mast, a boom, the bowsprit,
          the sternpost, etc.
      (c) (Mil.) In a small arm, the corner of the but which is
          upwards in the firing position.
      (d) (Mil.) The uppermost part of the blade of a sword,
          next to the hilt.
      (e) The part of any tool next the tang or handle; as, the
          heel of a scythe.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Man.) Management by the heel, especially the spurred
      heel; as, the horse understands the heel well.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Arch.)
      (a) The lower end of a timber in a frame, as a post or
          rafter. In the United States, specif., the obtuse
          angle of the lower end of a rafter set sloping.
      (b) A cyma reversa; -- so called by workmen. --Gwilt.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Golf) The part of the face of the club head nearest the
      shaft.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. In a carding machine, the part of a flat nearest the
      cylinder.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Heel chain} (Naut.), a chain passing from the bowsprit cap
      around the heel of the jib boom.

   {Heel plate}, the butt plate of a gun.

   {Heel of a rafter}. (Arch.) See {Heel}, n., 7.

   {Heel ring}, a ring for fastening a scythe blade to the
      snath.

   {Neck and heels}, the whole body. (Colloq.)

   {To be at the heels of}, to pursue closely; to follow hard;
      as, hungry want is at my heels. --Otway.

   {To be down at the heel}, to be slovenly or in a poor plight.
      

   {To be out at the heels}, to have on stockings that are worn
      out; hence, to be shabby, or in a poor plight. --Shak.

   {To cool the heels}. See under {Cool}.

   {To go heels over head}, to turn over so as to bring the
      heels uppermost; hence, to move in a inconsiderate, or
      rash, manner.

   {To have the heels of}, to outrun.

   {To lay by the heels}, to fetter; to shackle; to imprison.
      --Shak. --Addison.

   {To show the heels}, to flee; to run from.

   {To take to the heels}, to flee; to betake to flight.

   {To throw up another's heels}, to trip him. --Bunyan.

   {To tread upon one's heels}, to follow closely. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Heel \Heel\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Heeled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Heeling}.]
   1. To perform by the use of the heels, as in dancing,
      running, and the like. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I cannot sing,
            Nor heel the high lavolt.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To add a heel to; as, to heel a shoe.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To arm with a gaff, as a cock for fighting.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Golf) To hit (the ball) with the heel of the club.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   5. (Football) To make (a fair catch) standing with one foot
      advanced, the heel on the ground and the toe up.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>heel
     n 1: the bottom of a shoe or boot; the back part of a shoe or
          boot that touches the ground
     2: the back part of the human foot
     3: someone who is morally reprehensible; "you dirty dog" [syn:
        {cad}, {bounder}, {blackguard}, {dog}, {hound}]
     4: one of the crusty ends of a loaf of bread
     5: the lower end of a ship's mast
     6: (golf) the part of the clubhead where it joins the shaft
     7: the piece of leather that fits the heel [syn: {counter}]
     v 1: tilt to one side; "The balloon heeled over"; "the wind made
          the vessel heel"; "The ship listed to starboard" [syn: {list}]
     2: follow at the heels of a person
     3: perform with the heels; "heel that dance"
     4: strike with the heel of the club; "heel a golf ball"
     5: put a new heel on; "heel shoes" [syn: {reheel}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
