<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hero</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hero</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hero \He"ro\, n.; pl. {Heroes}. [F. h['e]ros, L. heros, Gr. ?.]
   1. (Myth.) An illustrious man, supposed to be exalted, after
      death, to a place among the gods; a demigod, as Hercules.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A man of distinguished valor or enterprise in danger, or
      fortitude in suffering; a prominent or central personage
      in any remarkable action or event; hence, a great or
      illustrious person.
      [1913 Webster]

            Each man is a hero and oracle to somebody.
                                                  --Emerson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The principal personage in a poem, story, and the like, or
      the person who has the principal share in the transactions
      related; as Achilles in the Iliad, Ulysses in the Odyssey,
      and [AE]neas in the [AE]neid.
      [1913 Webster]

            The shining quality of an epic hero.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Hero worship}, extravagant admiration for great men, likened
      to the ancient worship of heroes.
      [1913 Webster] 1

            Hero worship exists, has existed, and will forever
            exist, universally among mankind.     --Carlyle.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hero</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sub \Sub\, n.
   1. A subordinate; a subaltern. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. a shortened form of {submarine}, the boat.
      [PJC]

   3. a shortened form of {submarine sandwich}; also called
      {hero}, {hero sandwich}, and {grinder}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hero</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>submarine sandwich \sub`ma*rine" sand"wich\, n.
   A large sandwich on an elongated roll, usually incompletely
   cut into two halves, filed with various cold cuts, meatballs,
   lettuce, cheese, tomatoes, olives, etc., and spiced
   variously, and often having oil or other dressing applied;
   called also {hoagie}, {hero}, {hero sandwich}, {grinder},
   {sub}, {submarine}, {poor boy}, and {Italian sandwich}. A
   single such sandwich may consitute a substantial meal. Very
   large variants are sometimes prepared for social gatherings
   and cut into pieces for individual consumption.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hero</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hoagie \hoagie\, hoagy \hoagy\n.
   a large sandwich on a long crusty roll that is split
   lengthwise and filled with meats and cheese (and tomato and
   onion and lettuce and condiments); different names are used
   in different sections of the U. S., such as {hero},
   {grinder}, and {submarine}.

   Syn: bomber, grinder, hero, hero sandwich, hoagie, Cuban
        sandwich, Italian sandwich, poor boy, sub, submarine,
        submarine sandwich, torpedo, wedge, zep.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hero</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hero
     n 1: a man distinguished by exceptional courage and nobility and
          strength; "RAF pilots were the heroes of the Battle of
          Britain"
     2: the principal character in a play or movie or novel or poem
     3: someone who fights for a cause [syn: {champion}, {fighter},
        {paladin}]
     4: Greek mathematician and inventor who devised a way to
        determine the area of a triangle and who described various
        mechanical devices (first century) [syn: {Heron}, {Hero of
        Alexandria}]
     5: (classical mythology) a being of great strength and courage
        celebrated for bold exploits; often the offspring of a
        mortal and a god
     6: (Greek mythology) priestess of Aphrodite who killed herself
        when her lover Leander drowned while trying to swim the
        Hellespont to see her
     7: a large sandwich made of a long crusty roll split lengthwise
        and filled with meats and cheese (and tomato and onion and
        lettuce and condiments); different names are used in
        different sections of the United States [syn: {bomber}, {grinder},
         {hero sandwich}, {hoagie}, {hoagy}, {Cuban sandwich}, {Italian
        sandwich}, {poor boy}, {sub}, {submarine}, {submarine
        sandwich}, {torpedo}, {wedge}, {zep}]
     [also: {heroes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
