<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>heroic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heroic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Heroic \He*ro"ic\, a. [F. h['e]ro["i]que, L. hero["i]cus, Gr.
   ?.]
   1. Of or pertaining to, or like, a hero; of the nature of
      heroes; distinguished by the existence of heroes; as, the
      heroic age; an heroic people; heroic valor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Worthy of a hero; bold; daring; brave; illustrious; as,
      heroic action; heroic enterprises.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Sculpture &amp; Painting) Larger than life size, but smaller
      than colossal; -- said of the representation of a human
      figure.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Heroic Age}, the age when the heroes, or those called the
      children of the gods, are supposed to have lived.

   {Heroic poetry}, that which celebrates the deeds of a hero;
      epic poetry.

   {Heroic treatment} or {Heroic remedies} (Med.), treatment or
      remedies of a severe character, suited to a desperate
      case.

   {Heroic verse} (Pros.), the verse of heroic or epic poetry,
      being in English, German, and Italian the iambic of ten
      syllables; in French the iambic of twelve syllables; and
      in classic poetry the hexameter.

   Syn: Brave; intrepid; courageous; daring; valiant; bold;
        gallant; fearless; enterprising; noble; magnanimous;
        illustrious.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>heroic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>heroic
     adj 1: very imposing or impressive; surpassing the ordinary
            (especially in size or scale); "an epic voyage"; "of
            heroic proportions"; "heroic sculpture" [syn: {epic},
            {larger-than-life}]
     2: relating to or characteristic of heroes of antiquity;
        "heroic legends"; "the heroic age"
     3: having or displaying qualities appropriate for heroes; "the
        heroic attack on the beaches of Normandy"; "heroic
        explorers" [syn: {heroical}]
     4: impressive in size or scope; "heroic undertakings" [syn: {grand}]
     5: showing extreme courage; especially of actions courageously
        undertaken in desperation as a last resort; "made a last
        desperate attempt to reach the climber"; "the desperate
        gallantry of our naval task forces marked the turning
        point in the Pacific war"- G.C.Marshall; "they took heroic
        measures to save his life" [syn: {desperate}]
     n : a verse form suited to the treatment of heroic or elevated
         themes; dactylic hexameter or iambic pentameter [syn: {heroic
         verse}, {heroic meter}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
