<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hog</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>HOG, n.  A bird remarkable for the catholicity of its appetite and
serving to illustrate that of ours.  Among the Mahometans and Jews,
the hog is not in favor as an article of diet, but is respected for
the delicacy and the melody of its voice.  It is chiefly as a songster
that the fowl is esteemed; the cage of him in full chorus has been
known to draw tears from two persons at once.  The scientific name of
this dicky-bird is _Porcus Rockefelleri_.  Mr. Rockefeller did not
discover the hog, but it is considered his by right of resemblance.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hog
     
        1. Favoured term to describe programs or hardware that seem to
        eat far more than their share of a system's resources,
        especially those which noticeably degrade interactive
        response.  *Not* used of programs that are simply extremely
        large or complex or that are merely painfully slow themselves
        (see {pig, run like a}).  More often than not encountered in
        qualified forms, e.g. "memory hog", "core hog", "hog the
        processor", "hog the disk".  "A controller that never gives up
        the I/O bus gets killed after the bus-hog timer expires."
     
        2. Also said of *people* who use more than their fair share of
        resources (particularly disk, where it seems that 10% of the
        people use 90% of the disk, no matter how big the disk is or
        how many people use it).  Of course, once disk hogs fill up
        one file system, they typically find some other new one to
        infect, claiming to the sysadmin that they have an important
        new project to complete.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hog \Hog\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hogged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Hogging}.]
   1. To cut short like bristles; as, to hog the mane of a
      horse. --Smart.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) To scrub with a hog, or scrubbing broom.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hog \Hog\, v. i. (Naut.)
   To become bent upward in the middle, like a hog's back; --
   said of a ship broken or strained so as to have this form.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hog \Hog\ (h[o^]g), n. [Prob. akin to E. hack to cut, and
   meaning orig., a castrated boar; cf. also W. hwch swine, sow,
   Armor. houc'h, hoc'h. Cf. {Haggis}, {Hogget}, and
   {Hoggerel}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) A quadruped of the genus {Sus}, and allied
      genera of {Suid[ae]}; esp., the domesticated varieties of
      {Sus scrofa}, kept for their fat and meat, called,
      respectively, {lard} and {pork}; swine; porker;
      specifically, a castrated boar; a barrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The domestic hogs of Siam, China, and parts of Southern
         Europe, are thought to have been derived from {Sus
         Indicus}.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A mean, filthy, or gluttonous fellow. [Low.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A young sheep that has not been shorn. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Naut.) A rough, flat scrubbing broom for scrubbing a
      ship's bottom under water. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Paper Manuf.) A device for mixing and stirring the pulp
      of which paper is made.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bush hog}, {Ground hog}, etc.. See under {Bush}, {Ground},
      etc.

   {Hog caterpillar} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of the green
      grapevine sphinx; -- so called because the head and first
      three segments are much smaller than those behind them, so
      as to make a resemblance to a hog's snout. See {Hawk
      moth}.

   {Hog cholera}, an epidemic contagious fever of swine,
      attended by liquid, fetid, diarrhea, and by the appearance
      on the skin and mucous membrane of spots and patches of a
      scarlet, purple, or black color. It is fatal in from one
      to six days, or ends in a slow, uncertain recovery. --Law
      (Farmer's Veter. Adviser.)

   {Hog deer} (Zo["o]l.), the axis deer.

   {Hog gum} (Bot.), West Indian tree ({Symphonia globulifera}),
      yielding an aromatic gum.

   {Hog of wool}, the trade name for the fleece or wool of sheep
      of the second year.

   {Hog peanut} (Bot.), a kind of earth pea.

   {Hog plum} (Bot.), a tropical tree, of the genus {Spondias}
      ({Spondias lutea}), with fruit somewhat resembling plums,
      but chiefly eaten by hogs. It is found in the West Indies.
      

   {Hog's bean} (Bot.), the plant henbane.

   {Hog's bread}.(Bot.) See {Sow bread}.

   {Hog's fennel}. (Bot.) See under {Fennel}.

   {Mexican hog} (Zo["o]l.), the peccary.

   {Water hog}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Capybara}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hog n.,vt. 1. Favored term to describe programs or hardware that seem
   to eat far more than their share of a system's resources, esp. those
   which noticeably degrade interactive response. _Not_ used of programs
   that are simply extremely large or complex or that are merely painfully
   slow themselves. More often than not encountered in qualified forms,
   e.g., `memory hog', `core hog', `hog the processor', `hog the disk'. "A
   controller that never gives up the I/O bus gets killed after the bus-hog
   timer expires." 2. Also said of _people_ who use more than their fair
   share of resources (particularly disk, where it seems that 10% of the
   people use 90% of the disk, no matter how big the disk is or how many
   people use it). Of course, once disk hogs fill up one filesystem, they
   typically find some other new one to infect, claiming to the sysadmin
   that they have an important new project to complete.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hog
     n 1: a person regarded as greedy and pig-like [syn: {pig}]
     2: a sheep up to the age of one year; one yet to be sheared
        [syn: {hogget}, {hogg}]
     3: domestic swine [syn: {pig}, {grunter}, {squealer}, {Sus
        scrofa}]
     v : take greedily; take more than one's share
     [also: {hogging}, {hogged}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
