<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hold</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hold</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hold
   a fortress, the name given to David's lurking-places (1 Sam.
   22:4, 5; 24:22).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hold</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hold \Hold\ (h[=o]ld), n. [D. hol hole, hollow. See {Hole}.]
   (Naut.)
   The whole interior portion of a vessel below the lower deck,
   in which the cargo is stowed.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hold</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hold \Hold\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Held}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Holding}. {Holden}, p. p., is obs. in elegant writing,
   though still used in legal language.] [OE. haldan, D. houden,
   OHG. hoten, Icel. halda, Dan. holde, Sw. h[*a]lla, Goth.
   haldan to feed, tend (the cattle); of unknown origin. Gf.
   {Avast}, {Halt}, {Hod}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To cause to remain in a given situation, position, or
      relation, within certain limits, or the like; to prevent
      from falling or escaping; to sustain; to restrain; to keep
      in the grasp; to retain.
      [1913 Webster]

            The loops held one curtain to another. --Ex. xxxvi.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy right hand shall hold me.         --Ps. cxxxix.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

            They all hold swords, being expert in war. --Cant.
                                                  iii. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

            In vain he seeks, that having can not hold.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            France, thou mayst hold a serpent by the tongue, . .
            .
            A fasting tiger safer by the tooth,
            Than keep in peace that hand which thou dost hold.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To retain in one's keeping; to maintain possession of, or
      authority over; not to give up or relinquish; to keep; to
      defend.
      [1913 Webster]

            We mean to hold what anciently we claim
            Of deity or empire.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To have; to possess; to be in possession of; to occupy; to
      derive title to; as, to hold office.
      [1913 Webster]

            This noble merchant held a noble house. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of him to hold his seigniory for a yearly tribute.
                                                  --Knolles.
      [1913 Webster]

            And now the strand, and now the plain, they held.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To impose restraint upon; to limit in motion or action; to
      bind legally or morally; to confine; to restrain.
      [1913 Webster]

            We can not hold mortality's strong hand. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Death! what do'st? O, hold thy blow.  --Grashaw.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had not sufficient judgment and self-command to
            hold his tongue.                      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To maintain in being or action; to carry on; to prosecute,
      as a course of conduct or an argument; to continue; to
      sustain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hold not thy peace, and be not still. --Ps. lxxxiii.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Seedtime and harvest, heat and hoary frost,
            Shall hold their course.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To prosecute, have, take, or join in, as something which
      is the result of united action; as to, hold a meeting, a
      festival, a session, etc.; hence, to direct and bring
      about officially; to conduct or preside at; as, the
      general held a council of war; a judge holds a court; a
      clergyman holds a service.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would hold more talk with thee.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To receive and retain; to contain as a vessel; as, this
      pail holds milk; hence, to be able to receive and retain;
      to have capacity or containing power for.
      [1913 Webster]

            Broken cisterns that can hold no water. --Jer. ii.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            One sees more devils than vast hell can hold.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To accept, as an opinion; to be the adherent of, openly or
      privately; to persist in, as a purpose; to maintain; to
      sustain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Stand fast and hold the traditions which ye have
            been taught.                          --2 Thes.
                                                  ii.15.
      [1913 Webster]

            But still he held his purpose to depart. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To consider; to regard; to esteem; to account; to think;
      to judge.
      [1913 Webster]

            I hold him but a fool.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I shall never hold that man my friend. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord will not hold him guiltless that taketh his
            name in vain.                         --Ex. xx. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To bear, carry, or manage; as he holds himself erect; he
       holds his head high.
       [1913 Webster]

             Let him hold his fingers thus.       --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To hold a wager}, to lay or hazard a wager. --Swift.

   {To hold forth},
       (a) v. t.to offer; to exhibit; to propose; to put
           forward. ``The propositions which books hold forth
           and pretend to teach.'' --Locke.
       (b) v. i. To talk at length; to harangue.

   {To held in}, to restrain; to curd.

   {To hold in hand}, to toy with; to keep in expectation; to
      have in one's power. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            O, fie! to receive favors, return falsehoods,
            And hold a lady in hand.              --Beaw. &amp; Fl.

   {To hold in play}, to keep under control; to dally with.
      --Macaulay.

   {To hold off}, to keep at a distance.

   {To hold on}, to hold in being, continuance or position; as,
      to hold a rider on.

   {To hold one's day}, to keep one's appointment. [Obs.]
      --Chaucer.

   {To hold one's own}. To keep good one's present condition
      absolutely or relatively; not to fall off, or to lose
      ground; as, a ship holds her own when she does not lose
      ground in a race or chase; a man holds his own when he
      does not lose strength or weight.

   {To hold one's peace}, to keep silence.

   {To hold out}.
       (a) To extend; to offer. ``Fortune holds out these to you
           as rewards.'' --B. Jonson.
       (b) To continue to do or to suffer; to endure. ``He can
           not long hold out these pangs.'' --Shak.

   {To hold up}.
       (a) To raise; to lift; as, hold up your head.
       (b) To support; to sustain. ``He holds himself up in
           virtue.''--Sir P. Sidney.
       (c) To exhibit; to display; as, he was held up as an
           example.
       (d) To rein in; to check; to halt; as, hold up your
           horses.
       (e) to rob, usually at gunpoint; -- often with the demand
           to ``hold up'' the hands.
       (f) To delay.

   {To hold water}.
       (a) Literally, to retain water without leaking; hence
           (Fig.), to be whole, sound, consistent, without gaps
           or holes; -- commonly used in a negative sense; as,
           his statements will not hold water. [Colloq.]
       (b) (Naut.) To hold the oars steady in the water, thus
           checking the headway of a boat.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hold</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hold \Hold\ (h[=o]ld), n.
   1. The act of holding, as in or with the hands or arms; the
      manner of holding, whether firm or loose; seizure; grasp;
      clasp; grip; possession; -- often used with the verbs take
      and lay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ne have I not twelve pence within mine hold.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou should'st lay hold upon him.     --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

            My soul took hold on thee.            --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Take fast hold of instruction.        --Pror. iv.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The authority or ground to take or keep; claim.
      [1913 Webster]

            The law hath yet another hold on you. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Binding power and influence.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fear . . . by which God and his laws take the surest
            hold of.                              --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Something that may be grasped; means of support.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a man be upon an high place without rails or good
            hold, he is ready to fall.            --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A place of confinement; a prison; confinement; custody;
      guard.
      [1913 Webster]

            They . . . put them in hold unto the next day.
                                                  --Acts. iv. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

            King Richard, he is in the mighty hold
            Of Bolingbroke.                       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A place of security; a fortified place; a fort; a castle;
      -- often called a {stronghold}. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            New comers in an ancient hold         --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mus.) A character [thus ?] placed over or under a note or
      rest, and indicating that it is to be prolonged; -- called
      also {pause}, and {corona}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hold</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hold \Hold\, v. i.
   In general, to keep one's self in a given position or
   condition; to remain fixed. Hence:
   [1913 Webster]

   1. Not to move; to halt; to stop; -- mostly in the
      imperative.
      [1913 Webster]

            And damned be him that first cries, ``Hold,
            enough!''                             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not to give way; not to part or become separated; to
      remain unbroken or unsubdued.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our force by land hath nobly held.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Not to fail or be found wanting; to continue; to last; to
      endure a test or trial; to abide; to persist.
      [1913 Webster]

            While our obedience holds.            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rule holds in land as all other commodities.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Not to fall away, desert, or prove recreant; to remain
      attached; to cleave; -- often with with, to, or for.
      [1913 Webster]

            He will hold to the one and despise the other.
                                                  --Matt. vi. 24
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To restrain one's self; to refrain.
      [1913 Webster]

            His dauntless heart would fain have held
            From weeping, but his eyes rebelled.  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To derive right or title; -- generally with of.
      [1913 Webster]

            My crown is absolute, and holds of none. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            His imagination holds immediately from nature.
                                                  --Hazlitt.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Hold on!} {Hold up!} wait; stop; forbear. [Collog] -- {To
   hold forth}, to speak in public; to harangue; to preach.
      --L'Estrange.

   {To hold in}, to restrain one's self; as, he wanted to laugh
      and could hardly hold in.

   {To hold off}, to keep at a distance.

   {To hold on}, to keep fast hold; to continue; to go on. ``The
      trade held on for many years,'' --Swift.

   {To hold out}, to last; to endure; to continue; to maintain
      one's self; not to yield or give way.

   {To hold over}, to remain in office, possession, etc., beyond
      a certain date.

   {To hold to} or {To hold with}, to take sides with, as a
      person or opinion.

   {To hold together}, to be joined; not to separate; to remain
      in union. --Dryden. --Locke.

   {To hold up}.
      (a) To support one's self; to remain unbent or unbroken;
          as, to hold up under misfortunes.
      (b) To cease raining; to cease to stop; as, it holds up.
          --Hudibras.
      (c) To keep up; not to fall behind; not to lose ground.
          --Collier.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hold</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Corona \Co*ro"na\ (k?-r?"n?), n.; pl. L. {Coron[ae]} (-n?), E.
   {Coronas} (-n?z). [L. corona crown. See {Crown}.]
   1. A crown or garland bestowed among the Romans as a reward
      for distinguished services.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) The projecting part of a Classic cornice, the
      under side of which is cut with a recess or channel so as
      to form a drip. See Illust. of {Column}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Anat.) The upper surface of some part, as of a tooth or
      the skull; a crown.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) The shelly skeleton of a sea urchin.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Astronomy) A peculiar luminous appearance, or aureola,
      which surrounds the sun, and which is seen only when the
      sun is totally eclipsed by the moon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Bot.)
      (a) An inner appendage to a petal or a corolla, often
          forming a special cup, as in the daffodil and jonquil.
      (b) Any crownlike appendage at the top of an organ.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. (Meteorol.)
      (a) A circle, usually colored, seen in peculiar states of
          the atmosphere around and close to a luminous body, as
          the sun or moon.
      (b) A peculiar phase of the {aurora borealis}, formed by
          the concentration or convergence of luminous beams
          around the point in the heavens indicated by the
          direction of the dipping needle.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. A crown or circlet suspended from the roof or vaulting of
      churches, to hold tapers lighted on solemn occasions. It
      is sometimes formed of double or triple circlets, arranged
      pyramidically. Called also {corona lucis}. --Fairholt.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mus.) A character [[pause]] called the {pause} or {hold}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hold</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hold
     n 1: the act of grasping; "he released his clasp on my arm"; "he
          has a strong grip for an old man"; "she kept a firm hold
          on the railing" [syn: {clasp}, {clench}, {clutch}, {clutches},
           {grasp}, {grip}]
     2: understanding of the nature or meaning or quality or
        magnitude of something; "he has a good grasp of accounting
        practices" [syn: {appreciation}, {grasp}]
     3: power by which something or someone is affected or
        dominated; "he has a hold over them"
     4: time during which some action is awaited; "instant replay
        caused too long a delay"; "he ordered a hold in the
        action" [syn: {delay}, {time lag}, {postponement}, {wait}]
     5: a state of being confined (usually for a short time); "his
        detention was politically motivated"; "the prisoner is on
        hold"; "he is in the custody of police" [syn: {detention},
         {custody}]
     6: a stronghold
     7: a cell in a jail or prison [syn: {keep}]
     8: the appendage to an object that is designed to be held in
        order to use or move it; "he grabbed the hammer by the
        handle"; "it was an old briefcase but it still had a good
        grip" [syn: {handle}, {grip}, {handgrip}]
     9: the space in a ship or aircraft for storing cargo [syn: {cargo
        area}, {cargo deck}, {cargo hold}, {storage area}]
     v 1: organize or be responsible for; "hold a reception"; "have,
          throw, or make a party"; "give a course" [syn: {throw},
          {have}, {make}, {give}]
     2: keep in a certain state, position, or activity; e.g., "keep
        clean"; "hold in place"; "She always held herself as a
        lady"; "The students keep me on my toes" [syn: {keep}, {maintain}]
     3: have or hold in one's hands or grip; "Hold this bowl for a
        moment, please"; "A crazy idea took hold of him" [syn: {take
        hold}] [ant: {let go of}]
     4: to close within bounds, limit or hold back from movement;
        "This holds the local until the express passengers change
        trains"; "About a dozen animals were held inside the
        stockade"; "The illegal immigrants were held at a
        detention center"; "The terrorists held the journalists
        for ransom" [syn: {restrain}, {confine}]
     5: have rightfully; of rights, titles, and offices; "She bears
        the title of Duchess"; "He held the governorship for
        almost a decade" [syn: {bear}]
     6: have or possess, either in a concrete or an abstract sense;
        "She has $1,000 in the bank"; "He has got two beautiful
        daughters"; "She holds a Master's degree from Harvard"
        [syn: {have}, {have got}]
     7: keep in mind or convey as a conviction or view; "take for
        granted"; "view as important"; "hold these truths to be
        self-evident"; "I hold him personally responsible" [syn: {deem},
         {view as}, {take for}]
     8: contain or hold; have within; "The jar carries wine"; "The
        canteen holds fresh water"; "This can contains water"
        [syn: {bear}, {carry}, {contain}]
     9: lessen the intensity of; temper; hold in restraint; hold or
        keep within limits; "moderate your alcohol intake"; "hold
        your tongue"; "hold your temper"; "control your anger"
        [syn: {control}, {hold in}, {contain}, {check}, {curb}, {moderate}]
     10: remain in a certain state, position, or condition; "The
         weather held"; "They held on the road and kept marching"
     11: maintain (a theory, thoughts, or feelings); "bear a grudge";
         "entertain interesting notions"; "harbor a resentment"
         [syn: {harbor}, {harbour}, {entertain}, {nurse}]
     12: assert or affirm; "Rousseau's philosophy holds that people
         are inherently good"
     13: remain committed to; "I hold to these ideas"
     14: secure and keep for possible future use or application; "The
         landlord retained the security deposit"; "I reserve the
         right to disagree" [syn: {retain}, {keep back}, {hold
         back}]
     15: be the physical support of; carry the weight of; "The beam
         holds up the roof"; "He supported me with one hand while
         I balanced on the beam"; "What's holding that mirror?"
         [syn: {support}, {sustain}, {hold up}]
     16: hold the attention of; "The soprano held the audience";
         "This story held our interest"; "She can hold an audience
         spellbound"
     17: keep from exhaling or expelling; "hold your breath"
     18: support or hold in a certain manner; "She holds her head
         high"; "He carried himself upright" [syn: {carry}, {bear}]
     19: have room for; hold without crowding; "This hotel can
         accommodate 250 guests"; "The theater admits 300 people";
         "The auditorium can't hold more than 500 people" [syn: {accommodate},
          {admit}]
     20: be capable of holding or containing; "This box won't take
         all the items"; "The flask holds one gallon" [syn: {contain},
          {take}]
     21: be valid, applicable, or true; "This theory still holds"
         [syn: {prevail}, {obtain}]
     22: take and maintain control over, often by violent means; "The
         dissatisfied students held the President's office for
         almost a week"
     23: protect against a challenge or attack; "Hold that position
         behind the trees!"; "Hold the bridge against the enemy's
         attacks" [syn: {defend}, {guard}]
     24: declare to be; "She was declared incompetent"; "judge held
         that the defendant was innocent" [syn: {declare}, {adjudge}]
     25: have as a major characteristic; "The novel holds many
         surprises"; "The book holds in store much valuable
         advise"
     26: cause to stop; "Halt the engines"; "Arrest the progress";
         "halt the presses" [syn: {halt}, {arrest}]
     27: bind by an obligation; cause to be indebted; "He's held by a
         contract"; "I'll hold you by your promise" [syn: {oblige},
          {bind}, {obligate}]
     28: cover as for protection against noise or smell; "She held
         her ears when the jackhammer started to operate"; "hold
         one's nose"
     29: drink alcohol without showing ill effects; "He can hold his
         liquor"; "he had drunk more than he could carry" [syn: {carry}]
     30: be pertinent or relevant or applicable; "The same laws apply
         to you!"; "This theory holds for all irrational numbers";
         "The same rules go for everyone" [syn: {apply}, {go for}]
     31: arrange for and reserve (something for someone else) in
         advance; "reserve me a seat on a flight"; "The agent
         booked tickets to the show for the whole family"; "please
         hold a table at Maxim's" [syn: {reserve}, {book}]
     32: resist or confront with resistance; "The politician defied
         public opinion"; "The new material withstands even the
         greatest wear and tear"; "The bridge held" [syn: {defy},
         {withstand}, {hold up}]
     33: keep from departing; "Hold the taxi"; "Hold the horse"
     34: stop dealing with; "hold all calls to the President's office
         while he is in a meeting"
     35: aim, point, or direct; "Hold the fire extinguisher directly
         on the flames"
     36: be in accord; be in agreement; "We agreed on the terms of
         the settlement"; "I can't agree with you!"; "I hold with
         those who say life is sacred"; "Both philosophers concord
         on this point" [syn: {agree}, {concur}, {concord}] [ant:
         {disagree}]
     [also: {held}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
