<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>holding</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>holding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hold \Hold\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Held}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Holding}. {Holden}, p. p., is obs. in elegant writing,
   though still used in legal language.] [OE. haldan, D. houden,
   OHG. hoten, Icel. halda, Dan. holde, Sw. h[*a]lla, Goth.
   haldan to feed, tend (the cattle); of unknown origin. Gf.
   {Avast}, {Halt}, {Hod}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To cause to remain in a given situation, position, or
      relation, within certain limits, or the like; to prevent
      from falling or escaping; to sustain; to restrain; to keep
      in the grasp; to retain.
      [1913 Webster]

            The loops held one curtain to another. --Ex. xxxvi.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy right hand shall hold me.         --Ps. cxxxix.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

            They all hold swords, being expert in war. --Cant.
                                                  iii. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

            In vain he seeks, that having can not hold.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            France, thou mayst hold a serpent by the tongue, . .
            .
            A fasting tiger safer by the tooth,
            Than keep in peace that hand which thou dost hold.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To retain in one's keeping; to maintain possession of, or
      authority over; not to give up or relinquish; to keep; to
      defend.
      [1913 Webster]

            We mean to hold what anciently we claim
            Of deity or empire.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To have; to possess; to be in possession of; to occupy; to
      derive title to; as, to hold office.
      [1913 Webster]

            This noble merchant held a noble house. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of him to hold his seigniory for a yearly tribute.
                                                  --Knolles.
      [1913 Webster]

            And now the strand, and now the plain, they held.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To impose restraint upon; to limit in motion or action; to
      bind legally or morally; to confine; to restrain.
      [1913 Webster]

            We can not hold mortality's strong hand. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Death! what do'st? O, hold thy blow.  --Grashaw.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had not sufficient judgment and self-command to
            hold his tongue.                      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To maintain in being or action; to carry on; to prosecute,
      as a course of conduct or an argument; to continue; to
      sustain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hold not thy peace, and be not still. --Ps. lxxxiii.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Seedtime and harvest, heat and hoary frost,
            Shall hold their course.              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To prosecute, have, take, or join in, as something which
      is the result of united action; as to, hold a meeting, a
      festival, a session, etc.; hence, to direct and bring
      about officially; to conduct or preside at; as, the
      general held a council of war; a judge holds a court; a
      clergyman holds a service.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would hold more talk with thee.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To receive and retain; to contain as a vessel; as, this
      pail holds milk; hence, to be able to receive and retain;
      to have capacity or containing power for.
      [1913 Webster]

            Broken cisterns that can hold no water. --Jer. ii.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            One sees more devils than vast hell can hold.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To accept, as an opinion; to be the adherent of, openly or
      privately; to persist in, as a purpose; to maintain; to
      sustain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Stand fast and hold the traditions which ye have
            been taught.                          --2 Thes.
                                                  ii.15.
      [1913 Webster]

            But still he held his purpose to depart. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To consider; to regard; to esteem; to account; to think;
      to judge.
      [1913 Webster]

            I hold him but a fool.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I shall never hold that man my friend. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord will not hold him guiltless that taketh his
            name in vain.                         --Ex. xx. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To bear, carry, or manage; as he holds himself erect; he
       holds his head high.
       [1913 Webster]

             Let him hold his fingers thus.       --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To hold a wager}, to lay or hazard a wager. --Swift.

   {To hold forth},
       (a) v. t.to offer; to exhibit; to propose; to put
           forward. ``The propositions which books hold forth
           and pretend to teach.'' --Locke.
       (b) v. i. To talk at length; to harangue.

   {To held in}, to restrain; to curd.

   {To hold in hand}, to toy with; to keep in expectation; to
      have in one's power. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            O, fie! to receive favors, return falsehoods,
            And hold a lady in hand.              --Beaw. &amp; Fl.

   {To hold in play}, to keep under control; to dally with.
      --Macaulay.

   {To hold off}, to keep at a distance.

   {To hold on}, to hold in being, continuance or position; as,
      to hold a rider on.

   {To hold one's day}, to keep one's appointment. [Obs.]
      --Chaucer.

   {To hold one's own}. To keep good one's present condition
      absolutely or relatively; not to fall off, or to lose
      ground; as, a ship holds her own when she does not lose
      ground in a race or chase; a man holds his own when he
      does not lose strength or weight.

   {To hold one's peace}, to keep silence.

   {To hold out}.
       (a) To extend; to offer. ``Fortune holds out these to you
           as rewards.'' --B. Jonson.
       (b) To continue to do or to suffer; to endure. ``He can
           not long hold out these pangs.'' --Shak.

   {To hold up}.
       (a) To raise; to lift; as, hold up your head.
       (b) To support; to sustain. ``He holds himself up in
           virtue.''--Sir P. Sidney.
       (c) To exhibit; to display; as, he was held up as an
           example.
       (d) To rein in; to check; to halt; as, hold up your
           horses.
       (e) to rob, usually at gunpoint; -- often with the demand
           to ``hold up'' the hands.
       (f) To delay.

   {To hold water}.
       (a) Literally, to retain water without leaking; hence
           (Fig.), to be whole, sound, consistent, without gaps
           or holes; -- commonly used in a negative sense; as,
           his statements will not hold water. [Colloq.]
       (b) (Naut.) To hold the oars steady in the water, thus
           checking the headway of a boat.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>holding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Holding \Hold"ing\, n.
   1. The act or state of sustaining, grasping, or retaining.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A tenure; a farm or other estate held of another.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which holds, binds, or influences. --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The burden or chorus of a song. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Holding note} (Mus.), a note sustained in one part, while
      the other parts move.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>holding</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>holding
     adj : designed for (usually temporary) retention; "a holding pen";
           "a retaining wall" [syn: {retaining}]
     n 1: the act of keeping in your possession [syn: {retention}, {keeping}]
     2: something owned; any tangible or intangible possession that
        is owned by someone; "that hat is my property"; "he is a
        man of property"; [syn: {property}, {belongings}, {material
        possession}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
