<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>home</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Home, KS
  Zip code(s): 66438
Home, PA
  Zip code(s): 15747
Home, WA
  Zip code(s): 98349
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Home \Home\ (h[=o]m), n. (Zo["o]l.)
   See {Homelyn}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Home \Home\ (h[=o]m; 110), n. [OE. hom, ham, AS. h[=a]m; akin to
   OS. h[=e]m, D. &amp; G. heim, Sw. hem, Dan. hiem, Icel. heimr
   abode, world, heima home, Goth. haims village, Lith.
   k["e]mas, and perh. to Gr. kw`mh village, or to E. hind a
   peasant; cf. Skr. ksh[=e]ma abode, place of rest, security,
   kshi to dwell. [root]20, 220.]
   1. One's own dwelling place; the house in which one lives;
      esp., the house in which one lives with his family; the
      habitual abode of one's family; also, one's birthplace.
      [1913 Webster]

            The disciples went away again to their own home.
                                                  --John xx. 10.
      [1913 Webster]

            Home is the sacred refuge of our life. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Home! home! sweet, sweet home!
            There's no place like home.           --Payne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One's native land; the place or country in which one
      dwells; the place where one's ancestors dwell or dwelt.
      ``Our old home [England].'' --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The abiding place of the affections, especially of the
      domestic affections.
      [1913 Webster]

            He entered in his house -- his home no more,
            For without hearts there is no home.  --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The locality where a thing is usually found, or was first
      found, or where it is naturally abundant; habitat; seat;
      as, the home of the pine.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her eyes are homes of silent prayer.  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            Flandria, by plenty made the home of war. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A place of refuge and rest; an asylum; as, a home for
      outcasts; a home for the blind; hence, esp., the grave;
      the final rest; also, the native and eternal dwelling
      place of the soul.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man goeth to his long home, and the mourners go
            about the streets.                    --Eccl. xii.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Baseball) The {home base}; as, he started for home.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At home}.
      (a) At one's own house, or lodgings.
      (b) In one's own town or country; as, peace abroad and at
          home.
      (c) Prepared to receive callers.

   {Home department}, the department of executive
      administration, by which the internal affairs of a country
      are managed. [Eng.]

   {To be at home on any subject}, to be conversant or familiar
      with it.

   {To feel at home}, to be at one's ease.

   {To make one's self at home}, to conduct one's self with as
      much freedom as if at home.

   Syn: Tenement; house; dwelling; abode; domicile.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Home \Home\, adv.
   1. To one's home or country; as in the phrases, go home, come
      home, carry home.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Close; closely.
      [1913 Webster]

            How home the charge reaches us, has been made out.
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            They come home to men's business and bosoms.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To the place where it belongs; to the end of a course; to
      the full length; as, to drive a nail home; to ram a
      cartridge home.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wear thy good rapier bare and put it home. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Home is often used in the formation of compound words,
         many of which need no special definition; as,
         home-brewed, home-built, home-grown, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To bring home}. See under {Bring}.

   {To come home}.
      (a) To touch or affect personally. See under {Come}.
      (b) (Naut.) To drag toward the vessel, instead of holding
          firm, as the cable is shortened; -- said of an anchor.
          

   {To haul home the sheets of a sail} (Naut.), to haul the
      clews close to the sheave hole. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Home \Home\, a.
   1. Of or pertaining to one's dwelling or country; domestic;
      not foreign; as home manufactures; home comforts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Close; personal; pointed; as, a home thrust.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Games) In various games, the ultimate point aimed at in a
      progress; goal; as:
      (a) (Baseball) The plate at which the batter stands; same
          as {home base} and {home plate}.
      (b) (Lacrosse) The place of a player in front of an
          opponent's goal; also, the player.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Home base} or {Home plate} (Baseball), the base at which the
      batter stands when batting, and which is the last base to
      be reached in scoring a run.

   {Home farm}, {grounds}, etc., the farm, grounds, etc.,
      adjacent to the residence of the owner.

   {Home lot}, an inclosed plot on which the owner's home
      stands. [U. S.]

   {Home rule}, rule or government of an appendent or dependent
      country, as to all local and internal legislation, by
      means of a governing power vested in the people within the
      country itself, in contradistinction to a government
      established by the dominant country; as, home rule in
      Ireland. Also used adjectively; as, home-rule members of
      Parliament.

   {Home ruler}, one who favors or advocates home rule.

   {Home stretch} (Sport.), that part of a race course between
      the last curve and the winning post.

   {Home thrust}, a well directed or effective thrust; one that
      wounds in a vital part; hence, in controversy, a personal
      attack.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>home \home\ (h[=o]m), v. i.
   1. To return home.
      [PJC]

   2. To proceed toward an object or location intended as a
      target; -- of missiles which can change course in flight
      under internal or external control; usually used with in
      on; as, the missile homed in on the radar site.
      [PJC]

   3. [fig.] To arrive at or get closer to an object sought or
      an intended goal; used with in on; as, the repairman
      quickly homed in on the cause of the malfunction.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Homelyn \Home"lyn\, n. [Scot. hommelin.] (Zo["o]l)
   The European sand ray ({Raia maculata}); -- called also
   {home}, {mirror ray}, and {rough ray}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>home</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>home
     adj 1: used of your own ground; "a home game" [syn: {home(a)}]
            [ant: {away}]
     2: relating to or being where one lives or where one's roots
        are; "my home town"
     3: inside the country; "the British Home Office has broader
        responsibilities than the United States Department of the
        Interior"; "the nation's internal politics" [syn: {home(a)},
         {interior(a)}, {internal}, {national}]
     n 1: where you live at a particular time; "deliver the package to
          my home"; "he doesn't have a home to go to"; "your place
          or mine?" [syn: {place}]
     2: housing that someone is living in; "he built a modest
        dwelling near the pond"; "they raise money to provide
        homes for the homeless" [syn: {dwelling}, {domicile}, {abode},
         {habitation}, {dwelling house}]
     3: the country or state or city where you live; "Canadian
        tariffs enabled United States lumber companies to raise
        prices at home"; "his home is New Jersey"
     4: an environment offering affection and security; "home is
        where the heart is"; "he grew up in a good Christian
        home"; "there's no place like home"
     5: an institution where people are cared for; "a home for the
        elderly" [syn: {nursing home}, {rest home}]
     6: the place where you are stationed and from which missions
        start and end [syn: {base}]
     7: a social unit living together; "he moved his family to
        Virginia"; "It was a good Christian household"; "I waited
        until the whole house was asleep"; "the teacher asked how
        many people made up his home" [syn: {family}, {household},
         {house}, {menage}]
     8: (baseball) base consisting of a rubber slab where the batter
        stands; it must be touched by a base runner in order to
        score; "he ruled that the runner failed to touch home"
        [syn: {home plate}, {home base}, {plate}]
     9: place where something began and flourished; "the United
        States is the home of basketball"
     adv 1: at or to or in the direction of one's home or family; "He
            stays home on weekends"; "after the game the children
            brought friends home for supper"; "I'll be home
            tomorrow"; "came riding home in style"; "I hope you
            will come home for Christmas"; "I'll take her home";
            "don't forget to write home"
     2: on or to the point aimed at; "the arrow struck home"
     3: to the fullest extent; to the heart; "drove the nail home";
        "drove his point home"; "his comments hit home"
     v 1: provide with, or send to, a home
     2: return home accurately from a long distance; "homing
        pigeons"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
