<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hood</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hood
   (Heb. tsaniph) a tiara round the head (Isa. 3:23; R.V., pl.,
   "turbans"). Rendered "diadem," Job 29:14; high priest's "mitre,"
   Zech. 3:5; "royal diadem," Isa. 62:3.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>HOOD
     
        Hierarchical Object Oriented Design: a method for
        Architectural Design primarily for software to be developed in
        Ada, leading to automated checking, documentation and source
        code generation.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-hood \-hood\ [OE. hod, had, hed, hede, etc., person, rank,
   order, condition, AS. h[=a]d; akin to OS. h[=e]d, OHG. heit,
   G. -heit, D. -heid, Goth. haidus manner; cf. Skr. k[=e]tu
   brightness, cit to appear, be noticeable, notice. [root]217.
   Cf. {-head}.]
   A termination denoting state, condition, quality, character,
   totality, as in manhood, childhood, knighthood, brotherhood.
   Sometimes it is written, chiefly in obsolete words, in the
   form -head.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hood \Hood\, n. [OE. hood, hod, AS. h[=o]d; akin to D. hoed hat,
   G. hut, OHG. huot, also to E. hat, and prob. to E. heed.
   [root]13.]
   1. State; condition. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            How could thou ween, through that disguised hood
            To hide thy state from being understood? --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A covering or garment for the head or the head and
      shoulders, often attached to the body garment; especially:
      (a) A soft covering for the head, worn by women, which
          leaves only the face exposed.
      (b) A part of a monk's outer garment, with which he covers
          his head; a cowl. ``All hoods make not monks.''
          --Shak.
      (c) A like appendage to a cloak or loose overcoat, that
          may be drawn up over the head at pleasure.
      (d) An ornamental fold at the back of an academic gown or
          ecclesiastical vestment; as, a master's hood.
      (e) A covering for a horse's head.
      (f) (Falconry) A covering for a hawk's head and eyes. See
          Illust. of {Falcon}.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything resembling a hood in form or use; as:
      (a) The top or head of a carriage.
      (b) A chimney top, often contrived to secure a constant
          draught by turning with the wind.
      (c) A projecting cover above a hearth, forming the upper
          part of the fireplace, and confining the smoke to the
          flue.
      (d) The top of a pump.
      (e) (Ord.) A covering for a mortar.
      (f) (Bot.) The hood-shaped upper petal of some flowers, as
          of monkshood; -- called also {helmet}. --Gray.
      (g) (Naut.) A covering or porch for a companion hatch.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Shipbuilding) The endmost plank of a strake which reaches
      the stem or stern.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hood \Hood\ (h[oo^]d), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hooded}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Hooding}.]
   1. To cover with a hood; to furnish with a hood or
      hood-shaped appendage.
      [1913 Webster]

            The friar hooded, and the monarch crowned. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover; to hide; to blind.
      [1913 Webster]

            While grace is saying, I'll hood mine eyes
            Thus with my hat, and sigh and say, ``Amen.''
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Hooding end} (Shipbuilding), the end of a hood where it
      enters the rabbet in the stem post or stern post.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hoodlum \Hood"lum\, n.
   A young rowdy; a rough, lawless fellow; colloquially, called
   also {hood}. [Colloq. U.S.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Just tell your hoodlum friends outside
         You ain't got time to take no ride. --Yakety-Yak (Song)
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hood \Hood\, n.
   1. [shortened from hoodlum.] Same as {hoodlum}. [Colloq.]
      [PJC]

   2. [shortened from neighborhood.] Same as {neighborhood}.
      [slang]
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Bonnet \Bon"net\ (b[o^]n"n[e^]t), n. [OE. bonet, OF. bonet,
   bonete. F. bonnet fr. LL. bonneta, bonetum; orig. the name of
   a stuff, and of unknown origin.]
   1. A headdress for men and boys; a cap. [Obs.] --Milton.
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A soft, elastic, very durable cap, made of thick, seamless
      woolen stuff, and worn by men in Scotland.
      [1913 Webster]

            And p?i?s and bonnets waving high.    --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A covering for the head, worn by women, usually protecting
      more or less the back and sides of the head, but no part
      of the forehead. The shape of the bonnet varies greatly at
      different times; formerly the front part projected, and
      spread outward, like the mouth of a funnel.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything resembling a bonnet in shape or use; as,
      (a) (Fort.) A small defense work at a salient angle; or a
          part of a parapet elevated to screen the other part
          from enfilade fire.
      (b) A metallic canopy, or projection, over an opening, as
          a fireplace, or a cowl or hood to increase the draught
          of a chimney, etc.
      (c) A frame of wire netting over a locomotive chimney, to
          prevent escape of sparks.
      (d) A roofing over the cage of a mine, to protect its
          occupants from objects falling down the shaft.
      (e) In pumps, a metal covering for the openings in the
          valve chambers.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) An additional piece of canvas laced to the foot of
      a jib or foresail in moderate winds. --Hakluyt.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The second stomach of a ruminating animal.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. An accomplice of a gambler, auctioneer, etc., who entices
      others to bet or to bid; a decoy. [Cant]
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Automobiles) The metal cover or shield over the motor;
      predominantly British usage. In the U.S. it is called the
      {hood}. [Brit.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Bonnet limpet} (Zo["o]l.), a name given, from their shape,
      to various species of shells (family {Calyptr[ae]id[ae]}).
      

   {Bonnet monkey} (Zo["o]l.), an East Indian monkey ({Macacus
      sinicus}), with a tuft of hair on its head; the munga.

   {Bonnet piece}, a gold coin of the time of James V. of
      Scotland, the king's head on which wears a bonnet. --Sir
      W. Scott.

   {To have a bee in the bonnet}. See under {Bee}.

   {Black bonnet}. See under {Black}.

   {Blue bonnet}. See in the Vocabulary.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>'hood
     n : (slang) a neighborhood
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hood</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hood
     n 1: an aggressive and violent young criminal [syn: {hoodlum}, {goon},
           {punk}, {thug}, {tough}, {toughie}, {strong-armer}]
     2: metal covering leading to a vent that exhausts smoke or
        fumes [syn: {exhaust hood}]
     3: the folding roof of a carriage
     4: a headdress that protects the head and face
     5: protective covering consisting of a metal part that covers
        the engine; "there are powerful engines under the hoods of
        new cars"; "the mechanic removed the cowling in order to
        repair the plane's engine" [syn: {bonnet}, {cowl}, {cowling}]
     v : cover with a hood; "The bandits were hooded"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
