<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hook</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hook
   (1.) Heb. hah, a "ring" inserted in the nostrils of animals to
   which a cord was fastened for the purpose of restraining them (2
   Kings 19:28; Isa. 37:28, 29; Ezek. 29:4; 38:4). "The Orientals
   make use of this contrivance for curbing their
   work-beasts...When a beast becomes unruly they have only to draw
   the cord on one side, which, by stopping his breath, punishes
   him so effectually that after a few repetitions he fails not to
   become quite tractable whenever he begins to feel it"
   (Michaelis). So God's agents are never beyond his control.
   
     (2.) Hakkah, a fish "hook" (Job 41:2, Heb. Text, 40:25; Isa.
   19:8; Hab. 1:15).
   
     (3.) Vav, a "peg" on which the curtains of the tabernacle were
   hung (Ex. 26:32).
   
     (4.) Tsinnah, a fish-hooks (Amos 4:2).
   
     (5.) Mazleg, flesh-hooks (1 Sam. 2:13, 14), a kind of fork
   with three teeth for turning the sacrifices on the fire, etc.
   
     (6.) Mazmeroth, pruning-hooks (Isa. 2:4; Joel 3:10).
   
     (7.) 'Agmon (Job 41:2, Heb. Text 40:26), incorrectly rendered
   in the Authorized Version. Properly a rush-rope for binding
   animals, as in Revised Version margin.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>HOOK
     
        ? Object Oriented Kernel.  Delphia.  An object-oriented
        extension of Delphia Prolog.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hook
     
        &lt;programming&gt; A {software} or {hardware} feature included in
        order to simplify later additions or changes by a user.
     
        For example, a simple program that prints numbers might always
        print them in base 10, but a more flexible version would let a
        variable determine what base to use; setting the variable to 5
        would make the program print numbers in base 5.  The variable
        is a simple hook.  An even more flexible program might examine
        the variable and treat a value of 16 or less as the base to
        use, but treat any other number as the address of a
        user-supplied routine for printing a number.  This is a
        {hairy} but powerful hook; one can then write a routine to
        print numbers as Roman numerals, say, or as Hebrew characters,
        and plug it into the program through the hook.
     
        Often the difference between a good program and a superb one
        is that the latter has useful hooks in judiciously chosen
        places.  Both may do the original job about equally well, but
        the one with the hooks is much more flexible for future
        expansion of capabilities.
     
        {Emacs}, for example, is *all* hooks.
     
        The term "user exit" is synonymous but much more formal and
        less hackish.
     
        (1997-06-25)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hook \Hook\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hooked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Hooking}.]
   1. To catch or fasten with a hook or hooks; to seize,
      capture, or hold, as with a hook, esp. with a disguised or
      baited hook; hence, to secure by allurement or artifice;
      to entrap; to catch; as, to hook a dress; to hook a trout.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hook him, my poor dear, . . . at any sacrifice. --W.
                                                  Collins.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To seize or pierce with the points of the horns, as cattle
      in attacking enemies; to gore.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To steal. [Colloq. Eng. &amp; U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {To hook on}, to fasten or attach by, or as by, hook.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hook \Hook\, v. i.
   1. To bend; to curve as a hook.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move or go with a sudden turn; hence [Slang or Prov.
      Eng.], to make off; to clear out; -- often with it.
      ``Duncan was wounded, and the escort hooked it.''
      --Kipling.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hook \Hook\ (h[oo^]k; 277), n. [OE. hok, AS. h[=o]c; cf. D.
   haak, G. hake, haken, OHG. h[=a]ko, h[=a]go, h[=a]ggo, Icel.
   haki, Sw. hake, Dan. hage. Cf. {Arquebuse}, {Hagbut}, {Hake},
   {Hatch} a half door, {Heckle}.]
   1. A piece of metal, or other hard material, formed or bent
      into a curve or at an angle, for catching, holding, or
      sustaining anything; as, a hook for catching fish; a hook
      for fastening a gate; a boat hook, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That part of a hinge which is fixed to a post, and on
      which a door or gate hangs and turns.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An implement for cutting grass or grain; a sickle; an
      instrument for cutting or lopping; a billhook.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like slashing Bentley with his desperate hook.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Steam Engin.) See {Eccentric}, and {V-hook}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A snare; a trap. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A field sown two years in succession. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. The projecting points of the thigh bones of cattle; --
      called also {hook bones}.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Geog.) A spit or narrow cape of sand or gravel turned
      landward at the outer end; as, Sandy Hook in New Jersey.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   9. (Sports) The curving motion of a ball, as in bowling or
      baseball, curving away from the hand which threw the ball;
      in golf, a curving motion in the direction of the golfer
      who struck the ball.
      [PJC]

   10. (Computers) A procedure within the encoding of a computer
       program which allows the user to modify the program so as
       to import data from or export data to other programs.
       [PJC]

   {By hook or by crook}, one way or other; by any means, direct
      or indirect. --Milton. ``In hope her to attain by hook or
      crook.'' --Spenser.

   {Off the hook}, freed from some obligation or difficulty; as,
      to get off the hook by getting someone else to do the job.
      [Colloq.]

   {Off the hooks}, unhinged; disturbed; disordered. [Colloq.]
      ``In the evening, by water, to the Duke of Albemarle, whom
      I found mightly off the hooks that the ships are not gone
      out of the river.'' --Pepys.

   {On one's own hook}, on one's own account or responsibility;
      by one's self. [Colloq. U.S.] --Bartlett.

   {To go off the hooks}, to die. [Colloq.] --Thackeray.

   {Bid hook}, a small boat hook.

   {Chain hook}. See under {Chain}.

   {Deck hook}, a horizontal knee or frame, in the bow of a
      ship, on which the forward part of the deck rests.

   {Hook and eye}, one of the small wire hooks and loops for
      fastening together the opposite edges of a garment, etc.
      

   {Hook bill} (Zo["o]l.), the strongly curved beak of a bird.
      

   {Hook ladder}, a ladder with hooks at the end by which it can
      be suspended, as from the top of a wall.

   {Hook motion} (Steam Engin.), a valve gear which is reversed
      by V hooks.

   {Hook squid}, any squid which has the arms furnished with
      hooks, instead of suckers, as in the genera
      {Enoploteuthis} and {Onychteuthis}.

   {Hook wrench}, a wrench or spanner, having a hook at the end,
      instead of a jaw, for turning a bolthead, nut, or
      coupling.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hook n. A software or hardware feature included in order to simplify
   later additions or changes by a user. For example, a simple program that
   prints numbers might always print them in base 10, but a more flexible
   version would let a variable determine what base to use; setting the
   variable to 5 would make the program print numbers in base 5. The
   variable is a simple hook. An even more flexible program might examine
   the variable and treat a value of 16 or less as the base to use, but
   treat any other number as the address of a user-supplied routine for
   printing a number. This is a {hairy} but powerful hook; one can then
   write a routine to print numbers as Roman numerals, say, or as Hebrew
   characters, and plug it into the program through the hook. Often the
   difference between a good program and a superb one is that the latter
   has useful hooks in judiciously chosen places. Both may do the original
   job about equally well, but the one with the hooks is much more flexible
   for future expansion of capabilities ({EMACS}, for example, is _all_
   hooks). The term `user exit' is synonymous but much more formal and less
   hackish.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hook</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hook
     n 1: a catch for locking a door
     2: a sharp curve or crook; a shape resembling a hook [syn: {crotchet}]
     3: anything that serves as an enticement [syn: {bait}, {come-on},
         {lure}, {sweetener}]
     4: a mechanical device that is curved or bent to suspend or
        hold or pull something [syn: {claw}]
     5: a curved or bent implement for suspending or pulling
        something
     6: a golf shot that curves to the left for a right-handed
        golfer; "he tooks lessons to cure his hooking" [syn: {draw},
         {hooking}]
     7: a short swinging punch delivered from the side with the
        elbow bent
     8: a basketball shot made over the head with the hand that is
        farther from the basket [syn: {hook shot}]
     v 1: fasten with a hook [ant: {unhook}]
     2: rip off; ask an unreasonable price [syn: {overcharge}, {soak},
         {surcharge}, {gazump}, {fleece}, {plume}, {pluck}, {rob}]
        [ant: {undercharge}]
     3: make a piece of needlework by interlocking and looping
        thread with a hooked needle; "She sat there crocheting all
        day" [syn: {crochet}]
     4: hit a ball and put a spin on it so that it travels to the
        left
     5: take by theft; "Someone snitched my wallet!" [syn: {snitch},
         {thieve}, {cop}, {knock off}, {glom}]
     6: make off with belongings of others [syn: {pilfer}, {cabbage},
         {purloin}, {pinch}, {abstract}, {snarf}, {swipe}, {sneak},
         {filch}, {nobble}, {lift}]
     7: hit with a hook; "His opponent hooked him badly"
     8: catch with a hook; "hook a fish"
     9: to cause (someone or oneself) to become dependent (on
        something, especially a narcotic drug) [syn: {addict}]
     10: secure with the foot; "hook the ball"
     11: entice and trap; "The car salesman had snared three
         potential customers" [syn: {snare}]
     12: approach with an offer of sexual favors; "he was solicited
         by a prostitute"; "The young man was caught soliciting in
         the park" [syn: {solicit}, {accost}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
