<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>house</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>house</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>HOUSE, n.  A hollow edifice erected for the habitation of man, rat,
mouse, beelte, cockroach, fly, mosquito, flea, bacillus and microbe. 
_House of Correction_, a place of reward for political and personal
service, and for the detention of offenders and appropriations. 
_House of God_, a building with a steeple and a mortgage on it. 
_House-dog_, a pestilent beast kept on domestic premises to insult
persons passing by and appal the hardy visitor.  _House-maid_, a
youngerly person of the opposing sex employed to be variously
disagreeable and ingeniously unclean in the station in which it has
pleased God to place her.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>house</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>House
   Till their sojourn in Egypt the Hebrews dwelt in tents. They
   then for the first time inhabited cities (Gen. 47:3; Ex. 12:7;
   Heb. 11:9). From the earliest times the Assyrians and the
   Canaanites were builders of cities. The Hebrews after the
   Conquest took possession of the captured cities, and seem to
   have followed the methods of building that had been pursued by
   the Canaanites. Reference is made to the stone (1 Kings 7:9;
   Isa. 9:10) and marble (1 Chr. 29:2) used in building, and to the
   internal wood-work of the houses (1 Kings 6:15; 7:2; 10:11, 12;
   2 Chr. 3:5; Jer. 22:14). "Ceiled houses" were such as had beams
   inlaid in the walls to which wainscotting was fastened (Ezra
   6:4; Jer. 22:14; Hag. 1:4). "Ivory houses" had the upper parts
   of the walls adorned with figures in stucco with gold and ivory
   (1 Kings 22:39; 2 Chr. 3:6; Ps. 45:8).
   
     The roofs of the dwelling-houses were flat, and are often
   alluded to in Scripture (2 Sam. 11:2; Isa. 22:1; Matt. 24:17).
   Sometimes tents or booths were erected on them (2 Sam. 16:22).
   They were protected by parapets or low walls (Deut. 22:8). On
   the house-tops grass sometimes grew (Prov. 19:13; 27:15; Ps.
   129:6, 7). They were used, not only as places of recreation in
   the evening, but also sometimes as sleeping-places at night (1
   Sam. 9:25, 26; 2 Sam. 11:2; 16:22; Dan. 4:29; Job 27:18; Prov.
   21:9), and as places of devotion (Jer. 32:29; 19:13).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>house</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>House, NM (village, FIPS 33710)
  Location: 34.64797 N, 103.90328 W
  Population (1990): 85 (54 housing units)
  Area: 2.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 88121
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>house</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>House \House\ (hous), n.; pl. {Houses}. [OE. hous, hus, AS. h?s;
   akin to OS. &amp; OFries. h?s, D. huis, OHG. h?s, G. haus, Icel.
   h?s, Sw. hus, Dan. huus, Goth. gudh?s, house of God, temple;
   and prob. to E. hide to conceal. See {Hide}, and cf. {Hoard},
   {Husband}, {Hussy}, {Husting}.]
   1. A structure intended or used as a habitation or shelter
      for animals of any kind; but especially, a building or
      edifice for the habitation of man; a dwelling place, a
      mansion.
      [1913 Webster]

            Houses are built to live in; not to look on.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bees with smoke and doves with noisome stench
            Are from their hives and houses driven away. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Household affairs; domestic concerns; particularly in the
      phrase to keep house. See below.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Those who dwell in the same house; a household.
      [1913 Webster]

            One that feared God with all his house. --Acts x. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A family of ancestors, descendants, and kindred; a race of
      persons from the same stock; a tribe; especially, a noble
      family or an illustrious race; as, the house of Austria;
      the house of Hanover; the house of Israel.
      [1913 Webster]

            The last remaining pillar of their house,
            The one transmitter of their ancient name.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. One of the estates of a kingdom or other government
      assembled in parliament or legislature; a body of men
      united in a legislative capacity; as, the House of Lords;
      the House of Commons; the House of Representatives; also,
      a quorum of such a body. See {Congress}, and {Parliament}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Com.) A firm, or commercial establishment.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A public house; an inn; a hotel.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Astrol.) A twelfth part of the heavens, as divided by six
      circles intersecting at the north and south points of the
      horizon, used by astrologers in noting the positions of
      the heavenly bodies, and casting horoscopes or nativities.
      The houses were regarded as fixed in respect to the
      horizon, and numbered from the one at the eastern horizon,
      called the ascendant, first house, or house of life,
      downward, or in the direction of the earth's revolution,
      the stars and planets passing through them in the reverse
      order every twenty-four hours.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A square on a chessboard, regarded as the proper place of
      a piece.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. An audience; an assembly of hearers, as at a lecture, a
       theater, etc.; as, a thin or a full house.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. The body, as the habitation of the soul.
       [1913 Webster]

             This mortal house I'll ruin,
             Do C[ae]sar what he can.             --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12.

   Usage: [With an adj., as narrow, dark, etc.] The grave. ``The
          narrow house.'' --Bryant.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: House is much used adjectively and as the first element
         of compounds. The sense is usually obvious; as, house
         cricket, housemaid, house painter, housework.
         [1913 Webster]

   {House ant} (Zo["o]l.), a very small, yellowish brown ant
      ({Myrmica molesta}), which often infests houses, and
      sometimes becomes a great pest.

   {House of bishops} (Prot. Epis. Ch.), one of the two bodies
      composing a general convertion, the other being House of
      Clerical and Lay Deputies.

   {House boat}, a covered boat used as a dwelling.

   {House of call}, a place, usually a public house, where
      journeymen connected with a particular trade assemble when
      out of work, ready for the call of employers. [Eng.]

   {To bring down the house}. See under {Bring}.

   {To keep house}, to maintain an independent domestic
      establishment.

   {To keep open house}, to entertain friends at all times.

   Syn: Dwelling; residence; abode. See {Tenement}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>house</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>House \House\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Housed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Housing}.] [AS. h?sian.]
   1. To take or put into a house; to shelter under a roof; to
      cover from the inclemencies of the weather; to protect by
      covering; as, to house one's family in a comfortable home;
      to house farming utensils; to house cattle.
      [1913 Webster]

            At length have housed me in a humble shed. --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

            House your choicest carnations, or rather set them
            under a penthouse.                    --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To drive to a shelter. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To admit to residence; to harbor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Palladius wished him to house all the Helots. --Sir
                                                  P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To deposit and cover, as in the grave. --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) To stow in a safe place; to take down and make
      safe; as, to house the upper spars.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>house</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>House \House\, v. i.
   1. To take shelter or lodging; to abide to dwell; to lodge.
      [1913 Webster]

            You shall not house with me.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Astrol.) To have a position in one of the houses. See
      {House}, n., 8. ``Where Saturn houses.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>house</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>house
     n 1: a dwelling that serves as living quarters for one or more
          families; "he has a house on Cape Cod"; "she felt she
          had to get out of the house"
     2: an official assembly having legislative powers; "the
        legislature has two houses"
     3: a building in which something is sheltered or located; "they
        had a large carriage house"
     4: a social unit living together; "he moved his family to
        Virginia"; "It was a good Christian household"; "I waited
        until the whole house was asleep"; "the teacher asked how
        many people made up his home" [syn: {family}, {household},
         {home}, {menage}]
     5: a building where theatrical performances or motion-picture
        shows can be presented; "the house was full" [syn: {theater},
         {theatre}]
     6: members of a business organization that owns or operates one
        or more establishments; "he worked for a brokerage house"
        [syn: {firm}, {business firm}]
     7: aristocratic family line; "the House of York"
     8: the members of a religious community living together
     9: the audience gathered together in a theatre or cinema; "the
        house applauded"; "he counted the house"
     10: play in which children take the roles of father or mother or
         children and pretend to interact like adults; "the
         children were playing house"
     11: (astrology) one of 12 equal areas into which the zodiac is
         divided [syn: {sign of the zodiac}, {star sign}, {sign},
         {mansion}, {planetary house}]
     12: the management of a gambling house or casino; "the house
         gets a percentage of every bet"
     v 1: contain or cover; "This box houses the gears"
     2: provide housing for; "The immigrants were housed in a new
        development outside the town" [syn: {put up}, {domiciliate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
