<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>humor</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>humor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>humor
     
        {hacker humour}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>humor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Humor \Hu"mor\, n. [OE. humour, OF. humor, umor, F. humeur, L.
   humor, umor, moisture, fluid, fr. humere, umere, to be moist.
   See {Humid}.] [Written also {humour}.]
   1. Moisture, especially, the moisture or fluid of animal
      bodies, as the chyle, lymph, etc.; as, the humors of the
      eye, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The ancient physicians believed that there were four
         humors (the blood, phlegm, yellow bile or choler, and
         black bile or melancholy), on the relative proportion
         of which the temperament and health depended.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Med.) A vitiated or morbid animal fluid, such as often
      causes an eruption on the skin. ``A body full of humors.''
      --Sir W. Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. State of mind, whether habitual or temporary (as formerly
      supposed to depend on the character or combination of the
      fluids of the body); disposition; temper; mood; as, good
      humor; ill humor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Examine how your humor is inclined,
            And which the ruling passion of your mind.
                                                  --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

            A prince of a pleasant humor.         --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            I like not the humor of lying.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. pl. Changing and uncertain states of mind; caprices;
      freaks; vagaries; whims.
      [1913 Webster]

            Is my friend all perfection, all virtue and
            discretion? Has he not humors to be endured?
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That quality of the imagination which gives to ideas an
      incongruous or fantastic turn, and tends to excite
      laughter or mirth by ludicrous images or representations;
      a playful fancy; facetiousness.
      [1913 Webster]

            For thy sake I admit
            That a Scot may have humor, I'd almost said wit.
                                                  --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

            A great deal of excellent humor was expended on the
            perplexities of mine host.            --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Aqueous humor}, {Crystalline humor} or {Crystalline lens},
   {Vitreous humor}. (Anat.) See {Eye}.

   {Out of humor}, dissatisfied; displeased; in an unpleasant
      frame of mind.

   Syn: Wit; satire; pleasantry; temper; disposition; mood;
        frame; whim; fancy; caprice. See {Wit}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>humor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Humor \Hu"mor\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Humored}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Humoring}.]
   1. To comply with the humor of; to adjust matters so as suit
      the peculiarities, caprices, or exigencies of; to adapt
      one's self to; to indulge by skillful adaptation; as, to
      humor the mind.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is my part to invent, and the musician's to humor
            that invention.                       --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To help on by indulgence or compliant treatment; to
      soothe; to gratify; to please.
      [1913 Webster]

            You humor me when I am sick.          --Pope.

   Syn: To gratify; to indulge. See {Gratify}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>humor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>humor
     n 1: a message whose ingenuity or verbal skill or incongruity has
          the power to evoke laughter [syn: {wit}, {humour}, {witticism},
           {wittiness}]
     2: the trait of appreciating (and being able to express) the
        humorous; "she didn't appreciate my humor"; "you can't
        survive in the army without a sense of humor" [syn: {humour},
         {sense of humor}, {sense of humour}]
     3: a characteristic (habitual or relatively temporary) state of
        feeling; "whether he praised or cursed me depended on his
        temper at the time"; "he was in a bad humor" [syn: {temper},
         {mood}, {humour}]
     4: the quality of being funny; "I fail to see the humor in it"
        [syn: {humour}]
     5: (Middle Ages) one of the four fluids in the body whose
        balance was believed to determine your emotional and
        physical state; "the humors are blood and phlegm and
        yellow and black bile" [syn: {humour}]
     6: the liquid parts of the body [syn: {liquid body substance},
        {bodily fluid}, {body fluid}, {humour}]
     v : put into a good mood [syn: {humour}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
