<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hung</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hung</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hung
     
        ["hung up"] Equivalent to {wedged}, but more common at Unix/C
        sites.  Not generally used of people.  Synonym with {locked
        up}, {wedged}; compare {hosed}.  See also {hang}.  A hung
        state is distinguished from {crash}ed or {down}, where the
        program or system is also unusable but because it is not
        running rather than because it is waiting for something.
        However, the recovery from both situations is often the same.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hung</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hang \Hang\ (h[a^]ng), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hanged} (h[a^]ngd)
   or {Hung} (h[u^]ng); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Hanging}.

   Usage: The use of hanged is preferable to that of hung, when
          reference is had to death or execution by suspension,
          and it is also more common.] [OE. hangen, hongien, v.
          t. &amp; i., AS. hangian, v. i., fr. h[=o]n, v. t. (imp.
          heng, p. p. hongen); akin to OS. hang[=o]n, v. i., D.
          hangen, v. t. &amp; i., G. hangen, v. i, h["a]ngen, v. t.,
          Icel. hanga, v. i., Goth. h[=a]han, v. t. (imp.
          ha['i]hah), h[=a]han, v. i. (imp. hahaida), and perh.
          to L. cunctari to delay. [root]37. ]
   1. To suspend; to fasten to some elevated point without
      support from below; -- often used with up or out; as, to
      hang a coat on a hook; to hang up a sign; to hang out a
      banner.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fasten in a manner which will allow of free motion upon
      the point or points of suspension; -- said of a pendulum,
      a swing, a door, gate, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fit properly, as at a proper angle (a part of an
      implement that is swung in using), as a scythe to its
      snath, or an ax to its helve. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To put to death by suspending by the neck; -- a form of
      capital punishment; as, to hang a murderer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cover, decorate, or furnish by hanging pictures,
      trophies, drapery, and the like, or by covering with paper
      hangings; -- said of a wall, a room, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hung be the heavens with black.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And hung thy holy roofs with savage spoils.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To paste, as paper hangings, on the walls of a room.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To hold or bear in a suspended or inclined manner or
      position instead of erect; to droop; as, he hung his head
      in shame.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cowslips wan that hang the pensive head. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To prevent from reaching a decision, esp. by refusing to
      join in a verdict that must be unanimous; as, one
      obstinate juror can hang a jury.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To hang down}, to let fall below the proper position; to
      bend down; to decline; as, to hang down the head, or,
      elliptically, to hang the head.

   {To hang fire} (Mil.), to be slow in communicating fire
      through the vent to the charge; as, the gun hangs fire;
      hence, to hesitate, to hold back as if in suspense.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hung</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hung \Hung\,
   imp. &amp; p. p. of {Hang}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Hung beef}, the fleshy part of beef slightly salted and hung
      up to dry; dried beef.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hung</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hung adj. [from `hung up'; common] Equivalent to {wedged}, but more
   common at Unix/C sites. Not generally used of people. Syn. with {locked
   up}, {wedged}; compare {hosed}. See also {hang}. A hung state is
   distinguished from {crash}ed or {down}, where the program or system is
   also unusable but because it is not running rather than because it is
   waiting for something. However, the recovery from both situations is
   often the same. It is also distinguished from the similar but more
   drastic state {wedged} - hung software can be woken up with easy things
   like interrupt keys, but wedged will need a kill -9 or even reboot.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hung</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hung
     See {hang}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hung</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hang
     n 1: a special way of doing something; "he had a bent for it";
          "he had a special knack for getting into trouble"; "he
          couldn't get the hang of it" [syn: {bent}, {knack}]
     2: the way a garment hangs; "he adjusted the hang of his coat"
     3: a gymnastic exercise performed on the rings or horizontal
        bar or parallel bars when the gymnast's weight is
        supported by the arms
     v 1: be suspended or hanging; "The flag hung on the wall"
     2: cause to be hanging or suspended; "Hang that picture on the
        wall" [syn: {hang up}]
     3: kill by hanging; "The murdered was hanged on Friday" [syn: {string
        up}]
     4: let drop or droop; "Hang one's head in shame"
     5: fall or flow in a certain way; "This dress hangs well"; "Her
        long black hair flowed down her back" [syn: {fall}, {flow}]
     6: be menacing, burdensome, or oppressive; "This worry hangs on
        my mind"; "The cloud of suspicion hangs over her"
     7: give heed (to); "The children in the audience attended the
        recital quietly"; "She hung on his every word"; "They
        attended to everything he said" [syn: {attend}, {advert},
        {pay heed}, {give ear}]
     8: be suspended or poised; "Heavy fog hung over the valley"
     9: hold on tightly or tenaciously; "hang on to your father's
        hands"; "The child clung to his mother's apron" [syn: {cling}]
     10: be exhibited; "Picasso hangs in this new wing of the museum"
     11: prevent from reaching a verdict, of a jury
     12: decorate or furnish with something suspended; "Hang
         wallpaper"
     13: be placed in position as by a hinge; "This cabinet door
         doesn't hang right!"
     14: place in position as by a hinge so as to allow free movement
         in one direction; "hang a door"
     15: of meat, in order to get a gamey taste; "hang the venison
         for a few days"
     [also: {hung}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hung</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hung
     adj : (usually followed by `with' or used in a combining form)
           having items suspended on or from a support; "walls
           hung with valuable paintings"; "a vine-hung trellis"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
