<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hunting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hunting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hunting
   mentioned first in Gen. 10:9 in connection with Nimrod. Esau was
   "a cunning hunter" (Gen. 25:27). Hunting was practised by the
   Hebrews after their settlement in the "Land of Promise" (Lev.
   17:15; Prov. 12:27). The lion and other ravenous beasts were
   found in Palestine (1 Sam. 17:34; 2 Sam. 23:20; 1 Kings 13:24;
   Ezek. 19:3-8), and it must have been necessary to hunt and
   destroy them. Various snares and gins were used in hunting (Ps.
   91:3; Amos 3:5; 2 Sam. 23:20).
   
     War is referred to under the idea of hunting (Jer. 16:16;
   Ezek. 32:30).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hunting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hunt \Hunt\ (h[u^]nt), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Hunted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Hunting}.] [AS. huntian to hunt; cf. hentan to
   follow, pursue, Goth. hin?an (in comp.) to seize. [root]36.
   Cf. {Hent}.]
   1. To search for or follow after, as game or wild animals; to
      chase; to pursue for the purpose of catching or killing;
      to follow with dogs or guns for sport or exercise; as, to
      hunt a deer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like a dog, he hunts in dreams.       --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To search diligently after; to seek; to pursue; to follow;
      -- often with out or up; as, to hunt up the facts; to hunt
      out evidence.
      [1913 Webster]

            Evil shall hunt the violent man to overthrow him.
                                                  --Ps. cxl. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To drive; to chase; -- with down, from, away, etc.; as, to
      hunt down a criminal; he was hunted from the parish.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To use or manage in the chase, as hounds.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hunts a pack of dogs.              --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To use or traverse in pursuit of game; as, he hunts the
      woods, or the country.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Change Ringing) To move or shift the order of (a bell) in
      a regular course of changes.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hunting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hunting \Hunt"ing\, n.
   The pursuit of game or of wild animals. --A. Smith.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Happy hunting grounds}, the region to which, according to
      the belief of American Indians, the souls of warriors and
      hunters pass after death, to be happy in hunting and
      feasting. --Tylor.

   {Hunting box}. Same As {Hunting lodge} (below).

   {Hunting cat} (Zo["o]l.), the cheetah.

   {Hunting cog} (Mach.), a tooth in the larger of two geared
      wheels which makes its number of teeth prime to the number
      in the smaller wheel, thus preventing the frequent meeting
      of the same pairs of teeth.

   {Hunting dog} (Zo["o]l.), the hyena dog.

   {Hunting ground}, a region or district abounding in game;
      esp. (pl.), the regions roamed over by the North American
      Indians in search of game.

   {Hunting horn}, a bulge; a horn used in the chase. See
      {Horn}, and {Bulge}.

   {Hunting leopard} (Zo["o]l.), the cheetah.

   {Hunting lodge}, a temporary residence for the purpose of
      hunting.

   {Hunting seat}, a hunting lodge. --Gray.

   {Hunting shirt}, a coarse shirt for hunting, often of
      leather.

   {Hunting spider} (Zo["o]l.), a spider which hunts its prey,
      instead of catching it in a web; a wolf spider.

   {Hunting watch}. See {Hunter}, 6.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hunting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hunting
     n 1: the pursuit and killing or capture of wild animals regarded
          as a sport [syn: {hunt}]
     2: the activity of looking thoroughly in order to find
        something or someone [syn: {search}, {hunt}]
     3: the work of finding and killing or capturing animals for
        food or pelts [syn: {hunt}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
