<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>hypocrite</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hypocrite</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>HYPOCRITE, n.  One who, profession virtues that he does not respect
secures the advantage of seeming to be what he depises.


                                  I


I is the first letter of the alphabet, the first word of the language,
the first thought of the mind, the first object of affection.  In
grammar it is a pronoun of the first person and singular number.  Its
plural is said to be _We_, but how there can be more than one myself
is doubtless clearer the grammarians than it is to the author of this
incomparable dictionary.  Conception of two myselfs is difficult, but
fine.  The frank yet graceful use of "I" distinguishes a good writer
from a bad; the latter carries it with the manner of a thief trying to
cloak his loot.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hypocrite</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hypocrite
   one who puts on a mask and feigns himself to be what he is not;
   a dissembler in religion. Our Lord severely rebuked the scribes
   and Pharisees for their hypocrisy (Matt. 6:2, 5, 16). "The
   hypocrite's hope shall perish" (Job 8:13). The Hebrew word here
   rendered "hypocrite" rather means the "godless" or "profane," as
   it is rendered in Jer. 23:11, i.e., polluted with crimes.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hypocrite</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Hypocrite \Hyp"o*crite\, n. [F., fr. L. hypocrita, Gr. ? one who
   plays a part on the stage, a dissembler, feigner. See
   {Hypocrisy}.]
   One who plays a part; especially, one who, for the purpose of
   winning approbation of favor, puts on a fair outside seeming;
   one who feigns to be other and better than he is; a false
   pretender to virtue or piety; one who simulates virtue or
   piety.
   [1913 Webster]

         The hypocrite's hope shall perish.       --Job viii.
                                                  13.
   [1913 Webster]

         I dare swear he is no hypocrite, but prays from his
         heart.                                   --Shak.

   Syn: Deceiver; pretender; cheat. See {Dissembler}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>hypocrite</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hypocrite
     n : a person who professes beliefs and opinions that he does not
         hold [syn: {dissembler}, {phony}, {phoney}, {pretender}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
