<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mace</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MACE, n.  A staff of office signifying authority.  Its form, that of a
heavy club, indicates its original purpose and use in dissuading from
dissent.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MACE
     
        A concurrent {object-oriented} language.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mace \Mace\ (m[=a]s), n. [Jav. &amp; Malay. m[=a]s, fr. Skr.
   m[=a]sha a bean.]
   A money of account in China equal to one tenth of a tael;
   also, a weight of 57.98 grains. --S. W. Williams.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mace \Mace\, prop. n. [Trademark.]
   A chemical preparation containing tear gas in a solvent,
   packaged in the form of a spray, and used to temporarily
   incapacitate people, such as rioters or criminals, by causing
   intense eye and skin irritation; also called {chemical mace}.
   It is designed to be a non-lethal weapon for defending
   against violent people.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mace \Mace\, n. [F. macis, L. macis, macir, Gr. ?; cf. Skr.
   makaranda the nectar or honey of a flower, a fragrant mango.]
   (Bot.)
   A kind of spice; the aril which partly covers nutmegs. See
   {Nutmeg}.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: {Red mace} is the aril of {Myristica tingens}, and
         {white mace} that of {Myristica Otoba}, -- East Indian
         trees of the same genus with the nutmeg tree.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mace \Mace\, n. [OF. mace, F. masse, from (assumed) L. matea, of
   which the dim. mateola a kind of mallet or beetle, is found.]
   1. A heavy staff or club of metal; a spiked club; -- used as
      weapon in war before the general use of firearms,
      especially in the Middle Ages, for breaking metal armor.
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Death with his mace petrific . . . smote. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: A staff borne by, or carried before, a magistrate
      as an ensign of his authority. ``Swayed the royal mace.''
      --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An officer who carries a mace as an emblem of authority; a
      macebearer. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A knobbed mallet used by curriers in dressing leather to
      make it supple.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Billiards) A rod for playing billiards, having one end
      suited to resting on the table and pushed with one hand.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mace
     n 1: (trademark) a liquid that temporarily disables a person;
          prepared as an aerosol and sprayed in the face, it
          irritates the eyes and causes dizziness and
          immobilization [syn: {Chemical Mace}]
     2: an official who carries a mace of office [syn: {macebearer},
         {macer}]
     3: spice made from the dried fleshy covering of the nutmeg seed
     4: a ceremonial staff carried as a symbol of office or
        authority
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
