<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mafia</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mafia</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>organized crime \organized crime\ n.
   Groups of persons organized for illegal purposes, such as
   bootlegging, conducting illegal gambling, loansharking,
   extortion, etc.; -- a general term encompassing most forms of
   criminal groups, but especially those that are consolidated
   into ``families'' more or less recognizing each other's
   different regions of operation; sometimes considered
   synonymous with the {mafia} or the {syndicate}.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mafia</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Maffia \Maf"fi*a\, Mafia \Ma"fi*a\, n. [It. maffia.]
   1. A secret society which organized in Sicily as a political
      organization, but is now widespread among Italians, and is
      used to further or protect private interests, reputedly by
      illegal methods; called also the {Sicilian Mafia}.
      [WordNet sense 2]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. A group of loosely associated of criminal organizations in
      the United States, some having ties to the Sicilian Mafia,
      and organized in ``families''; the term is applied to the
      entire group of organizations, or to any one local group.
      Also, loosely, organized groups of criminals anywhere, as
      the Russian mafia. [WordNet sense 1]

   Syn: syndicate, mob, Cosa Nostra, La Cosa Nostra, organized
        crime.
        [WordNet 1.6 + PJC]

   3. Any tightly knit group of trusted associates having strong
      control or influence in some area; as, Kennedy and his
      Irish Mafia. [informal] [WordNet sense 3]
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mafia</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mafia \Maf"i*a\, Mafioso \Ma`fi*o"so\, n.
   see {maffia}, {maffioso}.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mafia</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Syndicate \Syn"di*cate\, n. [Cf. F. syndicat, LL. syndicatus.]
   1. The office or jurisdiction of a syndic; a council, or body
      of syndics. --Bp. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An association of persons officially authorized to
      undertake some duty or to negotiate some business; also,
      an association of persons who combine to carry out, on
      their own account, a financial or industrial project; as,
      a syndicate of bankers formed to take up and dispose of an
      entire issue of government bonds.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A more or less organized association of criminals
      controlling some aspects of criminal activity, in a
      specific area or country-wide; -- used loosely as a
      synonym for {organized crime} or the {mafia}.
      [PJC]

   4. (Journalism) a commercial organization that purchases
      various journalistic items, such as articles, columns, or
      comic strips, from their individual creators, and resells
      them to newspapers or other periodicals for simultaneous
      publication over a wide area.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mafia</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mafia
     n 1: a crime syndicate in the United States; organized in
          families; believed to have important relations to the
          Sicilian Mafia [syn: {Maffia}, {Cosa Nostra}]
     2: a secret terrorist group in Sicily; originally opposed
        tyranny but evolved into a criminal organization in the
        middle of the 19th century [syn: {Maffia}, {Sicilian Mafia}]
     3: any tightly knit group of trusted associates [syn: {maffia}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
