<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>magic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MAGIC, n.  An art of converting superstition into coin.  There are
other arts serving the same high purpose, but the discreet
lexicographer does not name them.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Magic
   The Jews seem early to have consulted the teraphim (q.v.) for
   oracular answers (Judg. 18:5, 6; Zech. 10:2). There is a
   remarkable illustration of this divining by teraphim in Ezek.
   21:19-22. We read also of the divining cup of Joseph (Gen.
   44:5). The magicians of Egypt are frequently referred to in the
   history of the Exodus. Magic was an inherent part of the ancient
   Egyptian religion, and entered largely into their daily life.
   
     All magical arts were distinctly prohibited under penalty of
   death in the Mosaic law. The Jews were commanded not to learn
   the "abomination" of the people of the Promised Land (Lev.
   19:31; Deut. 18:9-14). The history of Saul's consulting the
   witch of Endor (1 Sam. 28:3-20) gives no warrant for attributing
   supernatural power to magicians. From the first the witch is
   here only a bystander. The practice of magic lingered among the
   people till after the Captivity, when they gradually abandoned
   it.
   
     It is not much referred to in the New Testament. The Magi
   mentioned in Matt. 2:1-12 were not magicians in the ordinary
   sense of the word. They belonged to a religious caste, the
   followers of Zoroaster, the astrologers of the East. Simon, a
   magician, was found by Philip at Samaria (Acts 8:9-24); and Paul
   and Barnabas encountered Elymas, a Jewish sorcerer, at Paphos
   (13:6-12). At Ephesus there was a great destruction of magical
   books (Acts 19:18, 19).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MAGIC
     
        An early system on the {Midac} computer.
     
        [Listed in CACM 2(5):16 (May 1959)].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-01-25)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>magic
     
        1. As yet unexplained, or too complicated to explain; compare
        {automagically} and (Arthur C.) Clarke's Third Law:
     
        	Any sufficiently advanced technology is
        	indistinguishable from magic.
     
        "TTY echoing is controlled by a large number of magic bits."
        "This routine magically computes the parity of an 8-bit byte
        in three instructions."
     
        2. Characteristic of something that works although no one
        really understands why (this is especially called {black
        magic}).
     
        3. (Stanford) A feature not generally publicised that allows
        something otherwise impossible or a feature formerly in that
        category but now unveiled.
     
        Compare {wizardly}, {deep magic}, {heavy wizardry}.
     
        For more about hackish "magic" see {Magic Switch Story}.
     
        4. {magic number}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2001-03-19)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Magic \Mag"ic\, Magical \Mag"ic*al\, a. [L. magicus, Gr. ?, fr.
   ?: cf. F. magique. See {Magi}.]
   1. Pertaining to the hidden wisdom supposed to be possessed
      by the Magi; relating to the occult powers of nature, and
      the producing of effects by their agency.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Performed by, or proceeding from, occult and superhuman
      agencies; done by, or seemingly done by, enchantment or
      sorcery; as, a magical spell. Hence: Seemingly requiring
      more than human power; imposing or startling in
      performance; producing effects which seem supernatural or
      very extraordinary; having extraordinary properties; as, a
      magic lantern; a magic square or circle.
      [1913 Webster]

            The painter's magic skill.            --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Although with certain words magic is used more than
         magical, -- as, magic circle, magic square, magic wand,
         -- we may in general say magic or magical; as, a magic
         or magical effect; a magic or magical influence, etc.
         But when the adjective is predicative, magical, and not
         magic, is used; as, the effect was magical.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Magic circle}, a series of concentric circles containing the
      numbers 12 to 75 in eight radii, and having somewhat
      similar properties to the magic square.

   {Magic humming bird} (Zo["o]l.), a Mexican humming bird
      ({Iache magica}), having white downy thing tufts.

   {Magic lantern}. See {Lantern}.

   {Magic square}, numbers so disposed in parallel and equal
      rows in the form of a square, that each row, taken
      vertically, horizontally, or diagonally, shall give the
      same sum, the same product, or an harmonical series,
      according as the numbers taken are in arithmetical,
      geometrical, or harmonical progression.

   {Magic wand}, a wand used by a magician in performing feats
      of magic.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Magic \Mag"ic\, n. [OE. magique, L. magice, Gr. ? (sc. ?), fr.
   ?. See {Magic}, a., and {Magi}.]
   1. A comprehensive name for all of the pretended arts which
      claim to produce effects by the assistance of supernatural
      beings, or departed spirits, or by a mastery of secret
      forces in nature attained by a study of occult science,
      including enchantment, conjuration, witchcraft, sorcery,
      necromancy, incantation, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            An appearance made by some magic.     --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The art of creating illusions which appear to the observer
      to be inexplicable except by some supernatural influence;
      it includes simple sleight of hand (legerdemain) as well
      as more elaborate stage magic, using special devices
      constructed to produce mystifying effects; as, the magic
      of David Copperfield. It is practised as an entertainment,
      by magicians who do not pretend to have supernatural
      powers.
      [PJC]

   {Celestial magic}, a supposed supernatural power which gave
      to spirits a kind of dominion over the planets, and to the
      planets an influence over men.

   {Natural magic}, the art of employing the powers of nature to
      produce effects apparently supernatural.

   {Superstitious magic}, or {Geotic magic}, the invocation of
      devils or demons, involving the supposition of some tacit
      or express agreement between them and human beings.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Sorcery; witchcraft; necromancy; conjuration;
        enchantment.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>magic 1. adj. As yet unexplained, or too complicated to explain;
   compare {automagically} and (Arthur C.) Clarke's Third Law: "Any
   sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic." "TTY
   echoing is controlled by a large number of magic bits." "This routine
   magically computes the parity of an 8-bit byte in three instructions."
   2. adj. Characteristic of something that works although no one really
   understands why (this is especially called {black magic}). 3. n.
   [Stanford] A feature not generally publicized that allows something
   otherwise impossible, or a feature formerly in that category but now
   unveiled. 4. n. The ultimate goal of all engineering &amp; development,
   elegance in the extreme; from the first corollary to Clarke's Third Law:
   "Any technology distinguishable from magic is insufficiently advanced".

   Parodies playing on these senses of the term abound; some have made
   their way into serious documentation, as when a MAGIC directive was
   described in the Control Card Reference for GCOS c.1978. For more about
   hackish `magic', see {Appendix A}. Compare {black magic}, {wizardly},
   {deep magic}, {heavy wizardry}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>magic
     adj : possessing or using or characteristic of or appropriate to
           supernatural powers; "charming incantations"; "magic
           signs that protect against adverse influence"; "a
           magical spell"; "'tis now the very witching time of
           night"- Shakespeare; "wizard wands"; "wizardly powers"
           [syn: {charming}, {magical}, {sorcerous}, {witching(a)},
            {wizard(a)}, {wizardly}]
     n 1: any art that invokes supernatural powers
     2: an illusory feat; considered magical by naive observers
        [syn: {magic trick}, {conjuring trick}, {trick}, {legerdemain},
         {conjuration}, {illusion}, {deception}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
