<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>magnesium</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magnesium</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>elements</Id>
        <Name>Elements database 20001107</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>magnesium
Symbol: Mg
Atomic number: 12
Atomic weight: 24.312
Silvery metallic element belonging to group 2 of the periodic table
(alkaline-earth metals). It is essential for living organisms, and is used
in a number of light alloys. Chemically very reactive, it forms a
protective oxide coating when exposed to air and burns with an intense
white flame. It also reacts with sulphur, nitrogen and the halogens. First
isolated by Bussy in 1828.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magnesium</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Magnesium \Mag*ne"si*um\, n. [NL. &amp; F. See {Magnesia}.] (Chem.)
   A light silver-white metallic element of atomic number 12,
   malleable and ductile, quite permanent in dry air but
   tarnishing in moist air. It burns, forming (the oxide)
   magnesia, with the production of a blinding light (the
   so-called magnesium light) which is used in signaling, in
   pyrotechny, or in photography where a strong actinic
   illuminant is required. Its compounds occur abundantly, as in
   dolomite, talc, meerschaum, etc. Symbol Mg. Atomic weight,
   24.305. Specific gravity, 1.75.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Magnesium sulphate}. (Chem.) Same as {Epsom salts}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>magnesium</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>magnesium
     n : a light silver-white ductile bivalent metallic element; in
         pure form it burns with brilliant white flame; occurs
         naturally only in combination (as in magnesite and
         dolomite and carnallite and spinel and olivine) [syn: {Mg},
          {atomic number 12}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
