<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>maintenance</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>maintenance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>maintenance
     
        &lt;programming&gt; The modification of a software product, after
        delivery, to correct faults, to improve performance or other
        attributes, or to adapt the product to a changed environment.
     
        Maintenance is an important part of the {software life-cycle}.
        It is expensive in manpower and resources, and one of the aims
        of {software engineering} is to reduce its cost.
     
        (1996-12-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>maintenance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Maintenance \Main"te*nance\, n. [OF. maintenance. See
   {Maintain}.]
   1. The act of maintaining; sustenance; support; defense;
      vindication.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whatsoever is granted to the church for God's honor
            and the maintenance of his service, is granted to
            God.                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which maintains or supports; means of sustenance;
      supply of necessaries and conveniences.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those of better fortune not making learning their
            maintenance.                          --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Crim. Law) An officious or unlawful intermeddling in a
      cause depending between others, by assisting either party
      with money or means to carry it on. See {Champerty}.
      --Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Those actions required for the care of machinery, a
      building, etc., to keep it clean and in proper functioning
      condition, and to prevent or forestall damage due to
      normal use.
      [PJC]

   5. Payments, such as child support or alimony, to a dependent
      child not living with one or to a divorced wife.
      [PJC]

   {Cap of maintenance}. See under {Cap}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>maintenance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>maintenance
     n 1: activity involved in maintaining something in good working
          order; "he wrote the manual on car care" [syn: {care}, {upkeep}]
     2: means of maintenance of a family or group
     3: court-ordered support paid by one spouse to another after
        they are separated [syn: {alimony}]
     4: the act of sustaining life by food or providing a means of
        subsistence; "they were in want of sustenance"; "fishing
        was their main sustainment" [syn: {sustenance}, {sustentation},
         {sustainment}, {upkeep}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
