<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>malice</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>malice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>malice \mal"ice\ (m[a^]l"[i^]s), n. [F. malice, fr. L. malitia,
   from malus bad, ill, evil, prob. orig., dirty, black; cf. Gr.
   me`las black, Skr. mala dirt. Cf. {Mauger}.]
   1. Enmity of heart; malevolence; ill will; a spirit
      delighting in harm or misfortune to another; a disposition
      to injure another; a malignant design of evil. ``Nor set
      down aught in malice.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Envy, hatred, and malice are three distinct passions
            of the mind.                          --Ld. Holt.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) Any wicked or mischievous intention of the mind; a
      depraved inclination to mischief; an intention to vex,
      annoy, or injure another person, or to do a wrongful act
      without just cause or cause or excuse; a wanton disregard
      of the rights or safety of others; willfulness.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Malice aforethought} or {Malice prepense}, malice previously
      and deliberately entertained.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Spite; ill will; malevolence; grudge; pique; bitterness;
        animosity; malignity; maliciousness; rancor; virulence.

   Usage: See {Spite}. -- {Malevolence}, {Malignity},
          {Malignancy}. Malice is a stronger word than
          malevolence, which may imply only a desire that evil
          may befall another, while malice desires, and perhaps
          intends, to bring it about. Malignity is intense and
          deepseated malice. It implies a natural delight in
          hating and wronging others. One who is malignant must
          be both malevolent and malicious; but a man may be
          malicious without being malignant.
          [1913 Webster]

                Proud tyrants who maliciously destroy
                And ride o'er ruins with malignant joy.
                                                  --Somerville.
          [1913 Webster]

                in some connections, malignity seems rather more
                pertinently applied to a radical depravity of
                nature, and malignancy to indications of this
                depravity, in temper and conduct in particular
                instances.                        --Cogan.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>malice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Malice \Mal"ice\, v. t.
   To regard with extreme ill will. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>malice</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>malice
     n 1: feeling a need to see others suffer [syn: {maliciousness}, {spite},
           {spitefulness}, {venom}]
     2: the quality of threatening evil [syn: {malevolence}, {malevolency}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
