<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mandarin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mandarin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mandarin \Man`da*rin"\, n. [Pg. mandarim, from Malay mantr[=i]
   minister of state, prop. a Hind. word, fr. Skr. mantrin a
   counselor, manira a counsel, man to think.]
   1. A Chinese public officer or nobleman; a civil or military
      official in China and Annam.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: A powerful government official or bureaucrat,
      especially one who is pedantic and has a strong sense of
      his own importance and privelege.
      [PJC]

   3. Hence: A member of an influential, powerful or elite
      group, espcially within artistic or intellectual circles;
      -- used especially of elder members who are traditionalist
      or conservative about their specialties.
      [PJC]

   5. The form of the Chinese language spoken by members of the
      Chinese Imperial Court an officials of the empire.
      [PJC]

   6. Any of several closely related dialects of the Chinese
      language spoken by a mojority of the population of China,
      the standard variety of which is spoken in the region
      around Beijing.
      [PJC]

   7. (Bot.) A small flattish reddish-orange loose-skinned
      orange, with an easily separable rind. It is thought to be
      of Chinese origin, and is counted a distinct species
      ({Citrus reticulata} formerly {Citrus nobilis}); called
      also {mandarin orange} and {tangerine}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Mandarin language}, the spoken or colloquial language of
      educated people in China.

   {Mandarin yellow} (Chem.), an artificial aniline dyestuff
      used for coloring silk and wool, and regarded as a complex
      derivative of quinoline.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mandarin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mandarin
     n 1: shrub or small tree having flattened globose fruit with very
          sweet aromatic pulp and thin yellow-orange to
          flame-orange rind that is loose and easily removed;
          native to southeastern Asia [syn: {mandarin orange}, {mandarin
          orange tree}, {Citrus reticulata}]
     2: a member of an elite intellectual or cultural group
     3: any high government official or bureaucrat
     4: a high public official of imperial China
     5: a somewhat flat reddish-orange loose-skinned citrus of China
        [syn: {mandarin orange}]
     6: the dialect of Chinese spoken in Beijing and adopted as the
        official language for all of China [syn: {Mandarin Chinese},
         {Mandarin dialect}, {Beijing dialect}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
