<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>manner</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>manner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Manner \Man"ner\, n. [OE. manere, F. mani[`e]re, from OF.
   manier, adj., manual, skillful, handy, fr. (assumed) LL.
   manarius, for L. manuarius belonging to the hand, fr. manus
   the hand. See {Manual}.]
   1. Mode of action; way of performing or effecting anything;
      method; style; form; fashion.
      [1913 Webster]

            The nations which thou hast removed, and placed in
            the cities of Samaria, know not the manner of the
            God of the land.                      --2 Kings
                                                  xvii. 26.
      [1913 Webster]

            The temptations of prosperity insinuate themselves
            after a gentle, but very powerful, manner.
                                                  --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Characteristic mode of acting, conducting, carrying one's
      self, or the like; bearing; habitual style.
      [1913 Webster] Specifically:
      (a) Customary method of acting; habit.
          [1913 Webster]

                Paul, as his manner was, went in unto them.
                                                  --Acts xvii.
                                                  2.
          [1913 Webster]

                Air and manner are more expressive than words.
                                                  --Richardson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) pl. Carriage; behavior; deportment; also, becoming
          behavior; well-bred carriage and address; as, mind
          your manners!.
          [1913 Webster]

                Good manners are made up of petty sacrifices.
                                                  --Emerson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) The style of writing or thought of an author;
          characteristic peculiarity of an artist.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Certain degree or measure; as, it is in a manner done
      already.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bread is in a manner common.      --1 Sam.
                                                  xxi.5.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Sort; kind; style; -- in this application sometimes having
      the sense of a plural, sorts or kinds; as, all manners of
      people came to the rally.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            And they being afraid wondered, saying to one
            another, What manner of man is this! for he
            commandeth even the winds and the water, and they
            obey him.                             --Luke 8: 25.

            Ye tithe mint, and rue, and all manner of herbs.
                                                  --Luke xi. 42.
      [1913 Webster]

            I bid thee say,
            What manner of man art thou?          --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In old usage, of was often omitted after manner, when
         employed in this sense. ``A manner Latin corrupt was
         her speech.'' --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   {By any manner of means}, in any way possible; by any sort of
      means.

   {To be taken in the manner} or {To be taken with the manner}.
      [A corruption of to be taken in the mainor. See {Mainor}.]
      To be taken in the very act. [Obs.] See {Mainor}.

   {To make one's manners}, to make a bow or courtesy; to offer
      salutation.

   {Manners bit}, a portion left in a dish for the sake of good
      manners. --Hallwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Method; mode; custom; habit; fashion; air; look; mien;
        aspect; appearance. See {Method}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>manner</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>manner
     n 1: how something is done or how it happens; "her dignified
          manner"; "his rapid manner of talking"; "their nomadic
          mode of existence"; "in the characteristic New York
          style"; "a lonely way of life"; "in an abrasive fashion"
          [syn: {mode}, {style}, {way}, {fashion}]
     2: a way of acting or behaving [syn: {personal manner}]
     3: a kind; "what manner of man are you?"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
