<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>marble</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marble
   as a mineral, consists of carbonate of lime, its texture varying
   from the highly crystalline to the compact. In Esther 1:6 there
   are four Hebrew words which are rendered marble:, (1.) Shesh,
   "pillars of marble." But this word probably designates dark-blue
   limestone rather than marble. (2.) Dar, some regard as Parian
   marble. It is here rendered "white marble." But nothing is
   certainly known of it. (3.) Bahat, "red marble," probably the
   verd-antique or half-porphyry of Egypt. (4.) Sohareth, "black
   marble," probably some spotted variety of marble. "The marble
   pillars and tesserae of various colours of the palace at Susa
   came doubtless from Persia itself, where marble of various
   colours is found, especially in the province of Hamadan
   Susiana." The marble of Solomon's architectural works may have
   been limestone from near Jerusalem, or from Lebanon, or possibly
   white marble from Arabia. Herod employed Parian marble in the
   temple, and marble columns still exist in great abundance at
   Jerusalem.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marble, CO (town, FIPS 48555)
  Location: 39.07143 N, 107.18843 W
  Population (1990): 64 (70 housing units)
  Area: 0.8 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 81623
Marble, MN (city, FIPS 40418)
  Location: 47.32858 N, 93.29341 W
  Population (1990): 618 (287 housing units)
  Area: 11.2 sq km (land), 0.3 sq km (water)
Marble, NC
  Zip code(s): 28905
Marble, PA
  Zip code(s): 16334
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marble \Mar"ble\ (m[aum]r"b'l), n. [OE. marbel, marbre, F.
   marbre, L. marmor, fr. Gr. ma`rmaros, fr. marmai`rein to
   sparkle, flash. Cf. {Marmoreal}.]
   1. A massive, compact limestone; a variety of calcite,
      capable of being polished and used for architectural and
      ornamental purposes. The color varies from white to black,
      being sometimes yellow, red, and green, and frequently
      beautifully veined or clouded. The name is also given to
      other rocks of like use and appearance, as serpentine or
      verd antique marble, and less properly to polished
      porphyry, granite, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note:

   {Breccia marble} consists of limestone fragments cemented
      together.

   {Ruin marble}, when polished, shows forms resembling ruins,
      due to disseminated iron oxide.

   {Shell marble} contains fossil shells.

   {Statuary marble} is a pure, white, fine-grained kind,
      including Parian (from Paros) and Carrara marble. If
      coarsely granular it is called saccharoidal.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A thing made of, or resembling, marble, as a work of art,
      or record, in marble; or, in the plural, a collection of
      such works; as, the Arundel or Arundelian marbles; the
      Elgin marbles.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A little ball of glass, marble, porcelain, or of some
      other hard substance, used as a plaything by children; or,
      in the plural, a child's game played with marbles.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Marble is also much used in self-explaining compounds;
         when used figuratively in compounds it commonly means,
         hard, cold, destitute of compassion or feeling; as,
         marble-breasted, marble-faced, marble-hearted.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marble \Mar"ble\, a.
   1. Made of, or resembling, marble; as, a marble mantel;
      marble paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Cold; hard; unfeeling; as, a marble breast or heart.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marble \Mar"ble\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Marbled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Marbling}.] [Cf. F. marbrer. See {Marble}, n.]
   To stain or vein like marble; to variegate in color; as, to
   marble the edges of a book, or the surface of paper.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>marble
     n 1: a hard crystalline metamorphic rock that takes a high
          polish; used for sculpture and as building material
     2: a small ball of glass that is used in various games
     3: a sculpture carved from marble
     v : paint or stain like marble; "marble paper"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
