<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>margin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>margin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Margin \Mar"gin\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Margined}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Marginging}.]
   1. To furnish with a margin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To enter in the margin of a page.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>margin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Margin \Mar"gin\, n. [OE. margine, margent, L. margo, ginis. Cf.
   {March} a border, {Marge}.]
   1. A border; edge; brink; verge; as, the margin of a river or
      lake.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically: The part of a page at the edge left
      uncovered in writing or printing.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Com.) The difference between the cost and the selling
      price of an article.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Something allowed, or reserved, for that which can not be
      foreseen or known with certainty.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Brokerage) Collateral security deposited with a broker to
      secure him from loss on contracts entered into by him on
      behalf of his principial, as in the speculative buying and
      selling of stocks, wheat, etc. It is usually less than the
      full value of the security purchased, in which case it may
      be qualified by the portion of the full value required to
      be deposited; as, to buy stocks on 50% margin. --N.
      Biddle.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Margin draft} (Masonry), a smooth cut margin on the face of
      hammer-dressed ashlar, adjacent to the joints.

   {Margin of a course} (Arch.), that part of a course, as of
      slates or shingles, which is not covered by the course
      immediately above it. See 2d {Gauge}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Border; brink; verge; brim; rim.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>margin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>margin
     n 1: the boundary line or the area immediately inside the
          boundary [syn: {border}, {perimeter}]
     2: a permissible difference; allowing some freedom to move
        within limits [syn: {allowance}, {leeway}, {tolerance}]
     3: the amount of collateral a customer deposits with a broker
        when borrowing from the broker to buy securities [syn: {security
        deposit}]
     4: (finance) the net sales minus the cost of goods and services
        sold [syn: {gross profit}, {gross profit margin}]
     5: the blank space that surrounds the text on a page
     6: a strip near the boundary of an object; "he jotted a note on
        the margin of the page" [syn: {edge}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
