<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>marking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marking \Mark"ing\, n.
   The act of one who, or that which, marks; the mark or marks
   made; arrangement or disposition of marks or coloring; as,
   the marking of a bird's plumage.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Marking ink}, indelible ink, because used in marking linen.
      

   {Marking nut} (Bot.), the nut of the {Semecarpus Anacardium},
      an East Indian tree. The shell of the nut yields a
      blackish resinous juice used for marking cotton cloth, and
      an oil prepared from it is used for rheumatism.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark \Mark\ (m[aum]rk), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Marked}
   (m[aum]rkt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Marking}.] [OE. marken, merken,
   AS. mearcian, from mearc. See {Mark} the sign.]
   1. To put a mark upon; to affix a significant mark to; to
      make recognizable by a mark; as, to mark a box or bale of
      merchandise; to mark clothing.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be a mark upon; to designate; to indicate; -- used
      literally and figuratively; as, this monument marks the
      spot where Wolfe died; his courage and energy marked him
      for a leader.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To leave a trace, scratch, scar, or other mark, upon, or
      any evidence of action; as, a pencil marks paper; his
      hobnails marked the floor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To keep account of; to enumerate and register; as, to mark
      the points in a game of billiards or cards.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To notice or observe; to give attention to; to take note
      of; to remark; to heed; to regard; as, mark my words.
      ``Mark the perfect man.'' --Ps. xxxvii. 37.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To mark out}.
      (a) To designate, as by a mark; to select; as, the
          ringleaders were marked out for punishment.
      (b) To obliterate or cancel with a mark; as, to mark out
          an item in an account.

   {To mark time} (Mil.), to keep the time of a marching step by
      moving the legs alternately without advancing.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To note; remark; notice; observe; regard; heed; show;
        evince; indicate; point out; betoken; denote;
        characterize; stamp; imprint; impress; brand.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>marking
     n 1: a distinguishing symbol; "the owner's mark was on all the
          sheep" [syn: {marker}, {mark}]
     2: a pattern of marks
     3: evaluation of performance by assigning a grade or score;
        "what he disliked about teaching was all the grading he
        had to do" [syn: {grading}, {scoring}]
     4: the act of making a visible mark on a surface
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
