<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mark</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark
   the evangelist; "John whose surname was Mark" (Acts 12:12, 25).
   Mark (Marcus, Col. 4:10, etc.) was his Roman name, which
   gradually came to supersede his Jewish name John. He is called
   John in Acts 13:5, 13, and Mark in 15:39, 2 Tim. 4:11, etc.
   
     He was the son of Mary, a woman apparently of some means and
   influence, and was probably born in Jerusalem, where his mother
   resided (Acts 12:12). Of his father we know nothing. He was
   cousin of Barnabas (Col. 4:10). It was in his mother's house
   that Peter found "many gathered together praying" when he was
   released from prison; and it is probable that it was here that
   he was converted by Peter, who calls him his "son" (1 Pet.
   5:13). It is probable that the "young man" spoken of in Mark
   14:51, 52 was Mark himself. He is first mentioned in Acts 12:25.
   He went with Paul and Barnabas on their first journey (about
   A.D. 47) as their "minister," but from some cause turned back
   when they reached Perga in Pamphylia (Acts 12:25; 13:13). Three
   years afterwards a "sharp contention" arose between Paul and
   Barnabas (15:36-40), because Paul would not take Mark with him.
   He, however, was evidently at length reconciled to the apostle,
   for he was with him in his first imprisonment at Rome (Col.
   4:10; Philemon 1:24). At a later period he was with Peter in
   Babylon (1 Pet. 5:13), then, and for some centuries afterwards,
   one of the chief seats of Jewish learning; and he was with
   Timothy in Ephesus when Paul wrote him during his second
   imprisonment (2 Tim. 4:11). He then disappears from view.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark, IL (village, FIPS 46981)
  Location: 41.26416 N, 89.24839 W
  Population (1990): 391 (171 housing units)
  Area: 1.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark \Mark\, v. i.
   To take particular notice; to observe critically; to note; to
   remark.
   [1913 Webster]

         Mark, I pray you, and see how this man seeketh
         mischief.                                --1 Kings xx.
                                                  7.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marc \Marc\, n. [AS. marc; akin to G. mark, Icel. m["o]rk, perh.
   akin to E. mark a sign. [root]106, 273.] [Written also
   {mark}.]
   1. A weight of various commodities, esp. of gold and silver,
      used in different European countries. In France and
      Holland it was equal to eight ounces.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A coin formerly current in England and Scotland, equal to
      thirteen shillings and four pence.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A German coin and money of account. See {Mark}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark \Mark\, n. [OE. marke, merke, AS. mearc; akin to D. merk,
   MHG. marc, G. marke, Icel. mark, Dan. m[ae]rke; cf. Lith.
   margas party-colored. [root]106, 273. Cf. {Remark}.]
   1. A visible sign or impression made or left upon anything;
      esp., a line, point, stamp, figure, or the like, drawn or
      impressed, so as to attract the attention and convey some
      information or intimation; a token; a trace.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord set a mark upon Cain, lest any finding him
            should kill him.                      --Gen. iv. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically:
      (a) A character or device put on an article of merchandise
          by the maker to show by whom it was made; a
          trade-mark.
      (b) A character (usually a cross) made as a substitute for
          a signature by one who can not write.
          [1913 Webster]

                The mark of the artisan is found upon the most
                ancient fabrics that have come to light.
                                                  --Knight.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. A fixed object serving for guidance, as of a ship, a
      traveler, a surveyor, etc.; as, a seamark, a landmark.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A trace, dot, line, imprint, or discoloration, although
      not regarded as a token or sign; a scratch, scar, stain,
      etc.; as, this pencil makes a fine mark.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have some marks of yours upon my pate. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An evidence of presence, agency, or influence; a
      significative token; a symptom; a trace; specifically, a
      permanent impression of one's activity or character.
      [1913 Webster]

            The confusion of tongues was a mark of separation.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That toward which a missile is directed; a thing aimed at;
      what one seeks to hit or reach.
      [1913 Webster]

            France was a fairer mark to shoot at than Ireland.
                                                  --Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whate'er the motive, pleasure is the mark. --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Attention, regard, or respect.
      [1913 Webster]

            As much in mock as mark.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Limit or standard of action or fact; as, to be within the
      mark; to come up to the mark.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Badge or sign of honor, rank, or official station.
      [1913 Webster]

            In the official marks invested, you
            Anon do meet the Senate.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Pre["e]minence; high position; as, patricians of mark; a
       fellow of no mark.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Logic) A characteristic or essential attribute; a
       differential.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A number or other character used in registering; as,
       examination marks; a mark for tardiness.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Image; likeness; hence, those formed in one's image;
       children; descendants. [Obs.] ``All the mark of Adam.''
       --Chaucer.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Naut.) One of the bits of leather or colored bunting
       which are placed upon a sounding line at intervals of
       from two to five fathoms. The unmarked fathoms are called
       ``deeps.''
       [1913 Webster]

   {A man of mark}, a conspicuous or eminent man.

   {To make one's mark}. (a) To sign, as a letter or other
      writing, by making a cross or other mark.
       (b) To make a distinct or lasting impression on the
           public mind, or on affairs; to gain distinction.
           [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Impress; impression; stamp; print; trace; vestige;
        track; characteristic; evidence; proof; token; badge;
        indication; symptom.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark \Mark\ (m[aum]rk), n.
   A license of reprisals. See {Marque}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark \Mark\, n. [See 2d {Marc}.]
   1. An old weight and coin. See {Marc}. ``Lend me a mark.''
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The unit of monetary account of the German Empire, equal
      to 23.8 cents of United States money (1913); the
      equivalent of one hundred pfennigs. Also, a silver coin of
      this value. The unit was retained by subsequent German
      states up to the time of the Federal Republic of Germany.
      In 1995, the value was approximately 65 cents American. In
      1999 it began to be superseded by the Euro as a unit of
      currency in Germany and throughout much of the European
      union.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark \Mark\ (m[aum]rk), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Marked}
   (m[aum]rkt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Marking}.] [OE. marken, merken,
   AS. mearcian, from mearc. See {Mark} the sign.]
   1. To put a mark upon; to affix a significant mark to; to
      make recognizable by a mark; as, to mark a box or bale of
      merchandise; to mark clothing.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be a mark upon; to designate; to indicate; -- used
      literally and figuratively; as, this monument marks the
      spot where Wolfe died; his courage and energy marked him
      for a leader.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To leave a trace, scratch, scar, or other mark, upon, or
      any evidence of action; as, a pencil marks paper; his
      hobnails marked the floor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To keep account of; to enumerate and register; as, to mark
      the points in a game of billiards or cards.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To notice or observe; to give attention to; to take note
      of; to remark; to heed; to regard; as, mark my words.
      ``Mark the perfect man.'' --Ps. xxxvii. 37.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To mark out}.
      (a) To designate, as by a mark; to select; as, the
          ringleaders were marked out for punishment.
      (b) To obliterate or cancel with a mark; as, to mark out
          an item in an account.

   {To mark time} (Mil.), to keep the time of a marching step by
      moving the legs alternately without advancing.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To note; remark; notice; observe; regard; heed; show;
        evince; indicate; point out; betoken; denote;
        characterize; stamp; imprint; impress; brand.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mark, same as Marcus

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mark
     n 1: a number or letter indicating quality (especially of a
          student's performance); "she made good marks in
          algebra"; "grade A milk"; "what was your score on your
          homework?" [syn: {grade}, {score}]
     2: a distinguishing symbol; "the owner's mark was on all the
        sheep" [syn: {marker}, {marking}]
     3: a reference point to shoot at; "his arrow hit the mark"
        [syn: {target}]
     4: a visible indication made on a surface; "some previous
        reader had covered the pages with dozens of marks"; "paw
        prints were everywhere" [syn: {print}]
     5: the impression created by doing something unusual or
        extraordinary that people notice and remember; "it was in
        London that he made his mark"; "he left an indelible mark
        on the American theater"
     6: a symbol of disgrace or infamy; "And the Lord set a mark
        upon Cain"--Genesis [syn: {stigma}, {brand}, {stain}]
     7: formerly the basic unit of money in Germany [syn: {German
        mark}, {Deutsche Mark}, {Deutschmark}]
     8: Apostle and companion of Saint Peter; assumed to be the
        author of the second Gospel [syn: {Saint Mark}, {St. Mark}]
     9: a person who is gullible and easy to take advantage of [syn:
         {chump}, {fool}, {gull}, {patsy}, {fall guy}, {sucker}, {soft
        touch}, {mug}]
     10: a written or printed symbol (as for punctuation); "his
         answer was just a punctuation mark"
     11: a perceptible indication of something not immediately
         apparent (as a visible clue that something has happened);
         "he showed signs of strain"; "they welcomed the signs of
         spring" [syn: {sign}]
     12: the shortest of the four Gospels in the New Testament [syn:
         {Gospel According to Mark}]
     13: an indication of damage [syn: {scratch}, {scrape}, {scar}]
     14: marking consisting of crossing lines [syn: {crisscross}, {cross}]
     15: something that exactly succeeds in achieving its goal; "the
         new advertising campaign was a bell ringer"; "scored a
         bull's eye"; "hit the mark"; "the president's speech was
         a home run" [syn: {bell ringer}, {bull's eye}, {home run}]
     v 1: attach a tag or label to; "label these bottles" [syn: {tag},
           {label}]
     2: designate as if by a mark; "This sign marks the border"; "He
        indicated where the border ended"
     3: be a distinctive feature, attribute, or trait; sometimes in
        a very positive sense; "His modesty distinguishes him form
        his peers" [syn: {distinguish}, {differentiate}]
     4: mark by some ceremony or observation; "We marked the
        anniversary of his death" [syn: {commemorate}]
     5: make or leave a mark on; "mark the trail so that we can find
        our way back"
     6: to accuse or condemn or openly or formally or brand as
        disgraceful; "He denounced the government action"; "She
        was stigmatized by society because she had a child out of
        wedlock" [syn: {stigmatize}, {stigmatise}, {brand}, {denounce}]
     7: notice or perceive; "She noted that someone was following
        her"; "mark my words" [syn: {notice}, {note}] [ant: {ignore}]
     8: mark with a scar; "The skin disease scarred his face
        permanently" [syn: {scar}, {pock}, {pit}]
     9: make small marks into the surface of; "score the clay before
        firing it" [syn: {score}, {nock}]
     10: establish as the highest level or best performance; "set a
         record" [syn: {set}]
     11: make underscoring marks [syn: {score}]
     12: remove from a list; "Cross the name of the dead person off
         the list" [syn: {cross off}, {cross out}, {strike out}, {strike
         off}]
     13: put a check mark on or next to; "Please check each name on
         the list"; "tick off the items" [syn: {check}, {check off},
          {mark off}, {tick off}, {tick}]
     14: assign a grade or rank to, according to one's evaluation;
         "grade tests"; "score the SAT essays"; "mark homework"
         [syn: {grade}, {score}]
     15: insert punctuation marks into [syn: {punctuate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
