<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>marriage</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marriage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MARRIAGE, n.  The state or condition of a community consisting of a
master, a mistress and two slaves, making in all, two.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marriage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marriage
   was instituted in Paradise when man was in innocence (Gen.
   2:18-24). Here we have its original charter, which was confirmed
   by our Lord, as the basis on which all regulations are to be
   framed (Matt. 19:4, 5). It is evident that monogamy was the
   original law of marriage (Matt. 19:5; 1 Cor. 6:16). This law was
   violated in after times, when corrupt usages began to be
   introduced (Gen. 4:19; 6:2). We meet with the prevalence of
   polygamy and concubinage in the patriarchal age (Gen. 16:1-4;
   22:21-24; 28:8, 9; 29:23-30, etc.). Polygamy was acknowledged in
   the Mosaic law and made the basis of legislation, and continued
   to be practised all down through the period of Jewish histroy to
   the Captivity, after which there is no instance of it on record.
   
     It seems to have been the practice from the beginning for
   fathers to select wives for their sons (Gen. 24:3; 38:6).
   Sometimes also proposals were initiated by the father of the
   maiden (Ex. 2:21). The brothers of the maiden were also
   sometimes consulted (Gen. 24:51; 34:11), but her own consent was
   not required. The young man was bound to give a price to the
   father of the maiden (31:15; 34:12; Ex. 22:16, 17; 1 Sam. 18:23,
   25; Ruth 4:10; Hos. 3:2) On these patriarchal customs the Mosaic
   law made no change.
   
     In the pre-Mosaic times, when the proposals were accepted and
   the marriage price given, the bridegroom could come at once and
   take away his bride to his own house (Gen. 24:63-67). But in
   general the marriage was celebrated by a feast in the house of
   the bride's parents, to which all friends were invited (29:22,
   27); and on the day of the marriage the bride, concealed under a
   thick veil, was conducted to her future husband's home.
   
     Our Lord corrected many false notions then existing on the
   subject of marriage (Matt. 22:23-30), and placed it as a divine
   institution on the highest grounds. The apostles state clearly
   and enforce the nuptial duties of husband and wife (Eph.
   5:22-33; Col. 3:18, 19; 1 Pet. 3:1-7). Marriage is said to be
   "honourable" (Heb. 13:4), and the prohibition of it is noted as
   one of the marks of degenerate times (1 Tim. 4:3).
   
     The marriage relation is used to represent the union between
   God and his people (Isa. 54:5; Jer. 3:1-14; Hos. 2:9, 20). In
   the New Testament the same figure is employed in representing
   the love of Christ to his saints (Eph. 5:25-27). The Church of
   the redeemed is the "Bride, the Lamb's wife" (Rev. 19:7-9).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marriage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Marriage \Mar"riage\, n. [OE. mariage, F. mariage. See {Marry},
   v. t.]
   1. The act of marrying, or the state of being married; legal
      union of a man and a woman for life, as husband and wife;
      wedlock; matrimony.
      [1913 Webster]

            Marriage is honorable in all.         --Heb. xiii.
                                                  4.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The marriage vow or contract. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A feast made on the occasion of a marriage.
      [1913 Webster]

            The kingdom of heaven is like unto a certain king
            which made a marriage for his son.    --Matt. xxii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any intimate or close union.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. In pinochle, b['e]zique, and similar games at cards, the
      combination of a king and queen of the same suit. If of
      the trump suit, it is called a {royal marriage}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Marriage brokage}.
      (a) The business of bringing about marriages.
      (b) The payment made or demanded for the procurement of a
          marriage.

   {Marriage favors}, knots of white ribbons, or bunches of
      white flowers, worn at weddings.

   {Marriage settlement} (Law), a settlement of property in
      view, and in consideration, of marriage.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Matrimony; wedlock; wedding; nuptials.

   Usage: {Marriage}, {Matrimony}, {Wedlock}. Marriage is
          properly the act which unites the two parties, and
          matrimony the state into which they enter. Marriage
          is, however, often used for the state as well as the
          act. Wedlock is the old Anglo-Saxon term for
          matrimony.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>marriage</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>marriage
     n 1: the state of being a married couple voluntarily joined for
          life (or until divorce); "a long and happy marriage";
          "God bless this union" [syn: {matrimony}, {union}, {spousal
          relationship}, {wedlock}]
     2: two people who are married to each other; "his second
        marriage was happier than the first"; "a married couple
        without love" [syn: {married couple}, {man and wife}]
     3: the act of marrying; the nuptial ceremony; "their marriage
        was conducted in the chapel" [syn: {wedding}, {marriage
        ceremony}]
     4: a close and intimate union; "the marriage of music and
        dance"; "a marriage of ideas"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
