<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>martha</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>martha</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Martha
   bitterness, the sister of Lazarus and Mary, and probably the
   eldest of the family, who all resided at Bethany (Luke 10:38,
   40, 41; John 11:1-39). From the residence being called "her
   house," some have supposed that she was a widow, and that her
   brother and sister lodged with her. She seems to have been of an
   anxious, bustling spirit, anxious to be helpful in providing the
   best things for the Master's use, in contrast to the quiet
   earnestness of Mary, who was more concerned to avail herself of
   the opportunity of sitting at his feet and learning of him.
   Afterwards at a supper given to Christ and his disciples in her
   house "Martha served." Nothing further is known of her.
   
     "Mary and Martha are representatives of two orders of human
   character. One was absorbed, preoccupied, abstracted; the other
   was concentrated and single-hearted. Her own world was the all
   of Martha; Christ was the first thought with Mary. To Martha
   life was 'a succession of particular businesses;' to Mary life
   'was rather the flow of one spirit.' Martha was Petrine, Mary
   was Johannine. The one was a well-meaning, bustling busybody;
   the other was a reverent disciple, a wistful listener." Paul had
   such a picture as that of Martha in his mind when he spoke of
   serving the Lord "without distraction" (1 Cor. 7:35).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>martha</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Martha, KY
  Zip code(s): 41159
Martha, OK (town, FIPS 46700)
  Location: 34.72650 N, 99.38603 W
  Population (1990): 217 (90 housing units)
  Area: 0.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>martha</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Martha, who becomes bitter; provoking

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
