<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mask</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mask</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mask \Mask\ (m[.a]sk), n. [F. masque, LL. masca, mascha, mascus;
   cf. Sp. &amp; Pg. m['a]scara, It. maschera; all fr. Ar. maskharat
   buffoon, fool, pleasantry, anything ridiculous or mirthful,
   fr. sakhira to ridicule, to laugh at. Cf. {Masque},
   {Masquerade}.]
   1. A cover, or partial cover, for the face, used for disguise
      or protection; as, a dancer's mask; a fencer's mask; a
      ball player's mask.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which disguises; a pretext or subterfuge.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A festive entertainment of dancing or other diversions,
      where all wear masks; a masquerade; hence, a revel; a
      frolic; a delusive show. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            This thought might lead me through the world's vain
            mask.                                 --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A dramatic performance, formerly in vogue, in which the
      actors wore masks and represented mythical or allegorical
      characters.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Arch.) A grotesque head or face, used to adorn keystones
      and other prominent parts, to spout water in fountains,
      and the like; -- called also {mascaron}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Fort.)
      (a) In a permanent fortification, a redoubt which protects
          the caponiere.
      (b) A screen for a battery.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. (Zo["o]l.) The lower lip of the larva of a dragon fly,
      modified so as to form a prehensile organ.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A person wearing a mask; a masker.

            The mask that has the arm of the Indian queen. --G.
                                                  W. Cable.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Sporting) The head or face of a fox.

   {Mask house}, a house for masquerades. [Obs.]

   {Death mask}, a cast of the face of a dead person.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mask</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mask \Mask\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Masked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Masking}.]
   1. To cover, as the face, by way of concealment or defense
      against injury; to conceal with a mask or visor.
      [1913 Webster]

            They must all be masked and vizarded. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To disguise; to cover; to hide.
      [1913 Webster]

            Masking the business from the common eye. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil.)
      (a) To conceal; also, to intervene in the line of.
      (b) To cover or keep in check; as, to mask a body of
          troops or a fortress by a superior force, while some
          hostile evolution is being carried out.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mask</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mask \Mask\, v. i.
   1. To take part as a masker in a masquerade. --Cavendish.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To wear a mask; to be disguised in any way. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mask</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mask
     n 1: a covering to disguise or conceal the face
     2: activity that tries to conceal something; "no mask could
        conceal his ignorance"; "they moved in under a mask of
        friendship"
     3: a party of guests wearing costumes and masks [syn: {masquerade},
         {masque}]
     4: a protective covering worn over the face
     v 1: hide under a false appearance; "He masked his
          disappointment" [syn: {dissemble}, {cloak}]
     2: put a mask on or cover with a mask; "Mask the children for
        Halloween" [ant: {unmask}]
     3: cover with a sauce; "mask the meat"
     4: shield from light [syn: {block out}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
