<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>master</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>master</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>master
     
        {botmaster}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>master</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Master \Mast"er\, n. (Naut.)
   A vessel having (so many) masts; -- used only in compounds;
   as, a two-master.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>master</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Master \Mas"ter\ (m[.a]s"t[~e]r), n. [OE. maistre, maister, OF.
   maistre, mestre, F. ma[^i]tre, fr. L. magister, orig. a
   double comparative from the root of magnus great, akin to Gr.
   me`gas. Cf. {Maestro}, {Magister}, {Magistrate}, {Magnitude},
   {Major}, {Mister}, {Mistress}, {Mickle}.]
   1. A male person having another living being so far subject
      to his will, that he can, in the main, control his or its
      actions; -- formerly used with much more extensive
      application than now.
      (a) The employer of a servant.
      (b) The owner of a slave.
      (c) The person to whom an apprentice is articled.
      (d) A sovereign, prince, or feudal noble; a chief, or one
          exercising similar authority.
      (e) The head of a household.
      (f) The male head of a school or college.
      (g) A male teacher.
      (h) The director of a number of persons performing a
          ceremony or sharing a feast.
      (i) The owner of a docile brute, -- especially a dog or
          horse.
      (j) The controller of a familiar spirit or other
          supernatural being.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. One who uses, or controls at will, anything inanimate; as,
      to be master of one's time. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Master of a hundred thousand drachms. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are masters of the sea.            --Jowett
                                                  (Thucyd.).
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who has attained great skill in the use or application
      of anything; as, a master of oratorical art.
      [1913 Webster]

            Great masters of ridicule.            --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            No care is taken to improve young men in their own
            language, that they may thoroughly understand and be
            masters of it.                        --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A title given by courtesy, now commonly pronounced
      m[i^]ster, except when given to boys; -- sometimes written
      {Mister}, but usually abbreviated to Mr.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A young gentleman; a lad, or small boy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where there are little masters and misses in a
            house, they are impediments to the diversions of the
            servants.                             --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) The commander of a merchant vessel; -- usually
      called {captain}. Also, a commissioned officer in the navy
      ranking next above ensign and below lieutenant; formerly,
      an officer on a man-of-war who had immediate charge, under
      the commander, of sailing the vessel.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A person holding an office of authority among the
      Freemasons, esp. the presiding officer; also, a person
      holding a similar office in other civic societies.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Little masters}, certain German engravers of the 16th
      century, so called from the extreme smallness of their
      prints.

   {Master in chancery}, an officer of courts of equity, who
      acts as an assistant to the chancellor or judge, by
      inquiring into various matters referred to him, and
      reporting thereon to the court.

   {Master of arts}, one who takes the second degree at a
      university; also, the degree or title itself, indicated by
      the abbreviation M. A., or A. M.

   {Master of the horse}, the third great officer in the British
      court, having the management of the royal stables, etc. In
      ceremonial cavalcades he rides next to the sovereign.

   {Master of the rolls}, in England, an officer who has charge
      of the rolls and patents that pass the great seal, and of
      the records of the chancery, and acts as assistant judge
      of the court. --Bouvier. --Wharton.

   {Past master},
      (a) one who has held the office of master in a lodge of
          Freemasons or in a society similarly organized.
      (b) a person who is unusually expert, skilled, or
          experienced in some art, technique, or profession; --
          usually used with at or of.

   {The old masters}, distinguished painters who preceded modern
      painters; especially, the celebrated painters of the 16th
      and 17th centuries.

   {To be master of one's self}, to have entire self-control;
      not to be governed by passion.

   {To be one's own master}, to be at liberty to act as one
      chooses without dictation from anybody.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Master, signifying chief, principal, masterly,
         superior, thoroughly skilled, etc., is often used
         adjectively or in compounds; as, master builder or
         master-builder, master chord or master-chord, master
         mason or master-mason, master workman or
         master-workman, master mechanic, master mind, master
         spirit, master passion, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

               Throughout the city by the master gate.
                                                  --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Master joint} (Geol.), a quarryman's term for the more
      prominent and extended joints traversing a rock mass.

   {Master key}, a key adapted to open several locks differing
      somewhat from each other; figuratively, a rule or
      principle of general application in solving difficulties.
      

   {Master lode} (Mining), the principal vein of ore.

   {Master mariner}, an experienced and skilled seaman who is
      certified to be competent to command a merchant vessel.

   {Master sinew} (Far.), a large sinew that surrounds the hough
      of a horse, and divides it from the bone by a hollow
      place, where the windgalls are usually seated.

   {Master singer}. See {Mastersinger}.

   {Master stroke}, a capital performance; a masterly
      achievement; a consummate action; as, a master stroke of
      policy.

   {Master tap} (Mech.), a tap for forming the thread in a screw
      cutting die.

   {Master touch}.
      (a) The touch or skill of a master. --Pope.
      (b) Some part of a performance which exhibits very
          skillful work or treatment. ``Some master touches of
          this admirable piece.'' --Tatler.

   {Master work}, the most important work accomplished by a
      skilled person, as in architecture, literature, etc.;
      also, a work which shows the skill of a master; a
      masterpiece.

   {Master workman}, a man specially skilled in any art,
      handicraft, or trade, or who is an overseer, foreman, or
      employer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>master</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Master \Mas"ter\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Mastered}; p. pr. vb. n.
   {Mastering}.]
   1. To become the master of; to subject to one's will,
      control, or authority; to conquer; to overpower; to
      subdue.
      [1913 Webster]

            Obstinacy and willful neglects must be mastered,
            even though it cost blows.            --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To gain the command of, so as to understand or apply; to
      become an adept in; as, to master a science.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To own; to posses. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The wealth
            That the world masters.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>master</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Master \Mas"ter\, v. i.
   To be skillful; to excel. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>master</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>master
     n 1: an artist of consummate skill; "a master of the violin";
          "one of the old masters" [syn: {maestro}]
     2: a person who has general authority over others [syn: {overlord},
         {lord}]
     3: a combatant who is able to defeat rivals [syn: {victor}, {superior}]
     4: directs the work of other
     5: presiding officer of a school [syn: {headmaster}, {schoolmaster}]
     6: an original creation (i.e., an audio recording) from which
        copies can be made [syn: {master copy}, {original}]
     7: an officer who is licensed to command a merchant ship [syn:
        {captain}, {sea captain}, {skipper}]
     8: someone who holds a master's degree from academic
        institution
     9: an authority qualified to teach apprentices [syn: {professional}]
     10: key that secures entrance everywhere [syn: {passkey}, {passe-partout},
          {master key}]
     v 1: be or become completely proficient or skilled in; "She
          mastered Japanese in less than two years" [syn: {get the
          hang}]
     2: get on top of; deal with successfully; "He overcame his
        shyness" [syn: {overcome}, {get over}, {subdue}, {surmount}]
     3: have dominance or the power to defeat over; "Her pain
        completely mastered her"; "The methods can master the
        problems" [syn: {dominate}]
     4: have a firm understanding or knowledge of; be on top of; "Do
        you control these data?" [syn: {control}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
