<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>match</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>match</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Match \Match\ (m[a^]ch), n. [OE. macche, F. m[`e]che, F.
   m[`e]che, fr. L. myxa a lamp nozzle, Gr. my`xa mucus,
   nostril, a lamp nozzle. Cf. {Mucus}.]
   Anything used for catching and retaining or communicating
   fire, made of some substance which takes fire readily, or
   remains burning some time; esp., a small strip or splint of
   wood or cardboard dipped at one end in a substance which can
   be easily ignited by friction, as a preparation of phosphorus
   or chlorate of potassium.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Match tub}, a tub with a perforated cover for holding slow
      matches for firing cannon, esp. on board ship. The tub
      contains a little water in the bottom, for extinguishing
      sparks from the lighted matches.

   {Quick match}, threads of cotton or cotton wick soaked in a
      solution of gunpowder mixed with gum arabic and boiling
      water and afterwards strewed over with mealed powder. It
      burns at the rate of one yard in thirteen seconds, and is
      used as priming for heavy mortars, fireworks, etc.

   {Slow match}, slightly twisted hempen rope soaked in a
      solution of limewater and saltpeter or washed in a lye of
      water and wood ashes. It burns at the rate of four or five
      inches an hour, and is used for firing cannon, fireworks,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>match</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Match \Match\, n. [OE. macche, AS. gem[ae]cca; akin to gemaca,
   and to OS. gimako, OHG. gimah fitting, suitable, convenient,
   Icel. mark suitable, maki mate, Sw. make, Dan. mage; all from
   the root of E. make, v. See {Make} mate, and {Make}, v., and
   cf. {Mate} an associate.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A person or thing equal or similar to another; one able to
      mate or cope with another; an equal; a mate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Government . . . makes an innocent man, though of
            the lowest rank, a match for the mightiest of his
            fellow subjects.                      --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A bringing together of two parties suited to one another,
      as for a union, a trial of skill or force, a contest, or
      the like; specifically:
      (a) A contest to try strength or skill, or to determine
          superiority; a sporting contest; an emulous struggle.
          ``Many a warlike match.'' --Drayton.
          [1913 Webster]

                A solemn match was made; he lost the prize.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A matrimonial union; a marriage.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. An agreement, compact, etc. ``Thy hand upon that match.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Love doth seldom suffer itself to be confined by
            other matches than those of its own making. --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A candidate for matrimony; one to be gained in marriage.
      ``She . . . was looked upon as the richest match of the
      West.'' --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Equality of conditions in contest or competition, or one
      who provides equal competition to another in a contest;
      as, he had no match as a swordsman within the city.
      [1913 Webster]

            It were no match, your nail against his horn.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Suitable combination or bringing together; that which
      corresponds or harmonizes with something else; as, the
      carpet and curtains are a match.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Founding) A perforated board, block of plaster, hardened
      sand, etc., in which a pattern is partly imbedded when a
      mold is made, for giving shape to the surfaces of
      separation between the parts of the mold.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Match boarding} (Carp.), boards fitted together with tongue
      and groove, or prepared to be so fitted; a surface
      composed of match boarding. See {matchboard}.

   {Match game}, a game arranged as a test of superiority.

   {Match plane} (Carp.), either of the two planes used to shape
      the edges of boards which are joined by grooving and
      tonguing.

   {Match plate} (Founding), a board or plate on the opposite
      sides of which the halves of a pattern are fastened, to
      facilitate molding. --Knight.

   {Match wheel} (Mach.), a cogwheel of suitable pitch to work
      with another wheel; specifically, one of a pair of
      cogwheels of equal size.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>match</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Match \Match\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Matched}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Matching}.]
   1. To be a mate or match for; to be able to complete with; to
      rival successfully; to equal.
      [1913 Webster]

            No settled senses of the world can match
            The pleasure of that madness.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To furnish with its match; to bring a match, or equal,
      against; to show an equal competitor to; to set something
      in competition with, or in opposition to, as equal.
      [1913 Webster]

            No history or antiquity can matchis policies and his
            conduct.                              --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To oppose as equal; to contend successfully against.
      [1913 Webster]

            Eternal might
            To match with their inventions they presumed
            So easy, and of his thunder made a scorn. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make or procure the equal of, or that which is exactly
      similar to, or corresponds with; as, to match a vase or a
      horse; to match cloth. ``Matching of patterns and
      colors.'' --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To make equal, proportionate, or suitable; to adapt, fit,
      or suit (one thing to another).
      [1913 Webster]

            Let poets match their subject to their strength.
                                                  --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To marry; to give in marriage.
      [1913 Webster]

            A senator of Rome survived,
            Would not have matched his daughter with a king.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To fit together, or make suitable for fitting together;
      specifically, to furnish with a tongue and a groove, at
      the edges; as, to match boards.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Matching machine}, a planing machine for forming a tongue or
      a groove on the edge of a board.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>match</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Match \Match\, v. i.
   1. To be united in marriage; to mate.
      [1913 Webster]

            I hold it a sin to match in my kindred. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let tigers match with hinds, and wolves with sheep.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be of equal, or similar, size, figure, color, or
      quality; to tally; to suit; to correspond; as, these vases
      match.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>match</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Consolation game \Con`so*la"tion game\, match \match\, pot
\pot\, race \race\, etc.
   A game, match, etc., open only to losers in early stages of
   contests.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>match</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>match
     n 1: lighter consisting of a thin piece of wood or cardboard
          tipped with combustible chemical; ignites with friction;
          "he always carries matches to light his pipe" [syn: {lucifer},
           {friction match}]
     2: a formal contest in which two or more persons or teams
        compete
     3: a burning piece of wood or cardboard; "if you drop a match
        in there the whole place will explode"
     4: an exact duplicate; "when a match is found an entry is made
        in the notebook" [syn: {mate}]
     5: the score needed to win a match
     6: a person regarded as a good matrimonial prospect [syn: {catch}]
     7: a person who is of equal standing with another in a group
        [syn: {peer}, {equal}, {compeer}]
     8: a pair of people who live together; "a married couple from
        Chicago" [syn: {couple}, {mates}]
     9: something that resembles or harmonizes with; "that tie makes
        a good match with your jacket"
     v 1: be compatible, similar or consistent; coincide in their
          characteristics; "The two stories don't agree in many
          details"; "The handwriting checks with the signature on
          the check"; "The suspect's fingerprints don't match
          those on the gun" [syn: {fit}, {correspond}, {check}, {jibe},
           {gibe}, {tally}, {agree}] [ant: {disagree}]
     2: provide funds complementary to; "The company matched the
        employees' contributions"
     3: bring two objects, ideas, or people together; "This fact is
        coupled to the other one"; "Matchmaker, can you match my
        daughter with a nice young man?"; "The student was paired
        with a partner for collaboration on the project" [syn: {mate},
         {couple}, {pair}, {twin}]
     4: be equal to in quality or ability; "Nothing can rival cotton
        for durability"; "Your performance doesn't even touch that
        of your colleagues"; "Her persistence and ambition only
        matches that of her parents" [syn: {equal}, {touch}, {rival}]
     5: make correspond or harmonize; "Match my sweater" [syn: {fit}]
     6: satisfy or fulfill; "meet a need"; "this job doesn't match
        my dreams" [syn: {meet}, {cope with}]
     7: give or join in marriage
     8: set into opposition or rivalry; "let them match their best
        athletes against ours"; "pit a chess player against the
        Russian champion"; "He plays his two children off against
        each other" [syn: {pit}, {oppose}, {play off}]
     9: be equal or harmonize; "The two pieces match"
     10: make equal, uniform, corresponding, or matching; "let's
         equalize the duties among all employees in this office";
         "The company matched the discount policy of its
         competitors" [syn: {equal}, {equalize}, {equalise}, {equate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
