<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>matter</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>matter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Matter \Mat"ter\, n. [OE. matere, F. mati[`e]re, fr. L. materia;
   perh. akin to L. mater mother. Cf. {Mother}, {Madeira},
   {Material}.]
   1. That of which anything is composed; constituent substance;
      material; the material or substantial part of anything;
      the constituent elements of conception; that into which a
      notion may be analyzed; the essence; the pith; the
      embodiment.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is the matter of virtue.           --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That of which the sensible universe and all existent
      bodies are composed; anything which has extension,
      occupies space, or is perceptible by the senses; body;
      substance.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Matter is usually divided by philosophical writers into
         three kinds or classes: solid, liquid, and gaseous.
         Solid substances are those whose parts firmly cohere
         and resist impression, as wood or stone. Liquids have
         free motion among their parts, and easily yield to
         impression, as water and wine. Gaseous substances are
         elastic fluids, called vapors and gases, as air and
         oxygen gas.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. That with regard to, or about which, anything takes place
      or is done; the thing aimed at, treated of, or treated;
      subject of action, discussion, consideration, feeling,
      complaint, legal action, or the like; theme. ``If the
      matter should be tried by duel.'' --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Son of God, Savior of men! Thy name
            Shall be the copious matter of my song. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every great matter they shall bring unto thee, but
            every small matter they shall judge.  --Ex. xviii.
                                                  22.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which one has to treat, or with which one has to do;
      concern; affair; business.
      [1913 Webster]

            To help the matter, the alchemists call in many
            vanities out of astrology.            --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some young female seems to have carried matters so
            far, that she is ripe for asking advice.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Affair worthy of account; thing of consequence;
      importance; significance; moment; -- chiefly in the
      phrases what matter? no matter, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            A prophet some, and some a poet, cry;
            No matter which, so neither of them lie. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Inducing cause or occasion, especially of anything
      disagreeable or distressing; difficulty; trouble.
      [1913 Webster]

            And this is the matter why interpreters upon that
            passage in Hosea will not consent it to be a true
            story, that the prophet took a harlot to wife.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Amount; quantity; portion; space; -- often indefinite.
      [1913 Webster]

            Away he goes, . . . a matter of seven miles. --L'
                                                  Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have thoughts to tarry a small matter. --Congreve.
      [1913 Webster]

            No small matter of British forces were commanded
            over sea the year before.             --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Substance excreted from living animal bodies; that which
      is thrown out or discharged in a tumor, boil, or abscess;
      pus; purulent substance.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Metaph.) That which is permanent, or is supposed to be
      given, and in or upon which changes are effected by
      psychological or physical processes and relations; --
      opposed to {form}. --Mansel.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Print.) Written manuscript, or anything to be set in
       type; copy; also, type set up and ready to be used, or
       which has been used, in printing.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Dead matter} (Print.), type which has been used, or which is
      not to be used, in printing, and is ready for
      distribution.

   {Live matter} (Print.), type set up, but not yet printed
      from.

   {Matter in bar}, {Matter of fact}. See under {Bar}, and
      {Fact}.

   {Matter of record}, anything recorded.

   {Upon the matter}, or {Upon the whole matter}, considering
      the whole; taking all things into view; all things
      considered.
      [1913 Webster]

            Waller, with Sir William Balfour, exceeded in horse,
            but were, upon the whole matter, equal in foot.
                                                  --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>matter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Matter \Mat"ter\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Mattered}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Mattering}.]
   1. To be of importance; to import; to signify.
      [1913 Webster]

            It matters not how they were called.  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form pus or matter, as an abscess; to maturate. [R.]
      ``Each slight sore mattereth.'' --Sir P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>matter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Matter \Mat"ter\, v. t.
   To regard as important; to take account of; to care for.
   [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         He did not matter cold nor hunger.       --H. Brooke.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>matter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>matter
     n 1: that which has mass and occupies space; "an atom is the
          smallest indivisible unit of matter" [syn: {substance}]
     2: a vaguely specified concern; "several matters to attend to";
        "it is none of your affair"; "things are going well" [syn:
         {affair}, {thing}]
     3: some situation or event that is thought about; "he kept
        drifting off the topic"; "he had been thinking about the
        subject for several years"; "it is a matter for the
        police" [syn: {topic}, {subject}, {issue}]
     4: a problem; "is anything the matter?"
     5: (used with negation) having consequence; "they were friends
        and it was no matter who won the games"
     6: written works (especially in books or magazines); "he always
        took some reading matter with him on the plane"
     v : have weight; have import, carry weight; "It does not matter
         much" [syn: {count}, {weigh}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
