<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mean</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mean</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mean \Mean\ (m[=e]n), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Meant} (m[e^]nt); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Meaning}.] [OE. menen, AS. m[=ae]nan to recite,
   tell, intend, wish; akin to OS. m[=e]nian to have in mind,
   mean, D. meenen, G. meinen, OHG. meinan, Icel. meina, Sw.
   mena, Dan. mene, and to E. mind. [root]104. See {Mind}, and
   cf. {Moan}.]
   1. To have in the mind, as a purpose, intention, etc.; to
      intend; to purpose; to design; as, what do you mean to do?
      [1913 Webster]

            What mean ye by this service ?        --Ex. xii. 26.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye thought evil against me; but God meant it unto
            good.                                 --Gen. 1. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am not a Spaniard
            To say that it is yours and not to mean it.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To signify; to indicate; to import; to denote.
      [1913 Webster]

            What mean these seven ewe lambs ?     --Gen. xxi.
                                                  29.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go ye, and learn what that meaneth.   --Matt. ix.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mean</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mean \Mean\, v. i.
   To have a purpose or intention. [Rare, except in the phrase
   to mean well, or ill.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mean</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mean \Mean\ (m[=e]n), a. [Compar. {Meaner} (m[=e]n"[~e]r);
   superl. {Meanest}.] [OE. mene, AS. m[=ae]ne wicked; akin to
   m[=a]n, a., wicked, n., wickedness, OS. m[=e]n wickedness,
   OHG. mein, G. meineid perjury, Icel. mein harm, hurt, and
   perh. to AS. gem[=ae]ne common, general, D. gemeen, G.
   gemein, Goth. gam['a]ins, and L. communis. The AS. gem[=ae]ne
   prob. influenced the meaning.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Destitute of distinction or eminence; common; low; vulgar;
      humble. ``Of mean parentage.'' --Sir P. Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mean man boweth down, and the great man humbleth
            himself.                              --Is. ii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Wanting dignity of mind; low-minded; base; destitute of
      honor; spiritless; as, a mean motive.
      [1913 Webster]

            Can you imagine I so mean could prove,
            To save my life by changing of my love ? --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Of little value or account; worthy of little or no regard;
      contemptible; despicable.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Roman legions and great C[ae]sar found
            Our fathers no mean foes.             --J. Philips.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Of poor quality; as, mean fare.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Penurious; stingy; close-fisted; illiberal; as, mean
      hospitality.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Mean is sometimes used in the formation of compounds,
         the sense of which is obvious without explanation; as,
         meanborn, mean-looking, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Base; ignoble; abject; beggarly; wretched; degraded;
        degenerate; vulgar; vile; servile; menial; spiritless;
        groveling; slavish; dishonorable; disgraceful; shameful;
        despicable; contemptible; paltry; sordid. See {Base}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mean</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mean \Mean\, a. [OE. mene, OF. meiien, F. moyen, fr. L. medianus
   that is in the middle, fr. medius; akin to E. mid. See
   {Mid}.]
   1. Occupying a middle position; middle; being about midway
      between extremes.
      [1913 Webster]

            Being of middle age and a mean stature. --Sir. P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Intermediate in excellence of any kind.
      [1913 Webster]

            According to the fittest style of lofty, mean, or
            lowly.                                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Math.) Average; having an intermediate value between two
      extremes, or between the several successive values of a
      variable quantity during one cycle of variation; as, mean
      distance; mean motion; mean solar day.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Mean distance} (of a planet from the sun) (Astron.), the
      average of the distances throughout one revolution of the
      planet, equivalent to the semi-major axis of the orbit.

   {Mean error} (Math. Phys.), the average error of a number of
      observations found by taking the mean value of the
      positive and negative errors without regard to sign.

   {Mean-square error}, or {Error of the mean square} (Math.
      Phys.), the error the square of which is the mean of the
      squares of all the errors; -- called also, {mean square
      deviation}, {mean error}.

   {Mean line}. (Crystallog.) Same as {Bisectrix}.

   {Mean noon}, noon as determined by mean time.

   {Mean proportional} (between two numbers) (Math.), the square
      root of their product.

   {Mean sun}, a fictitious sun supposed to move uniformly in
      the equator so as to be on the meridian each day at mean
      noon.

   {Mean time}, time as measured by an equable motion, as of a
      perfect clock, or as reckoned on the supposition that all
      the days of the year are of a mean or uniform length, in
      contradistinction from apparent time, or that actually
      indicated by the sun, and from sidereal time, or that
      measured by the stars.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mean</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mean \Mean\, n.
   1. That which is mean, or intermediate, between two extremes
      of place, time, or number; the middle point or place;
      middle rate or degree; mediocrity; medium; absence of
      extremes or excess; moderation; measure.
      [1913 Webster]

            But to speak in a mean, the virtue of prosperity is
            temperance; the virtue of adversity is fortitude.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is a mean in all things.        --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The extremes we have mentioned, between which the
            wellinstracted Christian holds the mean, are
            correlatives.                         --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Math.) A quantity having an intermediate value between
      several others, from which it is derived, and of which it
      expresses the resultant value; usually, unless otherwise
      specified, it is the simple average, formed by adding the
      quantities together and dividing by their number, which is
      called an {arithmetical mean}. A {geometrical mean} is the
      nth root of the product of the n quantities being
      averaged.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That through which, or by the help of which, an end is
      attained; something tending to an object desired;
      intermediate agency or measure; necessary condition or
      coagent; instrument.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their virtuous conversation was a mean to work the
            conversion of the heathen to Christ.  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            You may be able, by this mean, to review your own
            scientific acquirements.              --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Philosophical doubt is not an end, but a mean. --Sir
                                                  W. Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense the word is usually employed in the
         plural form means, and often with a singular attribute
         or predicate, as if a singular noun.
         [1913 Webster]

               By this means he had them more at vantage.
                                                  --Bacon.
         [1913 Webster]

               What other means is left unto us.  --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. pl. Hence: Resources; property, revenue, or the like,
      considered as the condition of easy livelihood, or an
      instrumentality at command for effecting any purpose;
      disposable force or substance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your means are very slender, and your waste is
            great.                                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.) A part, whether alto or tenor, intermediate between
      the soprano and base; a middle part. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The mean is drowned with your unruly base. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Meantime; meanwhile. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A mediator; a go-between. [Obs.] --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            He wooeth her by means and by brokage. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {By all means}, certainly; without fail; as, go, by all
      means.

   {By any means}, in any way; possibly; at all.
      [1913 Webster]

            If by any means I might attain to the resurrection
            of the dead.                          --Phil. iii.
                                                  ll.
      [1913 Webster]

   {By no means}, or {By no manner of means}, not at all;
      certainly not; not in any degree.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wine on this side of the lake is by no means so
            good as that on the other.            --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mean</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mean
     adj 1: approximating the statistical norm or average or expected
            value; "the average income in New England is below
            that of the nation"; "of average height for his age";
            "the mean annual rainfall" [syn: {average}, {mean(a)}]
     2: characterized by malice; "a hateful thing to do"; "in a mean
        mood" [syn: {hateful}]
     3: having or showing an ignoble lack of honor or morality;
        "that liberal obedience without which your army would be a
        base rabble"- Edmund Burke; "taking a mean advantage";
        "chok'd with ambition of the meaner sort"- Shakespeare;
        "something essentially vulgar and meanspirited in
        politics" [syn: {base}, {meanspirited}]
     4: excellent; "famous for a mean backhand"
     5: marked by poverty befitting a beggar; "a beggarly existence
        in the slums"; "a mean hut" [syn: {beggarly}]
     6: used of persons or behavior; characterized by or indicative
        of lack of generosity; "a mean person"; "he left a miserly
        tip" [syn: {mingy}, {miserly}, {tight}]
     7: used of sums of money; so small in amount as to deserve
        contempt [syn: {beggarly}]
     n : an average of n numbers computed by adding some function of
         the numbers and dividing by some function of n [syn: {mean
         value}]
     v 1: mean or intend to express or convey; "You never understand
          what I mean!"; "what do his words intend?" [syn: {intend}]
     2: have as a logical consequence; "The water shortage means
        that we have to stop taking long showers" [syn: {entail},
        {imply}]
     3: denote or connote; "`maison' means `house' in French"; "An
        example sentence would show what this word means" [syn: {intend},
         {signify}, {stand for}]
     4: have in mind as a purpose; "I mean no harm"; "I only meant
        to help you"; "She didn't think to harm me"; "We thought
        to return early that night" [syn: {intend}, {think}]
     5: have a specified degree of importance; "My ex-husband means
        nothing to me"; "Happiness means everything"
     6: intend to refer to; "I'm thinking of good food when I talk
        about France"; "Yes, I meant you when I complained about
        people who gossip!" [syn: {think of}, {have in mind}]
     7: destine or designate for a certain purpose; "These flowers
        were meant for you"
     [also: {meant}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
