<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>measure</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Measure
   Several words are so rendered in the Authorized Version. (1.)
   Those which are indefinite. (a) Hok, Isa. 5:14, elsewhere
   "statute." (b) Mad, Job 11:9; Jer. 13:25, elsewhere "garment."
   (c) Middah, the word most frequently thus translated, Ex. 26:2,
   8, etc. (d) Mesurah, Lev. 19:35; 1 Chr. 23:29. (e) Mishpat, Jer.
   30:11, elsewhere "judgment." (f) Mithkoneth and token, Ezek.
   45:11. (g) In New Testament metron, the usual Greek word thus
   rendered (Matt. 7:2; 23:32; Mark 4:24).
   
     (2.) Those which are definite. (a) 'Eyphah, Deut. 25:14, 15,
   usually "ephah." (b) Ammah, Jer. 51:13, usually "cubit." (c)
   Kor, 1 Kings 4:22, elsewhere "cor;" Greek koros, Luke 16:7. (d)
   Seah, Gen. 18:6; 1 Sam. 25:18, a seah; Greek saton, Matt. 13:33;
   Luke 13:21. (e) Shalish, "a great measure," Isa. 40:12;
   literally a third, i.e., of an ephah. (f) In New Testament
   batos, Luke 16:6, the Hebrew "bath;" and choinix, Rev. 6:6, the
   choenix, equal in dry commodities to one-eighth of a modius.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>measure
     
        &lt;testing&gt; To ascertain or appraise by comparing to a
        {standard}; to apply a {metric}.
     
        (1996-12-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>measure \meas"ure\ (m[e^]zh"[-u]r; 135), n. [OE. mesure, F.
   mesure, L. mensura, fr. metiri, mensus, to measure; akin to
   metrum poetical measure, Gr. me`tron, E. meter. Cf.
   {Immense}, {Mensuration}, {Mete} to measure.]
   1. A standard of dimension; a fixed unit of quantity or
      extent; an extent or quantity in the fractions or
      multiples of which anything is estimated and stated;
      hence, a rule by which anything is adjusted or judged.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An instrument by means of which size or quantity is
      measured, as a graduated line, rod, vessel, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            False ells and measures be brought all clean adown.
                                                  --R. of
                                                  Gloucester.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The dimensions or capacity of anything, reckoned according
      to some standard; size or extent, determined and stated;
      estimated extent; as, to take one's measure for a coat.
      [1913 Webster]

            The measure thereof is longer than the earth, and
            broader than the sea.                 --Job xi. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The contents of a vessel by which quantity is measured; a
      quantity determined by a standard; a stated or limited
      quantity or amount.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is like leaven which a woman took and hid in
            three measures of meal.               --Luke xiii.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Extent or degree not excessive or beyong bounds;
      moderation; due restraint; esp. in the phrases, in
      measure; with measure; without or beyond measure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hell hath enlarged herself, and opened her mouth
            without measure.                      --Is. v. 14.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Determined extent, not to be exceeded; limit; allotted
      share, as of action, influence, ability, or the like; due
      proportion.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lord, make me to know mine end, and the measure of
            my days.                              --Ps. xxxix.
                                                  4.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The quantity determined by measuring, especially in buying
      and selling; as, to give good or full measure.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Undefined quantity; extent; degree.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is a great measure of discretion to be used in
            the performance of confession.        --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Regulated division of movement:
      (a) (Dancing) A regulated movement corresponding to the
          time in which the accompanying music is performed;
          but, especially, a slow and stately dance, like the
          minuet.
      (b) (Mus.) (1) The group or grouping of beats, caused by
          the regular recurrence of accented beats. (2) The
          space between two bars. See {Beat}, {Triple},
          {Quadruple}, {Sextuple}, {Compound time}, under
          {Compound}, a., and {Figure}.
      (c) (Poetry) The manner of ordering and combining the
          quantities, or long and short syllables; meter;
          rhythm; hence, a foot; as, a poem in iambic measure.
          [1913 Webster]

   10. (Arith.) A number which is contained in a given number a
       number of times without a remainder; as in the phrases,
       the common measure, the greatest common measure, etc., of
       two or more numbers; a denominator. See {common
       denominator} under {denominator}.
       [1913 Webster +PJC]

   11. A step or definite part of a progressive course or
       policy; a means to an end; an act designed for the
       accomplishment of an object; as, political measures;
       prudent measures; an inefficient measure.
       [1913 Webster]

             His majesty found what wrong measures he had taken
             in the conferring that trust, and lamented his
             error.                               --Clarendon.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. The act of measuring; measurement. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. pl. (Geol.) Beds or strata; as, coal measures; lead
       measures.
       [1913 Webster]

   {linear measure}, {lineal measure}, or {long measure},
      measure of length; the measure of lines or distances.

   {Liquid measure}, the measure of liquids.

   {Square measure}, the measure of superficial area of surfaces
      in square units, as inches, feet, miles, etc.

   {To have hard measure}, to have harsh treatment meted out to
      one; to be harshly or oppressively dealt with.

   {To take measures}, to make preparations; to provide means.
      

   {To take one's measure}, to measure one, as for a garment;
      hence, to form an opinion of one's disposition, character,
      ability, etc.

   {To tread a measure}, to dance in the style so called. See 9
       (a) .
           [1913 Webster]

                 Say to her, we have measured many miles
                 To tread a measure with her on this grass.
                                                  --Shak.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Measure \Meas"ure\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Measured}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Measuring}.] [F. mesurer, L. mensurare. See {Measure},
   n.]
   1. To ascertain by use of a measuring instrument; to compute
      or ascertain the extent, quantity, dimensions, or capacity
      of, by a certain rule or standard; to take the dimensions
      of; hence, to estimate; to judge of; to value; to
      appraise.
      [1913 Webster]

            Great are thy works, Jehovah, infinite
            Thy power! what thought can measure thee? --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To serve as the measure of; as, the thermometer measures
      changes of temperature.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass throught or over in journeying, as if laying off
      and determining the distance.
      [1913 Webster]

            A true devoted pilgrim is not weary
            To measure kingdoms with his feeble steps. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To adjust by a rule or standard.
      [1913 Webster]

            To secure a contented spirit, measure your desires
            by your fortunes, not your fortunes by your desires.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To allot or distribute by measure; to set off or apart by
      measure; -- often with out or off.
      [1913 Webster]

            With what measure ye mete, it shall be measured to
            you again.                            --Matt. vii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

            That portion of eternity which is called time,
            measured out by the sun.              --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To measure swords with one}, to try another's skill in the
      use of the sword; hence, figuratively, to match one's
      abilities against an antagonist's.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Measure \Meas"ure\, v. i.
   1. To make a measurement or measurements.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To result, or turn out, on measuring; as, the grain
      measures well; the pieces measure unequally.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be of a certain size or quantity, or to have a certain
      length, breadth, or thickness, or a certain capacity
      according to a standard measure; as, cloth measures three
      fourths of a yard; a tree measures three feet in diameter.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>measure
     n 1: the act or process of measuring; "the measurements were
          carefully done"; "his mental measurings proved
          remarkably accurate" [syn: {measurement}, {measuring}, {mensuration}]
     2: a basis for comparison; a reference point against which
        other things can be evaluated; "they set the measure for
        all subsequent work" [syn: {standard}, {criterion}, {touchstone}]
     3: how much there is of something that you can quantify [syn: {quantity},
         {amount}]
     4: any maneuver made as part of progress toward a goal; "the
        situation called for strong measures"; "the police took
        steps to reduce crime" [syn: {step}]
     5: a statute in draft before it becomes law; "they held a
        public hearing on the bill" [syn: {bill}]
     6: (prosody) the accent in a metrical foot of verse [syn: {meter},
         {metre}, {beat}, {cadence}]
     7: musical notation for a repeating pattern of musical beats;
        "the orchestra omitted the last twelve bars of the song"
        [syn: {bar}]
     8: measuring instrument having a sequence of marks at regular
        intervals; used as a reference in making measurements
        [syn: {measuring stick}, {measuring rod}]
     v 1: determine the measurements of something or somebody, take
          measurements of; "Measure the length of the wall" [syn:
          {mensurate}, {measure out}]
     2: express as a number or measure or quantity; "Can you
        quantify your results?" [syn: {quantify}]
     3: have certain dimensions; "This table surfaces measures
        20inches by 36 inches"
     4: place a value on; judge the worth of something; "I will have
        the family jewels appraised by a professional" [syn: {evaluate},
         {valuate}, {assess}, {appraise}, {value}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
