<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>measuring</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measuring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Inchworm \Inch"worm`\, n. (Zo["o]l.)
   The larva of any geometrid moth. It progresses forward by
   first bringing the rear end of the body forward, forming a
   loop, then moving the front part of the body; called also
   {measuring} worm, {measuringworm}, {spanner}, and {looper}.
   See {Geometrid}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measuring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Measure \Meas"ure\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Measured}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Measuring}.] [F. mesurer, L. mensurare. See {Measure},
   n.]
   1. To ascertain by use of a measuring instrument; to compute
      or ascertain the extent, quantity, dimensions, or capacity
      of, by a certain rule or standard; to take the dimensions
      of; hence, to estimate; to judge of; to value; to
      appraise.
      [1913 Webster]

            Great are thy works, Jehovah, infinite
            Thy power! what thought can measure thee? --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To serve as the measure of; as, the thermometer measures
      changes of temperature.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pass throught or over in journeying, as if laying off
      and determining the distance.
      [1913 Webster]

            A true devoted pilgrim is not weary
            To measure kingdoms with his feeble steps. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To adjust by a rule or standard.
      [1913 Webster]

            To secure a contented spirit, measure your desires
            by your fortunes, not your fortunes by your desires.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To allot or distribute by measure; to set off or apart by
      measure; -- often with out or off.
      [1913 Webster]

            With what measure ye mete, it shall be measured to
            you again.                            --Matt. vii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

            That portion of eternity which is called time,
            measured out by the sun.              --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To measure swords with one}, to try another's skill in the
      use of the sword; hence, figuratively, to match one's
      abilities against an antagonist's.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measuring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Measuring \Meas"ur*ing\, a.
   Used in, or adapted for, ascertaining measurements, or
   dividing by measure.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Measuring faucet}, a faucet which permits only a given
      quantity of liquid to pass each time it is opened, or one
      by means of which the liquid which passes can be measured.
      

   {Measuring worm} (Zo["o]l.), the larva of any geometrid moth.
      They are so called because they move by a process in which
      they first pull the rear legs forward toward their front
      legs, forming a loop which resembles the process of
      measuring with a tape measure. The motion is completed by
      subsequently moving the front legs forward to an advanced
      position. See {Geometrid}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>measuring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>measuring
     n : the act or process of measuring; "the measurements were
         carefully done"; "his mental measurings proved remarkably
         accurate" [syn: {measurement}, {measure}, {mensuration}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
