<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>meeting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>meeting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Meet \Meet\ (m[=e]t), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Met} (m[e^]t); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Meeting}.] [OE. meten, AS. m[=e]tan, fr. m[=o]t,
   gem[=o]t, a meeting; akin to OS. m[=o]tian to meet, Icel.
   m[ae]ta, Goth. gam[=o]tjan. See {Moot}, v. t.]
   1. To join, or come in contact with; esp., to come in contact
      with by approach from an opposite direction; to come upon
      or against, front to front, as distinguished from contact
      by following and overtaking.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To come in collision with; to confront in conflict; to
      encounter hostilely; as, they met the enemy and defeated
      them; the ship met opposing winds and currents.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To come into the presence of without contact; to come
      close to; to intercept; to come within the perception,
      influence, or recognition of; as, to meet a train at a
      junction; to meet carriages or persons in the street; to
      meet friends at a party; sweet sounds met the ear.
      [1913 Webster]

            His daughter came out to meet him.    --Judg. xi.
                                                  34.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To perceive; to come to a knowledge of; to have personal
      acquaintance with; to experience; to suffer; as, the eye
      met a horrid sight; he met his fate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of vice or virtue, whether blest or curst,
            Which meets contempt, or which compassion first.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To come up to; to be even with; to equal; to match; to
      satisfy; to ansver; as, to meet one's expectations; the
      supply meets the demand.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To meet half way}, literally, to go half the distance
      between in order to meet (one); hence, figuratively, to
      yield or concede half of the difference in order to effect
      a compromise or reconciliation with.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>meeting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Meeting \Meet"ing\ (m[=e]t"[i^]ng), n.
   1. A coming together; an assembling; as, the meeting of
      Congress.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A junction, crossing, or union; as, the meeting of the
      roads or of two rivers.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A congregation; a collection of people; a convention; as,
      a large meeting; an harmonious meeting.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An assembly for worship; as, to attend meeting on Sunday;
      -- in England, applied distinctively and disparagingly to
      the worshiping assemblies of Dissenters.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Conference; assembly; company; convention; congregation;
        junction; confluence; union.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>meeting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>meeting
     n 1: a formally arranged gathering; "next year the meeting will
          be in Chicago"; "the meeting elected a chairperson"
     2: the social act of assembling for some common purpose; "his
        meeting with the salesmen was the high point of his day"
        [syn: {coming together}]
     3: a small informal social gathering; "there was an informal
        meeting in my livingroom" [syn: {get together}]
     4: a casual or unexpected convergence; "he still remembers
        their meeting in Paris"; "there was a brief encounter in
        the hallway" [syn: {encounter}]
     5: the act of joining together as one; "the merging of the two
        groups occurred quickly"; "there was no meeting of minds"
        [syn: {merging}, {coming together}]
     6: a place where things merge or flow together (especially
        rivers); "Pittsburgh is located at the confluence of the
        Allegheny and Monongahela rivers" [syn: {confluence}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
