<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>member</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>member</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Member \Mem"ber\, v. t. [See {Remember}.]
   To remember; to cause to remember; to mention. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>member</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Member \Mem"ber\, n. [OE. membre, F. membre, fr. L. membrum; cf.
   Goth. mimz flesh, Skr. mamsa.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Anat.) A part of an animal capable of performing a
      distinct office; an organ; a limb.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have many members in one body, and all members
            have not the same office.             --Rom. xii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: A part of a whole; an independent constituent of a
      body; as:
      (a) A part of a discourse or of a period or sentence; a
          clause; a part of a verse.
      (b) (Math.) Either of the two parts of an algebraic
          equation, connected by the sign of equality.
      (c) (Engin.) Any essential part, as a post, tie rod,
          strut, etc., of a framed structure, as a bridge truss.
      (d) (Arch.) Any part of a building, whether
          constructional, as a pier, column, lintel, or the
          like, or decorative, as a molding, or group of
          moldings.
      (e) One of the persons composing a society, community, or
          the like; an individual forming part of an
          association; as, a member of the society of Friends.
      (f) (Math.) one of the elements which, taken together,
          comprise a set.
      (g) (Math.) one of the individual objects which comprise a
          group or class.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   {Compression member}, {Tension member} (Engin.), a member, as
      a rod, brace, etc., which is subjected to compression or
      tension, respectively.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>member</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>member
     n 1: one of the persons who compose a social group (especially
          individuals who have joined and participates in a group
          organization); "only members will be admitted"; "a
          member of the faculty"; "she was introduced to all the
          members of his family" [ant: {nonmember}]
     2: an organization that is a member of another organization
        (especially a state that belongs to a group of nations);
        "the library was a member of the interlibrary loan
        association"; "Canada is a member of the United Nations"
     3: an external body part that projects from the body; "it is
        important to keep the extremities warm" [syn: {extremity},
         {appendage}]
     4: anything that belongs to a set or class; "snakes are members
        of the class Reptilia"; "members of the opposite sex"
     5: the male organ of copulation (`member' is a euphemism) [syn:
         {penis}, {phallus}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
