<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>memory</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>memory</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>memory
     
        &lt;storage&gt; These days, usually used synonymously with {Random
        Access Memory} or {Read-Only Memory}, but in the general sense
        it can be any device that can hold {data} in
        {machine-readable} format.
     
        (1996-05-25)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>memory</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Memory \Mem"o*ry\, n.; pl. {Memories}. [OE. memorie, OF.
   memoire, memorie, F. m['e]moire, L. memoria, fr. memor
   mindful; cf. mora delay. Cf. {Demur}, {Martyr}, {Memoir},
   {Remember}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The faculty of the mind by which it retains the knowledge
      of previous thoughts, impressions, or events.
      [1913 Webster]

            Memory is the purveyor of reason.     --Rambler.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The reach and positiveness with which a person can
      remember; the strength and trustworthiness of one's power
      to reach and represent or to recall the past; as, his
      memory was never wrong.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The actual and distinct retention and recognition of past
      ideas in the mind; remembrance; as, in memory of youth;
      memories of foreign lands.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The time within which past events can be or are
      remembered; as, within the memory of man.
      [1913 Webster]

            And what, before thy memory, was done
            From the begining.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Something, or an aggregate of things, remembered; hence,
      character, conduct, etc., as preserved in remembrance,
      history, or tradition; posthumous fame; as, the war became
      only a memory.
      [1913 Webster]

            The memory of the just is blessed.    --Prov. x. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

            That ever-living man of memory, Henry the Fifth.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Nonconformists . . . have, as a body, always
            venerated her [Elizabeth's] memory.   --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A memorial. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            These weeds are memories of those worser hours.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: {Memory}, {Remembrance}, {Recollection}, {Reminiscence}.

   Usage: Memory is the generic term, denoting the power by
          which we reproduce past impressions. Remembrance is an
          exercise of that power when things occur spontaneously
          to our thoughts. In recollection we make a distinct
          effort to collect again, or call back, what we know
          has been formerly in the mind. Reminiscence is
          intermediate between remembrance and recollection,
          being a conscious process of recalling past
          occurrences, but without that full and varied
          reference to particular things which characterizes
          recollection. ``When an idea again recurs without the
          operation of the like object on the external sensory,
          it is remembrance; if it be sought after by the mind,
          and with pain and endeavor found, and brought again
          into view, it is recollection.'' --Locke.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To draw to memory}, to put on record; to record. [Obs.]
      --Chaucer. Gower.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>memory</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>memory
     n 1: something that is remembered; "search as he would, the
          memory was lost"
     2: the cognitive processes whereby past experience is
        remembered; "he can do it from memory"; "he enjoyed
        remembering his father" [syn: {remembering}]
     3: the power of retaining and recalling past experience; "he
        had a good memory when he was younger" [syn: {retention},
        {retentiveness}]
     4: an electronic memory device; "a memory and the CPU form the
        central part of a computer to which peripherals are
        attached" [syn: {computer memory}, {storage}, {computer
        storage}, {store}, {memory board}]
     5: the area of cognitive psychology that studies memory
        processes; "he taught a graduate course on learning and
        memory"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
