<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mercy</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mercy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MERCY, n.  An attribute beloved of detected offenders.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mercy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mercy
   compassion for the miserable. Its object is misery. By the
   atoning sacrifice of Christ a way is open for the exercise of
   mercy towards the sons of men, in harmony with the demands of
   truth and righteousness (Gen. 19:19; Ex. 20:6; 34:6, 7; Ps.
   85:10; 86:15, 16). In Christ mercy and truth meet together.
   Mercy is also a Christian grace (Matt. 5:7; 18:33-35).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mercy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mercy \Mer"cy\ (m[~e]r"s[y^]), n.; pl. {Mercies}. [OE. merci, F.
   merci, L. merces, mercedis, hire, pay, reward, LL., equiv. to
   misericordia pity, mercy. L. merces is probably akin to
   merere to deserve, acquire. See {Merit}, and cf. {Amerce}.]
   1. Forbearance to inflict harm under circumstances of
      provocation, when one has the power to inflict it;
      compassionate treatment of an offender or adversary;
      clemency.
      [1913 Webster]

            Examples of justice must be made for terror to some;
            examples of mercy for comfort to others. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Compassionate treatment of the unfortunate and helpless;
      sometimes, favor, beneficence. --Luke x. 37.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Disposition to exercise compassion or favor; pity;
      compassion; willingness to spare or to help.
      [1913 Webster]

            In whom mercy lacketh and is not founden. --Sir T.
                                                  Elyot.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A blessing regarded as a manifestation of compassion or
      favor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Father of mercies and the God of all comfort.
                                                  --2 Cor. i. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Mercy seat} (Bib.), the golden cover or lid of the Ark of
      the Covenant. See {Ark}, 2.

   {Sisters of Mercy} (R. C. Ch.),a religious order founded in
      Dublin in the year 1827. Communities of the same name have
      since been established in various American cities. The
      duties of those belonging to the order are, to attend
      lying-in hospitals, to superintend the education of girls,
      and protect decent women out of employment, to visit
      prisoners and the sick, and to attend persons condemned to
      death.

   {To be at the mercy of}, to be wholly in the power of.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See {Grace}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mercy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mercy
     n 1: leniency and compassion shown toward offenders by a person
          or agency charged with administering justice; "he threw
          himself on the mercy of the court" [syn: {clemency}, {mercifulness}]
     2: a disposition to be kind and forgiving; "in those days a
        wife had to depend on the mercifulness of her husband"
        [syn: {mercifulness}] [ant: {mercilessness}]
     3: the feeling that motivates compassion [syn: {mercifulness}]
     4: something for which to be thankful; "it was a mercy we got
        out alive"
     5: alleviation of distress; showing great kindness toward the
        distressed; "distributing food and clothing to the flood
        victims was an act of mercy"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
