<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>metal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>metal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>METAL
     
        1. Mega-Extensive Telecommunications Applications Language.
        BBS language for PRODOS 8 on Apple II.
     
        2. The syntax-definition formalism of the Mentor system.
        Metal specifications are compiled to specifications for a
        scanner/parser generator such as Lex/Yacc.  "Metal: A
        Formalism to Specify Formalisms", G.  Kahn et al, Sci Comp
        Prog 3:151-188 (1983).
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>metal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Metal \Met"al\ (? or ?; 277), n. [F. m['e]tal, L. metallum
   metal, mine, Gr. ? mine; cf. Gr. ? to search after. Cf.
   {Mettle}, {Medal}.]
   1. (Chem.) An elementary substance, as sodium, calcium, or
      copper, whose oxide or hydroxide has basic rather than
      acid properties, as contrasted with the nonmetals, or
      metalloids. No sharp line can be drawn between the metals
      and nonmetals, and certain elements partake of both acid
      and basic qualities, as chromium, manganese, bismuth, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Popularly, the name is applied to certain hard, fusible
         metals, as gold, silver, copper, iron, tin, lead, zinc,
         nickel, etc., and also to the mixed metals, or metallic
         alloys, as brass, bronze, steel, bell metal, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Ore from which a metal is derived; -- so called by miners.
      --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A mine from which ores are taken. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Slaves . . . and persons condemned to metals. --Jer.
                                                  Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The substance of which anything is made; material; hence,
      constitutional disposition; character; temper.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not till God make men of some other metal than
            earth.                                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Courage; spirit; mettle. See {Mettle}. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The allusion is to the temper of the metal of a sword
         blade. --Skeat.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. The broken stone used in macadamizing roads and ballasting
      railroads.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The effective power or caliber of guns carried by a vessel
      of war.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Glass in a state of fusion. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. pl. The rails of a railroad. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Base metal} (Chem.), any one of the metals, as iron, lead,
      etc., which are readily tarnished or oxidized, in contrast
      with the noble metals. In general, a metal of small value,
      as compared with gold or silver.

   {Fusible metal} (Metal.), a very fusible alloy, usually
      consisting of bismuth with lead, tin, or cadmium.

   {Heavy metals} (Chem.), the metallic elements not included in
      the groups of the alkalies, alkaline earths, or the
      earths; specifically, the heavy metals, as gold, mercury,
      platinum, lead, silver, etc.

   {Light metals} (Chem.), the metallic elements of the alkali
      and alkaline earth groups, as sodium, lithium, calcium,
      magnesium, etc.; also, sometimes, the metals of the
      earths, as aluminium.

   {Muntz metal}, an alloy for sheathing and other purposes,
      consisting of about sixty per cent of copper, and forty of
      zinc. Sometimes a little lead is added. It is named from
      the inventor.

   {Prince's metal} (Old Chem.), an alloy resembling brass,
      consisting of three parts of copper to one of zinc; --
      also called {Prince Rupert's metal}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>metal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Metal \Met"al\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Metaled} (? or ?) or
   {Metalled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Metaling} or {Metalling}.]
   To cover with metal; as, to metal a ship's bottom; to metal a
   road.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>metal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>METAL
     Machine Evaluation and Translation Language (Siemens)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>metal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>metal
     adj : containing or made of or resembling or characteristic of a
           metal; "a metallic compound"; "metallic luster"; "the
           strange metallic note of the meadow lark, suggesting
           the clash of vibrant blades"- Ambrose Bierce [syn: {metallic},
            {metal(a)}] [ant: {nonmetallic}]
     n 1: any of several chemical elements that are usually shiny
          solids that conduct heat or electricity and can be
          formed into sheets etc. [syn: {metallic element}]
     2: a mixture containing two or more metallic elements or
        metallic and nonmetallic elements usually fused together
        or dissolving into each other when molten; "brass is an
        alloy of zinc and copper" [syn: {alloy}]
     v : cover with metal
     [also: {metalling}, {metalled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
