<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>meteor</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>meteor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>METEOR
     
        A version of COMIT with Lisp-like syntax, written in MIT Lisp
        1.5 for the IBM 7090.  "METEOR - A List Interpreter for String
        Transformation", D.G. Bobrow in The Programming Language LISP
        and its Interpretation, E.D.  and D.G. Bobrow eds, 1964.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>meteor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Meteor \Me"te*or\, n. [F. m['e]t['e]ore, Gr. ?, pl. ? things in
   the air, fr. ? high in air, raised off the ground; ? beyond +
   ?, ?, a suspension or hovering in the air, fr. ? to lift,
   raise up.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Any phenomenon or appearance in the atmosphere, as clouds,
      rain, hail, snow, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hail, an ordinary meteor.             --Bp. Hall.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Specif.: A transient luminous body or appearance seen in
      the atmosphere, or in a more elevated region.
      [1913 Webster]

            The vaulty top of heaven
            Figured quite o'er with burning meteors. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A mass of stone or other substance which sometimes falls
      to the earth from space beyond the moon, burning up from
      atomospheric friction and creating a brilliant but usually
      very brief trail of light in the atmosphere; also called a
      {shooting star}.
      [PJC]

   Note: The term is especially applied to fireballs, and the
         masses of stone or other substances which sometimes
         fall to the earth; also to shooting stars and to ignes
         fatui. Meteors are often classed as: aerial meteors,
         winds, tornadoes, etc.; aqueous meteors, rain, hail,
         snow, dew, etc.; luminous meteors, rainbows, halos,
         etc.; and igneous meteors, lightning, shooting stars,
         and the like.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>meteor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>meteor
     n 1: a streak of light in the sky at night that results when a
          meteoroid hits the earth's atmosphere and air friction
          causes the meteoroid to melt or vaporize or explode
          [syn: {shooting star}]
     2: (astronomy) any of the small solid extraterrestrial bodies
        that hits the earth's atmosphere [syn: {meteoroid}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
