<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>milk</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>milk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Milk
   (1.) Hebrew halabh, "new milk", milk in its fresh state (Judg.
   4:19). It is frequently mentioned in connection with honey (Ex.
   3:8; 13:5; Josh. 5:6; Isa. 7:15, 22; Jer. 11:5). Sheep (Deut.
   32:14) and goats (Prov. 27:27) and camels (Gen. 32:15), as well
   as cows, are made to give their milk for the use of man. Milk is
   used figuratively as a sign of abundance (Gen. 49:12; Ezek.
   25:4; Joel 3:18). It is also a symbol of the rudiments of
   doctrine (1 Cor. 3:2; Heb. 5:12, 13), and of the unadulterated
   word of God (1 Pet. 2:2).
   
     (2.) Heb. hem'ah, always rendered "butter" in the Authorized
   Version. It means "butter," but also more frequently "cream," or
   perhaps, as some think, "curdled milk," such as that which
   Abraham set before the angels (Gen. 18:8), and which Jael gave
   to Sisera (Judg. 5:25). In this state milk was used by
   travellers (2 Sam. 17:29). If kept long enough, it acquired a
   slightly intoxicating or soporific power.
   
     This Hebrew word is also sometimes used for milk in general
   (Deut. 32:14; Job 20:17).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>milk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Milk \Milk\ (m[i^]lk), n. [AS. meoluc, meoloc, meolc, milc; akin
   to OFries. meloc, D. melk, G. milch, OHG. miluh, Icel.
   mj[=o]lk, Sw. mj["o]lk, Dan. melk, Goth. miluks, G. melken to
   milk, OHG. melchan, Lith. milszti, L. mulgere, Gr.
   'ame`lgein. [root]107. Cf. {Milch}, {Emulsion}, {Milt} soft
   roe of fishes.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Physiol.) A white fluid secreted by the mammary glands of
      female mammals for the nourishment of their young,
      consisting of minute globules of fat suspended in a
      solution of casein, albumin, milk sugar, and inorganic
      salts. ``White as morne milk.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) A kind of juice or sap, usually white in color,
      found in certain plants; latex. See {Latex}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An emulsion made by bruising seeds; as, the milk of
      almonds, produced by pounding almonds with sugar and
      water.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) The ripe, undischarged spat of an oyster.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Condensed milk}. See under {Condense}, v. t.

   {Milk crust} (Med.), vesicular eczema occurring on the face
      and scalp of nursing infants. See {Eczema}.

   {Milk fever}.
      (a) (Med.) A fever which accompanies or precedes the first
          lactation. It is usually transitory.
      (b) (Vet. Surg.) A form puerperal peritonitis in cattle;
          also, a variety of meningitis occurring in cows after
          calving.

   {Milk glass}, glass having a milky appearance.

   {Milk knot} (Med.), a hard lump forming in the breast of a
      nursing woman, due to obstruction to the flow of milk and
      congestion of the mammary glands.

   {Milk leg} (Med.), a swollen condition of the leg, usually in
      puerperal women, caused by an inflammation of veins, and
      characterized by a white appearance occasioned by an
      accumulation of serum and sometimes of pus in the cellular
      tissue.

   {Milk meats}, food made from milk, as butter and cheese.
      [Obs.] --Bailey.

   {Milk mirror}. Same as {Escutcheon}, 2.

   {Milk molar} (Anat.), one of the deciduous molar teeth which
      are shed and replaced by the premolars.

   {Milk of lime} (Chem.), a watery emulsion of calcium hydrate,
      produced by macerating quicklime in water.

   {Milk parsley} (Bot.), an umbelliferous plant ({Peucedanum
      palustre}) of Europe and Asia, having a milky juice.

   {Milk pea} (Bot.), a genus ({Galactia}) of leguminous and,
      usually, twining plants.

   {Milk sickness} (Med.), See {milk sickness} in the
      vocabulary.

   {Milk snake} (Zo["o]l.), a harmless American snake
      ({Ophibolus triangulus}, or {Ophibolus eximius}). It is
      variously marked with white, gray, and red. Called also
      {milk adder}, {chicken snake}, {house snake}, etc.

   {Milk sugar}. (Physiol. Chem.) See {Lactose}, and {Sugar of
      milk} (below).

   {Milk thistle} (Bot.), an esculent European thistle ({Silybum
      marianum}), having the veins of its leaves of a milky
      whiteness.

   {Milk thrush}. (Med.) See {Thrush}.

   {Milk tooth} (Anat.), one of the temporary first set of teeth
      in young mammals; in man there are twenty.

   {Milk tree} (Bot.), a tree yielding a milky juice, as the cow
      tree of South America ({Brosimum Galactodendron}), and the
      {Euphorbia balsamifera} of the Canaries, the milk of both
      of which is wholesome food.

   {Milk vessel} (Bot.), a special cell in the inner bark of a
      plant, or a series of cells, in which the milky juice is
      contained. See {Latex}.

   {Rock milk}. See {Agaric mineral}, under {Agaric}.

   {Sugar of milk}. The sugar characteristic of milk; a hard
      white crystalline slightly sweet substance obtained by
      evaporation of the whey of milk. It is used in pellets and
      powder as a vehicle for homeopathic medicines, and as an
      article of diet. See {Lactose}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>milk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Milk \Milk\ (m[i^]lk), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Milked} (m[i^]lkt);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Milking}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To draw or press milk from the breasts or udder of, by the
      hand or mouth; to withdraw the milk of. ``Milking the
      kine.'' --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have given suck, and know
            How tender 't is to love the babe that milks me.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw from the breasts or udder; to extract, as milk;
      as, to milk wholesome milk from healthy cows.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To draw anything from, as if by milking; to compel to
      yield profit or advantage; to plunder. --Tyndale.
      [1913 Webster]

            They [the lawyers] milk an unfortunate estate as
            regularly as a dairyman does his stock. --London
                                                  Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To milk the street}, to squeeze the smaller operators in
      stocks and extract a profit from them, by alternately
      raising and depressing prices within a short range; --
      said of the large dealers. [Cant]

   {To milk a telegram}, to use for one's own advantage the
      contents of a telegram belonging to another person. [Cant]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>milk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Milk \Milk\, v. i.
   1. To draw or to yield milk.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. (Elec.) To give off small gas bubbles during the final
      part of the charging operation; -- said of a storage
      battery.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>milk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>milk
     n 1: a white nutritious liquid secreted by mammals and used as
          food by human beings
     2: produced by mammary glands of female mammals for feeding
        their young
     3: a river that rises in the Rockies in northwestern Montana
        and flows eastward to become a tributary of the Missouri
        River [syn: {Milk River}]
     4: any of several nutritive milklike liquids
     v 1: take milk from female mammals; "Cows need to be milked every
          morning"
     2: exploit as much as possible; "I am milking this for all it's
        worth"
     3: add milk to; "milk the tea"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
