<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mill</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mill
   for grinding corn, mentioned as used in the time of Abraham
   (Gen. 18:6). That used by the Hebrews consisted of two circular
   stones, each 2 feet in diameter and half a foot thick, the lower
   of which was called the "nether millstone" (Job 41:24) and the
   upper the "rider." The upper stone was turned round by a stick
   fixed in it as a handle. There were then no public mills, and
   thus each family required to be provided with a hand-mill. The
   corn was ground daily, generally by the women of the house (Isa.
   47:1, 2; Matt. 24:41). It was with the upper stone of a
   hand-mill that "a certain woman" at Thebez broke Abimelech's
   skull (Judg. 9:53, "a piece of a millstone;" literally, "a
   millstone rider", i.e., the "runner," the stone which revolves.
   Comp. 2 Sam. 11:21). Millstones could not be pledged (Deut.
   24:6), as they were necessary in every family.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mill
     
        {Arithmetic and Logic Unit}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mill \Mill\ (m[i^]l), n. [L. mille a thousand. Cf. {Mile}.]
   A money of account of the United States, having the value of
   the tenth of a cent, or the thousandth of a dollar.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mill \Mill\, n. [OE. mille, melle, mulle, milne, AS. myln,
   mylen; akin to D. molen, G. m["u]hle, OHG. mul[=i], mul[=i]n,
   Icel. mylna; all prob. from L. molina, fr. mola millstone;
   prop., that which grinds, akin to molere to grind, Goth.
   malan, G. mahlen, and to E. meal. [root]108. See Meal flour,
   and cf. {Moline}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A machine for grinding or comminuting any substance, as
      grain, by rubbing and crushing it between two hard, rough,
      or indented surfaces; as, a gristmill, a coffee mill; a
      bone mill.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A machine used for expelling the juice, sap, etc., from
      vegetable tissues by pressure, or by pressure in
      combination with a grinding, or cutting process; as, a
      cider mill; a cane mill.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A machine for grinding and polishing; as, a lapidary mill.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A common name for various machines which produce a
      manufactured product, or change the form of a raw material
      by the continuous repetition of some simple action; as, a
      sawmill; a stamping mill, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A building or collection of buildings with machinery by
      which the processes of manufacturing are carried on; as, a
      cotton mill; a powder mill; a rolling mill.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Die Sinking) A hardened steel roller having a design in
      relief, used for imprinting a reversed copy of the design
      in a softer metal, as copper.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining)
      (a) An excavation in rock, transverse to the workings,
          from which material for filling is obtained.
      (b) A passage underground through which ore is shot.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. A milling cutter. See Illust. under {Milling}.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A pugilistic encounter. [Cant] --R. D. Blackmore.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Short for {Treadmill}.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. The raised or ridged edge or surface made in milling
       anything, as a coin or screw.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. A building or complex of buildings containing a mill[1]
       or other machinery to grind grains into flour.
       [PJC]

   {Edge mill}, {Flint mill}, etc. See under {Edge}, {Flint},
      etc.

   {Mill bar} (Iron Works), a rough bar rolled or drawn directly
      from a bloom or puddle bar for conversion into merchant
      iron in the mill.

   {Mill cinder}, slag from a puddling furnace.

   {Mill head}, the head of water employed to turn the wheel of
      a mill.

   {Mill pick}, a pick for dressing millstones.

   {Mill pond}, a pond that supplies the water for a mill.

   {Mill race}, the canal in which water is conveyed to a mill
      wheel, or the current of water which drives the wheel.

   {Mill tail}, the water which flows from a mill wheel after
      turning it, or the channel in which the water flows.

   {Mill tooth}, a grinder or molar tooth.

   {Mill wheel}, the water wheel that drives the machinery of a
      mill.

   {Gin mill}, a tavern; a bar; a saloon; especially, a cheap or
      seedy establishment that serves liquor by the drink.

   {Roller mill}, a mill in which flour or meal is made by
      crushing grain between rollers.

   {Stamp mill} (Mining), a mill in which ore is crushed by
      stamps.

   {To go through the mill}, to experience the suffering or
      discipline necessary to bring one to a certain degree of
      knowledge or skill, or to a certain mental state.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mill \Mill\, v. i. (Zo["o]l.)
   To swim under water; -- said of air-breathing creatures.
   [1913 Webster]

   2. To undergo hulling, as maize.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. To move in a circle, as cattle upon a plain; to move
      around aimlessly; -- usually used with around.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

            The deer and the pig and the nilghar were milling
            round and round in a circle of eight or ten miles
            radius.                               --Kipling.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. To swim suddenly in a new direction; -- said of whales.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   5. To take part in a mill; to box. [Cant]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mill \Mill\ (m[i^]l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Milled} (m[i^]ld); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Milling}.] [See {Mill}, n., and cf. {Muller}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To reduce to fine particles, or to small pieces, in a
      mill; to grind; to comminute.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To shape, finish, or transform by passing through a
      machine; specifically, to shape or dress, as metal, by
      means of a rotary cutter.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make a raised border around the edges of, or to cut
      fine grooves or indentations across the edges of, as of a
      coin, or a screw head; also, to stamp in a coining press;
      to coin.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To pass through a fulling mill; to full, as cloth.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To beat with the fists. [Cant] --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To roll into bars, as steel.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To mill chocolate}, to make it frothy, as by churning.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mill \Mill\, v. t.
   1. (Mining) To fill (a winze or interior incline) with broken
      ore, to be drawn out at the bottom.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. To cause to mill, or circle round, as cattle.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mill</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mill
     n 1: a plant consisting of buildings with facilities for
          manufacturing [syn: {factory}, {manufacturing plant}, {manufactory}]
     2: Scottish philosopher who expounded Bentham's utilitarianism;
        father of John Stuart Mill (1773-1836) [syn: {James Mill}]
     3: English philosopher and economist remembered for his
        interpretations of empiricism and utilitarianism
        (1806-1873) [syn: {John Mill}, {John Stuart Mill}]
     4: machine that processes materials by grinding or crushing
        [syn: {grinder}]
     5: the act of grinding to a powder or dust [syn: {grind}, {pulverization},
         {pulverisation}]
     v 1: move about in a confused manner [syn: {mill about}, {mill
          around}]
     2: grind with a mill; "mill grain"
     3: produce a ridge around the edge of; "mill a coin"
     4: roll out (metal) with a rolling machine
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
