<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mind</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MIND, n.  A mysterious form of matter secreted by the brain.  Its
chief activity consists in the endeavor to ascertain its own nature,
the futility of the attempt being due to the fact that it has nothing
but itself to know itself with.  From the Latin _mens_, a fact unknown
to that honest shoe-seller, who, observing that his learned competitor
over the way had displayed the motto "_Mens conscia recti_,"
emblazoned his own front with the words "Men's, women's and children's
conscia recti."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mind \Mind\ (m[imac]nd), n. [AS. mynd, gemynd; akin to OHG.
   minna memory, love, G. minne love, Dan. minde mind, memory,
   remembrance, consent, vote, Sw. minne memory, Icel. minni,
   Goth. gamunds, L. mens, mentis, mind, Gr. me`nos, Skr. manas
   mind, man to think. [root]104, 278. Cf. {Comment}, {Man},
   {Mean}, v., 3d {Mental}, {Mignonette}, {Minion}, {Mnemonic},
   {Money}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The intellectual or rational faculty in man; the
      understanding; the intellect; the power that conceives,
      judges, or reasons; also, the entire spiritual nature; the
      soul; -- often in distinction from the {body}.
      [1913 Webster]

            By the mind of man we understand that in him which
            thinks, remembers, reasons, wills.    --Reid.
      [1913 Webster]

            What we mean by mind is simply that which perceives,
            thinks, feels, wills, and desires.    --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let every man be fully persuaded in his own mind.
                                                  --Rom. xiv. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mind shall banquet, though the body pine.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state, at any given time, of the faculties of
      thinking, willing, choosing, and the like; psychical
      activity or state; as:
      (a) Opinion; judgment; belief.
          [1913 Webster]

                A fool uttereth all his mind.     --Prov. xxix.
                                                  11.
          [1913 Webster]

                Being so hard to me that brought your mind, I
                fear she'll prove as hard to you in telling her
                mind.                             --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) Choice; inclination; liking; intent; will.
          [1913 Webster]

                If it be your minds, then let none go forth. --2
                                                  Kings ix. 15.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) Courage; spirit. --Chapman.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Memory; remembrance; recollection; as, to have or keep in
      mind, to call to mind, to put in mind, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To have a mind} or {To have a great mind}, to be inclined or
      strongly inclined in purpose; -- used with an infinitive.
      ``Sir Roger de Coverly . . . told me that he had a great
      mind to see the new tragedy with me.'' --Addison.

   {To lose one's mind}, to become insane, or imbecile.

   {To make up one's mind}, to come to an opinion or decision;
      to determine.

   {To put in mind}, to remind. ``Regard us simply as putting
      you in mind of what you already know to be good policy.''
      --Jowett (Thucyd. ).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mind \Mind\, v. i.
   To give attention or heed; to obey; as, the dog minds well.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mind \Mind\ (m[imac]nd), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Minded}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Minding}.] [AS. myndian, gemynd[=i]an to remember.
   See {Mind}, n.]
   1. To fix the mind or thoughts on; to regard with attention;
      to treat as of consequence; to consider; to heed; to mark;
      to note. ``Mind not high things, but condescend to men of
      low estate.'' --Rom. xii. 16.
      [1913 Webster]

            My lord, you nod: you do not mind the play. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To occupy one's self with; to employ one's self about; to
      attend to; as, to mind one's business.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bidding him be a good child, and mind his book.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To obey; as, to mind parents; the dog minds his master.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To have in mind; to purpose. --Beaconsfield.
      [1913 Webster]

            I mind to tell him plainly what I think. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To put in mind; to remind. [Archaic] --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

            He minded them of the mutability of all earthly
            things.                               --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            I do thee wrong to mind thee of it.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Never mind}, do not regard it; it is of no consequence; no
      matter.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To notice; mark; regard; obey. See {Attend}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mind</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mind
     n 1: that which is responsible for one's thoughts and feelings;
          the seat of the faculty of reason; "his mind wandered";
          "I couldn't get his words out of my head" [syn: {head},
          {brain}, {psyche}, {nous}]
     2: recall or remembrance; "it came to mind"
     3: an opinion formed by judging something; "he was reluctant to
        make his judgment known"; "she changed her mind" [syn: {judgment},
         {judgement}]
     4: an important intellectual; "the great minds of the 17th
        century" [syn: {thinker}, {creative thinker}]
     5: attention; "don't pay him any mind"
     6: your intention; what you intend to do; "he had in mind to
        see his old teacher"; "the idea of the game is to capture
        all the pieces" [syn: {idea}]
     7: knowledge and intellectual ability; "he reads to improve his
        mind"; "he has a keen intellect" [syn: {intellect}]
     v 1: be offended or bothered by; take offense with, be bothered
          by; "I don't mind your behavior"
     2: be concerned with or about something or somebody
     3: be in charge of or deal with; "She takes care of all the
        necessary arrangements" [syn: {take care}]
     4: pay close attention to; give heed to; "Heed the advice of
        the old men" [syn: {heed}, {listen}]
     5: be on one's guard; be cautious or wary about; be alert to;
        "Beware of telephone salesmen" [syn: {beware}]
     6: keep in mind [syn: {bear in mind}] [ant: {forget}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
