<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mine</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MINE, adj.  Belonging to me if I can hold or seize it.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine
   The process of mining is described in Job 28:1-11. Moses speaks
   of the mineral wealth of Palestine (Deut. 8:9). Job 28:4 is
   rightly thus rendered in the Revised Version, "He breaketh open
   a shaft away from where men sojourn; they are forgotten of the
   foot [that passeth by]; they hang afar from men, they swing to
   and fro." These words illustrate ancient mining operations.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine \Mine\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Mined}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Mining}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To dig away, or otherwise remove, the substratum or
      foundation of; to lay a mine under; to sap; to undermine;
      hence, to ruin or destroy by slow degrees or secret means.
      [1913 Webster]

            They mined the walls.                 --Hayward.
      [1913 Webster]

            Too lazy to cut down these immense trees, the
            spoilers . . . had mined them, and placed a quantity
            of gunpowder in the cavity.           --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To dig into, for ore or metal.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lead veins have been traced . . . but they have not
            been mined.                           --Ure.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To get, as metals, out of the earth by digging.
      [1913 Webster]

            The principal ore mined there is the bituminous
            cinnabar.                             --Ure.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine \Mine\ (m[=e]n), n. [F.]
   See {Mien}. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine \Mine\ (m[imac]n), pron. &amp; a. [OE. min, fr. AS. m[=i]n;
   akin to D. mijn, OS., OFries., &amp; OHG. m[=i]n, G. mein, Sw. &amp;
   Dan. min, Icel. minn, Goth. meins my, mine, meina of me, and
   E. me. [root]187. See {Me}, and cf. {My}.]
   Belonging to me; my. Used as a pronominal to me; my. Used as
   a pronominal adjective in the predicate; as, ``Vengeance is
   mine; I will repay.'' --Rom. xii. 19. Also, in the old style,
   used attributively, instead of my, before a noun beginning
   with a vowel.
   [1913 Webster]

         I kept myself from mine iniquity.        --Ps. xviii.
                                                  23.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Mine is often used absolutely, the thing possessed
         being understood; as, his son is in the army, mine in
         the navy.
         [1913 Webster]

               When a man deceives me once, says the Italian
               proverb, it is his fault; when twice, it is mine.
                                                  --Bp. Horne.
         [1913 Webster]

               This title honors me and mine.     --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

               She shall have me and mine.        --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine \Mine\, v. i. [F. miner, L. minare to drive animals, in LL.
   also, to lead, conduct, dig a mine (cf. E. lode, and lead to
   conduct), akin to L. minari to threaten; cf. Sp. mina mine,
   conduit, subterraneous canal, a spring or source of water,
   It. mina. See {Menace}, and cf. {Mien}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To dig a mine or pit in the earth; to get ore, metals,
      coal, or precious stones, out of the earth; to dig in the
      earth for minerals; to dig a passage or cavity under
      anything in order to overthrow it by explosives or
      otherwise.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form subterraneous tunnel or hole; to form a burrow or
      lodge in the earth; as, the mining cony.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine \Mine\, n. [F., fr. LL. mina. See {Mine}, v. i.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A subterranean cavity or passage; especially:
      (a) A pit or excavation in the earth, from which metallic
          ores, precious stones, coal, or other mineral
          substances are taken by digging; -- distinguished from
          the pits from which stones for architectural purposes
          are taken, and which are called quarries.
      (b) (Mil.) A cavity or tunnel made under a fortification
          or other work, for the purpose of blowing up the
          superstructure with some explosive agent.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Any place where ore, metals, or precious stones are got by
      digging or washing the soil; as, a placer mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Fig.): A rich source of wealth or other good. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) An explosive device placed concealed in a location,
      on land or at sea, where an enemy vehicle or enemy
      personnel may pass through, having a triggering mechanism
      which detects people or vehicles, and which will explode
      and kill or maim personnel or destroy or damage vehicles.
      A mine placed at sea (formerly called a {torpedo}, see
      {torpedo}[2]
      (a) ) is also called an marine mine and underwater mine
          and sometimes called a floating mine, even though it
          may be anchored to the floor of the sea and not
          actually float freely. A mine placed on land (formerly
          called a {torpedo}, see {torpedo}[3]), usually buried,
          is called a land mine.
          [PJC]

   {Mine dial}, a form of magnetic compass used by miners.

   {Mine pig}, pig iron made wholly from ore; in distinction
      from {cinder pig}, which is made from ore mixed with forge
      or mill cinder.

   {gold mine}
      (a) a mine where gold is obtained.
      (b) (Fig.) a rich source of wealth or other good; same as
          {Mine} 3. --Raymond.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mine
     n 1: excavation in the earth from which ores and minerals are
          extracted
     2: explosive device that explodes on contact; designed to
        destroy vehicles or ships or to kill or maim personnel
     v 1: get from the earth by excavation; "mine ores and metals"
     2: lay mines; "The Vietnamese mined Cambodia"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
