<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>minister</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>minister</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MINISTER, n.  An agent of a higher power with a lower responsibility. 
In diplomacy and officer sent into a foreign country as the visible
embodiment of his sovereign's hostility.  His principal qualification
is a degree of plausible inveracity next below that of an ambassador.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>minister</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Minister
   one who serves, as distinguished from the master. (1.) Heb.
   meshereth, applied to an attendant on one of superior rank, as
   to Joshua, the servant of Moses (Ex. 33:11), and to the servant
   of Elisha (2 Kings 4:43). This name is also given to attendants
   at court (2 Chr. 22:8), and to the priests and Levites (Jer.
   33:21; Ezek. 44:11).
   
     (2.) Heb. pelah (Ezra 7:24), a "minister" of religion. Here
   used of that class of sanctuary servants called "Solomon's
   servants" in Ezra 2:55-58 and Neh. 7:57-60.
   
     (3.) Greek leitourgos, a subordinate public administrator, and
   in this sense applied to magistrates (Rom. 13:6). It is applied
   also to our Lord (Heb. 8:2), and to Paul in relation to Christ
   (Rom. 15:16).
   
     (4.) Greek hyperetes (literally, "under-rower"), a personal
   attendant on a superior, thus of the person who waited on the
   officiating priest in the synagogue (Luke 4:20). It is applied
   also to John Mark, the attendant on Paul and Barnabas (Acts
   13:5).
   
     (5.) Greek diaconos, usually a subordinate officer or
   assistant employed in relation to the ministry of the gospel, as
   to Paul and Apollos (1 Cor. 3:5), Tychicus (Eph. 6:21), Epaphras
   (Col. 1:7), Timothy (1 Thess. 3:2), and also to Christ (Rom.
   15:8).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>minister</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Minister \Min"is*ter\, n. [OE. ministre, F. ministre, fr. L.
   minister, orig. a double comparative from the root of minor
   less, and hence meaning, an inferior, a servant. See 1st
   {Minor}, and cf. {Master}, {Minstrel}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A servant; a subordinate; an officer or assistant of
      inferior rank; hence, an agent, an instrument.
      [1913 Webster]

            Moses rose up, and his minister Joshua. --Ex. xxiv.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            I chose
            Camillo for the minister, to poison
            My friend Polixenes.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An officer of justice. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I cry out the on the ministres, quod he,
            That shoulde keep and rule this cit['e]. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One to whom the sovereign or executive head of a
      government intrusts the management of affairs of state, or
      some department of such affairs.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ministers to kings, whose eyes, ears, and hands they
            are, must be answerable to God and man. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A representative of a government, sent to the court, or
      seat of government, of a foreign nation to transact
      diplomatic business.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Ambassadors are classed (in the diplomatic sense) in
         the first rank of public ministers, ministers
         plenipotentiary in the second. ``The United States
         diplomatic service employs two classes of ministers, --
         ministers plenipotentiary and ministers resident.''
         --Abbott.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. One who serves at the altar; one who performs sacerdotal
      duties; the pastor of a church duly authorized or licensed
      to preach the gospel and administer the sacraments.
      --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Delegate; official; ambassador; clergyman; parson;
        priest.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>minister</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Minister \Min"is*ter\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Ministered}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Ministering}.] [OE. ministren, OF. ministrer, fr.
   L. ministrare. See {Minister}, n.]
   To furnish or apply; to afford; to supply; to administer.
   [1913 Webster]

         He that ministereth seed to the sower.   --2 Cor. ix.
                                                  10.
   [1913 Webster]

         We minister to God reason to suspect us. --Jer. Taylor.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>minister</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Minister \Min"is*ter\, v. i.
   1. To act as a servant, attendant, or agent; to attend and
      serve; to perform service in any office, sacred or
      secular.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but
            to minister.                          --Matt. xx.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To supply or to things needful; esp., to supply
      consolation or remedies; as, to minister to the sick.
      --Matt. xxv. 44.
      [1913 Webster]

            Canst thou not minister to a mind diseased? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>minister</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>minister
     n 1: a person authorized to conduct religious worship [syn: {curate},
           {parson}, {pastor}, {rector}]
     2: a person appointed to a high office in the government;
        "Minister of Finance" [syn: {government minister}]
     3: a diplomat representing one government to another; ranks
        below ambassador [syn: {diplomatic minister}]
     4: the job of a head of a government department
     v 1: attend to the wants and needs of others; "I have to minister
          to my mother all the time"
     2: work as a minister; "She is ministering in an old parish"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
