<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mix</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mix</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MIX
     
        Knuth's hypothetical machine, used in The Art of Computer
        Programming v.1, Donald Knuth, A-W 1969.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mix</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mix \Mix\, v. i.
   1. To become united into a compound; to be blended
      promiscuously together.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To associate; to mingle; as, Democrats and Republicans
      mixed freely at the party.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            He had mixed
            Again in fancied safety with his kind. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mix</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mix \Mix\ (m[i^]ks), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Mixed} (m[i^]kst)
   (less properly {Mixt}); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Mixing}.] [AS.
   miscan; akin to OHG. misken, G. mischen, Russ. mieshate, W.
   mysgu, Gael. measg, L. miscere, mixtum, Gr. mi`sgein,
   migny`nai, Skr. mi[,c]ra mixed. The English word has been
   influenced by L. miscere, mixtum (cf. {Mixture}), and even
   the AS. miscan may have been borrowed fr. L. miscere. Cf.
   {Admix}, {Mash} to bruise, {Meddle}.]
   1. To cause a promiscuous interpenetration of the parts of,
      as of two or more substances with each other, or of one
      substance with others; to unite or blend into one mass or
      compound, as by stirring together; to mingle; to blend;
      as, to mix flour and salt; to mix wines.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fair persuasions mixed with sugared words. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To unite with in company; to join; to associate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ephraim, he hath mixed himself among the people.
                                                  --Hos. vii. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To form by mingling; to produce by the stirring together
      of ingredients; to compound of different parts.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hast thou no poison mixed?            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have chosen an argument mixed of religious and
            civil considerations.                 --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To combine (two or more activities) within a specified or
      implied time frame; as, to mix studying and partying while
      at college.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mix</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mix
     n 1: a commercially prepared mixture of dry ingredients [syn: {premix}]
     2: an event that combines things in a mixture; "a gradual
        mixture of cultures" [syn: {mixture}]
     3: the act of mixing together; "paste made by a mix of flour
        and water"; "the mixing of sound channels in the recording
        studio" [syn: {commixture}, {admixture}, {mixture}, {intermixture},
         {mixing}]
     v 1: mix together different elements; "The colors blend well"
          [syn: {blend}, {flux}, {conflate}, {commingle}, {immix},
           {fuse}, {coalesce}, {meld}, {combine}, {merge}]
     2: open (a place) to members of all races and ethnic groups;
        "This school is completely desegregated" [syn: {desegregate},
         {integrate}] [ant: {segregate}]
     3: to bring or combine together or with something else;
        "resourcefully he mingled music and dance" [syn: {mingle},
         {commix}, {unify}, {amalgamate}]
     4: as of electronic signals; "mixing sounds"
     5: add as an additional element or part; "mix water into the
        drink" [syn: {mix in}]
     6: mix so as to make a random order or arrangement; "shuffle
        the cards" [syn: {shuffle}, {ruffle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
