<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mode</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mode
     
        An {object-oriented language}.
     
        ["The Programming Language Mode: Language Definition and User
        Guide", J. Vihavainen, C-1987-50, U Helsinki, 1987].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1994-10-21)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mode
     
        1. A general state, usually used with an adjective describing
        the state.  Use of the word "mode" rather than "state" implies
        that the state is extended over time, and probably also that
        some activity characteristic of that state is being carried
        out. "No time to hack; I'm in thesis mode."
     
        In its jargon sense, "mode" is most often attributed to
        people, though it is sometimes applied to programs and
        inanimate objects.  In particular, see {hack mode}, {day
        mode}, {night mode}, {demo mode}, {fireworks mode}, and {yoyo
        mode}; also {chat}.
     
        2. More technically, a mode is a special state that certain
        user interfaces must pass into in order to perform certain
        functions.  For example, in order to insert characters into a
        document in the Unix editor "vi", one must type the "i" key,
        which invokes the "Insert" command.  The effect of this
        command is to put vi into "insert mode", in which typing the
        "i" key has a quite different effect (to wit, it inserts an
        "i" into the document).  One must then hit another special
        key, "ESC", in order to leave "insert mode".  Nowadays,
        modeful interfaces are generally considered {losing} but
        survive in quite a few widely used tools built in less
        enlightened times.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1994-12-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mode \Mode\ (m[=o]d), n. [L. modus a measure, due or proper
   measure, bound, manner, form; akin to E. mete: cf. F. mode.
   See {Mete}, and cf. {Commodious}, {Mood} in grammar,
   {Modus}.]
   1. Manner of doing or being; method; form; fashion; custom;
      way; style; as, the mode of speaking; the mode of
      dressing.
      [1913 Webster]

            The duty of itself being resolved on, the mode of
            doing it may easily be found.         --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            A table richly spread in regal mode.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Prevailing popular custom; fashion, especially in the
      phrase the mode.
      [1913 Webster]

            The easy, apathetic graces of a man of the mode.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Variety; gradation; degree. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Metaph.) Any combination of qualities or relations,
      considered apart from the substance to which they belong,
      and treated as entities; more generally, condition, or
      state of being; manner or form of arrangement or
      manifestation; form, as opposed to {matter}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Modes I call such complex ideas, which, however
            compounded, contain not in them the supposition of
            subsisting by themselves, but are considered as
            dependencies on, or affections of, substances.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Logic) The form in which the proposition connects the
      predicate and subject, whether by simple, contingent, or
      necessary assertion; the form of the syllogism, as
      determined by the quantity and quality of the constituent
      proposition; mood.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Gram.) Same as {Mood}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mus.) The scale as affected by the various positions in
      it of the minor intervals; as, the Dorian mode, the Ionic
      mode, etc., of ancient Greek music.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In modern music, only the major and the minor mode, of
         whatever key, are recognized.
         [1913 Webster]

   8. A kind of silk. See {Alamode}, n.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Gram.) the value of the variable in a frequency
      distribution or probability distribution, at which the
      probability or frequency has a maximum. The maximum may be
      local or global. Distributions with only one such maximum
      are called {unimodal}; with two maxima, {bimodal}, and
      with more than two, {multimodal}.
      [PJC]

   Syn: Method; manner. See {Method}.
        [1913 Webster]
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mode n. [common] A general state, usually used with an adjective
   describing the state. Use of the word `mode' rather than `state' implies
   that the state is extended over time, and probably also that some
   activity characteristic of that state is being carried out. "No time to
   hack; I'm in thesis mode." In its jargon sense, `mode' is most often
   attributed to people, though it is sometimes applied to programs and
   inanimate objects. In particular, see {hack mode}, {day mode}, {night
   mode}, {demo mode}, {fireworks mode}, and {yoyo mode}; also {talk mode}.

   One also often hears the verbs `enable' and `disable' used in
   connection with jargon modes. Thus, for example, a sillier way of saying
   "I'm going to crash" is "I'm going to enable crash mode now". One might
   also hear a request to "disable flame mode, please".

   In a usage much closer to techspeak, a mode is a special state that
   certain user interfaces must pass into in order to perform certain
   functions. For example, in order to insert characters into a document in
   the Unix editor `vi', one must type the "i" key, which invokes the
   "Insert" command. The effect of this command is to put vi into "insert
   mode", in which typing the "i" key has a quite different effect (to wit,
   it inserts an "i" into the document). One must then hit another special
   key, "ESC", in order to leave "insert mode". Nowadays, modeful
   interfaces are generally considered {losing} but survive in quite a few
   widely used tools built in less enlightened times.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mode
     n 1: how something is done or how it happens; "her dignified
          manner"; "his rapid manner of talking"; "their nomadic
          mode of existence"; "in the characteristic New York
          style"; "a lonely way of life"; "in an abrasive fashion"
          [syn: {manner}, {style}, {way}, {fashion}]
     2: a particular functioning condition or arrangement; "switched
        from keyboard to voice mode"
     3: a classification of propositions on the basis of whether
        they claim necessity or possibility or impossibility [syn:
         {modality}]
     4: verb inflections that express how the action or state is
        conceived by the speaker [syn: {mood}, {modality}]
     5: any of various fixed orders of the various diatonic notes
        within an octave [syn: {musical mode}]
     6: the most frequent value of a random variable [syn: {modal
        value}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
