<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>model</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>model</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MODEL
     
        &lt;language&gt; A {Pascal}-like language with extensions for
        large-scale system programming and interface with {Fortran}
        applications.  MODEL includes {generic procedures}, and a
        "static" {macro}-like approach to {data abstraction}.  It
        produces {P-code} and was used to implement the {DEMOS}
        {operating system} on the {Cray-1}.
     
        ["A Manual for the MODEL Programming Language", J.B. Morris,
        Los Alamos 1976].
     
        (1996-05-29)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>model</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>model
     
        &lt;simulation&gt; A description of observed behaviour, simplified
        by ignoring certain details.  Models allow complex {systems}
        to be understood and their behaviour predicted within the scope
        of the model, but may give incorrect descriptions and
        predictions for situations outside the realm of their intended
        use.  A model may be used as the basis for {simulation}.
     
        Note: British spelling: "modelling", US: "modeling".
     
        (1996-05-29)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>model</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Model \Mod"el\, n. [F. mod[`e]le, It. modello, fr. (assumed) L.
   modellus, fr. modulus a small measure, dim. of modus. See
   {Mode}, and cf. {Module}.]
   1. A miniature representation of a thing, with the several
      parts in due proportion; sometimes, a facsimile of the
      same size; as, a [frac1x100] scale model of the B-52
      bomber.
      [1913 Webster]

            In charts, in maps, and eke in models made.
                                                  --Gascoigne.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had my father's signet in my purse,
            Which was the model of that Danish seal. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            You have the models of several ancient temples,
            though the temples and the gods are perished.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Something intended to serve, or that may serve, as a
      pattern of something to be made; a material representation
      or embodiment of an ideal; sometimes, a drawing; a plan;
      as, the clay model of a sculpture; the inventor's model of
      a machine.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The application for a patent] must be accompanied
            by a full description of the invention, with
            drawings and a model where the case admits of it.
                                                  --Am. Cyc.
      [1913 Webster]

            When we mean to build
            We first survey the plot, then draw the model.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything which serves, or may serve, as an example for
      imitation; as, a government formed on the model of the
      American constitution; a model of eloquence, virtue, or
      behavior.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That by which a thing is to be measured; standard.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that despairs measures Providence by his own
            little, contracted model.             --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Any copy, or resemblance, more or less exact.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou seest thy wretched brother die,
            Who was the model of thy father's life. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A person who poses as a pattern for an artist; as, the
      artist used his daughter as a model for an Indian maiden.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   7. A person who is employed to wear clothing for the purpose
      of advertising or display, or who poses with a product for
      the same purpose; a mannequin[1]; as, a fashion model.

   Syn: mannequin[1].
        [PJC]

              A professional model.               --H. James.
        [1913 Webster]

   8. A particular version or design of an object that is made
      in multiple versions; as, the 1993 model of the Honda
      Accord; the latest model of the HP laserjet printer. For
      many manufactured products, the model name is encoded as
      part of the

   {model number}.

   Syn: modification[2].
        [PJC]

   9. An abstract and often simplified conceptual representation
      of the workings of a system of objects in the real world,
      which often includes mathematical or logical objects and
      relations representing the objects and relations in the
      real-world system, and constructed for the purpose of
      explaining the workings of the system or predicting its
      behavior under hypothetical conditions; as, the
      administration's model of the United States economy
      predicts budget surpluses for the next fifteen years;
      different models of the universe assume different values
      for the cosmological constant; models of proton structure
      have grown progressively more complex in the past century.
      [PJC]

   {Working model}, a model of a machine which can do on a small
      scale the work which the machine itself does, or is
      expected to do.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>model</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Model \Mod"el\, a.
   Suitable to be taken as a model or pattern; as, a model
   house; a model husband.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>model</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Model \Mod"el\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Modeled}or {Modelled}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Modeling} or {Modelling}.] [Cf. F. modeler, It.
   modellare.]
   To plan or form after a pattern; to form in model; to form a
   model or pattern for; to shape; to mold; to fashion; as, to
   model a house or a government; to model an edifice according
   to the plan delineated.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>model</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Model \Mod"el\, v. i. (Fine Arts)
   To make a copy or a pattern; to design or imitate forms; as,
   to model in wax.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>model</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>model
     adj : worthy of imitation; "exemplary behavior"; "model citizens"
           [syn: {exemplary}, {model(a)}]
     n 1: a simplified description of a complex entity or process;
          "the computer program was based on a model of the
          circulatory and respiratory systems" [syn: {theoretical
          account}, {framework}]
     2: a type of product; "his car was an old model"
     3: a person who poses for a photographer or painter or
        sculptor; "the president didn't have time to be a model so
        the artist worked from photos" [syn: {poser}]
     4: representation of something (sometimes on a smaller scale)
        [syn: {simulation}]
     5: something to be imitated; "an exemplar of success"; "a model
        of clarity"; "he is the very model of a modern major
        general" [syn: {exemplar}, {example}, {good example}]
     6: someone worthy of imitation; "every child needs a role
        model" [syn: {role model}]
     7: a representative form or pattern; "I profited from his
        example" [syn: {example}]
     8: a woman who wears clothes to display fashions; "she was too
        fat to be a mannequin" [syn: {mannequin}, {manikin}, {mannikin},
         {manakin}, {fashion model}]
     9: the act of representing something (usually on a smaller
        scale) [syn: {modelling}, {modeling}]
     v 1: plan or create according to a model or models [syn: {pattern}]
     2: form in clay, wax, etc; "model a head with clay" [syn: {mold},
         {mould}]
     3: assume a posture as for artistic purposes; "We don't know
        the woman who posed for Leonardo so often" [syn: {pose}, {sit},
         {posture}]
     4: display (clothes) as a mannequin; "model the latest fashion"
     5: create a representation or model of; "The pilots are trained
        in conditions simulating high-altitude flights" [syn: {simulate}]
     6: construct a model of; "model an airplane" [syn: {mock up}]
     [also: {modelling}, {modelled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
