<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>moment</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Moment \Mo"ment\, n. [F. moment, L. momentum, for movimentum
   movement, motion, moment, fr. movere to move. See {Move}, and
   cf. {Momentum}, {Movement}.]
   1. A minute portion of time; a point of time; an instant; as,
      at that very moment.
      [1913 Webster]

            In a moment, in the twinkling of an eye. --1 Cor.
                                                  xv. 52.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Impulsive power; force; momentum.
      [1913 Webster]

            The moments or quantities of motion in bodies.
                                                  --Berkley.
      [1913 Webster]

            Touch, with lightest moment of impulse,
            His free will.                        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Importance, as in influence or effect; consequence; weight
      or value; consideration.
      [1913 Webster]

            Matters of great moment.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is an abstruse speculation, but also of far less
            moment and consequence of us than the others.
                                                  --Bentley.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An essential element; a deciding point, fact, or
      consideration; an essential or influential circumstance.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) An infinitesimal change in a varying quantity; an
      increment or decrement. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mech.) Tendency, or measure of tendency, to produce
      motion, esp. motion about a fixed point or axis.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Moment of a couple} (Mech.), the product of either of its
      forces into the perpendicular distance between them.

   {Moment of a force}. (Mech.)
      (a) With respect to a point, the product of the intensity
          of the force into the perpendicular distance from the
          point to the line of direction of the force.
      (b) With respect to a line, the product of that component
          of the force which is perpendicular to the plane
          passing through the line and the point of application
          of the force, into the shortest distance between the
          line and this point.
      (c) With respect to a plane that is parallel to the force,
          the product of the force into the perpendicular
          distance of its point of application from the plane.
          

   {Moment of inertia}, of a rotating body, the sum of the mass
      of each particle of matter of the body into the square of
      its distance from the axis of rotation; -- called also
      {moment of rotation} and {moment of the mass}.

   {Statical moment}, the product of a force into its leverage;
      the same as {moment of a force} with respect to a point,
      line, etc.

   {Virtual moment}. See under {Virtual}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Instant; twinkling; consequence; weight; force; value;
        consideration; signification; avail.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moment</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>moment
     n 1: a particular point in time; "the moment he arrived the party
          began" [syn: {minute}, {second}, {instant}]
     2: an indefinitely short time; "wait just a moment"; "it only
        takes a minute"; "in just a bit" [syn: {minute}, {second},
         {bit}]
     3: at this time; "the disappointments of the here and now";
        "she is studying at the moment" [syn: {here and now}, {present
        moment}]
     4: having important effects or influence; "decisions of great
        consequence are made by the president himself"; "virtue is
        of more moment that security" [syn: {consequence}, {import}]
        [ant: {inconsequence}]
     5: the moment of a couple is the product of its force and the
        distance between its opposing forces
     6: the n-th moment of a distribution is the expected value of
        the n-th power of the deviations from a fixed value
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
