<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>money</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>money</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MONEY, n.  A blessing that is of no advantage to us excepting when we
part with it.  An evidence of culture and a passport to polite
society.  Supportable property.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>money</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Money
   Of uncoined money the first notice we have is in the history of
   Abraham (Gen. 13:2; 20:16; 24:35). Next, this word is used in
   connection with the purchase of the cave of Machpelah (23:16),
   and again in connection with Jacob's purchase of a field at
   Shalem (Gen. 33:18, 19) for "an hundred pieces of money"=an
   hundred Hebrew kesitahs (q.v.), i.e., probably pieces of money,
   as is supposed, bearing the figure of a lamb.
   
     The history of Joseph affords evidence of the constant use of
   money, silver of a fixed weight. This appears also in all the
   subsequent history of the Jewish people, in all their internal
   as well as foreign transactions. There were in common use in
   trade silver pieces of a definite weight, shekels, half-shekels,
   and quarter-shekels. But these were not properly coins, which
   are pieces of metal authoritatively issued, and bearing a stamp.
   
     Of the use of coined money we have no early notice among the
   Hebrews. The first mentioned is of Persian coinage, the daric
   (Ezra 2:69; Neh. 7:70) and the 'adarkon (Ezra 8:27). The daric
   (q.v.) was a gold piece current in Palestine in the time of
   Cyrus. As long as the Jews, after the Exile, lived under Persian
   rule, they used Persian coins. These gave place to Greek coins
   when Palestine came under the dominion of the Greeks (B.C. 331),
   the coins consisting of gold, silver, and copper pieces. The
   usual gold pieces were staters (q.v.), and the silver coins
   tetradrachms and drachms.
   
     In the year B.C. 140, Antiochus VII. gave permission to Simon
   the Maccabee to coin Jewish money. Shekels (q.v.) were then
   coined bearing the figure of the almond rod and the pot of
   manna.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>money</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Money \Mon"ey\, n.; pl. {Moneys}. [OE. moneie, OF. moneie, F.
   monnaie, fr. L. moneta. See {Mint} place where coin is made,
   {Mind}, and cf. {Moidore}, {Monetary}.]
   1. A piece of metal, as gold, silver, copper, etc., coined,
      or stamped, and issued by the sovereign authority as a
      medium of exchange in financial transactions between
      citizens and with government; also, any number of such
      pieces; coin.
      [1913 Webster]

            To prevent such abuses, . . . it has been found
            necessary . . . to affix a public stamp upon certain
            quantities of such particular metals, as were in
            those countries commonly made use of to purchase
            goods. Hence the origin of coined money, and of
            those public offices called mints.    --A. Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any written or stamped promise, certificate, or order, as
      a government note, a bank note, a certificate of deposit,
      etc., which is payable in standard coined money and is
      lawfully current in lieu of it; in a comprehensive sense,
      any currency usually and lawfully employed in buying and
      selling.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any article used as a medium of payment in financial
      transactions, such as checks drawn on checking accounts.
      [PJC]

   4. (Economics) Any form of wealth which affects a person's
      propensity to spend, such as checking accounts or time
      deposits in banks, credit accounts, letters of credit,
      etc. Various aggregates of money in different forms are
      given different names, such as {M-1}, the total sum of all
      currency in circulation plus all money in demand deposit
      accounts (checking accounts).
      [PJC]

   Note: Whatever, among barbarous nations, is used as a medium
         of effecting exchanges of property, and in the terms of
         which values are reckoned, as sheep, wampum, copper
         rings, quills of salt or of gold dust, shovel blades,
         etc., is, in common language, called their money.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. In general, wealth; property; as, he has much money in
      land, or in stocks; to make, or lose, money.
      [1913 Webster]

            The love of money is a root of all kinds of evil.
                                                  --1 Tim vi. 10
                                                  (Rev. Ver. ).
      [1913 Webster]

   {Money bill} (Legislation), a bill for raising revenue.

   {Money broker}, a broker who deals in different kinds of
      money; one who buys and sells bills of exchange; -- called
      also {money changer}.

   {Money cowrie} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      {Cypr[ae]a} (esp. {Cypr[ae]a moneta}) formerly much used
      as money by savage tribes. See {Cowrie}.

   {Money of account}, a denomination of value used in keeping
      accounts, for which there may, or may not, be an
      equivalent coin; e. g., the mill is a money of account in
      the United States, but not a coin.

   {Money order},
      (a) an order for the payment of money; specifically, a
          government order for the payment of money, issued at
          one post office as payable at another; -- called also
          {postal money order}.
      (b) a similar order issued by a bank or other financial
          institution.

   {Money scrivener}, a person who procures the loan of money to
      others. [Eng.]

   {Money spider}, {Money spinner} (Zo["o]l.), a small spider;
      -- so called as being popularly supposed to indicate that
      the person upon whom it crawls will be fortunate in money
      matters.

   {Money's worth}, a fair or full equivalent for the money
      which is paid.

   {A piece of money}, a single coin.

   {Ready money}, money held ready for payment, or actually
      paid, at the time of a transaction; cash.

   {plastic money}, credit cards, usually made out of plastic;
      also called {plastic}; as, put it on the plastic.

   {To make money}, to gain or acquire money or property; to
      make a profit in dealings.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>money</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Money \Mon"ey\, v. t.
   To supply with money. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>money</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>money
     n 1: the most common medium of exchange; functions as legal
          tender; "we tried to collect the money he owed us"
     2: wealth reckoned in terms of money; "all his money is in real
        estate"
     3: the official currency issued by a government or national
        bank; "he changed his money into francs"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
