<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>monitor</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>monitor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>monitor
     
        1. A {cathode-ray tube} and associated electronics connected
        to a computer's video output.  A monitor may be either
        {monochrome} (black and white) or colour ({RGB}).  Colour
        monitors may show either digital colour (each of the red,
        green and blue signals may be either on or off, giving eight
        possible colours: black, white, red, green, blue, cyan,
        magenta and yellow) or analog colour (red, green and blue
        signals are continuously variable allowing any combination to
        be displayed).  Digital monitors are sometimes known as {TTL}
        because the voltages on the red, green and blue inputs are
        compatible with TTL logic chips.
     
        See also {gamut}, {multisync}, {visual display unit}.
     
        2. A programming language construct which encapsulates
        variables, access procedures and initialisation code within an
        abstract data type.  The monitor's variable may only be
        accessed via its access procedures and only one process may be
        actively accessing the monitor at any one time.  The access
        procedures are {critical section}s.  A monitor may have a
        queue of processes which are waiting to access it.
     
        3. A hardware device that measures electrical events such as
        pulses or voltage levels in a digital computer.
     
        4. To oversee a program during execution.  For example, the
        monitor function in the {Unix} {C} library enables profiling
        of a certain range of code addresses.  A histogram is produced
        showing how often the {program counter} was found to be at
        each position and how often each profiled function was called.
     
        {Unix} {man} page: monitor(3).
     
        5. A control program within the {operating system} that
        manages the allocation of system resources to active
        programs.
     
        6. A program that measures software performance.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>monitor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Monitor \Mon"i*tor\, n. [L., fr. monere. See {Monition}, and cf.
   {Mentor}.]
   1. One who admonishes; one who warns of faults, informs of
      duty, or gives advice and instruction by way of reproof or
      caution.
      [1913 Webster]

            You need not be a monitor to the king. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, specifically, a pupil selected to look to the
      school in the absence of the instructor, to notice the
      absence or faults of the scholars, or to instruct a
      division or class.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) Any large Old World lizard of the genus
      {Varanus}; esp., the Egyptian species ({Varanus
      Niloticus}), which is useful because it devours the eggs
      and young of the crocodile. It is sometimes five or six
      feet long.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. [So called from the name given by Captain Ericson, its
      designer, to the first ship of the kind.] An ironclad war
      vessel, very low in the water, and having one or more
      heavily-armored revolving turrets, carrying heavy guns.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mach.) A tool holder, as for a lathe, shaped like a low
      turret, and capable of being revolved on a vertical pivot
      so as to bring successively the several tools in holds
      into proper position for cutting.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A monitor nozzle.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Monitor top}, the raised central portion, or clearstory, of
      a car roof, having low windows along its sides.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>monitor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>monitor
     n 1: display consisting of a device that takes signals from a
          computer and displays them on a CRT screen [syn: {monitoring
          device}]
     2: someone who supervises (an examination) [syn: {proctor}]
     3: someone who gives a warning so that a mistake can be avoided
        [syn: {admonisher}, {reminder}]
     4: an iron-clad vessel built by Federal forces to do battle
        with the Merrimac
     5: electronic equipment that is used to check the quality or
        content of electronic transmissions
     6: a piece of electronic equipment that keeps track of the
        operation of a system continuously and warns of trouble
     7: any of various large tropical carnivorous lizards of Africa
        and Asia and Australia; fabled to warn of crocodiles [syn:
         {monitor lizard}, {varan}]
     v : keep tabs on; keep an eye on; keep under surveillance [syn:
         {supervise}, {ride herd on}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
