<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>monk</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>monk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Monk \Monk\, n. [AS. munuc, munec, munc, L. monachus, Gr. ?, fr.
   mo`nos alone. Cf. {Monachism}.]
   1. A man who retires from the ordinary temporal concerns of
      the world, and devotes himself to religion; one of a
      religious community of men inhabiting a monastery, and
      bound by vows to a life of chastity, obedience, and
      poverty. ``A monk out of his cloister.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Monks in some respects agree with regulars, as in
            the substantial vows of religion; but in other
            respects monks and regulars differ; for that
            regulars, vows excepted, are not tied up to so
            strict a rule of life as monks are.   --Ayliffe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Print.) A blotch or spot of ink on a printed page, caused
      by the ink not being properly distributed. It is
      distinguished from a friar, or white spot caused by a
      deficiency of ink.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A piece of tinder made of agaric, used in firing the
      powder hose or train of a mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A South American monkey ({Pithecia monachus}); also
          applied to other species, as {Cebus xanthocephalus}.
      (b) The European bullfinch.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Monk bat} (Zo["o]l.), a South American and West Indian bat
      ({Molossus nasutus}); -- so called because the males live
      in communities by themselves.

   {Monk bird}(Zo["o]l.), the friar bird.

   {Monk seal} (Zo["o]l.), a species of seal ({Monachus
      albiventer}) inhabiting the Black Sea, the Mediterranean
      Sea, and the adjacent parts of the Atlantic.

   {Monk's rhubarb} (Bot.), a kind of dock; -- also called
      {patience} ({Rumex Patientia}).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>monk</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>monk
     n 1: a male religious living in a cloister and devoting himself
          to contemplation and prayer and work [syn: {monastic}]
     2: United States jazz pianist who was one of the founders of
        the bebop style (1917-1982) [syn: {Thelonious Monk}, {Thelonious
        Sphere Monk}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
