<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>moral</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moral</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MORAL, adj.  Conforming to a local and mutable standard of right. 
Having the quality of general expediency.

        It is sayd there be a raunge of mountaynes in the Easte, on
one syde of the which certayn conducts are immorall, yet on the other
syde they are holden in good esteeme; wherebye the mountayneer is much
conveenyenced, for it is given to him to goe downe eyther way and act
as it shall suite his moode, withouten offence.
                                                 _Gooke's Meditations_


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moral</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MORAL
     
        Mentioned in "An Overview of Ada", J.G.P. Barnes, Soft Prac &amp;
        Exp 10:851-887 (1980).
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moral</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Moral \Mor"al\, a. [F., fr. It. moralis, fr. mos, moris, manner,
   custom, habit, way of life, conduct.]
   1. Relating to duty or obligation; pertaining to those
      intentions and actions of which right and wrong, virtue
      and vice, are predicated, or to the rules by which such
      intentions and actions ought to be directed; relating to
      the practice, manners, or conduct of men as social beings
      in relation to each other, as respects right and wrong, so
      far as they are properly subject to rules.
      [1913 Webster]

            Keep at the least within the compass of moral
            actions, which have in them vice or virtue.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mankind is broken loose from moral bands. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            She had wandered without rule or guidance in a moral
            wilderness.                           --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Conformed to accepted rules of right; acting in conformity
      with such rules; virtuous; just; as, a moral man. Used
      sometimes in distinction from religious; as, a moral
      rather than a religious life.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wiser and more moral part of mankind. --Sir M.
                                                  Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Capable of right and wrong action or of being governed by
      a sense of right; subject to the law of duty.
      [1913 Webster]

            A moral agent is a being capable of those actions
            that have a moral quality, and which can properly be
            denominated good or evil in a moral sense. --J.
                                                  Edwards.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Acting upon or through one's moral nature or sense of
      right, or suited to act in such a manner; as, a moral
      arguments; moral considerations. Sometimes opposed to
      {material} and {physical}; as, moral pressure or support.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Supported by reason or probability; practically
      sufficient; -- opposed to {legal} or {demonstrable}; as, a
      moral evidence; a moral certainty.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Serving to teach or convey a moral; as, a moral lesson;
      moral tales.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Moral agent}, a being who is capable of acting with
      reference to right and wrong.

   {Moral certainty}, a very high degree or probability,
      although not demonstrable as a certainty; a probability of
      so high a degree that it can be confidently acted upon in
      the affairs of life; as, there is a moral certainty of his
      guilt.

   {Moral insanity}, insanity, so called, of the moral system;
      badness alleged to be irresponsible.

   {Moral philosophy}, the science of duty; the science which
      treats of the nature and condition of man as a moral
      being, of the duties which result from his moral
      relations, and the reasons on which they are founded.

   {Moral play}, an allegorical play; a morality. [Obs.]

   {Moral sense}, the power of moral judgment and feeling; the
      capacity to perceive what is right or wrong in moral
      conduct, and to approve or disapprove, independently of
      education or the knowledge of any positive rule or law.

   {Moral theology}, theology applied to morals; practical
      theology; casuistry.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moral</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Moral \Mor"al\, v. i.
   To moralize. [Obs.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moral</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Moral \Mor"al\, n.
   1. The doctrine or practice of the duties of life; manner of
      living as regards right and wrong; conduct; behavior; --
      usually in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            Corrupt in their morals as vice could make them.
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The inner meaning or significance of a fable, a narrative,
      an occurrence, an experience, etc.; the practical lesson
      which anything is designed or fitted to teach; the
      doctrine meant to be inculcated by a fiction; a maxim.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus may we gather honey from the weed,
            And make a moral of the devil himself. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To point a moral, or adorn a tale.    --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

            We protest against the principle that the world of
            pure comedy is one into which no moral enters.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A morality play. See {Morality}, 5.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>moral</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>moral
     adj 1: relating to principles of right and wrong; i.e. to morals or
            ethics; "moral philosophy"
     2: concerned with principles of right and wrong or conforming
        to standards of behavior and character based on those
        principles; "moral sense"; "a moral scrutiny"; "a moral
        lesson"; "a moral quandary"; "moral convictions"; "a moral
        life" [ant: {immoral}, {amoral}]
     3: adhering to ethical and moral principles; "it seems ethical
        and right"; "followed the only honorable course of
        action"; "had the moral courage to stand alone" [syn: {ethical},
         {honorable}, {honourable}]
     4: arising from the sense of right and wrong; "a moral
        obligation"
     5: psychological rather than physical or tangible in effect; "a
        moral victory"; "moral support"
     6: based on strong likelihood or firm conviction rather than
        actual evidence; "a moral certainty" [syn: {moral(a)}]
     n : the significance of a story or event; "the moral of the
         story is to love thy neighbor" [syn: {lesson}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
