<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mount</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mount</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mount
   Palestine is a hilly country (Deut. 3:25; 11:11; Ezek. 34:13).
   West of Jordan the mountains stretch from Lebanon far down into
   Galilee, terminating in Carmel. The isolated peak of Tabor rises
   from the elevated plain of Esdraelon, which, in the south, is
   shut in by hills spreading over the greater part of Samaria. The
   mountains of Western and Middle Palestine do not extend to the
   sea, but gently slope into plains, and toward the Jordan fall
   down into the Ghor.
   
     East of the Jordan the Anti-Lebanon, stretching south,
   terminates in the hilly district called Jebel Heish, which
   reaches down to the Sea of Gennesareth. South of the river
   Hieromax there is again a succession of hills, which are
   traversed by wadies running toward the Jordan. These gradually
   descend to a level at the river Arnon, which was the boundary of
   the ancient trans-Jordanic territory toward the south.
   
     The composition of the Palestinian hills is limestone, with
   occasional strata of chalk, and hence the numerous caves, some
   of large extent, found there.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mount</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mount
     
        &lt;file system&gt; To make a {file system} available for access.
     
        {Unix} does this by associating the file system with a
        {directory} (the "mount point") within a currently mounted
        file system.  The "root" file system is mounted on the {root
        directory}, "/" early in the {boot} sequence.  "mount" is also
        the {Unix} command to do this, "unmount" breaks the
        association.
     
        E.g., "mount attaches a named file system to the file system
        hierarchy at the pathname location directory [...]" -- {Unix
        manual page} mount(8).
     
        File systems are usually mounted either at {boot time} under
        control of {/etc/rc} (or one of its subfiles) or on demand by
        an {automounter} {daemon}.
     
        Other {operating systems} such as {VMS} and {DOS} mount file
        systems as separate directory hierarchies without any common
        ancestor or root directory.
     
        Apparently derived from the physical sense of "mount" meaning
        "attach", as in "head-mounted display", or "set up", as in
        "always mount a {scratch monkey}, etc."
     
        {Unix manual page}: mount(8).
     
        (1997-04-14)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mount</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mount \Mount\, n. [From {Mount}, v.]
   That upon which a person or thing is mounted, especially:
   (a) A horse.
       [1913 Webster]

             She had so good a seat and hand, she might be
             trusted with any mount.              --G. Eliot.
       [1913 Webster]
   (b) The cardboard or cloth on which a drawing, photograph, or
       the like is mounted; a mounting.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mount</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mount \Mount\, v. t.
   1. To get upon; to ascend; to climb; as, to mount the pulpit
      and deliver a sermon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shall we mount again the rural throne? --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To place one's self on, as a horse or other animal, or
      anything that one sits upon; to bestride.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to mount; to put on horseback; to furnish with
      animals for riding; to furnish with horses. ``To mount the
      Trojan troop.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence: To put upon anything that sustains and fits for
      use, as a gun on a carriage, a map or picture on cloth or
      paper; to prepare for being worn or otherwise used, as a
      diamond by setting, or a sword blade by adding the hilt,
      scabbard, etc.; as, to mount a picture or diploma in a
      frame
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To raise aloft; to lift on high.
      [1913 Webster]

            What power is it which mounts my love so high?
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A fort or ship is said to mount cannon, when it has
         them arranged for use in or about it.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To mount guard} (Mil.), to go on guard; to march on guard;
      to do duty as a guard.

   {To mount a play}, to prepare and arrange the scenery,
      furniture, etc., used in the play.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mount</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mount \Mount\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Mounted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Mounting}.] [OE. mounten, monten, F. monter, fr. L. mons,
   montis, mountain. See {Mount}, n. (above).]
   1. To rise on high; to go up; to be upraised or uplifted; to
      tower aloft; to ascend; -- often with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though Babylon should mount up to heaven. --Jer. li.
                                                  53.
      [1913 Webster]

            The fire of trees and houses mounts on high.
                                                  --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To get up on anything, as a platform or scaffold;
      especially, to seat one's self on a horse for riding.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To attain in value; to amount.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bring then these blessings to a strict account,
            Make fair deductions, see to what they mount.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mount</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mount \Mount\ (mount), n. [OE. munt, mont, mount, AS. munt, fr.
   L. mons, montis; cf. L. minae protections, E. eminent,
   menace: cf. F. mont. Cf. {Mount}, v., {Mountain}, {Mont},
   {Monte}, {Montem}.]
   1. A mass of earth, or earth and rock, rising considerably
      above the common surface of the surrounding land; a
      mountain; a high hill; -- used always instead of mountain,
      when put before a proper name; as, Mount Washington;
      otherwise, chiefly in poetry.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A bulwark for offense or defense; a mound. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Hew ye down trees, and cast a mount against
            Jerusalem.                            --Jer. vi. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. [See {Mont de pi['e]t['e]}.] A bank; a fund.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Palmistry) Any one of seven fleshy prominences in the
      palm of the hand which are taken as significant of the
      influence of ``planets,'' and called the mounts of
      Jupiter, Mars, Mercury, the Moon, Saturn, the Sun or
      Apollo, and Venus.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Mount of piety}. See {Mont de pi['e]t['e]}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mount</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mount
     n 1: a lightweight horse kept for riding only [syn: {saddle horse},
           {riding horse}]
     2: the act of climbing something; "it was a difficult climb to
        the top" [syn: {climb}]
     3: a land mass that projects well above its surroundings;
        higher than a hill [syn: {mountain}]
     4: mounting consisting of a piece of metal (as in a ring or
        other jewelry) that holds a gem in place; "the diamond was
        in a plain gold mount" [syn: {setting}]
     5: something forming a back that is added for strengthening
        [syn: {backing}]
     v 1: attach to a support; "They mounted the aerator on a
          floating"
     2: go up or advance; "Sales were climbing after prices were
        lowered" [syn: {wax}, {climb}, {rise}] [ant: {wane}]
     3: fix onto a backing, setting, or support; "mount slides for
        macroscopic analysis"
     4: put up or launch; "mount a campaign against pronography"
     5: get on the back of; "mount a horse" [syn: {hop on}, {mount
        up}, {get on}, {jump on}, {climb on}, {bestride}] [ant: {hop
        out}]
     6: go upward with gradual or continuous progress; "Did you ever
        climb up the hill behind your house?" [syn: {climb}, {climb
        up}, {go up}]
     7: prepare and supply with the necessary equipment for
        execution or performance; "mount a theater production";
        "mount an attack"; "mount a play" [syn: {put on}]
     8: copulate with; "The bull was riding the cow" [syn: {ride}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
