<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mountain</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mountain, ND (city, FIPS 54740)
  Location: 48.68345 N, 97.86340 W
  Population (1990): 134 (57 housing units)
  Area: 0.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 58262
Mountain, WI
  Zip code(s): 54149
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gun \Gun\ (g[u^]n), n. [OE. gonne, gunne; of uncertain origin;
   cf. Ir., Gael., &amp; LL. gunna, W. gum; possibly (like cannon)
   fr. L. canna reed, tube; or abbreviated fr. OF. mangonnel, E.
   mangonel, a machine for hurling stones.]
   1. A weapon which throws or propels a missile to a distance;
      any firearm or instrument for throwing projectiles,
      consisting of a tube or barrel closed at one end, in which
      the projectile is placed, with an explosive charge (such
      as guncotton or gunpowder) behind, which is ignited by
      various means. Pistols, rifles, carbines, muskets, and
      fowling pieces are smaller guns, for hand use, and are
      called {small arms}. Larger guns are called {cannon},
      {ordnance}, {fieldpieces}, {carronades}, {howitzers}, etc.
      See these terms in the Vocabulary.
      [1913 Webster]

            As swift as a pellet out of a gunne
            When fire is in the powder runne.     --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The word gun was in use in England for an engine to
            cast a thing from a man long before there was any
            gunpowder found out.                  --Selden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) A piece of heavy ordnance; in a restricted sense, a
      cannon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. (Naut.) Violent blasts of wind.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Guns are classified, according to their construction or
         manner of loading as {rifled} or {smoothbore},
         {breech-loading} or {muzzle-loading}, {cast} or
         {built-up guns}; or according to their use, as {field},
         {mountain}, {prairie}, {seacoast}, and {siege guns}.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Armstrong gun}, a wrought iron breech-loading cannon named
      after its English inventor, Sir William Armstrong.

   {Big gun} or {Great gun}, a piece of heavy ordnance; hence
      (Fig.), a person superior in any way; as, bring in the big
      guns to tackle the problem.

   {Gun barrel}, the barrel or tube of a gun.

   {Gun carriage}, the carriage on which a gun is mounted or
      moved.

   {Gun cotton} (Chem.), a general name for a series of
      explosive nitric ethers of cellulose, obtained by steeping
      cotton in nitric and sulphuric acids. Although there are
      formed substances containing nitric acid radicals, yet the
      results exactly resemble ordinary cotton in appearance. It
      burns without ash, with explosion if confined, but quietly
      and harmlessly if free and open, and in small quantity.
      Specifically, the lower nitrates of cellulose which are
      insoluble in ether and alcohol in distinction from the
      highest (pyroxylin) which is soluble. See {Pyroxylin}, and
      cf. {Xyloidin}. The gun cottons are used for blasting and
      somewhat in gunnery: for making celluloid when compounded
      with camphor; and the soluble variety (pyroxylin) for
      making collodion. See {Celluloid}, and {Collodion}. Gun
      cotton is frequenty but improperly called
      {nitrocellulose}. It is not a nitro compound, but an ester
      of nitric acid.

   {Gun deck}. See under {Deck}.

   {Gun fire}, the time at which the morning or the evening gun
      is fired.

   {Gun metal}, a bronze, ordinarily composed of nine parts of
      copper and one of tin, used for cannon, etc. The name is
      also given to certain strong mixtures of cast iron.

   {Gun port} (Naut.), an opening in a ship through which a
      cannon's muzzle is run out for firing.

   {Gun tackle} (Naut.), the blocks and pulleys affixed to the
      side of a ship, by which a gun carriage is run to and from
      the gun port.

   {Gun tackle purchase} (Naut.), a tackle composed of two
      single blocks and a fall. --Totten.

   {Krupp gun}, a wrought steel breech-loading cannon, named
      after its German inventor, Herr Krupp.

   {Machine gun}, a breech-loading gun or a group of such guns,
      mounted on a carriage or other holder, and having a
      reservoir containing cartridges which are loaded into the
      gun or guns and fired in rapid succession. In earlier
      models, such as the {Gatling gun}, the cartridges were
      loaded by machinery operated by turning a crank. In modern
      versions the loading of cartidges is accomplished by
      levers operated by the recoil of the explosion driving the
      bullet, or by the pressure of gas within the barrel.
      Several hundred shots can be fired in a minute by such
      weapons, with accurate aim. The {Gatling gun}, {Gardner
      gun}, {Hotchkiss gun}, and {Nordenfelt gun}, named for
      their inventors, and the French {mitrailleuse}, are
      machine guns.

   {To blow great guns} (Naut.), to blow a gale. See {Gun}, n.,
      3.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mountain \Moun"tain\ (moun"t[i^]n), a.
   1. Of or pertaining to a mountain or mountains; growing or
      living on a mountain; found on or peculiar to mountains;
      among mountains; as, a mountain torrent; mountain pines;
      mountain goats; mountain air; mountain howitzer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Like a mountain; mountainous; vast; very great.
      [1913 Webster]

            The high, the mountain majesty of worth. --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Mountain antelope} (Zo["o]l.), the goral.

   {Mountain ash} (Bot.), an ornamental tree, the {Pyrus
      Americana} (or {Sorbus Americana}), producing beautiful
      bunches of red berries. Its leaves are pinnate, and its
      flowers white, growing in fragrant clusters. The European
      species is the {Pyrus aucuparia}, or rowan tree.

   {Mountain barometer}, a portable barometer, adapted for safe
      transportation, used in measuring the heights of
      mountains.

   {Mountain beaver} (Zo["o]l.), the sewellel.

   {Mountain blue} (Min.), blue carbonate of copper; azurite.

   {Mountain cat} (Zo["o]l.), the catamount. See {Catamount}.

   {Mountain chain}, a series of contiguous mountain ranges,
      generally in parallel or consecutive lines or curves.

   {Mountain cock} (Zo["o]l.), capercailzie. See {Capercailzie}.
      

   {Mountain cork} (Min.), a variety of asbestus, resembling
      cork in its texture.

   {Mountain crystal}. See under {Crystal}.

   {Mountain damson} (Bot.), a large tree of the genus
      {Simaruba} ({Simaruba amarga}) growing in the West Indies,
      which affords a bitter tonic and astringent, sometimes
      used in medicine.

   {Mountain dew}, Scotch whisky, so called because often
      illicitly distilled among the mountains. [Humorous]

   {Mountain ebony} (Bot.), a small leguminous tree ({Bauhinia
      variegata}) of the East and West Indies; -- so called
      because of its dark wood. The bark is used medicinally and
      in tanning.

   {Mountain flax} (Min.), a variety of asbestus, having very
      fine fibers; amianthus. See {Amianthus}.

   {Mountain fringe} (Bot.), climbing fumitory. See under
      {Fumitory}.

   {Mountain goat}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Mazama}.

   {Mountain green}. (Min.)
      (a) Green malachite, or carbonate of copper.
      (b) See {Green earth}, under {Green}, a.

   {Mountain holly} (Bot.), a branching shrub ({Nemopanthes
      Canadensis}), having smooth oblong leaves and red berries.
      It is found in the Northern United States.

   {Mountain laurel} (Bot.), an American shrub ({Kalmia
      latifolia}) with glossy evergreen leaves and showy
      clusters of rose-colored or white flowers. The foliage is
      poisonous. Called also {American laurel}, {ivy bush}, and
      {calico bush}. See {Kalmia}.

   {Mountain leather} (Min.), a variety of asbestus, resembling
      leather in its texture.

   {Mountain licorice} (Bot.), a plant of the genus {Trifolium}
      ({Trifolium Alpinum}).

   {Mountain limestone} (Geol.), a series of marine limestone
      strata below the coal measures, and above the old red
      standstone of Great Britain. See Chart of {Geology}.

   {Mountain linnet} (Zo["o]l.), the twite.

   {Mountain magpie}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The yaffle, or green woodpecker.
      (b) The European gray shrike.

   {Mountain mahogany} (Bot.) See under {Mahogany}.

   {Mountain meal} (Min.), a light powdery variety of calcite,
      occurring as an efflorescence.

   {Mountain milk} (Min.), a soft spongy variety of carbonate of
      lime.

   {Mountain mint}. (Bot.) See {Mint}.

   {Mountain ousel} (Zo["o]l.), the ring ousel; -- called also
      {mountain thrush} and {mountain colley}. See {Ousel}.

   {Mountain pride}, or {Mountain green} (Bot.), a tree of
      Jamaica ({Spathelia simplex}), which has an unbranched
      palmlike stem, and a terminal cluster of large, pinnate
      leaves.

   {Mountain quail} (Zo["o]l.), the plumed partridge ({Oreortyx
      pictus}) of California. It has two long, slender,
      plumelike feathers on the head. The throat and sides are
      chestnut; the belly is brown with transverse bars of black
      and white; the neck and breast are dark gray.

   {Mountain range}, a series of mountains closely related in
      position and direction.

   {Mountain rice}. (Bot.)
      (a) An upland variety of rice, grown without irrigation,
          in some parts of Asia, Europe, and the United States.
      (b) An American genus of grasses ({Oryzopsis}).

   {Mountain rose} (Bot.), a species of rose with solitary
      flowers, growing in the mountains of Europe ({Rosa
      alpina}).

   {Mountain soap} (Min.), a soft earthy mineral, of a brownish
      color, used in crayon painting; saxonite.

   {Mountain sorrel} (Bot.), a low perennial plant ({Oxyria
      digyna} with rounded kidney-form leaves, and small
      greenish flowers, found in the White Mountains of New
      Hampshire, and in high northern latitudes. --Gray.

   {Mountain sparrow} (Zo["o]l.), the European tree sparrow.

   {Mountain spinach}. (Bot.) See {Orach}.

   {Mountain tobacco} (Bot.), a composite plant ({Arnica
      montana}) of Europe; called also {leopard's bane}.

   {Mountain witch} (Zo["o]l.), a ground pigeon of Jamaica, of
      the genus {Geotrygon}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mountain \Moun"tain\, n. [OE. mountaine, montaine, F. montagne,
   LL. montanea, montania, fr. L. mons, montis, a mountain; cf.
   montanus belonging to a mountain. See 1st {Mount}.]
   1. A large mass of earth and rock, rising above the common
      level of the earth or adjacent land; earth and rock
      forming an isolated peak or a ridge; an eminence higher
      than a hill; a mount.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. A range, chain, or group of such elevations; as, the
      White Mountains.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A mountainlike mass; something of great bulk; a large
      quantity.
      [1913 Webster]

            I should have been a mountain of mummy. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {The Mountain} (--La montagne) (French Hist.), a popular name
      given in 1793 to a party of extreme Jacobins in the
      National Convention, who occupied the highest rows of
      seats.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mountain</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mountain
     adj : relating to or located in mountains; "mountain people" [syn:
            {mountain(a)}]
     n 1: a land mass that projects well above its surroundings;
          higher than a hill [syn: {mount}]
     2: a large number or amount; "made lots of new friends"; "she
        amassed a mountain of newspapers" [syn: {tons}, {dozens},
        {heaps}, {lots}, {piles}, {scores}, {stacks}, {loads}, {rafts},
         {slews}, {wads}, {oodles}, {gobs}, {scads}, {lashings}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
