<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>movement</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>movement</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Movement \Move"ment\, n. [F. mouvement. See {Move}, and cf.
   {Moment}.]
   1. The act of moving in space; change of place or posture;
      motion; as, the movement of an army in marching or
      maneuvering; the movement of a wheel or a machine.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Manner or style of moving; as, a slow, or quick, or
      sudden, movement.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Transference, by any means, from one situation to another;
      a change of situation; progress toward a goal;
      advancement; as, after months of fruitless discussion
      there was finally some movement toward an agreement.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. Motion of the mind or feelings; emotion.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.)
      (a) The rhythmical progression, pace, and tempo of a
          piece. ``Any change of time is a change of movement.''
          --Busby.
      (b) One of the several strains or pieces, each complete in
          itself, with its own time and rhythm, which make up a
          larger work; as, the several movements of a suite or a
          symphony.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mech.) A system of mechanism for transmitting motion of a
      definite character, or for transforming motion; as, the
      wheelwork of a watch; as, a seventeen jewel movement.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A more or less organized effort by many people to achieve
      some goal, especially a social or artistic goal; as, the
      women's liberation movement; the progressive movement in
      architecture.
      [PJC]

   {Febrile movement} (Med.), an elevation of the body
      temperature; a fever.

   {Movement cure}. (Med.) See {Kinesiatrics}.

   {Movement of the bowels}, an evacuation or stool; a passage
      or discharge.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Motion.

   Usage: {Movement}, {Motion}. Motion expresses a general idea
          of not being at rest; movement is oftener used to
          express a definite, regulated motion, esp. a progress.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>movement</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>movement
     n 1: a change of position that does not entail a change of
          location; "the reflex motion of his eyebrows revealed
          his surprise"; "movement is a sign of life"; "an
          impatient move of his hand"; "gastrointestinal motility"
          [syn: {motion}, {move}, {motility}]
     2: a natural event that involves a change in the position or
        location of something [syn: {motion}]
     3: the act of changing location from one place to another;
        "police controlled the motion of the crowd"; "the movement
        of people from the farms to the cities"; "his move put him
        directly in my path" [syn: {motion}, {move}]
     4: a group of people with a common ideology who try together to
        achieve certain general goals; "he was a charter member of
        the movement"; "politicians have to respect a mass
        movement"; "he led the national liberation front" [syn: {social
        movement}, {front}]
     5: a major self-contained part of a symphony or sonata; "the
        second movement is slow and melodic"
     6: a series of actions advancing a principle or tending toward
        a particular end; "he supported populist campaigns"; "they
        worked in the cause of world peace"; "the team was ready
        for a drive toward the pennant"; "the movement to end
        slavery"; "contributed to the war effort" [syn: {campaign},
         {cause}, {crusade}, {drive}, {effort}]
     7: an optical illusion of motion produced by viewing a rapid
        succession of still pictures of a moving object; "the
        cinema relies on apparent motion"; "the succession of
        flashing lights gave an illusion of movement" [syn: {apparent
        motion}, {motion}, {apparent movement}]
     8: a euphemism for defecation; "he had a bowel movement" [syn:
        {bowel movement}, {bm}]
     9: a general tendency to change (as of opinion); "not openly
        liberal but that is the trend of the book"; "a broad
        movement of the electorate to the right" [syn: {drift}, {trend}]
     10: the driving and regulating parts of a mechanism (as of a
         watch or clock); "it was an expensive watch with a
         diamond movement"
     11: the act of changing the location of something; "the movement
         of cargo onto the vessel"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
