<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>multiplication</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>multiplication</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compound \Com"pound\, a. [OE. compouned, p. p. of compounen. See
   {Compound}, v. t.]
   Composed of two or more elements, ingredients, parts;
   produced by the union of several ingredients, parts, or
   things; composite; as, a compound word.
   [1913 Webster]

         Compound substances are made up of two or more simple
         substances.                              --I. Watts.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Compound addition}, {subtraction}, {multiplication},
   {division} (Arith.), the addition, subtraction, etc., of
      compound numbers.

   {Compound crystal} (Crystallog.), a twin crystal, or one
      seeming to be made up of two or more crystals combined
      according to regular laws of composition.

   {Compound engine} (Mech.), a form of steam engine in which
      the steam that has been used in a high-pressure cylinder
      is made to do further service in a larger low-pressure
      cylinder, sometimes in several larger cylinders,
      successively.

   {Compound ether}. (Chem.) See under {Ether}.

   {Compound flower} (Bot.), a flower head resembling a single
      flower, but really composed of several florets inclosed in
      a common calyxlike involucre, as the sunflower or
      dandelion.

   {Compound fraction}. (Math.) See {Fraction}.

   {Compound fracture}. See {Fracture}.

   {Compound householder}, a householder who compounds or
      arranges with his landlord that his rates shall be
      included in his rents. [Eng.]

   {Compound interest}. See {Interest}.

   {Compound larceny}. (Law) See {Larceny}.

   {Compound leaf} (Bot.), a leaf having two or more separate
      blades or leaflets on a common leafstalk.

   {Compound microscope}. See {Microscope}.

   {Compound motion}. See {Motion}.

   {Compound number} (Math.), one constructed according to a
      varying scale of denomination; as, 3 cwt., 1 qr., 5 lb.;
      -- called also {denominate number}.

   {Compound pier} (Arch.), a clustered column.

   {Compound quantity} (Alg.), a quantity composed of two or
      more simple quantities or terms, connected by the sign +
      (plus) or - (minus). Thus, a + b - c, and bb - b, are
      compound quantities.

   {Compound radical}. (Chem.) See {Radical}.

   {Compound ratio} (Math.), the product of two or more ratios;
      thus ab:cd is a ratio compounded of the simple ratios a:c
      and b:d.

   {Compound rest} (Mech.), the tool carriage of an engine
      lathe.

   {Compound screw} (Mech.), a screw having on the same axis two
      or more screws with different pitch (a differential
      screw), or running in different directions (a right and
      left screw).

   {Compound time} (Mus.), that in which two or more simple
      measures are combined in one; as, 6-8 time is the joining
      of two measures of 3-8 time.

   {Compound word}, a word composed of two or more words;
      specifically, two or more words joined together by a
      hyphen.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>multiplication</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Multiplication \Mul`ti*pli*ca"tion\, n. [L. multiplicatio: cf.
   F. multiplication. See {Multiply}.]
   1. The act or process of multiplying, or of increasing in
      number; the state of being multiplied; as, the
      multiplication of the human species by natural generation.
      [1913 Webster]

            The increase and multiplication of the world.
                                                  --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Math.) The process of repeating, or adding to itself, any
      given number or quantity a certain number of times;
      commonly, the process of ascertaining by a briefer
      computation the result of such repeated additions; also,
      the rule by which the operation is performed; -- the
      reverse of division.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The word multiplication is sometimes used in
         mathematics, particularly in multiple algebra, to
         denote any distributive operation expressed by one
         symbol upon any quantity or any thing expressed by
         another symbol. Corresponding extensions of meaning are
         given to the words multiply, multiplier, multiplicand,
         and product. Thus, since [phi](x + y) = [phi]x + [phi]y
         (see under {Distributive}), where [phi](x + y), [phi]x,
         and [phi]y indicate the results of any distributive
         operation represented by the symbol [phi] upon x + y,
         x, and y, severally, then because of many very useful
         analogies [phi](x + y) is called the product of [phi]
         and x + y, and the operation indicated by [phi] is
         called multiplication. Cf. {Facient}, n., 2.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) An increase above the normal number of parts,
      especially of petals; augmentation.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The art of increasing gold or silver by magic, --
      attributed formerly to the alchemists. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Multiplication table}, a table giving the product of a set
      of numbers multiplied in some regular way; commonly, a
      table giving the products of the first ten or twelve
      numbers multiplied successively by 1, 2, 3, etc., up to 10
      or 12. Called also a {times table}, used by students in
      elementary school prior to memorization of the table.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>multiplication</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>multiplication
     n 1: an arithmetic operation that is the inverse of division; the
          product of two numbers is computed; "the multiplication
          of four by three gives twelve"; "four times three equals
          twelve" [syn: {times}]
     2: the act of producing offspring or multiplying by such
        production [syn: {generation}, {propagation}]
     3: a multiplicative increase; "repeated copying leads to a
        multiplication of errors"; "this multiplication of cells
        is a natural correlate of growth"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
