<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>multiple</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>multiple</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Parallel \Par"al*lel\, n.
   1. A line which, throughout its whole extent, is equidistant
      from another line; a parallel line, a parallel plane, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who made the spider parallels design,
            Sure as De Moivre, without rule or line ? --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Direction conformable to that of another line,
      [1913 Webster]

            Lines that from their parallel decline. --Garth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Conformity continued through many particulars or in all
      essential points; resemblance; similarity.
      [1913 Webster]

            Twixt earthly females and the moon
            All parallels exactly run.            --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A comparison made; elaborate tracing of similarity; as,
      Johnson's parallel between Dryden and Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Anything equal to, or resembling, another in all essential
      particulars; a counterpart.
      [1913 Webster]

            None but thyself can be thy parallel. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Geog.) One of the imaginary circles on the surface of the
      earth, parallel to the equator, marking the latitude;
      also, the corresponding line on a globe or map; as, the
      counry was divided into North and South at the 38th
      parallel.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   7. (Mil.) One of a series of long trenches constructed before
      a besieged fortress, by the besieging force, as a cover
      for troops supporting the attacking batteries. They are
      roughly parallel to the line of outer defenses of the
      fortress.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Print.) A character consisting of two parallel vertical
      lines (thus, ||) used in the text to direct attention to a
      similarly marked note in the margin or at the foot of a
      page.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Elec.) That arrangement of an electrical system in which
      all positive poles, electrodes, terminals, etc., are
      joined to one conductor, and all negative poles, etc., to
      another conductor; -- called also {multiple}. Opposed to
      {series}.

   Note: Parts of a system so arranged are said to be

   {in parallel} or

   {in multiple}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Limiting parallels}. See under {Limit}, v. t.

   {Parallel of altitude} (Astron.), one of the small circles of
      the sphere, parallel to the horizon; an almucantar.

   {Parallel of declination} (Astron.), one of the small circles
      of the sphere, parallel to the equator.

   {Parallel of latitude}.
      (a) (Geog.) See def. 6. above.
      (b) (Astron.) One of the small circles of the sphere,
          parallel to the ecliptic.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>multiple</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Multiple \Mul"ti*ple\, a. [Cf. F. multiple, and E. quadruple,
   and multiply.]
   Containing more than once, or more than one; consisting of
   more than one; manifold; repeated many times; having several,
   or many, parts.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Law of multiple proportion} (Chem.), the generalization that
      when the same elements unite in more than one proportion,
      forming two or more different compounds, the higher
      proportions of the elements in such compounds are simple
      multiples of the lowest proportion, or the proportions are
      connected by some simple common factor; thus, iron and
      oxygen unite in the proportions {FeO}, {Fe2O3}, {Fe3O4},
      in which compounds, considering the oxygen, 3 and 4 are
      simple multiplies of 1. Called also the {Law of Dalton} or
      {Dalton's Law}, from its discoverer.

   {Multiple algebra}, a branch of advanced mathematics that
      treats of operations upon units compounded of two or more
      unlike units.

   {Multiple conjugation} (Biol.), a coalescence of many cells
      (as where an indefinite number of am[oe]boid cells flow
      together into a single mass) from which conjugation proper
      and even fertilization may have been evolved.

   {Multiple fruits}. (Bot.) See {Collective fruit}, under
      {Collective}.

   {Multiple star} (Astron.), several stars in close proximity,
      which appear to form a single system.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>multiple</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Multiple \Mul"ti*ple\, n. (Math.)
   A quantity containing another quantity an integral number of
   times without a remainder.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: A

   {common multiple} of two or more numbers contains each of
      them a number of times exactly; thus, 24 is a common
      multiple of 3 and 4. The

   {least common multiple} is the smallest number that will do
      this; thus, 12 is the least common multiple of 3 and 4
      (abbreviated LCM).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>multiple</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>multiple
     adj : having or involving or consisting of more than one part or
           entity or individual; "multiple birth"; "multiple
           ownership"; "made multiple copies of the speech"; "his
           multiple achievements in public life"; "her multiple
           personalities"; "a pineapple is a multiple fruit" [ant:
            {single(a)}]
     n : the product of a quantity by an integer; "36 is a multiple
         of 9"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
