<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mumble</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mumble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mumble
     
        1. Said when the correct response is too complicated to
        enunciate, or the speaker has not thought it out.  Often
        prefaces a longer answer, or indicates a general reluctance to
        get into a long discussion.  "Don't you think that we could
        improve LISP performance by using a hybrid reference-count
        transaction garbage collector, if the cache is big enough and
        there are some extra cache bits for the {microcode} to use?"
        "Well, mumble ... I'll have to think about it."
     
        2. Yet another {metasyntactic variable}, like {foo}.
     
        3. Sometimes used in "public" contexts on-line as a
        placefiller for things one is barred from giving details
        about.  For example, a poster with pre-released hardware in
        his machine might say "Yup, my machine now has an extra 16M of
        memory, thanks to the card I'm testing for Mumbleco."
     
        4. A conversational wild card used to designate something one
        doesn't want to bother spelling out, but which can be
        {glark}ed from context.  Compare {blurgle}.
     
        5. [XEROX PARC] A colloquialism used to suggest that further
        discussion would be fruitless.
     
        (1997-03-27)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mumble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mumble \Mum"ble\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Mumbled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Mumbling}.] [OE. momelen; cf. D. mompelen, mommelen, G.
   mummelen, Sw. mumla, Dan. mumle. Cf. {Mum}, a., {Mumm},
   {Mump}, v.]
   1. To speak with the lips partly closed, so as to render the
      sounds inarticulate and imperfect; to utter words in a
      grumbling indistinct manner, indicating discontent or
      displeasure; to mutter.
      [1913 Webster]

            Peace, you mumbling fool.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A wrinkled hag, with age grown double,
            Picking dry sticks, and mumbling to herself.
                                                  --Otway.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To chew something gently with closed lips.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mumble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mumble \Mum"ble\ (m[u^]m"b'l), v. t.
   1. To utter with a low, inarticulate voice. --Bp. Hall.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To chew or bite gently, as one without teeth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gums unarmed, to mumble meat in vain. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To suppress, or utter imperfectly.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mumble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mumble interj. 1. Said when the correct response is too complicated to
   enunciate, or the speaker has not thought it out. Often prefaces a
   longer answer, or indicates a general reluctance to get into a long
   discussion. "Don't you think that we could improve LISP performance by
   using a hybrid reference-count transaction garbage collector, if the
   cache is big enough and there are some extra cache bits for the
   microcode to use?" "Well, mumble ... I'll have to think about it." 2.
   [MIT] Expression of not-quite-articulated agreement, often used as an
   informal vote of consensus in a meeting: "So, shall we dike out the
   COBOL emulation?" "Mumble!" 3. Sometimes used as an expression of
   disagreement (distinguished from sense 2 by tone of voice and other
   cues). "I think we should buy a {VAX}." "Mumble!" Common variant:
   `mumble frotz' (see {frotz}; interestingly, one does not say `mumble
   frobnitz' even though `frotz' is short for `frobnitz'). 4. Yet another
   {metasyntactic variable}, like {foo}. 5. When used as a question
   ("Mumble?") means "I didn't understand you". 6. Sometimes used in
   `public' contexts on-line as a placefiller for things one is barred from
   giving details about. For example, a poster with pre-released hardware
   in his machine might say "Yup, my machine now has an extra 16M of
   memory, thanks to the card I'm testing for Mumbleco." 7. A
   conversational wild card used to designate something one doesn't want to
   bother spelling out, but which can be {glark}ed from context. Compare
   {blurgle}. 8. [XEROX PARC] A colloquialism used to suggest that further
   discussion would be fruitless.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mumble</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mumble
     v 1: talk indistinctly; usually in a low voice [syn: {mutter}, {maunder},
           {mussitate}]
     2: grind with the gums; chew without teeth and with great
        difficulty; "the old man had no teeth left and mumbled his
        food" [syn: {gum}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
