<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mummy</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mummy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>MUMMY, n.  An ancient Egyptian, formerly in universal use among modern
civilized nations as medicine, and now engaged in supplying art with
an excellent pigment.  He is handy, too, in museums in gratifying the
vulgar curiosity that serves to distinguish man from the lower
animals.

    By means of the Mummy, mankind, it is said,
    Attests to the gods its respect for the dead.
    We plunder his tomb, be he sinner or saint,
    Distil him for physic and grind him for paint,
    Exhibit for money his poor, shrunken frame,
    And with levity flock to the scene of the shame.
    O, tell me, ye gods, for the use of my rhyme:
    For respecting the dead what's the limit of time?
                                                          Scopas Brune


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mummy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mummy \Mum"my\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Mummied}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Mummying}.]
   To embalm; to mummify.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mummy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mummy \Mum"my\ (m[u^]m"m[y^]), n.; pl. {Mummies}
   (m[u^]m"m[i^]z). [F. momie; cf. Sp. &amp; Pg. momia, It. mummia;
   all fr. Per. m[=u]miy[=a], fr. m[=u]m wax.]
   1. A dead body embalmed and dried after the manner of the
      ancient Egyptians; also, a body preserved, by any means,
      in a dry state, from the process of putrefaction. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Dried flesh of a mummy. [Obs.] --Sir. J. Hill.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A gummy liquor that exudes from embalmed flesh when
      heated; -- formerly supposed to have magical and medicinal
      properties. [Obs.] --Shak. --Sir T. Herbert.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A brown color obtained from bitumen. See {Mummy brown}
      (below).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Gardening) A sort of wax used in grafting, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. One whose affections and energies are withered.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Mummy brown}, a brown color, nearly intermediate in tint
      between burnt umber and raw umber. A pigment of this color
      is prepared from bitumen, etc., obtained from Egyptian
      tombs.

   {Mummy wheat} (Bot.), wheat found in the ancient mummy cases
      of Egypt. No botanist now believes that genuine mummy
      wheat has been made to germinate in modern times.

   {To beat to a mummy}, to beat to a senseless mass; to beat
      soundly.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mummy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mummy
     n 1: informal terms for a mother [syn: {ma}, {mama}, {mamma}, {mom},
           {momma}, {mommy}, {mammy}, {mum}, {mater}]
     2: a body embalmed and dried and wrapped for burial (as in
        ancient Egypt)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
