<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mushroom</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mushroom</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mushroom \Mush"room\, n. [OE. muscheron, OF. mouscheron, F.
   mousseron; perhaps fr. mousse moss, of German origin. See
   {Moss}.]
   1. (Bot.)
      (a) An edible fungus ({Agaricus campestris}), having a
          white stalk which bears a convex or oven flattish
          expanded portion called the pileus. This is whitish
          and silky or somewhat scaly above, and bears on the
          under side radiating gills which are at first
          flesh-colored, but gradually become brown. The plant
          grows in rich pastures and is proverbial for rapidity
          of growth and shortness of duration. It has a pleasant
          smell, and is largely used as food. It is also
          cultivated from spawn.
      (b) Any large fungus developing a visible fruiting body
          with a stem and cap, usu. of the basidiomycetes;
          especially one of the genus {Agaricus}; a toadstool.
          Several species are edible; but many are very
          poisonous. The term mushroom is used most often for
          edible varieties, the poisonous ones being termed
          {toadstools} or other names. But this distinction is
          often ignored.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. One who rises suddenly from a low condition in life; an
      upstart. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mushroom</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mushroom \mush"room\, v. i.
   1. to grow or expand rapidly.
      [PJC]

   2. to grow so much and so rapidly as to change qualitatively;
      used with into; as, a minor border skirmish mushroomed
      into a full-blown war.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mushroom</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mushroom \Mush"room\, a.
   1. Of or pertaining to mushrooms; as, mushroom catchup.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Resembling mushrooms in rapidity of growth and shortness
      of duration; short-lived; ephemerial; as, mushroom cities.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Mushroom anchor}, an anchor shaped like a mushroom, capable
      of grasping the ground in whatever way it falls.

   {Mushroom coral} (Zo["o]l.), any coral of the genus {Fungia}.
      See {Fungia}.

   {Mushroom spawn} (Bot.), the mycelium, or primary filamentous
      growth, of the mushroom; also, cakes of earth and manure
      containing this growth, which are used for propagation of
      the mushroom.

   {mushroom cloud}, a cloud of smoke rising and then spreading
      laterally to take on the shape of a mushroom -- caused by
      large fires or explosions, esp. nuclear explosions.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mushroom</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mushroom
     n 1: common name for an edible agaric (contrasting with the
          inedible toadstool) [ant: {toadstool}]
     2: any of various fleshy fungi of the subdivision Basidiomycota
        consisting of a cap at the end of a stem arising from an
        underground mycelium
     3: a large cloud of rubble and dust shaped like a mushroom and
        rising into the sky after an explosion (especially of a
        nuclear bomb) [syn: {mushroom cloud}, {mushroom-shaped
        cloud}]
     4: fleshy body of any of numerous edible fungi
     v 1: pick or gather mushrooms; "We went mushrooming in the Fall"
     2: grow and spread fast; "The problem mushroomed"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
