<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>music</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>music</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Music
   Jubal was the inventor of musical instruments (Gen. 4:21). The
   Hebrews were much given to the cultivation of music. Their whole
   history and literature afford abundant evidence of this. After
   the Deluge, the first mention of music is in the account of
   Laban's interview with Jacob (Gen. 31:27). After their triumphal
   passage of the Red Sea, Moses and the children of Israel sang
   their song of deliverance (Ex. 15).
   
     But the period of Samuel, David, and Solomon was the golden
   age of Hebrew music, as it was of Hebrew poetry. Music was now
   for the first time systematically cultivated. It was an
   essential part of training in the schools of the prophets (1
   Sam. 10:5; 19:19-24; 2 Kings 3:15; 1 Chr. 25:6). There now arose
   also a class of professional singers (2 Sam. 19:35; Eccl. 2:8).
   The temple, however, was the great school of music. In the
   conducting of its services large bands of trained singers and
   players on instruments were constantly employed (2 Sam. 6:5; 1
   Chr. 15; 16; 23;5; 25:1-6).
   
     In private life also music seems to have held an important
   place among the Hebrews (Eccl. 2:8; Amos 6:4-6; Isa. 5:11, 12;
   24:8, 9; Ps. 137; Jer. 48:33; Luke 15:25).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>music</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Music
     
        &lt;language, music&gt; A series of languages for musical sound
        synthesis from {Bell Labs}, 1960's.  Versions: Music I through
        Music V.
     
        ["An Acoustical Compiler for Music and Psychological Stimuli",
        M.V. Mathews, Bell Sys Tech J 40 (1961)].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1999-06-04)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>music</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Music \Mu"sic\, n. [F. musique, fr. L. musica, Gr. ? (sc. ?),
   any art over which the Muses presided, especially music,
   lyric poetry set and sung to music, fr. ? belonging to Muses
   or fine arts, fr. ? Muse.]
   1. The science and the art of tones, or musical sounds, i.
      e., sounds of higher or lower pitch, begotten of uniform
      and synchronous vibrations, as of a string at various
      degrees of tension; the science of harmonical tones which
      treats of the principles of harmony, or the properties,
      dependences, and relations of tones to each other; the art
      of combining tones in a manner to please the ear.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Not all sounds are tones. Sounds may be unmusical and
         yet please the ear. Music deals with tones, and with no
         other sounds. See {Tone}.
         [1913 Webster]

   2.
      (a) Melody; a rhythmical and otherwise agreeable
          succession of tones.
      (b) Harmony; an accordant combination of simultaneous
          tones.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. The written and printed notation of a musical composition;
      the score.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Love of music; capacity of enjoying music.
      [1913 Webster]

            The man that hath no music in himself
            Nor is not moved with concord of sweet sounds,
            Is fit for treasons, stratagems, and spoils. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.) A more or less musical sound made by many of
      the lower animals. See {Stridulation}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Magic music}, a game in which a person is guided in finding
      a hidden article, or in doing a specific art required, by
      music which is made more loud or rapid as he approaches
      success, and slower as he recedes. --Tennyson.

   {Music box}. See {Musical box}, under {Musical}.

   {Music hall}, a place for public musical entertainments.

   {Music loft}, a gallery for musicians, as in a dancing room
      or a church.

   {Music of the spheres}, the harmony supposed to be produced
      by the accordant movement of the celestial spheres.

   {Music paper}, paper ruled with the musical staff, for the
      use of composers and copyists.

   {Music pen}, a pen for ruling at one time the five lines of
      the musical staff.

   {Music shell} (Zo["o]l.), a handsomely colored marine
      gastropod shell ({Voluta musica}) found in the East
      Indies; -- so called because the color markings often
      resemble printed music. Sometimes applied to other shells
      similarly marked.

   {To face the music}, to meet any disagreeable necessity, such
      as a reprimand for an error or misdeed, without flinching.
      [Colloq. or Slang]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>music</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>music n. A common extracurricular interest of hackers (compare
   {{science-fiction fandom}}, {{oriental food}}; see also {filk}). Hackish
   folklore has long claimed that musical and programming abilities are
   closely related, and there has been at least one large-scale statistical
   study that supports this. Hackers, as a rule, like music and often
   develop musical appreciation in unusual and interesting directions. Folk
   music is very big in hacker circles; so is electronic music, and the
   sort of elaborate instrumental jazz/rock that used to be called
   `progressive' and isn't recorded much any more. The hacker's musical
   range tends to be wide; many can listen with equal appreciation to (say)
   Talking Heads, Yes, Gentle Giant, Pat Metheny, Scott Joplin, Tangerine
   Dream, Dream Theater, King Sunny Ade, The Pretenders, Screaming Trees,
   or the Brandenburg Concerti. It is also apparently true that hackerdom
   includes a much higher concentration of talented amateur musicians than
   one would expect from a similar-sized control group of {mundane} types.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>music</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>music
     n 1: an artistic form of auditory communication incorporating
          instrumental or vocal tones in a structured and
          continuous manner
     2: any agreeable (pleasing and harmonious) sounds; "he fell
        asleep to the music of the wind chimes" [syn: {euphony}]
     3: musical activity (singing or whistling etc.); "his music was
        his central interest"
     4: (music) the sounds produced by singers or musical
        instruments (or reproductions of such sounds)
     5: punishment for one's actions; "you have to face the music";
        "take your medicine" [syn: {medicine}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
