<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>mustard</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mustard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mustard
   a plant of the genus sinapis, a pod-bearing, shrub-like plant,
   growing wild, and also cultivated in gardens. The little round
   seeds were an emblem of any small insignificant object. It is
   not mentioned in the Old Testament; and in each of the three
   instances of its occurrence in the New Testament (Matt. 13:31,
   32; Mark 4:31, 32; Luke 13:18, 19) it is spoken of only with
   reference to the smallness of its seed. The common mustard of
   Palestine is the Sinapis nigra. This garden herb sometimes grows
   to a considerable height, so as to be spoken of as "a tree" as
   compared with garden herbs.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mustard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mustard \Mus"tard\, n. [OF. moustarde, F. moutarde, fr. L.
   mustum must, -- mustard was prepared for use by being mixed
   with must. See {Must}, n.]
   1. (Bot.) The name of several cruciferous plants of the genus
      {Brassica} (formerly {Sinapis}), as {white mustard}
      ({Brassica alba}), {black mustard} ({Brassica Nigra}),
      {wild mustard} or {charlock} ({Brassica Sinapistrum}).
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: There are also many herbs of the same family which are
         called mustard, and have more or less of the flavor of
         the true mustard; as, bowyer's mustard ({Lepidium
         ruderale}); hedge mustard ({Sisymbrium officinale});
         Mithridate mustard ({Thlaspi arvense}); tower mustard
         ({Arabis perfoliata}); treacle mustard ({Erysimum
         cheiranthoides}).
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A powder or a paste made from the seeds of black or white
      mustard, used as a condiment and a rubefacient. Taken
      internally it is stimulant and diuretic, and in large
      doses is emetic.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Mustard oil} (Chem.), a substance obtained from mustard, as
      a transparent, volatile and intensely pungent oil. The
      name is also extended to a number of analogous compounds
      produced either naturally or artificially.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>mustard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>mustard
     n 1: any of several cruciferous plants of the genus Brassica
     2: pungent powder or paste prepared from ground mustard seeds
        [syn: {table mustard}]
     3: leaves eaten as cooked greens [syn: {mustard greens}, {leaf
        mustard}, {Indian mustard}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
