<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>d</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>d</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>D
     
        1. "The Data Language."  {MS-DOS} 4GL.
     
        2. A {Haskell}-like language, with {type class}es.
     
        E-mail: &lt;polar@cs.syr.edu&gt;.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>d</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mute \Mute\, n.
   1. One who does not speak, whether from physical inability,
      unwillingness, or other cause. Specifically:
      (a) One who, from deafness, either congenital or from
          early life, is unable to use articulate language; a
          deaf-mute.
      (b) A person employed by undertakers at a funeral.
      (c) A person whose part in a play does not require him to
          speak.
      (d) Among the Turks, an officer or attendant who is
          selected for his place because he can not speak.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. (Phon.) A letter which represents no sound; a silent
      letter; also, a close articulation; an element of speech
      formed by a position of the mouth organs which stops the
      passage of the breath; as, {p}, {b}, {d}, {k}, {t}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.) A little utensil made of brass, ivory, or other
      material, so formed that it can be fixed in an erect
      position on the bridge of a violin, or similar instrument,
      in order to deaden or soften the tone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>d</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>D \D\ (d[=e])
   1. The fourth letter of the English alphabet, and a vocal
      consonant. The English letter is from Latin, which is from
      Greek, which took it from Ph[oe]nician, the probable
      ultimate origin being Egyptian. It is related most nearly
      to t and th; as, Eng. deep, G. tief; Eng. daughter, G.
      tochter, Gr. qyga`thr, Skr. duhitr. See Guide to
      Pronunciation, [root]178, 179, 229.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mus.) The nominal of the second tone in the model major
      scale (that in C), or of the fourth tone in the relative
      minor scale of C (that in A minor), or of the key tone in
      the relative minor of F.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. As a numeral D stands for 500. in this use it is not the
      initial of any word, or even strictly a letter, but one
      half of the sign ? (or ? ) the original Tuscan numeral for
      1000.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>d</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>d
     adj : denoting a quantity consisting of 500 items or units [syn: {five
           hundred}, {500}]
     n 1: a fat-soluble vitamin that prevents rickets [syn: {vitamin D},
           {calciferol}, {viosterol}, {ergocalciferol}, {cholecarciferol}]
     2: the cardinal number that is the product of one hundred and
        five [syn: {five hundred}, {500}]
     3: the 4th letter of the Roman alphabet
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
