<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>da</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>da</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Referendum \Ref`er*en"dum\ (r?f`?r*?n"d?m), n.; pl. {-da}
   [Gerundive fr. L. referre. See {Refer}.]
   1. A diplomatic agent's note asking for instructions from his
      government concerning a particular matter or point.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The right to approve or reject by popular vote a meassure
      passed upon by a legislature.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The principle or practice of referring measures passed
      upon by the legislative body to the body of voters, or
      electorate, for approval or rejection, as in the Swiss
      cantons (except Freiburg) and in various local governments
      in the United States, and also in the local option laws,
      etc.; also, the right to so approve or reject laws, or the
      vote by which this is done. Referendum is distinguished
      from the mandate, or instruction of representatives by the
      people, from direct government by the people, in which
      they initiate and make the laws by direct action without
      representation, and from a plebiscite, or popular vote
      taken on any measure proposed by a person or body having
      the initiative but not constituting a representative or
      constituent body.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>da</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DA
     Destination [MAC] Address (SNA, Token Ring, ATM, FDDI, ...)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>da</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DA
     Digital-to-Analog (D/A), "D/A"
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>da</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DA
     n : an official prosecutor for a judicial district [syn: {district
         attorney}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
