<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>day</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>day</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DAY, n.  A period of twenty-four hours, mostly misspent.  This period
is divided into two parts, the day proper and the night, or day
improper -- the former devoted to sins of business, the latter
consecrated to the other sort.  These two kinds of social activity
overlap.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>day</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Day
   The Jews reckoned the day from sunset to sunset (Lev. 23:32). It
   was originally divided into three parts (Ps. 55:17). "The heat
   of the day" (1 Sam. 11:11; Neh. 7:3) was at our nine o'clock,
   and "the cool of the day" just before sunset (Gen. 3:8). Before
   the Captivity the Jews divided the night into three watches, (1)
   from sunset to midnight (Lam. 2:19); (2) from midnight till the
   cock-crowing (Judg. 7:19); and (3) from the cock-crowing till
   sunrise (Ex. 14:24). In the New Testament the division of the
   Greeks and Romans into four watches was adopted (Mark 13:35).
   (See {WATCHES}.)
   
     The division of the day by hours is first mentioned in Dan.
   3:6, 15; 4:19; 5:5. This mode of reckoning was borrowed from the
   Chaldeans. The reckoning of twelve hours was from sunrise to
   sunset, and accordingly the hours were of variable length (John
   11:9).
   
     The word "day" sometimes signifies an indefinite time (Gen.
   2:4; Isa. 22:5; Heb. 3:8, etc.). In Job 3:1 it denotes a
   birthday, and in Isa. 2:12, Acts 17:31, and 2 Tim. 1:18, the
   great day of final judgment.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>day</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Day, FL
  Zip code(s): 32013
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>day</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sidereal \Si*de"re*al\, a. [L. sidereus, from sidus, sideris, a
   constellation, a star. Cf. {Sideral}, {Consider}, {Desire}.]
   1. Relating to the stars; starry; astral; as, sidereal
      astronomy.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Astron.) Measuring by the apparent motion of the stars;
      designated, marked out, or accompanied, by a return to the
      same position in respect to the stars; as, the sidereal
      revolution of a planet; a sidereal day.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Sidereal clock}, {day}, {month}, {year}. See under {Clock},
      {Day}, etc.

   {Sideral time}, time as reckoned by sideral days, or, taking
      the sidereal day as the unit, the time elapsed since a
      transit of the vernal equinox, reckoned in parts of a
      sidereal day. This is, strictly, apparent sidereal time,
      mean sidereal time being reckoned from the transit, not of
      the true, but of the mean, equinoctial point.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>day</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Day \Day\ (d[=a]), n. [OE. day, dai, dei, AS. d[ae]g; akin to
   OS., D., Dan., &amp; Sw. dag, G. tag, Icel. dagr, Goth. dags; cf.
   Skr. dah (for dhagh ?) to burn. [root]69. Cf. {Dawn}.]
   1. The time of light, or interval between one night and the
      next; the time between sunrise and sunset, or from dawn to
      darkness; hence, the light; sunshine; -- also called
      {daytime}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. The period of the earth's revolution on its axis. --
      ordinarily divided into twenty-four hours. It is measured
      by the interval between two successive transits of a
      celestial body over the same meridian, and takes a
      specific name from that of the body. Thus, if this is the
      sun, the day (the interval between two successive transits
      of the sun's center over the same meridian) is called a
      {solar day}; if it is a star, a {sidereal day}; if it is
      the moon, a {lunar day}. See {Civil day}, {Sidereal day},
      below.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Those hours, or the daily recurring period, allotted by
      usage or law for work.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A specified time or period; time, considered with
      reference to the existence or prominence of a person or
      thing; age; time.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man who was great among the Hellenes of his day.
                                                  --Jowett
                                                  (Thucyd. )
      [1913 Webster]

            If my debtors do not keep their day, . . .
            I must with patience all the terms attend. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Preceded by the) Some day in particular, as some day of
      contest, some anniversary, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            The field of Agincourt,
            Fought on the day of Crispin Crispianus. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            His name struck fear, his conduct won the day.
                                                  --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Day is much used in self-explaining compounds; as,
         daybreak, daylight, workday, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Anniversary day}. See {Anniversary}, n.

   {Astronomical day}, a period equal to the mean solar day, but
      beginning at noon instead of at midnight, its twenty-four
      hours being numbered from 1 to 24; also, the sidereal day,
      as that most used by astronomers.

   {Born days}. See under {Born}.

   {Canicular days}. See {Dog day}.

   {Civil day}, the mean solar day, used in the ordinary
      reckoning of time, and among most modern nations beginning
      at mean midnight; its hours are usually numbered in two
      series, each from 1 to 12. This is the period recognized
      by courts as constituting a day. The Babylonians and
      Hindoos began their day at sunrise, the Athenians and Jews
      at sunset, the ancient Egyptians and Romans at midnight.
      

   {Day blindness}. (Med.) See {Nyctalopia}.

   {Day by day}, or {Day after day}, daily; every day;
      continually; without intermission of a day. See under
      {By}. ``Day by day we magnify thee.'' --Book of Common
      Prayer.

   {Days in bank} (Eng. Law), certain stated days for the return
      of writs and the appearance of parties; -- so called
      because originally peculiar to the Court of Common Bench,
      or Bench (bank) as it was formerly termed. --Burrill.

   {Day in court}, a day for the appearance of parties in a
      suit.

   {Days of devotion} (R. C. Ch.), certain festivals on which
      devotion leads the faithful to attend mass. --Shipley.

   {Days of grace}. See {Grace}.

   {Days of obligation} (R. C. Ch.), festival days when it is
      obligatory on the faithful to attend Mass. --Shipley.

   {Day owl}, (Zo["o]l.), an owl that flies by day. See {Hawk
      owl}.

   {Day rule} (Eng. Law), an order of court (now abolished)
      allowing a prisoner, under certain circumstances, to go
      beyond the prison limits for a single day.

   {Day school}, one which the pupils attend only in daytime, in
      distinction from a boarding school.

   {Day sight}. (Med.) See {Hemeralopia}.

   {Day's work} (Naut.), the account or reckoning of a ship's
      course for twenty-four hours, from noon to noon.

   {From day to day}, as time passes; in the course of time; as,
      he improves from day to day.

   {Jewish day}, the time between sunset and sunset.

   {Mean solar day} (Astron.), the mean or average of all the
      apparent solar days of the year.

   {One day}, {One of these days}, at an uncertain time, usually
      of the future, rarely of the past; sooner or later.
      ``Well, niece, I hope to see you one day fitted with a
      husband.'' --Shak.

   {Only from day to day}, without certainty of continuance;
      temporarily. --Bacon.

   {Sidereal day}, the interval between two successive transits
      of the first point of Aries over the same meridian. The
      Sidereal day is 23 h. 56 m. 4.09 s. of mean solar time.

   {To win the day}, to gain the victory, to be successful. --S.
      Butler.

   {Week day}, any day of the week except Sunday; a working day.
      

   {Working day}.
      (a) A day when work may be legally done, in distinction
          from Sundays and legal holidays.
      (b) The number of hours, determined by law or custom,
          during which a workman, hired at a stated price per
          day, must work to be entitled to a day's pay.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>day</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>day
     n 1: time for Earth to make a complete rotation on its axis; "two
          days later they left"; "they put on two performances
          every day"; "there are 30,000 passengers per day" [syn:
          {twenty-four hours}, {solar day}, {mean solar day}]
     2: some point or period in time; "it should arrive any day
        now"; "after that day she never trusted him again"; "those
        were the days"; "these days it is not unusual"
     3: the time after sunrise and before sunset while it is light
        outside; "the dawn turned night into day"; "it is easier
        to make the repairs in the daytime" [syn: {daytime}, {daylight}]
        [ant: {night}]
     4: a day assigned to a particular purpose or observance;
        "Mother's Day"
     5: the recurring hours when you are not sleeping (especially
        those when you are working); "my day began early this
        morning"; "it was a busy day on the stock exchange"; "she
        called it a day and went to bed"
     6: an era of existence or influence; "in the day of the
        dinosaurs"; "in the days of the Roman Empire"; "in the
        days of sailing ships"; "he was a successful pianist in
        his day"
     7: a period of opportunity; "he deserves his day in court";
        "every dog has his day"
     8: the period of time taken by a particular planet (e.g. Mars)
        to make a complete rotation on its axis; "how long is a
        day on Jupiter?"
     9: the time for one complete rotation of the earth relative to
        a particular star, about 4 minutes shorter than a mean
        solar day [syn: {sidereal day}]
     10: United States writer best known for his autobiographical
         works (1874-1935) [syn: {Clarence Day}, {Clarence Shepard
         Day Jr.}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
