<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dead</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DEAD, adj.

    Done with the work of breathing; done
    With all the world; the mad race run
    Though to the end; the golden goal
    Attained and found to be a hole!
                                                        Squatol Johnes


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dead
     
        1. Non-functional; {down}; {crash}ed.  Especially used of
        {hardware}.
     
        2. At {XEROX PARC}, software that is working but not
        undergoing continued development and support.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sainted \Saint"ed\, a.
   1. Consecrated; sacred; holy; pious. ``A most sainted king.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Amongst the enthroned gods on sainted seats.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Entered into heaven; -- a euphemism for {dead}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dead \Dead\ (d[e^]d), a. [OE. ded, dead, deed, AS. de['a]d; akin
   to OS. d[=o]d, D. dood, G. todt, tot, Icel. dau[eth]r, Sw. &amp;
   Dan. d["o]d, Goth. daubs; prop. p. p. of an old verb meaning
   to die. See {Die}, and cf. {Death}.]
   1. Deprived of life; -- opposed to {alive} and {living};
      reduced to that state of a being in which the organs of
      motion and life have irrevocably ceased to perform their
      functions; as, a dead tree; a dead man. ``The queen, my
      lord, is dead.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The crew, all except himself, were dead of hunger.
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

            Seek him with candle, bring him dead or living.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Destitute of life; inanimate; as, dead matter.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Resembling death in appearance or quality; without show of
      life; deathlike; as, a dead sleep.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Still as death; motionless; inactive; useless; as, dead
      calm; a dead load or weight.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. So constructed as not to transmit sound; soundless; as, a
      dead floor.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Unproductive; bringing no gain; unprofitable; as, dead
      capital; dead stock in trade.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Lacking spirit; dull; lusterless; cheerless; as, dead eye;
      dead fire; dead color, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Monotonous or unvaried; as, a dead level or pain; a dead
      wall. ``The ground is a dead flat.'' --C. Reade.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Sure as death; unerring; fixed; complete; as, a dead shot;
      a dead certainty.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had them a dead bargain.            --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Bringing death; deadly. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Wanting in religious spirit and vitality; as, dead faith;
       dead works. ``Dead in trespasses.'' --Eph. ii. 1.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Paint.)
       (a) Flat; without gloss; -- said of painting which has
           been applied purposely to have this effect.
       (b) Not brilliant; not rich; thus, brown is a dead color,
           as compared with crimson.
           [1913 Webster]

   13. (Law) Cut off from the rights of a citizen; deprived of
       the power of enjoying the rights of property; as, one
       banished or becoming a monk is civilly dead.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Mach.) Not imparting motion or power; as, the dead
       spindle of a lathe, etc. See {Spindle}.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Elec.) Carrying no current, or producing no useful
       effect; -- said of a conductor in a dynamo or motor, also
       of a telegraph wire which has no instrument attached and,
       therefore, is not in use.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   16. Out of play; regarded as out of the game; -- said of a
       ball, a piece, or a player under certain conditions in
       cricket, baseball, checkers, and some other games.

             [In golf], a ball is said to lie dead when it lies
             so near the hole that the player is certain to hole
             it in the next stroke.               --Encyc. of
                                                  Sport.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Dead ahead} (Naut.), directly ahead; -- said of a ship or
      any object, esp. of the wind when blowing from that point
      toward which a vessel would go.

   {Dead angle} (Mil.), an angle or space which can not be seen
      or defended from behind the parapet.

   {Dead block}, either of two wooden or iron blocks intended to
      serve instead of buffers at the end of a freight car.

   {Dead calm} (Naut.), no wind at all.

   {Dead center}, or {Dead point} (Mach.), either of two points
      in the orbit of a crank, at which the crank and connecting
      rod lie a straight line. It corresponds to the end of a
      stroke; as, A and B are dead centers of the crank
      mechanism in which the crank C drives, or is driven by,
      the lever L.

   {Dead color} (Paint.), a color which has no gloss upon it.

   {Dead coloring} (Oil paint.), the layer of colors, the
      preparation for what is to follow. In modern painting this
      is usually in monochrome.

   {Dead door} (Shipbuilding), a storm shutter fitted to the
      outside of the quarter-gallery door.

   {Dead flat} (Naut.), the widest or midship frame.

   {Dead freight} (Mar. Law), a sum of money paid by a person
      who charters a whole vessel but fails to make out a full
      cargo. The payment is made for the unoccupied capacity.
      --Abbott.

   {Dead ground} (Mining), the portion of a vein in which there
      is no ore.

   {Dead hand}, a hand that can not alienate, as of a person
      civilly dead. ``Serfs held in dead hand.'' --Morley. See
      {Mortmain}.

   {Dead head} (Naut.), a rough block of wood used as an anchor
      buoy.

   {Dead heat}, a heat or course between two or more race
      horses, boats, etc., in which they come out exactly equal,
      so that neither wins.

   {Dead horse}, an expression applied to a debt for wages paid
      in advance. [Law]

   {Dead language}, a language which is no longer spoken or in
      common use by a people, and is known only in writings, as
      the Hebrew, Greek, and Latin.

   {Dead plate} (Mach.), a solid covering over a part of a fire
      grate, to prevent the entrance of air through that part.
      

   {Dead pledge}, a mortgage. See {Mortgage}.

   {Dead point}. (Mach.) See {Dead center}.

   {Dead reckoning} (Naut.), the method of determining the place
      of a ship from a record kept of the courses sailed as
      given by compass, and the distance made on each course as
      found by log, with allowance for leeway, etc., without the
      aid of celestial observations.

   {Dead rise}, the transverse upward curvature of a vessel's
      floor.

   {Dead rising}, an elliptical line drawn on the sheer plan to
      determine the sweep of the floorheads throughout the
      ship's length.

   {Dead-Sea apple}. See under {Apple}.

   {Dead set}. See under {Set}.

   {Dead shot}.
       (a) An unerring marksman.
       (b) A shot certain to be made.

   {Dead smooth}, the finest cut made; -- said of files.

   {Dead wall} (Arch.), a blank wall unbroken by windows or
      other openings.

   {Dead water} (Naut.), the eddy water closing in under a
      ship's stern when sailing.

   {Dead weight}.
       (a) A heavy or oppressive burden. --Dryden.
       (b) (Shipping) A ship's lading, when it consists of heavy
           goods; or, the heaviest part of a ship's cargo.
       (c) (Railroad) The weight of rolling stock, the live
           weight being the load. --Knight.

   {Dead wind} (Naut.), a wind directly ahead, or opposed to the
      ship's course.

   {To be dead}, to die. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I deme thee, thou must algate be dead. --Chaucer.

   Syn: Inanimate; deceased; extinct. See {Lifeless}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dead \Dead\ (d[e^]d), adv.
   To a degree resembling death; to the last degree; completely;
   wholly. [Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]

         I was tired of reading, and dead sleepy. --Dickens.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Dead drunk}, so drunk as to be unconscious.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dead \Dead\ (d[e^]d), n.
   1. The most quiet or deathlike time; the period of
      profoundest repose, inertness, or gloom; as, the dead of
      winter.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the drum beat at dead of night.  --Campbell.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One who is dead; -- commonly used collectively.
      [1913 Webster]

            And Abraham stood up from before his dead. --Gen.
                                                  xxiii. 3.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dead \Dead\, v. t.
   To make dead; to deaden; to deprive of life, force, or vigor.
   [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Heaven's stern decree,
         With many an ill, hath numbed and deaded me. --Chapman.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dead \Dead\, v. i.
   To die; to lose life or force. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         So iron, as soon as it is out of the fire, deadeth
         straightway.                             --Bacon.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dead adj. 1. Non-functional; {down}; {crash}ed. Especially used of
   hardware. 2. At XEROX PARC, software that is working but not undergoing
   continued development and support. 3. Useless; inaccessible. Antonym:
   `live'. Compare {dead code}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dead</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dead
     adj 1: no longer having or seeming to have or expecting to have
            life; "the nerve is dead"; "a dead pallor"; "he was
            marked as a dead man by the assassin" [ant: {alive(p)}]
     2: not showing characteristics of life especially the capacity
        to sustain life; no longer exerting force or having energy
        or heat; "Mars is a dead planet"; "a dead battery"; "dead
        soil"; "dead coals"; "the fire is dead" [ant: {live}]
     3: very tired; "was all in at the end of the day"; "so beat I
        could flop down and go to sleep anywhere"; "bushed after
        all that exercise"; "I'm dead after that long trip" [syn:
        {all in(p)}, {beat(p)}, {bushed(p)}, {dead(p)}]
     4: unerringly accurate; "a dead shot"; "took dead aim"
     5: physically inactive; "Crater Lake is in the crater of a dead
        volcano of the Cascade Range"
     6: total; "dead silence"; "utter seriousness" [syn: {dead(a)},
        {utter(a)}]
     7: not endowed with life; "the inorganic world is inanimate";
        "inanimate objects"; "dead stones" [syn: {inanimate}, {nonliving}]
        [ant: {animate}]
     8: (followed by `to') not showing human feeling or sensitivity;
        unresponsive; "passersby were dead to our plea for help";
        "numb to the cries for mercy" [syn: {dead(p)}, {numb(p)}]
     9: devoid of physical sensation; numb; "his gums were dead from
        the novocain"; "she felt no discomfort as the dentist
        drilled her deadened tooth"; "a public desensitized by
        continuous television coverage of atrocities" [syn: {deadened}]
     10: lacking acoustic resonance; "dead sounds characteristic of
         some compact discs"; "the dead wall surfaces of a
         recording studio"
     11: not yielding a return; "dead capital"; "idle funds" [syn: {idle}]
     12: not circulating or flowing; "dead air"; "dead water";
         "stagnant water" [syn: {dead(a)}, {stagnant}]
     13: out of use or operation because of a fault or breakdown; "a
         dead telephone line"; "the motor is dead"
     14: not surviving in active use; "Latin is a dead language"
     15: lacking resilience or bounce; "a dead tennis ball"
     16: no longer in force or use; inactive; "a defunct (or dead)
         law"; "a defunct organization" [syn: {defunct}]
     17: no longer having force or relevance; "a dead issue"
     18: sudden and complete; "came to a dead stop" [syn: {dead(a)}]
     19: drained of electric charge; discharged; "a dead battery";
         "left the lights on and came back to find the battery
         drained" [syn: {drained}]
     20: lacking animation or excitement or activity; "the party
         being dead we left early"; "it was a lifeless party until
         she arrived" [syn: {lifeless}]
     21: devoid of activity; "this is a dead town; nothing ever
         happens here"
     n 1: people who are no longer living; "they buried the dead"
          [ant: {living}]
     2: a time when coldness (or some other quality associated with
        death) is intense; "the dead of winter"
     adv 1: quickly and without warning; "he stopped suddenly" [syn: {abruptly},
             {suddenly}, {short}]
     2: completely and without qualification; used informally as
        intensifiers; "an absolutely magnificent painting"; "a
        perfectly idiotic idea"; "you're perfectly right";
        "utterly miserable"; "you can be dead sure of my
        innocence"; "was dead tired"; "dead right" [syn: {absolutely},
         {perfectly}, {utterly}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
