<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>death</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>death</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Death
   may be simply defined as the termination of life. It is
   represented under a variety of aspects in Scripture: (1.) "The
   dust shall return to the earth as it was" (Eccl. 12:7).
   
     (2.) "Thou takest away their breath, they die" (Ps. 104:29).
   
     (3.) It is the dissolution of "our earthly house of this
   tabernacle" (2 Cor. 5:1); the "putting off this tabernacle" (2
   Pet. 1:13, 14).
   
     (4.) Being "unclothed" (2 Cor. 5:3, 4).
   
     (5.) "Falling on sleep" (Ps. 76:5; Jer. 51:39; Acts 13:36; 2
   Pet. 3:9.
   
     (6.) "I go whence I shall not return" (Job 10:21); "Make me to
   know mine end" (Ps. 39:4); "to depart" (Phil. 1:23).
   
     The grave is represented as "the gates of death" (Job 38:17;
   Ps. 9:13; 107:18). The gloomy silence of the grave is spoken of
   under the figure of the "shadow of death" (Jer. 2:6).
   
     Death is the effect of sin (Heb. 2:14), and not a "debt of
   nature." It is but once (9:27), universal (Gen. 3:19), necessary
   (Luke 2:28-30). Jesus has by his own death taken away its sting
   for all his followers (1 Cor. 15:55-57).
   
     There is a spiritual death in trespasses and sins, i.e., the
   death of the soul under the power of sin (Rom. 8:6; Eph. 2:1, 3;
   Col. 2:13).
   
     The "second death" (Rev. 2:11) is the everlasting perdition of
   the wicked (Rev. 21:8), and "second" in respect to natural or
   temporal death.
   
     THE DEATH OF CHRIST is the procuring cause incidentally of all
   the blessings men enjoy on earth. But specially it is the
   procuring cause of the actual salvation of all his people,
   together with all the means that lead thereto. It does not make
   their salvation merely possible, but certain (Matt. 18:11; Rom.
   5:10; 2 Cor. 5:21; Gal. 1:4; 3:13; Eph. 1:7; 2:16; Rom.
   8:32-35).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>death</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Death \Death\ (d[e^]th), n. [OE. deth, dea[eth], AS.
   de['a][eth]; akin to OS. d[=o][eth], D. dood, G. tod, Icel.
   dau[eth]i, Sw. &amp; Dan. d["o]d, Goth. dau[thorn]us; from a verb
   meaning to die. See {Die}, v. i., and cf. {Dead}.]
   1. The cessation of all vital phenomena without capability of
      resuscitation, either in animals or plants.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Local death is going on at all times and in all parts
         of the living body, in which individual cells and
         elements are being cast off and replaced by new; a
         process essential to life. General death is of two
         kinds; death of the body as a whole (somatic or
         systemic death), and death of the tissues. By the
         former is implied the absolute cessation of the
         functions of the brain, the circulatory and the
         respiratory organs; by the latter the entire
         disappearance of the vital actions of the ultimate
         structural constituents of the body. When death takes
         place, the body as a whole dies first, the death of the
         tissues sometimes not occurring until after a
         considerable interval. --Huxley.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Total privation or loss; extinction; cessation; as, the
      death of memory.
      [1913 Webster]

            The death of a language can not be exactly compared
            with the death of a plant.            --J. Peile.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Manner of dying; act or state of passing from life.
      [1913 Webster]

            A death that I abhor.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let me die the death of the righteous. --Num. xxiii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Cause of loss of life.
      [1913 Webster]

            Swiftly flies the feathered death.    --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            He caught his death the last county sessions.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Personified: The destroyer of life, -- conventionally
      represented as a skeleton with a scythe.
      [1913 Webster]

            Death! great proprietor of all.       --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

            And I looked, and behold a pale horse; and his name
            that sat on him was Death.            --Rev. vi. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Danger of death. ``In deaths oft.'' --2 Cor. xi. 23.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Murder; murderous character.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not to suffer a man of death to live. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Theol.) Loss of spiritual life.
      [1913 Webster]

            To be carnally minded is death.       --Rom. viii.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Anything so dreadful as to be like death.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was death to them to think of entertaining such
            doctrines.                            --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

            And urged him, so that his soul was vexed unto
            death.                                --Judg. xvi.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Death is much used adjectively and as the first part of
         a compound, meaning, in general, of or pertaining to
         death, causing or presaging death; as, deathbed or
         death bed; deathblow or death blow, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Black death}. See {Black death}, in the Vocabulary.

   {Civil death}, the separation of a man from civil society, or
      the debarring him from the enjoyment of civil rights, as
      by banishment, attainder, abjuration of the realm,
      entering a monastery, etc. --Blackstone.

   {Death adder}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A kind of viper found in South Africa ({Acanthophis
          tortor}); -- so called from the virulence of its
          venom.
      (b) A venomous Australian snake of the family
          {Elapid[ae]}, of several species, as the
          {Hoplocephalus superbus} and {Acanthopis antarctica}.
          

   {Death bell}, a bell that announces a death.
      [1913 Webster]

            The death bell thrice was heard to ring. --Mickle.

   {Death candle}, a light like that of a candle, viewed by the
      superstitious as presaging death.

   {Death damp}, a cold sweat at the coming on of death.

   {Death fire}, a kind of ignis fatuus supposed to forebode
      death.
      [1913 Webster]

            And round about in reel and rout,
            The death fires danced at night.      --Coleridge.

   {Death grapple}, a grapple or struggle for life.

   {Death in life}, a condition but little removed from death; a
      living death. [Poetic] ``Lay lingering out a five years'
      death in life.'' --Tennyson.

   {Death rate}, the relation or ratio of the number of deaths
      to the population.
      [1913 Webster]

            At all ages the death rate is higher in towns than
            in rural districts.                   --Darwin.

   {Death rattle}, a rattling or gurgling in the throat of a
      dying person.

   {Death's door}, the boundary of life; the partition dividing
      life from death.

   {Death stroke}, a stroke causing death.

   {Death throe}, the spasm of death.

   {Death token}, the signal of approaching death.

   {Death warrant}.
      (a) (Law) An order from the proper authority for the
          execution of a criminal.
      (b) That which puts an end to expectation, hope, or joy.
          

   {Death wound}.
      (a) A fatal wound or injury.
      (b) (Naut.) The springing of a fatal leak.

   {Spiritual death} (Scripture), the corruption and perversion
      of the soul by sin, with the loss of the favor of God.

   {The gates of death}, the grave.
      [1913 Webster]

            Have the gates of death been opened unto thee? --Job
                                                  xxxviii. 17.

   {The second death}, condemnation to eternal separation from
      God. --Rev. ii. 11.

   {To be the death of}, to be the cause of death to; to make
      die. ``It was one who should be the death of both his
      parents.'' --Milton.

   Syn: {Death}, {Decease}, {Demise}, {Departure}, {Release}.

   Usage: Death applies to the termination of every form of
          existence, both animal and vegetable; the other words
          only to the human race. Decease is the term used in
          law for the removal of a human being out of life in
          the ordinary course of nature. Demise was formerly
          confined to decease of princes, but is now sometimes
          used of distinguished men in general; as, the demise
          of Mr. Pitt. Departure and release are peculiarly
          terms of Christian affection and hope. A violent death
          is not usually called a decease. Departure implies a
          friendly taking leave of life. Release implies a
          deliverance from a life of suffering or sorrow.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>death</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>death
     n 1: the event of dying or departure from life; "her death came
          as a terrible shock"; "upon your decease the capital
          will pass to your grandchildren" [syn: {decease}] [ant:
          {birth}]
     2: the permanent end of all life functions in an organism or
        part of an organism; "the animal died a painful death"
     3: the time at which life ends; continuing until dead; "she
        stayed until his death"; "a struggle to the last" [syn: {last}]
     4: the personification of death; "Death walked the streets of
        the plague-bound city"
     5: the absence of life or state of being dead; "he seemed more
        content in death than he had ever been in life"
     6: the time when something ends; "it was the death of all his
        plans"; "a dying of old hopes" [syn: {dying}, {demise}]
        [ant: {birth}]
     7: the act of killing; "he had two deaths on his conscience"
     8: a final state; "he came to a bad end"; "the so-called
        glorious experiment came to an inglorious end" [syn: {end},
         {destruction}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
