<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>deceive</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>deceive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Deceive \De*ceive"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Deceived}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Deceiving}.] [OE. deceveir, F. d['e]cevoir, fr. L.
   decipere to catch, insnare, deceive; de- + capere to take,
   catch. See {Capable}, and cf. {Deceit}, {Deception}.]
   1. To lead into error; to cause to believe what is false, or
      disbelieve what is true; to impose upon; to mislead; to
      cheat; to disappoint; to delude; to insnare.
      [1913 Webster]

            Evil men and seducers shall wax worse and worse,
            deceiving, and being deceived.        --2 Tim. iii.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nimble jugglers that deceive the eye. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            What can 'scape the eye
            Of God all-seeing, or deceive his heart? --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To beguile; to amuse, so as to divert the attention; to
      while away; to take away as if by deception.
      [1913 Webster]

            These occupations oftentimes deceived
            The listless hour.                    --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To deprive by fraud or stealth; to defraud. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Plant fruit trees in large borders, and set therein
            fine flowers, but thin and sparingly, lest they
            deceive the trees.                    --Bacon.

   Syn: {Deceive}, {Delude}, {Mislead}.

   Usage: Deceive is a general word applicable to any kind of
          misrepresentation affecting faith or life. To delude,
          primarily, is to make sport of, by deceiving, and is
          accomplished by playing upon one's imagination or
          credulity, as by exciting false hopes, causing him to
          undertake or expect what is impracticable, and making
          his failure ridiculous. It implies some infirmity of
          judgment in the victim, and intention to deceive in
          the deluder. But it is often used reflexively,
          indicating that a person's own weakness has made him
          the sport of others or of fortune; as, he deluded
          himself with a belief that luck would always favor
          him. To mislead is to lead, guide, or direct in a
          wrong way, either willfully or ignorantly.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>deceive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>deceive
     v 1: be false to; be dishonest with [syn: {lead on}, {delude}, {cozen}]
     2: cause someone to believe an untruth; "The insurance company
        deceived me when they told me they were covering my house"
        [syn: {betray}, {lead astray}] [ant: {undeceive}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
