<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>decided</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>decided</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Decide \De*cide"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Decided}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Deciding}.] [L. dec[=i]dere; de- + caedere to cut, cut
   off; prob. akin to E. shed, v.: cf. F. d['e]cider. Cf.
   {Decision}.]
   1. To cut off; to separate. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Our seat denies us traffic here;
            The sea, too near, decides us from the rest.
                                                  --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring to a termination, as a question, controversy,
      struggle, by giving the victory to one side or party; to
      render judgment concerning; to determine; to settle.
      [1913 Webster]

            So shall thy judgment be; thyself hast decided it.
                                                  --1 Kings xx.
                                                  40.
      [1913 Webster]

            The quarrel toucheth none but us alone;
            Betwixt ourselves let us decide it then. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>decided</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Decided \De*cid"ed\, a.
   1. Free from ambiguity; unequivocal; unmistakable;
      unquestionable; clear; evident; as, a decided advantage.
      ``A more decided taste for science.'' --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Free from doubt or wavering; determined; of fixed purpose;
      fully settled; positive; resolute; as, a decided opinion
      or purpose.

   Syn: {Decided}, {Decisive}.

   Usage: We call a thing decisive when it has the power or
          quality of deciding; as, a decisive battle; we speak
          of it as decided when it is so fully settled as to
          leave no room for doubt; as, a decided preference, a
          decided aversion. Hence, a decided victory is one
          about which there is no question; a decisive victory
          is one which ends the contest. Decisive is applied
          only to things; as, a decisive sentence, a decisive
          decree, a decisive judgment. Decided is applied
          equally to persons and things. Thus we speak of a man
          as decided in his whole of conduct; and as having a
          decided disgust, or a decided reluctance, to certain
          measures. ``A politic caution, a guarded
          circumspection, were among the ruling principles of
          our forefathers in their most decided conduct.''
          --Burke. ``The sentences of superior judges are final,
          decisive, and irrevocable. --Blackstone.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>decided</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>decided
     adj : recognizable; marked; "noticed a distinct improvement"; "at
           a distinct (or decided) disadvantage" [syn: {distinct}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
