<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>demolished</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demolished</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Demolish \De*mol"ish\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Demolished}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Demolishing}.] [F. d['e]molir, fr. L. demoliri, p.
   p. demolitus; de- + moliri to set a thing in motion, to work,
   construct, from moles a huge mass or structure. See {Mole} a
   mound, and {Finish}.]
   To throw or pull down; to raze; to destroy the fabric of; to
   pull to pieces; to ruin; as, to demolish an edifice, or a
   wall.
   [1913 Webster]

         I expected the fabric of my book would long since have
         been demolished, and laid even with the ground.
                                                  --Tillotson.

   Syn: To {Demolish}, {Overturn}, {Destroy}, {Dismantle},
        {Raze}. That is overturned or overthrown which had stood
        upright; that is destroyed whose component parts are
        scattered; that is demolished which had formed a mass or
        structure; that is dismantled which is stripped of its
        covering, as a vessel of its sails, or a fortress of its
        bastions, etc.; that is razed which is brought down
        smooth, and level to the ground. An ancient pillar is
        overturned or overthrown as the result of decay; a city
        is destroyed by an invasion of its enemies; a monument,
        the walls of a castle, a church, or any structure, real
        or imaginary, may be demolished; a fortress may be
        dismantled from motives of prudence, in order to render
        it defenseless; a city may be razed by way of
        punishment, and its ruins become a memorial of
        vengeance.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demolished</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>demolished
     adj : torn down and broken up [syn: {dismantled}, {razed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
