<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>demon</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Demon
   See {DAEMON}.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>demon
     
        1. &lt;operating system&gt; (Often used equivalently to {daemon},
        especially in the {Unix} world, where the latter spelling and
        pronunciation is considered mildly archaic).  A program or
        part of a program which is not invoked explicitly, but that
        lies dormant waiting for some condition(s) to occur.
     
        At {MIT} they use "demon" for part of a program and "daemon"
        for an {operating system} process.
     
        Demons (parts of programs) are particularly common in {AI}
        programs.  For example, a {knowledge}-manipulation program
        might implement {inference rules} as demons.  Whenever a new
        piece of knowledge was added, various demons would activate
        (which demons depends on the particular piece of data) and
        would create additional pieces of knowledge by applying their
        respective inference rules to the original piece.  These new
        pieces could in turn activate more demons as the inferences
        filtered down through chains of logic.  Meanwhile, the main
        program could continue with whatever its primary task was.
        This is similar to the {triggers} used in {relational
        databases}.
     
        The use of this term may derive from "Maxwell's Demons" -
        minute beings which can reverse the normal flow of heat from a
        hot body to a cold body by only allowing fast moving molecules
        to go from the cold body to the hot one and slow molecules
        from hot to cold.  The solution to this apparent thermodynamic
        paradox is that the demons would require an external supply of
        energy to do their work and it is only in the absence of such
        a supply that heat must necessarily flow from hot to cold.
     
        Walt Bunch believes the term comes from the demons in Oliver
        Selfridge's paper "Pandemonium", MIT 1958, which was named
        after the capital of Hell in Milton's "Paradise Lost".
        Selfridge likened neural cells firing in response to input
        patterns to the chaos of millions of demons shrieking in
        Pandemonium.
     
        2. &lt;company&gt; {Demon Internet} Ltd.
     
        3. A {program generator} for {differential equation} problems.
     
        [N.W. Bennett, Australian AEC Research Establishment,
        AAEC/E142, Aug 1965].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1998-09-04)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Demon \De"mon\, n. [F. d['e]mon, L. daemon a spirit, an evil
   spirit, fr. Gr. dai`mwn a divinity; of uncertain origin.]
   1. (Gr. Antiq.) A spirit, or immaterial being, holding a
      middle place between men and deities in pagan mythology.
      [1913 Webster]

            The demon kind is of an intermediate nature between
            the divine and the human.             --Sydenham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One's genius; a tutelary spirit or internal voice; as, the
      demon of Socrates. [Often written {d[ae]mon}.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An evil spirit; a devil.
      [1913 Webster]

            That same demon that hath gulled thee thus. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>demon n. 1. [MIT] A portion of a program that is not invoked
   explicitly, but that lies dormant waiting for some condition(s) to
   occur. See {daemon}. The distinction is that demons are usually
   processes within a program, while daemons are usually programs running
   on an operating system. 2. [outside MIT] Often used equivalently to
   {daemon} -- especially in the {{Unix}} world, where the latter spelling
   and pronunciation is considered mildly archaic.

   Demons in sense 1 are particularly common in AI programs. For example,
   a knowledge-manipulation program might implement inference rules as
   demons. Whenever a new piece of knowledge was added, various demons
   would activate (which demons depends on the particular piece of data)
   and would create additional pieces of knowledge by applying their
   respective inference rules to the original piece. These new pieces could
   in turn activate more demons as the inferences filtered down through
   chains of logic. Meanwhile, the main program could continue with
   whatever its primary task was.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>demon
     n 1: one of the evil spirits of traditional Jewish and Christian
          belief [syn: {devil}, {fiend}, {daemon}, {daimon}]
     2: a cruel wicked and inhuman person [syn: {monster}, {fiend},
        {devil}, {ogre}]
     3: someone extremely diligent or skillful; "he worked like a
        demon to finish the job on time"; "she's a demon at math"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
