<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>demonstration</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demonstration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Demonstration \Dem`on*stra"tion\, n. [L. demonstratio: cf. F.
   d['e]monstration.]
   1. The act of demonstrating; an exhibition; proof;
      especially, proof beyond the possibility of doubt;
      indubitable evidence, to the senses or reason.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those intervening ideas which serve to show the
            agreement of any two others are called ``proofs;''
            and where agreement or disagreement is by this means
            plainly and clearly perceived, it is called
            demonstration.                        --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An expression, as of the feelings, by outward signs; a
      manifestation; a show. See also sense 7 for a more
      specific related meaning.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            Did your letters pierce the queen to any
            demonstration of grief?               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Loyal demonstrations toward the prince. --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Anat.) The exhibition and explanation of a dissection or
      other anatomical preparation.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) a decisive exhibition of force, or a movement
      indicating an attack.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Logic) The act of proving by the syllogistic process, or
      the proof itself.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Math.) A course of reasoning showing that a certain
      result is a necessary consequence of assumed premises; --
      these premises being definitions, axioms, and previously
      established propositions.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. a public gathering of people to express some sentiment or
      feelings by explicit means, such as picketing, parading,
      carrying signs or shouting, usually in favor of or opposed
      to some action of government or of a business.
      [PJC]

   8. the act of showing how a certain device, machine or
      product operates, or how a procedure is performed; --
      usually done for the purpose of inducing prospective
      customers to buy a product; as, a demonstration of the
      simple operation of a microwave oven.
      [PJC]

   {Direct demonstration}, or {Positive demonstration}, (Logic &amp;
      Math.), one in which the correct conclusion is the
      immediate sequence of reasoning from axiomatic or
      established premises; -- opposed to

   {Indirect demonstration}, or {Negative demonstration} (called
      also {reductio ad absurdum}), in which the correct
      conclusion is an inference from the demonstration that any
      other hypothesis must be incorrect.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>demonstration</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>demonstration
     n 1: a show or display; the act of presenting something to sight
          or view; "the presentation of new data"; "he gave the
          customer a demonstration" [syn: {presentation}, {presentment}]
     2: a show of military force or preparedness; "he confused the
        enemy with feints and demonstrations"
     3: a public display of group feelings (usually of a political
        nature); "there were violent demonstrations against the
        war" [syn: {manifestation}]
     4: proof by a process of argument or a series of proposition
        proving an asserted conclusion [syn: {monstrance}]
     5: a visual presentation showing how something works; "the
        lecture was accompanied by dramatic demonstrations"; "the
        lecturer shot off a pistol as a demonstration of the
        startle response" [syn: {demo}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
