<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>depending</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>depending</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Depend \De*pend"\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Depended}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Depending}.] [F. d['e]pendre, fr. L. depend?re; de- +
   pend?re to hang. See {Pendant}.]
   1. To hang down; to be sustained by being fastened or
      attached to something above.
      [1913 Webster]

            And ever-living lamps depend in rows. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To hang in suspense; to be pending; to be undetermined or
      undecided; as, a cause depending in court.
      [1913 Webster]

            You will not think it unnatural that those who have
            an object depending, which strongly engages their
            hopes and fears, should be somewhat inclined to
            superstition.                         --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To rely for support; to be conditioned or contingent; to
      be connected with anything, as a cause of existence, or as
      a necessary condition; -- followed by on or upon, formerly
      by of.
      [1913 Webster]

            The truth of God's word dependeth not of the truth
            of the congregation.                  --Tyndale.
      [1913 Webster]

            The conclusion . . . that our happiness depends
            little on political institutions, and much on the
            temper and regulation of our own minds. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Heaven forming each on other to depend. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To trust; to rest with confidence; to rely; to confide; to
      be certain; -- with on or upon; as, we depend on the word
      or assurance of our friends; we depend on the mail at the
      usual hour.
      [1913 Webster]

            But if you 're rough, and use him like a dog,
            Depend upon it -- he 'll remain incog. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To serve; to attend; to act as a dependent or retainer.
      [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To impend. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
