<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>depth</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>depth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Depth \Depth\ (s[e^]pth), n. [From {Deep}; akin to D. diepte,
   Icel. d[=y]pt, d[=y]p[eth], Goth. diupi[thorn]a.]
   1. The quality of being deep; deepness; perpendicular
      measurement downward from the surface, or horizontal
      measurement backward from the front; as, the depth of a
      river; the depth of a body of troops.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Profoundness; extent or degree of intensity; abundance;
      completeness; as, depth of knowledge, or color.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mindful of that heavenly love
            Which knows no end in depth or height. --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Lowness; as, depth of sound.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is deep; a deep, or the deepest, part or place;
      the deep; the middle part; as, the depth of night, or of
      winter.
      [1913 Webster]

            From you unclouded depth above.       --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

            The depth closed me round about.      --Jonah ii. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Logic) The number of simple elements which an abstract
      conception or notion includes; the comprehension or
      content.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Horology) A pair of toothed wheels which work together.
      [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (A["e]ronautics) The perpendicular distance from the chord
      to the farthest point of an arched surface.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. (Computers) the maximum number of times a type of
      procedure is reiteratively called before the last call is
      exited; -- of subroutines or procedures which are
      reentrant; -- used of call stacks.
      [PJC]

   {Depth of a sail} (Naut.), the extent of a square sail from
      the head rope to the foot rope; the length of the after
      leach of a staysail or boom sail; -- commonly called the
      {drop of a sail}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>depth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>depth
     n 1: extent downward or backward or inward; "the depth of the
          water"; "depth of a shelf"; "depth of a closet"
     2: degree of psychological or intellectual depth
     3: (usually plural) the deepest and most remote part; "from the
        depths of darkest Africa"; "signals received from the
        depths of space"
     4: (usually plural) a low moral state; "he had sunk to the
        depths of addiction"
     5: the intellectual ability to penetrate deeply into ideas
        [syn: {astuteness}, {profundity}, {profoundness}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
