<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>derivative</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>derivative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Derivative \De*riv"a*tive\, a. [L. derivativus: cf. F.
   d['e]rivatif.]
   Obtained by derivation; derived; not radical, original, or
   fundamental; originating, deduced, or formed from something
   else; secondary; as, a derivative conveyance; a derivative
   word.
   [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, unoriginal (said of art or other intellectual
      products.
      [PJC]

   {Derivative circulation}, a modification of the circulation
      found in some parts of the body, in which the arteries
      empty directly into the veins without the interposition of
      capillaries. --Flint. -- {De*riv"a*tive*ly}, adv. --
      {De*riv"a*tive*ness}, n.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>derivative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Derivative \De*riv"a*tive\, n.
   1. That which is derived; anything obtained or deduced from
      another.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Gram.) A word formed from another word, by a prefix or
      suffix, an internal modification, or some other change; a
      word which takes its origin from a root.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.) A chord, not fundamental, but obtained from another
      by inversion; or, vice versa, a ground tone or root
      implied in its harmonics in an actual chord.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Med.) An agent which is adapted to produce a derivation
      (in the medical sense).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) A derived function; a function obtained from a
      given function by a certain algebraic process.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Except in the mode of derivation the derivative is the
         same as the differential coefficient. See {Differential
         coefficient}, under {Differential}.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. (Chem.) A substance so related to another substance by
      modification or partial substitution as to be regarded as
      derived from it; thus, the amido compounds are derivatives
      of ammonia, and the hydrocarbons are derivatives of
      methane, benzene, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>derivative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>derivative
     adj : resulting from or employing derivation; "a derivative
           process"; "a highly derivative prose style"
     n 1: the result of mathematical differentiation; the
          instantaneous change of one quantity relative to
          another; df(x)/dx [syn: {derived function}, {differential
          coefficient}, {differential}, {first derivative}]
     2: a financial instrument whose value is based on another
        security [syn: {derivative instrument}]
     3: (linguistics) a word that is derived from another word;
        "`electricity' is a derivative of `electric'"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
