<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>design</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>design</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>design
     
        &lt;process&gt; The approach that engineering (and some other)
        disciplines use to specify how to create or do something.  A
        successful design must satisfies a (perhaps informal)
        {functional specification} (do what it was designed to do);
        conforms to the limitations of the target medium (it is
        possible to implement); meets implicit or explicit
        requirements on performance and resource usage (it is
        efficient enough).
     
        A design may also have to satisfy restrictions on the design
        process itself, such as its length or cost, or the tools
        available for doing the design.
     
        In the {software life-cycle}, design follows {requirements
        analysis} and is followed by implementation.
     
        ["Object-Oriented Analysis and Design with Applications", 2nd
        ed., Grady Booch].
     
        (1996-12-08)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>design</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Design \De*sign"\ (?; 277), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Designed}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Designing}.] [F. d['e]signer to designate, cf.
   F. dessiner to draw, dessin drawing, dessein a plan or
   scheme; all, ultimately, from L. designare to designate; de-
   + signare to mark, mark out, signum mark, sign. See {Sign},
   and cf. {Design}, n., {Designate}.]
   1. To draw preliminary outline or main features of; to sketch
      for a pattern or model; to delineate; to trace out; to
      draw. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mark out and exhibit; to designate; to indicate; to
      show; to point out; to appoint.
      [1913 Webster]

            We shall see
            Justice design the victor's chivalry. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Meet me to-morrow where the master
            And this fraternity shall design.     --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To create or produce, as a work of art; to form a plan or
      scheme of; to form in idea; to invent; to project; to lay
      out in the mind; as, a man designs an essay, a poem, a
      statue, or a cathedral.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To intend or purpose; -- usually with for before the
      remote object, but sometimes with to.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ask of politicians the end for which laws were
            originally designed.                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was designed to the study of the law. --Dryden.

   Syn: To sketch; plan; purpose; intend; propose; project;
        mean.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>design</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Design \De*sign"\, v. i.
   To form a design or designs; to plan.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Design for}, to intend to go to. [Obs.] ``From this city she
      designed for Collin [Cologne].'' --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>design</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Design \De*sign"\, n. [Cf. dessein, dessin.]
   1. A preliminary sketch; an outline or pattern of the main
      features of something to be executed, as of a picture, a
      building, or a decoration; a delineation; a plan.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A plan or scheme formed in the mind of something to be
      done; preliminary conception; idea intended to be
      expressed in a visible form or carried into action;
      intention; purpose; -- often used in a bad sense for evil
      intention or purpose; scheme; plot.
      [1913 Webster]

            The vast design and purpos? of the King. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            The leaders of that assembly who withstood the
            designs of a besotted woman.          --Hallam.
      [1913 Webster]

            A . . . settled design upon another man's life.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            How little he could guess the secret designs of the
            court!                                --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically, intention or purpose as revealed or inferred
      from the adaptation of means to an end; as, the argument
      from design.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The realization of an inventive or decorative plan; esp.,
      a work of decorative art considered as a new creation;
      conception or plan shown in completed work; as, this
      carved panel is a fine design, or of a fine design.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.) The invention and conduct of the subject; the
      disposition of every part, and the general order of the
      whole.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Arts of design}, those into which the designing of artistic
      forms and figures enters as a principal part, as
      architecture, painting, engraving, sculpture.

   {School of design}, one in which are taught the invention and
      delineation of artistic or decorative figures, patterns,
      and the like.

   Syn: Intention; purpose; scheme; project; plan; idea.

   Usage: {Design}, {Intention}, {Purpose}. Design has reference
          to something definitely aimed at. Intention points to
          the feelings or desires with which a thing is sought.
          Purpose has reference to a settled choice or
          determination for its attainment. ``I had no design to
          injure you,'' means it was no part of my aim or
          object. ``I had no intention to injure you,'' means, I
          had no wish or desire of that kind. ``My purpose was
          directly the reverse,'' makes the case still stronger.
          [1913 Webster]

                Is he a prudent man . . . that lays designs only
                for a day, without any prospect to the remaining
                part of his life?                 --Tillotson.
          [1913 Webster]

                I wish others the same intention, and greater
                successes.                        --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
          [1913 Webster]

                It is the purpose that makes strong the vow.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>design</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>design
     n 1: the act of working out the form of something (as by making a
          sketch or outline or plan); "he contributed to the
          design of a new instrument" [syn: {designing}]
     2: an arrangement scheme; "the awkward design of the keyboard
        made operation difficult"; "it was an excellent design for
        living"; "a plan for seating guests" [syn: {plan}]
     3: something intended as a guide for making something else; "a
        blueprint for a house"; "a pattern for a skirt" [syn: {blueprint},
         {pattern}]
     4: a decorative or artistic work; "the coach had a design on
        the doors" [syn: {pattern}, {figure}]
     5: an anticipated outcome that is intended or that guides your
        planned actions; "his intent was to provide a new
        translation"; "good intentions are not enough"; "it was
        created with the conscious aim of answering immediate
        needs"; "he made no secret of his designs" [syn: {purpose},
         {intent}, {intention}, {aim}]
     6: a preliminary sketch indicating the plan for something; "the
        design of a building"
     7: the creation of something in the mind [syn: {invention}, {innovation},
         {excogitation}, {conception}]
     v 1: make or work out a plan for; devise; "They contrived to
          murder their boss"; "design a new sales strategy"; "plan
          an attack" [syn: {plan}, {project}, {contrive}]
     2: design something for a specific role or purpose or effect;
        "This room is not designed for work"
     3: create the design for; create or execute in an artistic or
        highly skilled manner; "Chanel designed the famous suit"
     4: make a design of; plan out in systematic, often graphic
        form; "design a better mousetrap"; "plan the new wing of
        the museum" [syn: {plan}]
     5: create designs; "Dupont designs for the house of Chanel"
     6: conceive or fashion in the mind; invent; "She designed a
        good excuse for not attending classes that day"
     7: intend or have as a purpose; "She designed to go far in the
        world of business"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
