<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>develop</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>develop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Develop \De*vel"op\, v. i.
   1. To go through a process of natural evolution or growth, by
      successive changes from a less perfect to a more perfect
      or more highly organized state; to advance from a simpler
      form of existence to one more complex either in structure
      or function; as, a blossom develops from a bud; the seed
      develops into a plant; the embryo develops into a
      well-formed animal; the mind develops year by year.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor poets enough to understand
            That life develops from within.       --Mrs.
                                                  Browning.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To become apparent gradually; as, a picture on sensitive
      paper develops on the application of heat; the plans of
      the conspirators develop.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>develop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Develop \De*vel"op\ (d[-e]*v[e^]l"[o^]p), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Developed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Developing}.] [F. d['e]veloper;
   d['e]- (L. dis-) + OF. voluper, voleper, to envelop, perh.
   from L. volup agreeably, delightfully, and hence orig., to
   make agreeable or comfortable by enveloping, to keep snug
   (cf. {Voluptuous}); or. perh. fr. a derivative of volvere,
   volutum, to roll (cf. {Devolve}). Cf. {Envelop}.] [Written
   also {develope}.]
   1. To free from that which infolds or envelops; to unfold; to
      lay open by degrees or in detail; to make visible or
      known; to disclose; to produce or give forth; as, to
      develop theories; a motor that develops 100 horse power.
      [1913 Webster]

            These serve to develop its tenets.    --Milner.
      [1913 Webster]

            The 20th was spent in strengthening our position and
            developing the line of the enemy.     --The Century.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To unfold gradually, as a flower from a bud; hence, to
      bring through a succession of states or stages, each of
      which is preparatory to the next; to form or expand by a
      process of growth; to cause to change gradually from an
      embryo, or a lower state, to a higher state or form of
      being; as, sunshine and rain develop the bud into a
      flower; to develop the mind.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sound developed itself into a real compound.
                                                  --J. Peile.
      [1913 Webster]

            All insects . . . acquire the jointed legs before
            the wings are fully developed.        --Owen.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To advance; to further; to prefect; to make to increase;
      to promote the growth of.
      [1913 Webster]

            We must develop our own resources to the utmost.
                                                  --Jowett
                                                  (Thucyd).
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Math.) To change the form of, as of an algebraic
      expression, by executing certain indicated operations
      without changing the value.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Photog.) To cause to become visible, as an invisible or
      latent image upon plate, by submitting it to chemical
      agents; to bring to view.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To develop a curved surface on a plane} (Geom.), to produce
      on the plane an equivalent surface, as if by rolling the
      curved surface so that all parts shall successively touch
      the plane.

   Syn: To uncover; unfold; evolve; promote; project; lay open;
        disclose; exhibit; unravel; disentangle.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>develop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>develop
     v 1: make something new, such as a product or a mental or
          artistic creation; "Her company developed a new kind of
          building material that withstands all kinds of weather";
          "They developed a new technique"
     2: work out; "We have developed a new theory of evolution"
        [syn: {evolve}, {germinate}]
     3: gain through experience; "I acquired a strong aversion to
        television"; "Children must develop a sense of right and
        wrong"; "Dave developed leadership qualities in his new
        position"; "develop a passion for painting" [syn: {acquire},
         {evolve}]
     4: come to have or undergo a change of (physical features and
        attributes); "He grew a beard"; "The patient developed
        abdominal pains"; "I got funny spots all over my body";
        "Well-developed breasts" [syn: {grow}, {produce}, {get}, {acquire}]
     5: come into existence; take on form or shape; "A new religious
        movement originated in that country"; "a love that sprang
        up from friendship"; "the idea for the book grew out of a
        short story"; "An interesting phenomenon uprose" [syn: {originate},
         {arise}, {rise}, {uprise}, {spring up}, {grow}]
     6: change the use of and make available or usable; "develop
        land"; "The country developed its natural resources"; "The
        remote areas of the country were gradually built up" [syn:
         {build up}]
     7: elaborate, as of theories and hypotheses; "Could you develop
        the ideas in your thesis" [syn: {explicate}, {formulate}]
     8: create by training and teaching; "The old master is training
        world-class violinists"; "we develop the leaders for the
        future" [syn: {train}, {prepare}, {educate}]
     9: be gradually disclosed or unfolded; become manifest; "The
        plot developed slowly";
     10: grow, progress, unfold, or evolve through a process of
         evolution, natural growth, differentiation, or a
         conducive environment; "A flower developed on the
         branch"; "The country developed into a mighty
         superpower"; "The embryo develops into a fetus"; "This
         situation has developed over a long time"
     11: become technologically advanced; "Many countries in Asia are
         now developing at a very fast pace"; "Viet Nam is
         modernizing rapidly" [syn: {modernize}, {modernise}]
     12: cause to grow and differentiate in ways conforming to its
         natural development; "The perfect climate here develops
         the grain"; "He developed a new kind of apple" [syn: {make
         grow}]
     13: generate gradually; "We must develop more potential
         customers"; "develop a market for the new mobile phone"
     14: grow emotionally or mature; "The child developed beautifully
         in her new kindergarten"; "When he spent a summer at
         camp, the boy grew noticeably and no longer showed some
         of his old adolescent behavior" [syn: {grow}]
     15: make visible by means of chemical solutions; "Please develop
         this roll of film for me"
     16: superimpose a three-dimensional surface on a plane without
         stretching, in geometry
     17: move one's pieces into strategically more advantageous
         positions; "Spassky developed quickly"
     18: move into a strategically more advantageous position;
         "develop the rook"
     19: elaborate by the unfolding of a musical idea and by the
         working out of the rhythmic and harmonic changes in the
         theme; "develop the melody and change the key"
     20: happen; "Report the news as it develops"; "These political
         movements recrudesce from time to time" [syn: {break}, {recrudesce}]
     21: expand in the form of a series; "Develop the function in the
         following form"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
