<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>device</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>device</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>device
     
        {peripheral}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>device</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Device \De*vice"\, n. [OE. devis, devise, will, intention,
   opinion, invention, fr. F. devis architect's plan and
   estimates (in OF., division, plan, wish), devise device (in
   sense 3), in OF. also, division, wish, last will, fr.
   deviser. See {Devise}, v. t., and cf. {Devise}, n.]
   1. That which is devised, or formed by design; a contrivance;
      an invention; a project; a scheme; often, a scheme to
      deceive; a stratagem; an artifice.
      [1913 Webster]

            His device in against Babylon, to destroy it. --Jer.
                                                  li. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their recent device of demanding benevolences.
                                                  --Hallam.
      [1913 Webster]

            He disappointeth the devices of the crafty. --Job v.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Power of devising; invention; contrivance.
      [1913 Webster]

            I must have instruments of my own device. --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

   3.
      (a) An emblematic design, generally consisting of one or
          more figures with a motto, used apart from heraldic
          bearings to denote the historical situation, the
          ambition, or the desire of the person adopting it. See
          {Cognizance}.
      (b) Improperly, an heraldic bearing.
          [1913 Webster]

                Knights-errant used to distinguish themselves by
                devices on their shields.         --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

                A banner with this strange device 
                Excelsior.                        --Longfellow.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything fancifully conceived. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A spectacle or show. [Obs.] --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Opinion; decision. [Obs.] --Rom. of R.

   7. any artifactual object designed to perform an action or
      process, with or without an operator in attendance.
      [PJC]

   Syn: Contrivance; invention; design; scheme; project;
        stratagem; shift.

   Usage: -- {Device}, {Contrivance}. Device implies more of
          inventive power, and contrivance more of skill and
          dexterity in execution. A device usually has reference
          to something worked out for exhibition or show; a
          contrivance usually respects the arrangement or
          disposition of things with reference to securing some
          end. Devices were worn by knights-errant on their
          shields; contrivances are generally used to promote
          the practical convenience of life. The word device is
          often used in a bad sense; as, a crafty device;
          contrivance is almost always used in a good sense; as,
          a useful contrivance.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>device</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>device
     n 1: an instrumentality invented for a particular purpose; "the
          device is small enough to wear on your wrist"; "a device
          intended to conserve water"
     2: something in an artistic work designed to achieve a
        particular effect
     3: any clever (deceptive) maneuver; "he would stoop to any
        device to win a point" [syn: {gimmick}, {twist}]
     4: any ornamental pattern or design (as in embroidery)
     5: an emblematic design (especially in heraldry); "he was
        recognized by the device on his shield"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
