<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>diabetes</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>diabetes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>diabetes \di`a*be"tes\, n. [NL., from Gr. ?, fr. ? to pass or
   cross over. See {Diabase}.] (Med.)
   Any of several diseases which is attended with a persistent,
   excessive discharge of urine; when used without
   qualification, the term usually refers to {diabetes
   mellitus}. The most common form is {diabetes mellitus}, in
   which the urine is not only increased in quantity, but
   contains saccharine matter, and the condition if untreated is
   generally fatal.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: The two major subtypes recognized are

   {diabetes insipidus} and

   {diabetes mellitus}. In {diabetes insipidus} there is
      excretion of large amounts of urine of relatively low
      density, accompanied by extreme thirst, but the urine
      contains no abnormal constituent. The more serious form
      {diabetes mellitus} (from Latin mellitus, sweetened with
      honey) is a metabolic disease in which the utilization of
      carbohydrate is reduced and that of lipids and proteins is
      increased. This form is caused by a deficiency in insulin
      (which is mostly formed in the pancreas), and may be
      accompanied by glucosuria, hyperglycemia, elecrolyte loss,
      ketoacidosis, and sometimes coma. It has severe long-term
      effects, including damage to the nerves, the retina, and
      the kidney, and degeneration of blood vessels which may
      lead to poor circulation, especially in the limbs,
      subsequent infection, and eventual loss of limbs.
      Diabetes mellitus itself has recognized variants, being
      divided into {insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus} and
      {non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus}.
      Non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus is also called
      {adult-onset diabetes} (abbreviated NIDDM), and is the
      less severe form of diabetes mellitus, occurring mostly in
      obese individuals over the age of 35. It may be treated by
      diet and oral hypoglycemic agents, though occasionally
      serious degenerative effects may develop.
      Insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus (abbreviated IDDM),
      also called {type I diabetes}, is a severe form of the
      disease, usually starting when the affected person is
      young (hence also called {juvenile-onset diabetes}). In
      addition to the increased urine (polyuria) common to all
      forms of diabetes, this form is characterized by low
      levels of insulin in the blood, ketoacidosis, increased
      appetite, and increased fluid intake, and may lead to
      weight loss and eventually the severe degenerative effects
      mentioned above. Treatment requires administration of
      insulin and careful regulation of the diet. --Stedman
      [PJC]

   {Diabetes mellitus} [NL., sweet diabetes], that form of
      diabetes in which the urine contains saccharine matter.

   {Diabetes insipidus} [NL., lit., diabetes], the form of
      diabetes in which the urine contains no abnormal
      constituent.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>diabetes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>diabetes
     n : any of several metabolic disorders marked by excessive
         urination and persistent thirst
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
