<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dial</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dial</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dial
   for the measurement of time, only once mentioned in the Bible,
   erected by Ahaz (2 Kings 20:11; Isa. 38:8). The Hebrew word
   (ma'aloth) is rendered "steps" in Ex. 20:26, 1 Kings 10:19, and
   "degrees" in 2 Kings 20:9, 10, 11. The _ma'aloth_ was probably
   stairs on which the shadow of a column or obelisk placed on the
   top fell. The shadow would cover a greater or smaller number of
   steps, according as the sun was low or high.
   
     Probably the sun-dial was a Babylonian invention. Daniel at
   Babylon (Dan. 3:6) is the first to make mention of the "hour."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dial</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dial \Di"al\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dialed}or {Dialled}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Dialing} or {Dialling}.]
   1. To measure with a dial.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hours of that true time which is dialed in heaven.
                                                  --Talfourd.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mining) To survey with a dial. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dial</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dial \Di"al\, n. [LL. dialis daily, fr. L. dies day. See
   {Deity}.]
   1. An instrument, formerly much used for showing the time of
      day from the shadow of a style or gnomon on a graduated
      arc or surface; esp., a sundial; but there are lunar and
      astral dials. The style or gnomon is usually parallel to
      the earth's axis, but the dial plate may be either
      horizontal or vertical.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The graduated face of a timepiece, on which the time of
      day is shown by pointers or hands.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A miner's compass.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Dial bird} (Zo["o]l.), an Indian bird ({Copsychus
      saularius}), allied to the European robin. The name is
      also given to other related species.

   {Dial lock}, a lock provided with one or more plates having
      numbers or letters upon them. These plates must be
      adjusted in a certain determined way before the lock can
      be operated.

   {Dial plate}, the plane or disk of a dial or timepiece on
      which lines and figures for indicating the time are
      placed.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dial</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dial
     n 1: the face of a timepiece; graduated to show the hours
     2: the control on a radio or television set that is used for
        tuning
     3: the circular graduated indicator on various measuring
        instruments
     4: a disc on a telephone that is rotated a fixed distance for
        each number called [syn: {telephone dial}]
     v 1: operate a dial to select a telephone number; "You must take
          the receiver off the hook before you dial"
     2: choose by means of a dial; "dial a telephone number"
     [also: {dialling}, {dialled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
