<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>die</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>die</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DIE, n.  The singular of "dice."  We seldom hear the word, because
there is a prohibitory proverb, "Never say die."  At long intervals,
however, some one says:  "The die is cast," which is not true, for it
is cut.  The word is found in an immortal couplet by that eminent poet
and domestic economist, Senator Depew:

    A cube of cheese no larger than a die
    May bait the trap to catch a nibbling mie.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>die</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>die
     
        1. &lt;jargon&gt; {crash}.  Unlike {crash}, which is used primarily
        of hardware, this verb is used of both hardware and software.
     
        See also {go flatline}, {casters-up mode}.
     
        2. &lt;electronics&gt; Plural: dies.  An unpackaged {integrated
        circuit}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (2002-12-09)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>die</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dice \Dice\ (d[imac]s), n.; pl. of {Die}.
   Small cubes used in gaming or in determining by chance; also,
   the game played with dice. See {Die}, n.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Dice coal}, a kind of coal easily splitting into cubical
      fragments. --Brande &amp; C.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>die</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Die \Die\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Died}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Dying}.]
   [OE. deyen, dien, of Scand. origin; cf. Icel. deyja; akin to
   Dan. d["o]e, Sw. d["o], Goth. diwan (cf. Goth. afd?jan to
   harass), OFries. d?ia to kill, OS. doian to die, OHG. touwen,
   OSlav. daviti to choke, Lith. dovyti to torment. Cf. {Dead},
   {Death}.]
   1. To pass from an animate to a lifeless state; to cease to
      live; to suffer a total and irreparable loss of action of
      the vital functions; to become dead; to expire; to perish;
      -- said of animals and vegetables; often with of, by,
      with, from, and rarely for, before the cause or occasion
      of death; as, to die of disease or hardships; to die by
      fire or the sword; to die with horror at the thought.
      [1913 Webster]

            To die by the roadside of grief and hunger.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            She will die from want of care.       --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To suffer death; to lose life.
      [1913 Webster]

            In due time Christ died for the ungodly. --Rom. v.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To perish in any manner; to cease; to become lost or
      extinct; to be extinguished.
      [1913 Webster]

            Letting the secret die within his own breast.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

            Great deeds can not die.              --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To sink; to faint; to pine; to languish, with weakness,
      discouragement, love, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            His heart died within, and he became as a stone. --1
                                                  Sam. xxv. 37.
      [1913 Webster]

            The young men acknowledged, in love letters, that
            they died for Rebecca.                --Tatler.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To become indifferent; to cease to be subject; as, to die
      to pleasure or to sin.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To recede and grow fainter; to become imperceptible; to
      vanish; -- often with out or away.
      [1913 Webster]

            Blemishes may die away and disappear amidst the
            brightness.                           --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Arch.) To disappear gradually in another surface, as
      where moldings are lost in a sloped or curved face.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To become vapid, flat, or spiritless, as liquor.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To die in the last ditch}, to fight till death; to die
      rather than surrender.
      [1913 Webster]

            ``There is one certain way,'' replied the Prince
            [William of Orange] `` by which I can be sure never
            to see my country's ruin, -- I will die in the last
            ditch.''                              --Hume (Hist.
                                                  of Eng. ).

   {To die out}, to cease gradually; as, the prejudice has died
      out.

   Syn: To expire; decease; perish; depart; vanish.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>die</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Die \Die\, n.; pl. in 1 and (usually) in 2, {Dice} (d[=i]s); in
   4 &amp; 5, {Dies} (d[=i]z). [OE. dee, die, F. d['e], fr. L. datus
   given, thrown, p. p. of dare to give, throw. See {Date} a
   point of time.]
   1. A small cube, marked on its faces with spots from one to
      six, and used in playing games by being shaken in a box
      and thrown from it. See {Dice}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any small cubical or square body.
      [1913 Webster]

            Words . . . pasted upon little flat tablets or dies.
                                                  --Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is, or might be, determined, by a throw of the
      die; hazard; chance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Such is the die of war.               --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Arch.) That part of a pedestal included between base and
      cornice; the dado.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mach.)
      (a) A metal or plate (often one of a pair) so cut or
          shaped as to give a certain desired form to, or
          impress any desired device on, an object or surface,
          by pressure or by a blow; used in forging metals,
          coining, striking up sheet metal, etc.
      (b) A perforated block, commonly of hardened steel used in
          connection with a punch, for punching holes, as
          through plates, or blanks from plates, or for forming
          cups or capsules, as from sheet metal, by drawing.
      (c) A hollow internally threaded screw-cutting tool, made
          in one piece or composed of several parts, for forming
          screw threads on bolts, etc.; one of the separate
          parts which make up such a tool.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Cutting die} (Mech.), a thin, deep steel frame, sharpened to
      a cutting edge, for cutting out articles from leather,
      cloth, paper, etc.

   {The die is cast}, the hazard must be run; the step is taken,
      and it is too late to draw back; the last chance is taken.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>die</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>die v. Syn. {crash}. Unlike {crash}, which is used primarily of
   hardware, this verb is used of both hardware and software. See also {go
   flatline}, {casters-up mode}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>die</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>die
     n 1: small cubes with 1 to 6 spots on the faces; used to generate
          random numbers [syn: {dice}]
     2: a device used for shaping metal
     3: a cutting tool that is fitted into a diestock and used for
        cutting male (external) screw threads on screws or bolts
        or pipes or rods
     v 1: pass from physical life and lose all all bodily attributes
          and functions necessary to sustain life; "She died from
          cancer"; "They children perished in the fire"; "The
          patient went peacefully" [syn: {decease}, {perish}, {go},
           {exit}, {pass away}, {expire}, {pass}] [ant: {be born}]
     2: suffer or face the pain of death; "Martyrs may die every day
        for their faith"
     3: be brought to or as if to the point of death by an intense
        emotion such as embarrassment, amusement, or shame; "I was
        dying with embarrassment when my little lie was
        discovered"; "We almost died laughing during the show"
     4: stop operating or functioning; "The engine finally went";
        "The car died on the road"; "The bus we travelled in broke
        down on the way to town"; "The coffee maker broke"; "The
        engine failed on the way to town"; "her eyesight went
        after the accident" [syn: {fail}, {go bad}, {give way}, {give
        out}, {conk out}, {go}, {break}, {break down}]
     5: feel indifferent towards; "She died to worldly things and
        eventually entered a monastery"
     6: languish as with love or desire; "She dying for a
        cigarette"; "I was dying to leave"
     7: cut or shape with a die; "Die out leather for belts" [syn: {die
        out}]
     8: to be on base at the end of an inning, of a player
     9: lose sparkle or bouquet; "wine and beer can pall" [syn: {pall},
         {become flat}]
     10: disappear or come to an end; "Their anger died"; "My secret
         will die with me!"
     11: suffer spiritual death; be damned (in the religious sense);
         "Whosoever..believes in me shall never die"
     [also: {dying}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
