<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>died</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>died</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Die \Die\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Died}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Dying}.]
   [OE. deyen, dien, of Scand. origin; cf. Icel. deyja; akin to
   Dan. d["o]e, Sw. d["o], Goth. diwan (cf. Goth. afd?jan to
   harass), OFries. d?ia to kill, OS. doian to die, OHG. touwen,
   OSlav. daviti to choke, Lith. dovyti to torment. Cf. {Dead},
   {Death}.]
   1. To pass from an animate to a lifeless state; to cease to
      live; to suffer a total and irreparable loss of action of
      the vital functions; to become dead; to expire; to perish;
      -- said of animals and vegetables; often with of, by,
      with, from, and rarely for, before the cause or occasion
      of death; as, to die of disease or hardships; to die by
      fire or the sword; to die with horror at the thought.
      [1913 Webster]

            To die by the roadside of grief and hunger.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            She will die from want of care.       --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To suffer death; to lose life.
      [1913 Webster]

            In due time Christ died for the ungodly. --Rom. v.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To perish in any manner; to cease; to become lost or
      extinct; to be extinguished.
      [1913 Webster]

            Letting the secret die within his own breast.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

            Great deeds can not die.              --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To sink; to faint; to pine; to languish, with weakness,
      discouragement, love, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            His heart died within, and he became as a stone. --1
                                                  Sam. xxv. 37.
      [1913 Webster]

            The young men acknowledged, in love letters, that
            they died for Rebecca.                --Tatler.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To become indifferent; to cease to be subject; as, to die
      to pleasure or to sin.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To recede and grow fainter; to become imperceptible; to
      vanish; -- often with out or away.
      [1913 Webster]

            Blemishes may die away and disappear amidst the
            brightness.                           --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Arch.) To disappear gradually in another surface, as
      where moldings are lost in a sloped or curved face.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To become vapid, flat, or spiritless, as liquor.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To die in the last ditch}, to fight till death; to die
      rather than surrender.
      [1913 Webster]

            ``There is one certain way,'' replied the Prince
            [William of Orange] `` by which I can be sure never
            to see my country's ruin, -- I will die in the last
            ditch.''                              --Hume (Hist.
                                                  of Eng. ).

   {To die out}, to cease gradually; as, the prejudice has died
      out.

   Syn: To expire; decease; perish; depart; vanish.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
