<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>digest</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>digest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>digest
     
        A periodical collection of messages which have been posted to
        a {newsgroup} or {mailing list}.  A digest is prepared by a
        {moderator} who selects articles from the group or list,
        formats them and adds a contents list.  The digest is then
        either mailed to an alternative {mailing list} or posted to an
        alternative newsgroup.
     
        Some {news reader}s and {electronic mail} programs provide
        commands to "undigestify" a digest, i.e. to split it up into
        individual articles which may then be read and saved or
        discarded separately.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>digest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Digest \Di*gest"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Digested}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Digesting}.] [L. digestus, p. p. of digerere to separate,
   arrange, dissolve, digest; di- = dis- + gerere to bear,
   carry, wear. See {Jest}.]
   1. To distribute or arrange methodically; to work over and
      classify; to reduce to portions for ready use or
      application; as, to digest the laws, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Joining them together and digesting them into order.
                                                  --Blair.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have cause to be glad that matters are so well
            digested.                             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Physiol.) To separate (the food) in its passage through
      the alimentary canal into the nutritive and nonnutritive
      elements; to prepare, by the action of the digestive
      juices, for conversion into blood; to convert into chyme.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To think over and arrange methodically in the mind; to
      reduce to a plan or method; to receive in the mind and
      consider carefully; to get an understanding of; to
      comprehend.
      [1913 Webster]

            Feelingly digest the words you speak in prayer.
                                                  --Sir H.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

            How shall this bosom multiplied digest
            The senate's courtesy?                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To appropriate for strengthening and comfort.
      [1913 Webster]

            Grant that we may in such wise hear them [the
            Scriptures], read, mark, learn, and inwardly digest
            them.                                 --Book of
                                                  Common Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence: To bear comfortably or patiently; to be reconciled
      to; to brook.
      [1913 Webster]

            I never can digest the loss of most of Origin's
            works.                                --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Chem.) To soften by heat and moisture; to expose to a
      gentle heat in a boiler or matrass, as a preparation for
      chemical operations.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Med.) To dispose to suppurate, or generate healthy pus,
      as an ulcer or wound.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To ripen; to mature. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Well-digested fruits.                 --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To quiet or abate, as anger or grief.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>digest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Digest \Di*gest"\, v. i.
   1. To undergo digestion; as, food digests well or ill.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Med.) To suppurate; to generate pus, as an ulcer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>digest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Digest \Di"gest\, n. [L. digestum, pl. digesta, neut., fr.
   digestus, p. p.: cf. F. digeste. See {Digest}, v. t.]
   That which is digested; especially, that which is worked
   over, classified, and arranged under proper heads or titles;
   esp. (Law), A compilation of statutes or decisions
   analytically arranged. The term is applied in a general sense
   to the Pandects of Justinian (see {Pandect}), but is also
   specially given by authors to compilations of laws on
   particular topics; a summary of laws; as, Comyn's Digest; the
   United States Digest.
   [1913 Webster]

         A complete digest of Hindu and Mahommedan laws after
         the model of Justinian's celebrated Pandects. --Sir W.
                                                  Jones.
   [1913 Webster]

         They made a sort of institute and digest of anarchy,
         called the Rights of Man.                --Burke.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>digest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>digest
     n 1: a periodical that summarizes the news
     2: something that is compiled (as into a single book or file)
        [syn: {compilation}]
     v 1: convert food into absorbable substances; "I cannot digest
          milk products"
     2: arrange and integrate in the mind; "I cannot digest all this
        information"
     3: put up with something or somebody unpleasant; "I cannot bear
        his constant criticism"; "The new secretary had to endure
        a lot of unprofessional remarks"; "he learned to tolerate
        the heat"; "She stuck out two years in a miserable
        marriage" [syn: {endure}, {stick out}, {stomach}, {bear},
        {stand}, {tolerate}, {support}, {brook}, {abide}, {suffer},
         {put up}]
     4: become assimilated into the body; "Protein digests in a few
        hours"
     5: systematize, as by classifying and summarizing; "the
        government digested the entire law into a code"
     6: soften or disintegrate, as by undergoing exposure to heat or
        moisture
     7: make more concise; "condense the contents of a book into a
        summary" [syn: {condense}, {concentrate}]
     8: soften or disintegrate by means of chemical action, heat, or
        moisture
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
