<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dimension</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dimension</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dimension \Di*men"sion\, n. [L. dimensio, fr. dimensus, p. p. of
   dimetiri to measure out; di- = dis- + metiri to measure: cf.
   F. dimension. See {Measure}.]
   1. Measure in a single line, as length, breadth, height,
      thickness, or circumference; extension; measurement; --
      usually, in the plural, measure in length and breadth, or
      in length, breadth, and thickness; extent; size; as, the
      dimensions of a room, or of a ship; the dimensions of a
      farm, of a kingdom.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gentlemen of more than ordinary dimensions. --W.
                                                  Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Space of dimension}, extension that has length but no
      breadth or thickness; a straight or curved line.

   {Space of two dimensions}, extension which has length and
      breadth, but no thickness; a plane or curved surface.

   {Space of three dimensions}, extension which has length,
      breadth, and thickness; a solid.

   {Space of four dimensions}, as imaginary kind of extension,
      which is assumed to have length, breadth, thickness, and
      also a fourth imaginary dimension. Space of five or six,
      or more dimensions is also sometimes assumed in
      mathematics.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Extent; reach; scope; importance; as, a project of large
      dimensions.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Math.) The degree of manifoldness of a quantity; as, time
      is quantity having one dimension; volume has three
      dimensions, relative to extension.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Alg.) A literal factor, as numbered in characterizing a
      term. The term dimensions forms with the cardinal numbers
      a phrase equivalent to degree with the ordinal; thus,
      a^{2}b^{2}c is a term of five dimensions, or of the fifth
      degree.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. (Phys.) The manifoldness with which the fundamental
      units of time, length, and mass are involved in
      determining the units of other physical quantities.

   Note: Thus, since the unit of velocity varies directly as the
         unit of length and inversely as the unit of time, the
         dimensions of velocity are said to be length [divby]
         time; the dimensions of work are mass [times]
         (length)^{2} [divby] (time)^{2}; the dimensions of
         density are mass [divby] (length)^{3}.

   {Dimensional lumber}, {Dimension lumber}, {Dimension
   scantling}, or {Dimension stock} (Carp.), lumber for
      building, etc., cut to the sizes usually in demand, or to
      special sizes as ordered.

   {Dimension stone}, stone delivered from the quarry rough, but
      brought to such sizes as are requisite for cutting to
      dimensions given.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dimension</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dimension
     n 1: the magnitude of something in a particular direction
          (especially length or width or height)
     2: a construct whereby objects or individuals can be
        distinguished; "self-confidence is not an endearing
        property" [syn: {property}, {attribute}]
     3: one of three cartesian coordinates that determine a position
        in space
     4: magnitude or extent; "a building of vast proportions" [syn:
        {proportion}]
     v 1: indicate the dimensions on; "These techniques permit us to
          dimension the human heart"
     2: shape or form to required dimensions
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
