<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>diminished</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>diminished</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Diminish \Di*min"ish\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Diminished}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Diminishing}.] [Pref. di- (= L. dis-) + minish: cf.
   L. diminuere, F. diminuer, OE. diminuen. See {Dis-}, and
   {Minish}.]
   1. To make smaller in any manner; to reduce in bulk or
      amount; to lessen; -- opposed to {augment} or {increase}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not diminish, but rather increase, the debt.
                                                  --Barrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lessen the authority or dignity of; to put down; to
      degrade; to abase; to weaken.
      [1913 Webster]

            This doth nothing diminish their opinion. --Robynson
                                                  (More's
                                                  Utopia).
      [1913 Webster]

            I will diminish them, that they shall no more rule
            over the nations.                     --Ezek. xxix.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

            O thou . . . at whose sight all the stars
            Hide their diminished heads.          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.) To make smaller by a half step; to make (an
      interval) less than minor; as, a diminished seventh.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To take away; to subtract.
      [1913 Webster]

            Neither shall ye diminish aught from it. --Deut. iv.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Diminished column}, one whose upper diameter is less than
      the lower.

   {Diminished scale}, or {Diminishing scale}, a scale of
      gradation used in finding the different points for drawing
      the spiral curve of the volute. --Gwilt.

   {Diminishing rule} (Arch.), a board cut with a concave edge,
      for fixing the entasis and curvature of a shaft.

   {Diminishing stile} (Arch.), a stile which is narrower in one
      part than in another, as in many glazed doors.

   Syn: To decrease; lessen; abate; reduce; contract; curtail;
        impair; degrade. See {Decrease}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>diminished</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>diminished
     adj 1: impaired by diminution [syn: {lessened}, {vitiated}, {weakened}]
     2: (of an organ or body part) diminished in size or strength as
        a result of disease or injury or lack of use; "partial
        paralysis resulted in an atrophied left arm" [syn: {atrophied},
         {wasted}] [ant: {hypertrophied}]
     3: (of musical intervals) reduction by a semitone of any
        perfect or minor musical interval; "a diminished fifth"
     4: made to seem smaller or less (especially in worth); "her
        comments made me feel small" [syn: {belittled}, {small}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
