<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dip</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DIP
     
        1. {Dual In-line Package}.
     
        2. {Document Image Processing}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Magnetic \Mag*net"ic\, Magnetical \Mag*net"ic*al\, a. [L.
   magneticus: cf. F. magn['e]tique.]
   1. Pertaining to the magnet; possessing the properties of the
      magnet, or corresponding properties; as, a magnetic bar of
      iron; a magnetic needle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of or pertaining to, or characterized by, the earth's
      magnetism; as, the magnetic north; the magnetic meridian.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Capable of becoming a magnet; susceptible to magnetism;
      as, the magnetic metals.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Endowed with extraordinary personal power to excite the
      feelings and to win the affections; attractive; inducing
      attachment.
      [1913 Webster]

            She that had all magnetic force alone. --Donne.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Having, susceptible to, or induced by, animal magnetism,
      so called; hypnotic; as, a magnetic sleep. See
      {Magnetism}. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   {Magnetic amplitude}, {attraction}, {dip}, {induction}, etc.
      See under {Amplitude}, {Attraction}, etc.

   {Magnetic battery}, a combination of bar or horseshoe magnets
      with the like poles adjacent, so as to act together with
      great power.

   {Magnetic compensator}, a contrivance connected with a ship's
      compass for compensating or neutralizing the effect of the
      iron of the ship upon the needle.

   {Magnetic curves}, curves indicating lines of magnetic force,
      as in the arrangement of iron filings between the poles of
      a powerful magnet.

   {Magnetic elements}.
      (a) (Chem. Physics) Those elements, as iron, nickel,
          cobalt, chromium, manganese, etc., which are capable
          or becoming magnetic.
      (b) (Physics) In respect to terrestrial magnetism, the
          declination, inclination, and intensity.
      (c) See under {Element}.

   {Magnetic fluid}, the hypothetical fluid whose existence was
      formerly assumed in the explanations of the phenomena of
      magnetism; -- no longer considered a meaningful concept.
      

   {Magnetic iron}, or {Magnetic iron ore}. (Min.) Same as
      {Magnetite}.

   {Magnetic needle}, a slender bar of steel, magnetized and
      suspended at its center on a sharp-pointed pivot, or by a
      delicate fiber, so that it may take freely the direction
      of the magnetic meridian. It constitutes the essential
      part of a compass, such as the mariner's and the
      surveyor's.

   {Magnetic poles}, the two points in the opposite polar
      regions of the earth at which the direction of the dipping
      needle is vertical.

   {Magnetic pyrites}. See {Pyrrhotite}.

   {Magnetic storm} (Terrestrial Physics), a disturbance of the
      earth's magnetic force characterized by great and sudden
      changes.

   {Magnetic telegraph}, a telegraph acting by means of a
      magnet. See {Telegraph}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dip \Dip\, n.
   1. The action of dipping or plunging for a moment into a
      liquid. ``The dip of oars in unison.'' --Glover.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Inclination downward; direction below a horizontal line;
      slope; pitch.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. a hollow or depression in a surface, especially in the
      ground.
      [PJC]

   4. A liquid, as a sauce or gravy, served at table with a
      ladle or spoon. [Local, U.S.] --Bartlett.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A dipped candle. [Colloq.] --Marryat.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A gymnastic exercise on the parallel bars in which the
      performer, resting on his hands, lets his arms bend and
      his body sink until his chin is level with the bars, and
      then raises himself by straightening his arms.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. In the turpentine industry, the viscid exudation, which is
      dipped out from incisions in the trees; as, virgin dip
      (the runnings of the first year), yellow dip (the runnings
      of subsequent years).
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. (A["e]ronautics) A sudden drop followed by a climb,
      usually to avoid obstacles or as the result of getting
      into an airhole.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. a liquid, in which objects are soaked by dipping; e.g., a
      parasiticide or insecticide solution into which animals
      are dipped (see {sheep-dip}).
      [PJC]

   10. a sauce into which foods are dipped to enhance the
       flavor; e. g., an {onion dip} made from sour cream and
       dried onions, into which potato chips are dipped.
       [PJC]

   11. a {pickpocket}. [slang]
       [PJC]

   {Dip of the horizon} (Astron.), the angular depression of the
      seen or visible horizon below the true or natural horizon;
      the angle at the eye of an observer between a horizontal
      line and a tangent drawn from the eye to the surface of
      the ocean.

   {Dip of the needle}, or {Magnetic dip}, the angle formed, in
      a vertical plane, by a freely suspended magnetic needle,
      or the line of magnetic force, with a horizontal line; --
      called also {inclination}.

   {Dip of a stratum} (Geol.), its greatest angle of inclination
      to the horizon, or that of a line perpendicular to its
      direction or strike; -- called also the {pitch}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dip \Dip\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dipped}or {Dipt} (?); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Dipping}.] [OE. dippen, duppen, AS. dyppan; akin to
   Dan. dyppe, Sw. doppa, and to AS. d?pan to baptize, OS.
   d?pian, D. doopen, G. taufen, Sw. d["o]pa, Goth. daupjan,
   Lith. dubus deep, hollow, OSlav. dupl? hollow, and to E.
   dive. Cf. {Deep}, {Dive}.]
   1. To plunge or immerse; especially, to put for a moment into
      a liquid; to insert into a fluid and withdraw again.
      [1913 Webster]

            The priest shall dip his finger in the blood. --Lev.
                                                  iv. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            [Wat'ry fowl] now dip their pinions in the briny
            deep.                                 --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            While the prime swallow dips his wing. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To immerse for baptism; to baptize by immersion. --Book of
      Common Prayer. Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To wet, as if by immersing; to moisten. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            A cold shuddering dew
            Dips me all o'er.                     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To plunge or engage thoroughly in any affair.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was . . . dipt in the rebellion of the Commons.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To take out, by dipping a dipper, ladle, or other
      receptacle, into a fluid and removing a part; -- often
      with out; as, to dip water from a boiler; to dip out
      water.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To engage as a pledge; to mortgage. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Live on the use and never dip thy lands. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Dipped candle}, a candle made by repeatedly dipping a wick
      in melted tallow.

   {To dip snuff}, to take snuff by rubbing it on the gums and
      teeth. [Southern U. S.]

   {To dip the colors} (Naut.), to lower the colors and return
      them to place; -- a form of naval salute.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dip \Dip\, v. i.
   1. To immerse one's self; to become plunged in a liquid; to
      sink.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sun's rim dips; the stars rush out. --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perform the action of plunging some receptacle, as a
      dipper, ladle. etc.; into a liquid or a soft substance and
      removing a part.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whoever dips too deep will find death in the pot.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pierce; to penetrate; -- followed by in or into.
      [1913 Webster]

            When I dipt into the future.          --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To enter slightly or cursorily; to engage one's self
      desultorily or by the way; to partake limitedly; --
      followed by in or into. ``Dipped into a multitude of
      books.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To incline downward from the plane of the horizon; as,
      strata of rock dip.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To dip snuff. [Southern U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DIP
     Dial-up Internet Protocol (Linux)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DIP
     Dual In-line Package (IC, DRAM)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dip</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dip
     n 1: a depression in an otherwise level surface; "there was a dip
          in the road"
     2: (physics) the angle that a magnetic needle makes with the
        plane of the horizon [syn: {angle of dip}, {magnetic dip},
         {magnetic inclination}, {inclination}]
     3: a thief who steals from the pockets or purses of others in
        public places [syn: {pickpocket}, {cutpurse}]
     4: tasty mixture or liquid into which bite-sized foods are
        dipped
     5: a brief immersion
     6: a sudden sharp decrease in some quantity; "a drop of 57
        points on the Dow Jones index"; "there was a drop in
        pressure in the pulmonary artery"; "a dip in prices";
        "when that became known the price of their stock went into
        free fall" [syn: {drop}, {fall}, {free fall}]
     7: a candle that is made by repeated dipping in a pool of wax
        or tallow
     8: a brief swim in water [syn: {plunge}]
     9: a gymnastic exercise on the parallel bars in which the body
        is lowered and raised by bending and straightening the
        arms
     v 1: immerse briefly into a liquid so as to wet, coat, or
          saturate; "dip the garment into the cleaning solution";
          "dip the brush into the paint" [syn: {dunk}, {souse}, {plunge},
           {douse}]
     2: dip into a liquid while eating; "She dunked the piece of
        bread in the sauce" [syn: {dunk}]
     3: go down momentarily; "Prices dipped"
     4: stain an object by immersing it in a liquid
     5: switch (a car's headlights) from a higher to a lower beam
        [syn: {dim}]
     6: lower briefly; "She dipped her knee"
     7: appear to move downward; "The sun dipped below the horizon";
        "The setting sun sank below the tree line" [syn: {sink}]
     8: slope downwards; "Our property dips towards the river"
     9: dip into a liquid; "He dipped into the pool" [syn: {douse},
        {duck}]
     10: of candles; by dipping the wick into hot, liquid wax
     11: immerse in a disinfectant solution; "dip the sheep"
     12: scoop up by plunging one's hand or a ladle below the
         surface; "dip water out of a container"
     [also: {dipping}, {dipped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
