<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>directed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>directed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Direct \Di*rect"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Directed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Directing}.]
   1. To arrange in a direct or straight line, as against a
      mark, or towards a goal; to point; to aim; as, to direct
      an arrow or a piece of ordnance.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To point out or show to (any one), as the direct or right
      course or way; to guide, as by pointing out the way; as,
      he directed me to the left-hand road.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord direct your into the love of God. --2
                                                  Thess. iii. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

            The next points to which I will direct your
            attention.                            --Lubbock.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To determine the direction or course of; to cause to go on
      in a particular manner; to order in the way to a certain
      end; to regulate; to govern; as, to direct the affairs of
      a nation or the movements of an army.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will direct their work in truth.    --Is. lxi. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To point out to with authority; to instruct as a superior;
      to order; as, he directed them to go.
      [1913 Webster]

            I 'll first direct my men what they shall do.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To put a direction or address upon; to mark with the name
      and residence of the person to whom anything is sent; to
      superscribe; as, to direct a letter.

   Syn: To guide; lead; conduct; dispose; manage; regulate;
        order; instruct; command.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>directed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>directed \directed\ adj.
   1. having a specified direction; often used in combination;
      as, goal-directed.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   2. marked with a destination; -- of mail or parcels; as, I
      throw away all mail directed to `resident'. Opposite of
      {unaddressed}.

   Syn: addressed.
        [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>directed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>directed
     adj 1: (often used in combination) having a specified direction; "a
            positively directed vector"; "goal-directed"
     2: manageable by a supervising agent; "a directed program of
        study"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
