<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>discovered</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>discovered</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Discover \Dis*cov"er\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Discovered}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Discovering}.] [OE. discoveren, discuren, descuren,
   OF. descovrir, descouvrir, F. d['e]couvrir; des- (L. dis-) +
   couvrir to cover. See {Cover}.]
   1. To uncover. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether any man hath pulled down or discovered any
            church.                               --Abp.
                                                  Grindal.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To disclose; to lay open to view; to make visible; to
      reveal; to make known; to show (what has been secret,
      unseen, or unknown). [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Go, draw aside the curtains, and discover
            The several caskets to this noble prince. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Prosperity doth best discover vice; but adversity
            doth best discover virtue.            --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            We will discover ourselves unto them. --1 Sam. xiv.
                                                  8.
      [1913 Webster]

            Discover not a secret to another.     --Prov. xxv.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To obtain for the first time sight or knowledge of, as of
      a thing existing already, but not perceived or known; to
      find; to ascertain; to espy; to detect. [WordNet sense
      1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8]
      [1913 Webster]

            Some to discover islands far away.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To manifest without design; to show.
      [1913 Webster]

            The youth discovered a taste for sculpture. --C. J.
                                                  Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To explore; to examine. [Obs.]

   Syn: To disclose; bring out; exhibit; show; manifest; reveal;
        communicate; impart; tell; espy; find; out; detect. --
        To {Discover}, {Invent}. We discover what existed
        before, but remained unknown; we invent by forming
        combinations which are either entirely new, or which
        attain their end by means unknown before. Columbus
        discovered America; Newton discovered the law of
        gravitation; Whitney invented the cotton gin; Galileo
        invented the telescope.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>discovered</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>discovered
     adj 1: no longer concealed; uncovered as by opening a curtain;
            `discovered' is archaic and primarily a theater term;
            "the scene disclosed was of a moonlit forest" [syn: {disclosed},
             {revealed}]
     2: discovered or determined by scientific observation;
        "variation in the ascertained flux depends on a number of
        factors"; "the discovered behavior norms"; "discovered
        differences in achievement"; "no explanation for the
        observed phenomena" [syn: {ascertained}, {observed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
