<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>discuss</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>discuss</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Discuss \Dis*cuss"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Discussed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Discussing}.] [L. discussus, p. p. of discutere to
   strike asunder (hence came the sense to separate mentally,
   distinguish); dis- + quatere to shake, strike. See {Quash}.]
   1. To break to pieces; to shatter. [Obs.] --Sir T. Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To break up; to disperse; to scatter; to dissipate; to
      drive away; -- said especially of tumors. [archaic]

   Note: This usage is preserved only in the word {discussive}.
         [1913 Webster]

               Many arts were used to discuss the beginnings of
               new affection.                     --Sir H.
                                                  Wotton.
         [1913 Webster]

               A pomade . . . of virtue to discuss pimples.
                                                  --Rambler.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. To shake; to put away; to finish. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            All regard of shame she had discussed. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To examine in detail or by disputation; to reason upon by
      presenting favorable and adverse considerations; to
      debate; to sift; to investigate; to ventilate. ``We sat
      and . . . discussed the farm . . . and the price of
      grain.'' --Tennyson. ``To discuss questions of taste.''
      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To deal with, in eating or drinking. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            We sat quietly down and discussed a cold fowl that
            we had brought with us.               --Sir S.
                                                  Baker.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law) To examine or search thoroughly; to exhaust a remedy
      against, as against a principal debtor before proceeding
      against the surety. --Burrill.

   Syn: To {Discuss}, {Examine}, {Debate}. We speak of examining
        a subject when we ponder it with care, in order to
        discover its real state, or the truth respecting it. We
        speak of discussing a topic when we examine it
        thoroughly in its distinct parts. The word is very
        commonly applied to matters of opinion. We may discuss a
        subject without giving in an adhesion to any conclusion.
        We speak of debating a point when we examine it in
        mutual argumentation between opposing parties. In debate
        we contend for or against some conclusion or view.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>discuss</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>discuss
     v 1: to consider or examine in speech or writing; "The article
          covered all the different aspects of this question";
          "The class discussed Dante's `Inferno'" [syn: {discourse},
           {talk about}]
     2: speak with others about (something); talk (something) over
        in detail; have a discussion; "We discussed our household
        budget" [syn: {hash out}, {talk over}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
