<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dish</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dish</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dish
   for eating from (2 Kings 21:13). Judas dipped his hand with a
   "sop" or piece of bread in the same dish with our Lord, thereby
   indicating friendly intimacy (Matt. 26:23). The "lordly dish" in
   Judg. 5:25 was probably the shallow drinking cup, usually of
   brass. In Judg. 6:38 the same Hebrew word is rendered "bowl."
   
     The dishes of the tabernacle were made of pure gold (Ex.
   25:29; 37:16).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dish</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dish \Dish\ (d[i^]sh), n. [AS. disc, L. discus dish, disc,
   quoit, fr. Gr. di`skos quoit, fr. dikei^n to throw. Cf.
   {Dais}, {Desk}, {Disc}, {Discus}.]
   1. A vessel, as a platter, a plate, a bowl, used for serving
      up food at the table.
      [1913 Webster]

            She brought forth butter in a lordly dish. --Judg.
                                                  v. 25.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The food served in a dish; hence, any particular kind of
      food, especially prepared food; as, a cold dish; a warm
      dish; a delicious dish. ``A dish fit for the gods.''
      --Shak.

            Home-home dishes that drive one from home. --Hood.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The state of being concave, or like a dish, or the degree
      of such concavity; as, the dish of a wheel.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A hollow place, as in a field. --Ogilvie.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mining)
      (a) A trough about 28 inches long, 4 deep, and 6 wide, in
          which ore is measured.
      (b) That portion of the produce of a mine which is paid to
          the land owner or proprietor.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. anything with a discoid and concave shape, like that of a
      dish.
      [PJC]

   7. an electronic device with a concave reflecting surface
      which focuses reflected radio waves to or from a point,
      used as a receiving or transmitting antenna; also called
      {dish antenna}. The dish is often shaped as a paraboloid
      so as to achieve a high sensitivity and enable reception
      of weak signals when used as a receiving antenna, or to
      focus transmitted signals into a narrow beam when used as
      a transmitting antenna.

   Syn: dish aerial, dish antenna, saucer. [PJC]

   8. a very attractive woman or young lady, especaially one
      sexually attractive; -- sometimes considered offensive and
      sexist; as, the departmental secretary is quite a dish.
      [slang]

   Syn: smasher, stunner, knockout, beauty, sweetheart, peach,
        lulu, looker, mantrap, dish. [WordNet 1.5 + PJC]

   9. a favorite activity, or an activity at which one excels.
      [slang]

   Syn: cup of tea, bag. [WordNet 1.5 + PJC]

   10. the quantity that a dish will hold, or a dish filled with
       some material.

   Syn: dishful. [WordNet 1.5 + PJC]

   {satellite dish} a dish antenna used to receive signals from
      or to transmit signals to a satellite which transmits or
      receives radio signals. In most common usage, it refers to
      small dish antennas used to receive television programs
      broadcast from geostationary satellites.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dish</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dish \Dish\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dished}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Dishing}.]
   1. To put in a dish, ready for the table.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make concave, or depress in the middle, like a dish;
      as, to dish a wheel by inclining the spokes.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To frustrate; to beat; to ruin. [Low]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. to talk about (a person) in a disparaging manner; to
      gossip about (a person); as, the secretaries spent their
      break time dishing the newest employee. [slang]
      [PJC]

   {To dish out}.

   1. To serve out of a dish; to distribute in portions at
      table.

   2. (Arch.) To hollow out, as a gutter in stone or wood.

   2. to dispense freely; -- also used figuratively; as, to dish
      out punishment; to dish out abuse or insult.

   {To dish up}, to take (food) from the oven, pots, etc., and
      put in dishes to be served at table.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dish</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dish
     n 1: a piece of dishware normally used as a container for holding
          or serving food; "we gave them a set of dishes for a
          wedding present"
     2: a particular item of prepared food; "she prepared a special
        dish for dinner"
     3: the quantity that a dish will hold; "they served me a dish
        of rice" [syn: {dishful}]
     4: a very attractive or seductive looking woman [syn: {smasher},
         {stunner}, {knockout}, {beauty}, {ravisher}, {sweetheart},
         {peach}, {lulu}, {looker}, {mantrap}]
     5: directional antenna consisting of a parabolic reflector for
        microwave or radio frequency radiation [syn: {dish aerial},
         {dish antenna}, {saucer}]
     6: an activity that you like or at which you are superior;
        "chemistry is not my cup of tea"; "his bag now is learning
        to play golf"; "marriage was scarcely his dish" [syn: {cup
        of tea}, {bag}]
     v 1: provide (usually but not necessarily food); "We serve meals
          for the homeless"; "She dished out the soup at 8 P.M.";
          "The entertainers served up a lively show" [syn: {serve},
           {serve up}, {dish out}, {dish up}]
     2: make concave; shape like a dish
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
