<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>distance</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DISTANCE, n.  The only thing that the rich are willing for the poor to
call theirs, and keep.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Distance \Dis"tance\, n. [F. distance, L. distantia.]
   1. The space between two objects; the length of a line,
      especially the shortest line joining two points or things
      that are separate; measure of separation in place.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every particle attracts every other with a force . .
            . inversely proportioned to the square of the
            distance.                             --Sir I.
                                                  Newton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Remoteness of place; a remote place.
      [1913 Webster]

            Easily managed from a distance.       --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is distance lends enchantment to the view. --T.
                                                  Campbell.
      [1913 Webster]

            [He] waits at distance till he hears from Cato.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Racing) A space marked out in the last part of a race
      course.
      [1913 Webster]

            The horse that ran the whole field out of distance.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In trotting matches under the rules of the American
         Association, the distance varies with the conditions of
         the race, being 80 yards in races of mile heats, best
         two in three, and 150 yards in races of two-mile heats.
         At that distance from the winning post is placed the
         distance post. If any horse has not reached this
         distance post before the first horse in that heat has
         reached the winning post, such horse is distanced, and
         disqualified for running again during that race.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) Relative space, between troops in ranks, measured
      from front to rear; -- contrasted with {interval}, which
      is measured from right to left. ``Distance between
      companies in close column is twelve yards.'' --Farrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Space between two antagonists in fencing. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Painting) The part of a picture which contains the
      representation of those objects which are the farthest
      away, esp. in a landscape.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In a picture, the

   {Middle distance} is the central portion between the
      foreground and the distance or the extreme distance. In a
      perspective drawing, the

   {Point of distance} is the point where the visual rays meet.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Ideal disjunction; discrepancy; contrariety. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Length or interval of time; period, past or future,
      between two eras or events.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ten years' distance between one and the other.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

            The writings of Euclid at the distance of two
            thousand years.                       --Playfair.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The remoteness or reserve which respect requires; hence,
      respect; ceremoniousness.
      [1913 Webster]

            I hope your modesty
            Will know what distance to the crown is due.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is by respect and distance that authority is
            upheld.                               --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A withholding of intimacy; alienation; coldness;
       disagreement; variance; restraint; reserve.
       [1913 Webster]

             Setting them [factions] at distance, or at least
             distrust amongst themselves.         --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

             On the part of Heaven,
             Now alienated, distance and distaste. --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Remoteness in succession or relation; as, the distance
       between a descendant and his ancestor.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Mus.) The interval between two notes; as, the distance
       of a fourth or seventh.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Angular distance}, the distance made at the eye by lines
      drawn from the eye to two objects.

   {Lunar distance}. See under {Lunar}.

   {North polar distance} (Astron.), the distance on the heavens
      of a heavenly body from the north pole. It is the
      complement of the declination.

   {Zenith distance} (Astron.), the arc on the heavens from a
      heavenly body to the zenith of the observer. It is the
      complement of the altitude.

   {To keep one's distance}, to stand aloof; to refrain from
      familiarity.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a man makes me keep my distance, the comfort is
            he keeps his at the same time.        --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Distance \Dis"tance\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Distanced}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Distancing}.]
   1. To place at a distance or remotely.
      [1913 Webster]

            I heard nothing thereof at Oxford, being then miles
            distanced thence.                     --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to appear as if at a distance; to make seem
      remote.
      [1913 Webster]

            His peculiar art of distancing an object to
            aggrandize his space.                 --H. Miller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To outstrip by as much as a distance (see {Distance}, n.,
      3); to leave far behind; to surpass greatly.
      [1913 Webster]

            He distanced the most skillful of his
            contemporaries.                       --Milner.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>distance
     n 1: the property created by the space between two objects or
          points
     2: a distant region; "I could see it in the distance"
     3: size of the gap between two places; "the distance from New
        York to Chicago"; "he determined the length of the
        shortest line segment joining the two points" [syn: {length}]
     4: indifference by personal withdrawal; "emotional distance"
        [syn: {aloofness}]
     5: the interval between two times; "the distance from birth to
        death"; "it all happened in the space of 10 minutes" [syn:
         {space}]
     6: a remote point in time; "if that happens it will be at some
        distance in the future"; "at a distance of ten years he
        had forgotten many of the details"
     v 1: keep at a distance; "we have to distance ourselves from
          these events in order to continue living"
     2: go far ahead of; "He outdistanced the other runners" [syn: {outdistance},
         {outstrip}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
