<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>distinguishing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distinguishing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Distinguish \Dis*tin"guish\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Distinguished}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Distinguishing}.] [F.
   distinguer, L. distinguere, distinctum; di- = dis- +
   stinguere to quench, extinguish; prob. orig., to prick, and
   so akin to G. stechen, E. stick, and perh. sting. Cf.
   {Extinguish}.]
   1. Not set apart from others by visible marks; to make
      distinctive or discernible by exhibiting differences; to
      mark off by some characteristic.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not more distinguished by her purple vest,
            Than by the charming features of her face. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Milton has distinguished the sweetbrier and the
            eglantine.                            --Nares.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To separate by definition of terms or logical division of
      a subject with regard to difference; as, to distinguish
      sounds into high and low.
      [1913 Webster]

            Moses distinguished the causes of the flood into
            those that belong to the heavens, and those that
            belong to the earth.                  --T. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To recognize or discern by marks, signs, or characteristic
      quality or qualities; to know and discriminate (anything)
      from other things with which it might be confounded; as,
      to distinguish the sound of a drum.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are enabled to distinguish good from evil, as
            well as truth from falsehood.         --Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor more can you distinguish of a man,
            Than of his outward show.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To constitute a difference; to make to differ.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who distinguisheth thee?              --1 Cor. iv.
                                                  7. (Douay
                                                  version).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To separate from others by a mark of honor; to make
      eminent or known; to confer distinction upon; -- with by
      or for.``To distinguish themselves by means never tried
      before.'' --Johnson.

   Syn: To mark; discriminate; differentiate; characterize;
        discern; perceive; signalize; honor; glorify.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distinguishing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Distinguishing \Dis*tin"guish*ing\, a.
   Constituting difference, or distinction from everything else;
   distinctive; peculiar; characteristic.
   [1913 Webster]

         The distinguishing doctrines of our holy religion.
                                                  --Locke.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Distinguishing pennant} (Naut.), a special pennant by which
      any particular vessel in a fleet is recognized and
      signaled. --Simmonds.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distinguishing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>distinguishing
     adj : serving to distinguish or identify a species or group; "the
           distinguishing mark of the species is its plumage";
           "distinctive tribal tattoos"; "we were asked to
           describe any identifying marks or distinguishing
           features" [syn: {distinctive}, {identifying(a)}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
