<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>distress</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DISTRESS, n.  A disease incurred by exposure to the prosperity of a
friend.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Distress \Dis*tress"\, n. [OE. destresse, distresse, OF.
   destresse, destrece, F. d['e]tresse, OF. destrecier to
   distress, (assumed) LL. districtiare, fr. L. districtus, p.
   p. of distringere. See {Distrain}, and cf. {Stress}.]
   1. Extreme pain or suffering; anguish of body or mind; as, to
      suffer distress from the gout, or from the loss of
      friends.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not fearing death nor shrinking for distress.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which occasions suffering; painful situation;
      misfortune; affliction; misery.
      [1913 Webster]

            Affliction's sons are brothers in distress. --Burns.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A state of danger or necessity; as, a ship in distress,
      from leaking, loss of spars, want of provisions or water,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law)
      (a) The act of distraining; the taking of a personal
          chattel out of the possession of a wrongdoer, by way
          of pledge for redress of an injury, or for the
          performance of a duty, as for nonpayment of rent or
          taxes, or for injury done by cattle, etc.
      (b) The thing taken by distraining; that which is seized
          to procure satisfaction. --Bouvier. --Kent. --Burrill.
          [1913 Webster]

                If he were not paid, he would straight go and
                take a distress of goods and cattle. --Spenser.
          [1913 Webster]

                The distress thus taken must be proportioned to
                the thing distrained for.         --Blackstone.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Abuse of distress}. (Law) See under {Abuse}.

   Syn: Affliction; suffering; pain; agony; misery; torment;
        anguish; grief; sorrow; calamity; misfortune; trouble;
        adversity. See {Affliction}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Distress \Dis*tress"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Distressed}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Distressing}.] [Cf. OF. destrecier. See {Distress},
   n.]
   1. To cause pain or anguish to; to pain; to oppress with
      calamity; to afflict; to harass; to make miserable.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are troubled on every side, yet not distressed.
                                                  --2 Cor. iv.
                                                  8.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To compel by pain or suffering.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men who can neither be distressed nor won into a
            sacrifice of duty.                    --A. Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) To seize for debt; to distrain.

   Syn: To pain; grieve; harass; trouble; perplex; afflict;
        worry; annoy.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>distress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>distress
     n 1: psychological suffering; "the death of his wife caused him
          great distress" [syn: {hurt}, {suffering}]
     2: a state of adversity (danger or affliction or need); "a ship
        in distress"; "she was the classic maiden in distress"
     3: extreme physical pain; "the patient appeared to be in
        distress"
     4: the seizure and holding of property as security for payment
        of a debt or satisfaction of a claim; "Originally distress
        was a landloard's remedy against a tenant for unpaid rents
        or property damage but now the landlord is given a
        landlord's lien" [syn: {distraint}]
     v : cause mental pain to; "The news of her child's illness
         distressed the mother"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
