<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>division</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>division</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Compound \Com"pound\, a. [OE. compouned, p. p. of compounen. See
   {Compound}, v. t.]
   Composed of two or more elements, ingredients, parts;
   produced by the union of several ingredients, parts, or
   things; composite; as, a compound word.
   [1913 Webster]

         Compound substances are made up of two or more simple
         substances.                              --I. Watts.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Compound addition}, {subtraction}, {multiplication},
   {division} (Arith.), the addition, subtraction, etc., of
      compound numbers.

   {Compound crystal} (Crystallog.), a twin crystal, or one
      seeming to be made up of two or more crystals combined
      according to regular laws of composition.

   {Compound engine} (Mech.), a form of steam engine in which
      the steam that has been used in a high-pressure cylinder
      is made to do further service in a larger low-pressure
      cylinder, sometimes in several larger cylinders,
      successively.

   {Compound ether}. (Chem.) See under {Ether}.

   {Compound flower} (Bot.), a flower head resembling a single
      flower, but really composed of several florets inclosed in
      a common calyxlike involucre, as the sunflower or
      dandelion.

   {Compound fraction}. (Math.) See {Fraction}.

   {Compound fracture}. See {Fracture}.

   {Compound householder}, a householder who compounds or
      arranges with his landlord that his rates shall be
      included in his rents. [Eng.]

   {Compound interest}. See {Interest}.

   {Compound larceny}. (Law) See {Larceny}.

   {Compound leaf} (Bot.), a leaf having two or more separate
      blades or leaflets on a common leafstalk.

   {Compound microscope}. See {Microscope}.

   {Compound motion}. See {Motion}.

   {Compound number} (Math.), one constructed according to a
      varying scale of denomination; as, 3 cwt., 1 qr., 5 lb.;
      -- called also {denominate number}.

   {Compound pier} (Arch.), a clustered column.

   {Compound quantity} (Alg.), a quantity composed of two or
      more simple quantities or terms, connected by the sign +
      (plus) or - (minus). Thus, a + b - c, and bb - b, are
      compound quantities.

   {Compound radical}. (Chem.) See {Radical}.

   {Compound ratio} (Math.), the product of two or more ratios;
      thus ab:cd is a ratio compounded of the simple ratios a:c
      and b:d.

   {Compound rest} (Mech.), the tool carriage of an engine
      lathe.

   {Compound screw} (Mech.), a screw having on the same axis two
      or more screws with different pitch (a differential
      screw), or running in different directions (a right and
      left screw).

   {Compound time} (Mus.), that in which two or more simple
      measures are combined in one; as, 6-8 time is the joining
      of two measures of 3-8 time.

   {Compound word}, a word composed of two or more words;
      specifically, two or more words joined together by a
      hyphen.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>division</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Division \Di*vi"sion\, n. [F. division, L. divisio, from
   dividere. See {Divide}.]
   1. The act or process of diving anything into parts, or the
      state of being so divided; separation.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was overlooked in the division of the spoil.
                                                  --Gibbon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which divides or keeps apart; a partition.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The portion separated by the divining of a mass or body; a
      distinct segment or section.
      [1913 Webster]

            Communities and divisions of men.     --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Disunion; difference in opinion or feeling; discord;
      variance; alienation.
      [1913 Webster]

            There was a division among the people. --John vii.
                                                  43.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Difference of condition; state of distinction;
      distinction; contrast. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will put a division between my people and thy
            people.                               --Ex. viii.
                                                  23.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Separation of the members of a deliberative body, esp. of
      the Houses of Parliament, to ascertain the vote.
      [1913 Webster]

            The motion passed without a division. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Math.) The process of finding how many times one number
      or quantity is contained in another; the reverse of
      multiplication; also, the rule by which the operation is
      performed.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Logic) The separation of a genus into its constituent
      species.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mil.)
      (a) Two or more brigades under the command of a general
          officer.
      (b) Two companies of infantry maneuvering as one
          subdivision of a battalion.
      (c) One of the larger districts into which a country is
          divided for administering military affairs.
          [1913 Webster]

   10. (Naut.) One of the groups into which a fleet is divided.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Mus.) A course of notes so running into each other as to
       form one series or chain, to be sung in one breath to one
       syllable.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Rhet.) The distribution of a discourse into parts; a
       part so distinguished.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Biol.) A grade or rank in classification; a portion of a
       tribe or of a class; or, in some recent authorities,
       equivalent to a subkingdom.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Cell division} (Biol.), a method of cell increase, in which
      new cells are formed by the division of the parent cell.
      In this process, the cell nucleus undergoes peculiar
      differentiations and changes, as shown in the figure (see
      also {Karyokinesis}). At the same time the protoplasm of
      the cell becomes gradually constricted by a furrow
      transverse to the long axis of the nuclear spindle,
      followed, on the completion of the division of the
      nucleus, by a separation of the cell contents into two
      masses, called the daughter cells.

   {Long division} (Math.), the process of division when the
      operations are mostly written down.

   {Short division} (Math.), the process of division when the
      operations are mentally performed and only the results
      written down; -- used principally when the divisor is not
      greater than ten or twelve.

   Syn: compartment; section; share; allotment; distribution;
        separation; partition; disjunction; disconnection;
        difference; variance; discord; disunion.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>division</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>division
     n 1: an army unit large enough to sustain combat; "two infantry
          divisions were held in reserve"
     2: one of the portions into which something is regarded as
        divided and which together constitute a whole; "the
        written part of the exam"; "the finance section of the
        company"; "the BBC's engineering division" [syn: {part}, {section}]
     3: the act or process of dividing
     4: an administrative unit in government or business
     5: an arithmetic operation that is the inverse of
        multiplication; the quotient of two numbers is computed
     6: discord that splits a group [syn: {variance}]
     7: a league ranked by quality; "he played baseball in class D
        for two years"; "Princeton is in the NCAA Division 1-AA"
        [syn: {class}]
     8: (biology) a group of organisms forming a subdivision of a
        larger category
     9: (botany) taxonomic unit of plants corresponding to a phylum
     10: a unit of the United States Air Force usually comprising two
         or more wings [syn: {air division}]
     11: a group of ships of similar type [syn: {naval division}]
     12: the act of dividing or partitioning; separation by the
         creation of a boundary that divides or keeps apart [syn:
         {partition}, {partitioning}, {segmentation}, {sectionalization},
          {sectionalisation}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
