<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dog</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DOG, n.  A kind of additional or subsidiary Deity designed to catch
the overflow and surplus of the world's worship.  This Divine Being in
some of his smaller and silkier incarnations takes, in the affection
of Woman, the place to which there is no human male aspirant.  The Dog
is a survival -- an anachronism.  He toils not, neither does he spin,
yet Solomon in all his glory never lay upon a door-mat all day long,
sun-soaked and fly-fed and fat, while his master worked for the means
wherewith to purchase the idle wag of the Solomonic tail, seasoned
with a look of tolerant recognition.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dog
   frequently mentioned both in the Old and New Testaments. Dogs
   were used by the Hebrews as a watch for their houses (Isa.
   56:10), and for guarding their flocks (Job 30:1). There were
   also then as now troops of semi-wild dogs that wandered about
   devouring dead bodies and the offal of the streets (1 Kings
   14:11; 16:4; 21:19, 23; 22:38; Ps. 59:6, 14).
   
     As the dog was an unclean animal, the terms "dog," "dog's
   head," "dead dog," were used as terms of reproach or of
   humiliation (1 Sam. 24:14; 2 Sam. 3:8; 9:8; 16:9). Paul calls
   false apostles "dogs" (Phil. 3:2). Those who are shut out of the
   kingdom of heaven are also so designated (Rev. 22:15).
   Persecutors are called "dogs" (Ps. 22:16). Hazael's words, "Thy
   servant which is but a dog" (2 Kings 8:13), are spoken in mock
   humility=impossible that one so contemptible as he should attain
   to such power.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Sundog \Sun"dog`\, n. (Meteorol.)
   1. A luminous spot occasionally seen a few degrees from the
      sun, supposed to be formed by the intersection of two or
      more halos, or in a manner similar to that of halos.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A fragmentary rainbow; a small rainbow near the horizon;
      -- called also {dog} and {weathergaw}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dog \Dog\ (d[o^]g), n. [AS. docga; akin to D. dog mastiff, Dan.
   dogge, Sw. dogg.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) A quadruped of the genus {Canis}, esp. the
      domestic dog ({Canis familiaris}).

   Note: The dog is distinguished above all others of the
         inferior animals for intelligence, docility, and
         attachment to man. There are numerous carefully bred
         varieties, as the {akita}, {beagle}, {bloodhound},
         {bulldog}, {coachdog}, {collie}, {Danish dog},
         {foxhound}, {greyhound}, {mastiff}, {pointer},
         {poodle}, {St. Bernard}, {setter}, {spaniel}, {spitz
         dog}, {terrier}, {German shepherd}, {pit bull},
         {Chihuahua}, etc. There are also many mixed breeds, and
         partially domesticated varieties, as well as wild dogs,
         like the dingo and dhole. (See these names in the
         Vocabulary.)
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. A mean, worthless fellow; a wretch.
      [1913 Webster]

            What is thy servant, which is but a dog, that he
            should do this great thing?           -- 2 Kings
                                                  viii. 13 (Rev.
                                                  Ver. )
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A fellow; -- used humorously or contemptuously; as, a sly
      dog; a lazy dog. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Astron.) One of the two constellations, Canis Major and
      Canis Minor, or the Greater Dog and the Lesser Dog. Canis
      Major contains the Dog Star (Sirius).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An iron for holding wood in a fireplace; a firedog; an
      andiron.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mech.)
      (a) A grappling iron, with a claw or claws, for fastening
          into wood or other heavy articles, for the purpose of
          raising or moving them.
      (b) An iron with fangs fastening a log in a saw pit, or on
          the carriage of a sawmill.
      (c) A piece in machinery acting as a catch or clutch;
          especially, the carrier of a lathe, also, an
          adjustable stop to change motion, as in a machine
          tool.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. an ugly or crude person, especially an ugly woman. [slang]
      [PJC]

   8. a {hot dog}. [slang]
      [PJC]

   Note: Dog is used adjectively or in composition, commonly in
         the sense of relating to, or characteristic of, a dog.
         It is also used to denote a male; as, dog fox or g-fox,
         a male fox; dog otter or dog-otter, dog wolf, etc.; --
         also to denote a thing of cheap or mean quality; as,
         dog Latin.
         [1913 Webster]

   {A dead dog}, a thing of no use or value. --1 Sam. xxiv. 14.

   {A dog in the manger}, an ugly-natured person who prevents
      others from enjoying what would be an advantage to them
      but is none to him.

   {Dog ape} (Zo["o]l.), a male ape.

   {Dog cabbage}, or {Dog's cabbage} (Bot.), a succulent herb,
      native to the Mediterranean region ({Thelygonum
      Cynocrambe}).

   {Dog cheap}, very cheap. See under {Cheap}.

   {Dog ear} (Arch.), an acroterium. [Colloq.]

   {Dog flea} (Zo["o]l.), a species of flea ({Pulex canis})
      which infests dogs and cats, and is often troublesome to
      man. In America it is the common flea. See {Flea}, and
      {Aphaniptera}.

   {Dog grass} (Bot.), a grass ({Triticum caninum}) of the same
      genus as wheat.

   {Dog Latin}, barbarous Latin; as, the dog Latin of pharmacy.
      

   {Dog lichen} (Bot.), a kind of lichen ({Peltigera canina})
      growing on earth, rocks, and tree trunks, -- a lobed
      expansion, dingy green above and whitish with fuscous
      veins beneath.

   {Dog louse} (Zo["o]l.), a louse that infests the dog, esp.
      {H[ae]matopinus piliferus}; another species is
      {Trichodectes latus}.

   {Dog power}, a machine operated by the weight of a dog
      traveling in a drum, or on an endless track, as for
      churning.

   {Dog salmon} (Zo["o]l.), a salmon of northwest America and
      northern Asia; -- the {gorbuscha}; -- called also {holia},
      and {hone}.

   {Dog shark}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Dogfish}.

   {Dog's meat}, meat fit only for dogs; refuse; offal.

   {Dog Star}. See in the Vocabulary.

   {Dog wheat} (Bot.), Dog grass.

   {Dog whelk} (Zo["o]l.), any species of univalve shells of the
      family {Nassid[ae]}, esp. the {Nassa reticulata} of
      England.

   {To give to the dogs}, or {To throw to the dogs}, to throw
      away as useless. ``Throw physic to the dogs; I'll none of
      it.'' --Shak.

   {To go to the dogs}, to go to ruin; to be ruined.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dog \Dog\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dogged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Dogging}.]
   To hunt or track like a hound; to follow insidiously or
   indefatigably; to chase with a dog or dogs; to worry, as if
   by dogs; to hound with importunity.
   [1913 Webster]

         I have been pursued, dogged, and waylaid. -- Pope.
   [1913 Webster]

         Your sins will dog you, pursue you.      --Burroughs.
   [1913 Webster]

         Eager ill-bred petitioners, who do not so properly
         supplicate as hunt the person whom they address to,
         dogging him from place to place, till they even extort
         an answer to their rude requests.        -- South.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dog</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dog
     n 1: a member of the genus Canis (probably descended from the
          common wolf) that has been domesticated by man since
          prehistoric times; occurs in many breeds; "the dog
          barked all night" [syn: {domestic dog}, {Canis
          familiaris}]
     2: a dull unattractive unpleasant girl or woman; "she got a
        reputation as a frump"; "she's a real dog" [syn: {frump}]
     3: informal term for a man; "you lucky dog"
     4: someone who is morally reprehensible; "you dirty dog" [syn:
        {cad}, {bounder}, {blackguard}, {hound}, {heel}]
     5: a smooth-textured sausage of minced beef or pork usually
        smoked; often served on a bread roll [syn: {frank}, {frankfurter},
         {hotdog}, {hot dog}, {wiener}, {wienerwurst}, {weenie}]
     6: a hinged catch that fits into a notch of a ratchet to move a
        wheel forward or prevent it from moving backward [syn: {pawl},
         {detent}, {click}]
     7: metal supports for logs in a fireplace; "the andirons were
        too hot to touch" [syn: {andiron}, {firedog}, {dog-iron}]
     v : go after with the intent to catch; "The policeman chased the
         mugger down the alley"; "the dog chased the rabbit" [syn:
          {chase}, {chase after}, {trail}, {tail}, {tag}, {give
         chase}, {go after}, {track}]
     [also: {dogging}, {dogged}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
