<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>doing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>doing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>do \do\ (d[=oo]), v. t. or auxiliary. [imp. {did} (d[i^]d); p.
   p. {done} (d[u^]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Doing} (d[=oo]"[i^]ng).
   This verb, when transitive, is formed in the indicative,
   present tense, thus: I do, thou doest (d[=oo]"[e^]st) or dost
   (d[u^]st), he does (d[u^]z), doeth (d[=oo]"[e^]th), or doth
   (d[u^]th); when auxiliary, the second person is, thou dost.
   As an independent verb, dost is obsolete or rare, except in
   poetry. ``What dost thou in this world?'' --Milton. The form
   doeth is a verb unlimited, doth, formerly so used, now being
   the auxiliary form. The second pers, sing., imperfect tense,
   is didst (d[i^]dst), formerly didest (d[i^]d"[e^]st).] [AS.
   d[=o]n; akin to D. doen, OS. duan, OHG. tuon, G. thun, Lith.
   deti, OSlav. d[=e]ti, OIr. d['e]nim I do, Gr. tiqe`nai to
   put, Skr. dh[=a], and to E. suffix -dom, and prob. to L.
   facere to do, E. fact, and perh. to L. -dere in some
   compounds, as addere to add, credere to trust. [root]65. Cf.
   {Deed}, {Deem}, {Doom}, {Fact}, {Creed}, {Theme}.]
   1. To place; to put. [Obs.] --Tale of a Usurer (about 1330).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause; to make; -- with an infinitive. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            My lord Abbot of Westminster did do shewe to me late
            certain evidences.                    --W. Caxton.
      [1913 Webster]

            I shall . . . your cloister do make.  --Piers
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            A fatal plague which many did to die. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            We do you to wit [i. e., We make you to know] of the
            grace of God bestowed on the churches of Macedonia.
                                                  --2 Cor. viii.
                                                  1.

   Note: We have lost the idiom shown by the citations (do used
         like the French faire or laisser), in which the verb in
         the infinitive apparently, but not really, has a
         passive signification, i. e., cause . . . to be made.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. To bring about; to produce, as an effect or result; to
      effect; to achieve.
      [1913 Webster]

            The neglecting it may do much danger. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He waved indifferently 'twixt doing them neither
            good not harm.                        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To perform, as an action; to execute; to transact to carry
      out in action; as, to do a good or a bad act; do our duty;
      to do what I can.
      [1913 Webster]

            Six days shalt thou labor and do all thy work. --Ex.
                                                  xx. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            We did not do these things.           --Ld. Lytton.
      [1913 Webster]

            You can not do wrong without suffering wrong.
                                                  --Emerson.
      Hence: To do homage, honor, favor, justice, etc., to
      render homage, honor, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To bring to an end by action; to perform completely; to
      finish; to accomplish; -- a sense conveyed by the
      construction, which is that of the past participle done.
      ``Ere summer half be done.'' ``I have done weeping.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To make ready for an object, purpose, or use, as food by
      cooking; to cook completely or sufficiently; as, the meat
      is done on one side only.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To put or bring into a form, state, or condition,
      especially in the phrases, to do death, to put to death;
      to slay; to do away (often do away with), to put away; to
      remove; to do on, to put on; to don; to do off, to take
      off, as dress; to doff; to do into, to put into the form
      of; to translate or transform into, as a text.
      [1913 Webster]

            Done to death by slanderous tongues.  -- Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ground of the difficulty is done away. -- Paley.
      [1913 Webster]

            Suspicions regarding his loyalty were entirely done
            away.                                 --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

            To do on our own harness, that we may not; but we
            must do on the armor of God.          -- Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then Jason rose and did on him a fair
            Blue woolen tunic.                    -- W. Morris
                                                  (Jason).
      [1913 Webster]

            Though the former legal pollution be now done off,
            yet there is a spiritual contagion in idolatry as
            much to be shunned.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            It [``Pilgrim's Progress''] has been done into
            verse: it has been done into modern English. --
                                                  Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To cheat; to gull; to overreach. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He was not be done, at his time of life, by
            frivolous offers of a compromise that might have
            secured him seventy-five per cent.    -- De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To see or inspect; to explore; as, to do all the points of
      interest. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Stock Exchange) To cash or to advance money for, as a
       bill or note.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To perform work upon, about, for, or at, by way of caring
       for, looking after, preparing, cleaning, keeping in
       order, or the like.

             The sergeants seem to do themselves pretty well.
                                                  --Harper's
                                                  Mag.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. To deal with for good and all; to finish up; to undo; to
       ruin; to do for. [Colloq. or Slang]

             Sometimes they lie in wait in these dark streets,
             and fracture his skull, . . . or break his arm, or
             cut the sinew of his wrist; and that they call
             doing him.                           --Charles
                                                  Reade.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note:
       (a) Do and did are much employed as auxiliaries, the verb
           to which they are joined being an infinitive. As an
           auxiliary the verb do has no participle. ``I do set
           my bow in the cloud.'' --Gen. ix. 13. [Now archaic or
           rare except for emphatic assertion.]
           [1913 Webster]

                 Rarely . . . did the wrongs of individuals to
                 the knowledge of the public.     -- Macaulay.
       (b) They are often used in emphatic construction. ``You
           don't say so, Mr. Jobson. -- but I do say so.'' --Sir
           W. Scott. ``I did love him, but scorn him now.''
           --Latham.
       (c) In negative and interrogative constructions, do and
           did are in common use. I do not wish to see them;
           what do you think? Did C[ae]sar cross the Tiber? He
           did not. ``Do you love me?'' --Shak.
       (d) Do, as an auxiliary, is supposed to have been first
           used before imperatives. It expresses entreaty or
           earnest request; as, do help me. In the imperative
           mood, but not in the indicative, it may be used with
           the verb to be; as, do be quiet. Do, did, and done
           often stand as a general substitute or representative
           verb, and thus save the repetition of the principal
           verb. ``To live and die is all we have to do.''
           --Denham. In the case of do and did as auxiliaries,
           the sense may be completed by the infinitive (without
           to) of the verb represented. ``When beauty lived and
           died as flowers do now.'' --Shak. ``I . . . chose my
           wife as she did her wedding gown.'' --Goldsmith.
           [1913 Webster]

                 My brightest hopes giving dark fears a being.
                 As the light does the shadow.    -- Longfellow.
           In unemphatic affirmative sentences do is, for the
           most part, archaic or poetical; as, ``This just
           reproach their virtue does excite.'' --Dryden.
           [1913 Webster]

   {To do one's best}, {To do one's diligence} (and the like),
      to exert one's self; to put forth one's best or most or
      most diligent efforts. ``We will . . . do our best to gain
      their assent.'' --Jowett (Thucyd.).

   {To do one's business}, to ruin one. [Colloq.] --Wycherley.

   {To do one shame}, to cause one shame. [Obs.]

   {To do over}.
       (a) To make over; to perform a second time.
       (b) To cover; to spread; to smear. ``Boats . . . sewed
           together and done over with a kind of slimy stuff
           like rosin.'' --De Foe.

   {To do to death}, to put to death. (See 7.) [Obs.]

   {To do up}.
       (a) To put up; to raise. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
       (b) To pack together and envelop; to pack up.
       (c) To accomplish thoroughly. [Colloq.]
       (d) To starch and iron. ``A rich gown of velvet, and a
           ruff done up with the famous yellow starch.''
           --Hawthorne.

   {To do way}, to put away; to lay aside. [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {To do with}, to dispose of; to make use of; to employ; --
      usually preceded by what. ``Men are many times brought to
      that extremity, that were it not for God they would not
      know what to do with themselves.'' --Tillotson.

   {To have to do with}, to have concern, business or
      intercourse with; to deal with. When preceded by what, the
      notion is usually implied that the affair does not concern
      the person denoted by the subject of have. ``Philology has
      to do with language in its fullest sense.'' --Earle.
      ``What have I to do with you, ye sons of Zeruiah? --2 Sam.
      xvi. 10.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>doing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Doing \Do"ing\, n.; pl. {Doings}.
   Anything done; a deed; an action good or bad; hence, in the
   plural, conduct; behavior. See {Do}.
   [1913 Webster]

         To render an account of his doings.      -- Barrow.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
