<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dope</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dope</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dope \Dope\ (d[=o]p), n. [D. doop a dipping, fr. doopen to dip.
   Cf. {Dip}.]
   1. Any thick liquid or pasty preparation, as of opium for
      medicinal purposes, of grease for a lubricant, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. Any preparation, as of opium, used to stupefy or, in the
      case of a race horse, to stimulate. [Slang or Cant]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. An absorbent material; esp., in high explosives, the
      sawdust, infusorial earth, mica, etc., mixed with
      nitroglycerin to make a damp powder (dynamite, etc.) less
      dangerous to transport, and ordinarily explosive only by
      suitable fulminating caps.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. Information concerning the previous performances of race
      horses, or other facts concerning them which may be of
      assistance in judging of their chances of winning future
      races; similar information concerning other sports; by
      extension, any information not generally known, especially
      when coming from an inside source; as, the inside dope.
      [Sporting Slang]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   5. an ignorant or stupid person. [Colloq.]
      [PJC]

   {get the dope on} learn the true story; get the inside
      information.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dope</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dope \Dope\, v. t.
   1. To treat or affect with dope; as, to dope nitroglycerin;
      specif.:
      (a) To give stupefying drugs to; to drug. [Slang]
      (b) To administer a stimulant to (a horse) to increase his
          speed. It is a serious offense against the laws of
          racing. [Race-track Slang]
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. To judge or guess; to predict the result of, as by the aid
      of dope. [Slang]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. to impregnate with a dopant.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dope</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dope
     n 1: street names for marijuana [syn: {pot}, {grass}, {green
          goddess}, {weed}, {gage}, {sess}, {sens}, {smoke}, {skunk},
           {locoweed}, {Mary Jane}]
     2: an ignorant or foolish person [syn: {dumbbell}, {dummy}, {boob},
         {booby}, {pinhead}]
     3: carbonated drink flavored with extract from Kola nuts
        (`dope' is a southernism in the United States) [syn: {cola}]
     4: slang terms for inside information; "is that the straight
        dope?" [syn: {poop}, {the skinny}, {low-down}]
     v 1: take drugs to improve one's athletic performance
     2: add impurities to (a semiconductor) in order to produce or
        modify its properties; "The resistors have been doped"
     3: give a narcotic to; "The athletes were dope by the coach
        before the race" [syn: {dope up}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
