<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>doubt</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>doubt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Doubt \Doubt\ (dout), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Doubted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Doubting}.] [OE. duten, douten, OF. duter, doter,
   douter, F. douter, fr. L. dubitare; akin to dubius doubtful.
   See {Dubious}.]
   1. To waver in opinion or judgment; to be in uncertainty as
      to belief respecting anything; to hesitate in belief; to
      be undecided as to the truth of the negative or the
      affirmative proposition; to b e undetermined.
      [1913 Webster]

            Even in matters divine, concerning some things, we
            may lawfully doubt, and suspend our judgment.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            To try your love and make you doubt of mine.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To suspect; to fear; to be apprehensive. [Obs.]

   Syn: To waver; vacillate; fluctuate; hesitate; demur;
        scruple; question.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>doubt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Doubt \Doubt\, v. t.
   1. To question or hold questionable; to withhold assent to;
      to hesitate to believe, or to be inclined not to believe;
      to withhold confidence from; to distrust; as, I have heard
      the story, but I doubt the truth of it.
      [1913 Webster]

            To admire superior sense, and doubt their own!
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            I doubt not that however changed, you keep
            So much of what is graceful.          --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To doubt not but}.

            I do not doubt but I have been to blame. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            We doubt not now
            But every rub is smoothed on our way. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: That is, we have no doubt to prevent us from believing,
         etc. (or notwithstanding all that may be said to the
         contrary) -- but having a preventive sense, after verbs
         of ``doubting'' and ``denying'' that convey a notion of
         hindrance. --E. A. Abbott.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To suspect; to fear; to be apprehensive of. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Edmond [was a] good man and doubted God. --R. of
                                                  Gloucester.
      [1913 Webster]

            I doubt some foul play.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            That I of doubted danger had no fear. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fill with fear; to affright. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The virtues of the valiant Caratach
            More doubt me than all Britain.       --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>doubt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Doubt \Doubt\, n. [OE. dute, doute, F. doute, fr. douter to
   doubt. See {Doubt}, v. i.]
   1. A fluctuation of mind arising from defect of knowledge or
      evidence; uncertainty of judgment or mind; unsettled state
      of opinion concerning the reality of an event, or the
      truth of an assertion, etc.; hesitation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Doubt is the beginning and the end of our efforts to
            know.                                 --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Doubt, in order to be operative in requiring an
            acquittal, is not the want of perfect certainty
            (which can never exist in any question of fact) but
            a defect of proof preventing a reasonable assurance
            of quilt.                             --Wharton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Uncertainty of condition.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy life shall hang in doubt before thee. --Deut.
                                                  xxviii. 66.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Suspicion; fear; apprehension; dread. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I stand in doubt of you.              --Gal. iv. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor slack her threatful hand for danger's doubt.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Difficulty expressed or urged for solution; point
      unsettled; objection.
      [1913 Webster]

            To every doubt your answer is the same. --Blackmore.
      [1913 Webster]

   {No doubt}, undoubtedly; without doubt.

   {Out of doubt}, beyond doubt. [Obs.] --Spenser.

   Syn: Uncertainty; hesitation; suspense; indecision;
        irresolution; distrust; suspicion; scruple; perplexity;
        ambiguity; skepticism.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>doubt</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>doubt
     n 1: the state of being unsure of something [syn: {uncertainty},
          {incertitude}, {dubiety}, {doubtfulness}, {dubiousness}]
          [ant: {certainty}]
     2: uncertainty about the truth or factuality of existence of
        something; "the dubiousness of his claim"; "there is no
        question about the validity of the enterprise" [syn: {dubiousness},
         {doubtfulness}, {question}]
     v 1: consider unlikely or have doubts about; "I doubt that she
          will accept his proposal of marriage"
     2: lack confidence in or have doubts about; "I doubt these
        reports"; "I suspect her true motives"; "she distrusts her
        stepmother"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
