<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>draft</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Draft \Draft\, a.
   1. Pertaining to, or used for, drawing or pulling (as
      vehicles, loads, etc.). Same as {Draught}; as, a draft
      horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Relating to, or characterized by, a draft, or current of
      air. Same as {Draught}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The forms draft and draught, in the senses above-given,
         are both in approved use.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Draft box}, {Draft engine}, {Draft horse}, {Draft net},
   {Draft ox}, {Draft tube}. Same as {Draught box}, {Draught
      engine}, etc. See under {Draught}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Draft \Draft\ (dr[.a]ft), n. [The same word as draught. OE.
   draught, draht, fr. AS. dragan to draw. See {Draw}, and cf.
   {Draught}.]
   1. The act of drawing; also, the thing drawn. Same as
      {Draught}.
      [1913 Webster]

            Everything available for draft burden. -- S. G.
                                                  Goodrich.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) A selecting or detaching of soldiers from an army,
      or from any part of it, or from a military post; also from
      any district, or any company or collection of persons, or
      from the people at large; also, the body of men thus
      drafted.
      [1913 Webster]

            Several of the States had supplied the deficiency by
            drafts to serve for the year.         --Marshall.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An order from one person or party to another, directing
      the payment of money; a bill of exchange.
      [1913 Webster]

            I thought it most prudent to defer the drafts till
            advice was received of the progress of the loan. --
                                                  A. Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An allowance or deduction made from the gross weight of
      goods. -- Simmonds.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A drawing of lines for a plan; a plan delineated, or drawn
      in outline; a delineation. See {Draught}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The form of any writing as first drawn up; the first rough
      sketch of written composition, to be filled in, or
      completed. See {Draught}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Masonry)
      (a) A narrow border left on a finished stone, worked
          differently from the rest of its face.
      (b) A narrow border worked to a plane surface along the
          edge of a stone, or across its face, as a guide to the
          stone-cutter.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Milling) The slant given to the furrows in the dress of a
      millstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) Depth of water necessary to float a ship. See
      {Draught}.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A current of air. Same as {Draught}.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A quantity of liquid poured out for drinking; a dose.
       [PJC]

   12. The act of drawing a quantity of liquid from a large
       container; also, the quantity of liquid so drawn.
       [PJC]

   13. A device for regulating the flow of gases in a chimney,
       stovepipe, fireplace, etc.; as, to close the chimney
       draft. It is usually a flat plate of the same internal
       dimensions as the flue, which can be rotated to be
       parallel to or perpendicular to the current of gases.
       [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Draft \Draft\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Drafted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Drafting}.]
   1. To draw the outline of; to delineate.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To compose and write; as, to draft a memorial.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To draw from a military band or post, or from any
      district, company, or society; to detach; to select;
      especially, to compulsorily select and induct members of a
      population to serve in the armed forces.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            HotLips Houlihan: How did a degenerate person like
            him achieve such a position of responsibility in the
            army? Radar: He was drafted.          --M*A*S*H (the
                                                  movie)

            Some royal seminary in Upper Egypt, from whence they
            drafted novices to supply their colleges and
            temples.                              -- Holwell.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To transfer by draft.
      [1913 Webster]

            All her rents been drafted to London. -- Fielding.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draft</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>draft
     n 1: a document ordering the payment of money; drawn by one
          person or bank on another [syn: {bill of exchange}, {order
          of payment}]
     2: a current of air (usually coming into a room or vehicle)
        [syn: {draught}]
     3: a preliminary sketch of a design or picture [syn: {rough
        drawing}]
     4: a serving of drink (usually alcoholic) drawn from a keg;
        "they served beer on draft" [syn: {draught}, {potation}, {tipple}]
     5: preliminary version of a written work [syn: {draft copy}]
     6: the depth of a vessel's keel below the surface (especially
        when loaded) [syn: {draught}]
     7: a regulator for controlling the flow of air in a fireplace
     8: a dose of liquid medicine; "he took a sleeping draft" [syn:
        {draught}]
     9: compulsory military service [syn: {conscription}, {muster},
        {selective service}]
     10: a large and hurried swallow; "he finished it at a single
         gulp" [syn: {gulp}, {draught}, {swig}]
     11: the act of moving a load by drawing or pulling [syn: {draught},
          {drawing}]
     v 1: draw up an outline or sketch for something; "draft a speech"
          [syn: {outline}]
     2: engage somebody to enter the army [syn: {enlist}, {muster in}]
        [ant: {discharge}]
     3: make a blueprint of [syn: {blueprint}, {draught}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
