<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dragged</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dragged</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drag \Drag\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dragged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Dragging}.] [OE. draggen; akin to Sw. dragga to search with
   a grapnel, fr. dragg grapnel, fr. draga to draw, the same
   word as E. draw. ? See {Draw}.]
   1. To draw slowly or heavily onward; to pull along the ground
      by main force; to haul; to trail; -- applied to drawing
      heavy or resisting bodies or those inapt for drawing, with
      labor, along the ground or other surface; as, to drag
      stone or timber; to drag a net in fishing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Dragged by the cords which through his feet were
            thrust.                               --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

            The grossness of his nature will have weight to drag
            thee down.                            --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            A needless Alexandrine ends the song
            That, like a wounded snake, drags its slow length
            along.                                --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To break, as land, by drawing a drag or harrow over it; to
      harrow; to draw a drag along the bottom of, as a stream or
      other water; hence, to search, as by means of a drag.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then while I dragged my brains for such a song.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To draw along, as something burdensome; hence, to pass in
      pain or with difficulty.
      [1913 Webster]

            Have dragged a lingering life.        -- Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To drag an anchor} (Naut.), to trail it along the bottom
      when the anchor will not hold the ship.

   Syn: See {Draw}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dragged</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>drag
     n 1: the phenomenon of resistance to motion through a fluid [syn:
           {retarding force}]
     2: something that slows or delays progress; "taxation is a drag
        on the economy"; "too many laws are a drag on the use of
        new land"
     3: something tedious and boring; "peeling potatoes is a drag"
     4: clothing that is conventionally worn by the opposite sex
        (especially women's clothing when worn by a man); "he went
        to the party dressed in drag"; "the waitresses looked like
        missionaries in drag"
     5: a slow inhalation (as of tobacco smoke); "he took a puff on
        his pipe"; "he took a drag on his cigarette and expelled
        the smoke slowly" [syn: {puff}, {pull}]
     6: the act of dragging (pulling with force); "the drag up the
        hill exhausted him"
     v 1: pull, as against a resistance; "He dragged the big suitcase
          behind him"; "These worries were dragging at him"
     2: draw slowly or heavily; "haul stones"; "haul nets" [syn: {haul},
         {hale}, {cart}]
     3: force into some kind of situation, condition, or course of
        action; "They were swept up by the events"; "don't drag me
        into this business" [syn: {embroil}, {tangle}, {sweep}, {sweep
        up}, {drag in}]
     4: move slowly and as if with great effort
     5: to lag or linger behind; "But in so many other areas we
        still are dragging" [syn: {trail}, {get behind}, {hang
        back}, {drop behind}]
     6: suck in or take (air); "draw a deep breath"; "draw on a
        cigarette" [syn: {puff}, {draw}]
     7: use a computer mouse to move icons on the screen and select
        commands from a menu; "drag this icon to the lower right
        hand corner of the screen"
     8: walk without lifting the feet [syn: {scuff}]
     9: search (as the bottom of a body of water) for something
        valuable or lost [syn: {dredge}]
     10: persuade to come away from something attractive or
         interesting; "He dragged me away from the television set"
     11: proceed for an extended period of time; "The speech dragged
         on for two hours" [syn: {drag on}, {drag out}]
     [also: {dragging}, {dragged}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dragged</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dragged
     See {drag}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
