<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>draw</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>draw \draw\ (dr[add]), v. t. [imp. {Drew} (dr[udd]); p. p.
   {Drawn} (dr[add]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Drawing}.] [OE.
   dra[yogh]en, drahen, draien, drawen, AS. dragan; akin to
   Icel. &amp; Sw. draga, Dan. drage to draw, carry, and prob. to
   OS. dragan to bear, carry, D. dragen, G. tragen, Goth.
   dragan; cf. Skr. dhraj to move along, glide; and perh. akin
   to Skr. dhar to hold, bear. [root]73. Cf. 2d {Drag}, {Dray} a
   cart, 1st {Dredge}.]
   1. To cause to move continuously by force applied in advance
      of the thing moved; to pull along; to haul; to drag; to
      cause to follow.
      [1913 Webster]

            He cast him down to ground, and all along
            Drew him through dirt and mire without remorse.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hastened to draw the stranger into a private
            room.                                 --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Do not rich men oppress you, and draw you before the
            judgment seats?                       --James ii. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            The arrow is now drawn to the head.   --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To influence to move or tend toward one's self; to
      exercise an attracting force upon; to call towards itself;
      to attract; hence, to entice; to allure; to induce.
      [1913 Webster]

            The poet
            Did feign that Orpheus drew trees, stones, and
            floods.                               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All eyes you draw, and with the eyes the heart.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to come out for one's use or benefit; to extract;
      to educe; to bring forth; as:
      (a) To bring or take out, or to let out, from some
          receptacle, as a stick or post from a hole, water from
          a cask or well, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

                The drew out the staves of the ark. --2 Chron.
                                                  v. 9.
          [1913 Webster]

                Draw thee waters for the siege.   --Nahum iii.
                                                  14.
          [1913 Webster]

                I opened the tumor by the point of a lancet
                without drawing one drop of blood. --Wiseman.
      (b) To pull from a sheath, as a sword.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will draw my sword, my hand shall destroy
                them.                             --Ex. xv. 9.
      (c) To extract; to force out; to elicit; to derive.
          [1913 Webster]

                Spirits, by distillations, may be drawn out of
                vegetable juices, which shall flame and fume of
                themselves.                       --Cheyne.
          [1913 Webster]

                Until you had drawn oaths from him. --Shak.
      (d) To obtain from some cause or origin; to infer from
          evidence or reasons; to deduce from premises; to
          derive.
          [1913 Webster]

                We do not draw the moral lessons we might from
                history.                          --Burke.
      (e) To take or procure from a place of deposit; to call
          for and receive from a fund, or the like; as, to draw
          money from a bank.
      (f) To take from a box or wheel, as a lottery ticket; to
          receive from a lottery by the drawing out of the
          numbers for prizes or blanks; hence, to obtain by good
          fortune; to win; to gain; as, he drew a prize.
      (g) To select by the drawing of lots.
          [1913 Webster]

                Provided magistracies were filled by men freely
                chosen or drawn.                  --Freeman.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. To remove the contents of; as:
      (a) To drain by emptying; to suck dry.
          [1913 Webster]

                Sucking and drawing the breast dischargeth the
                milk as fast as it can generated. --Wiseman.
      (b) To extract the bowels of; to eviscerate; as, to draw a
          fowl; to hang, draw, and quarter a criminal.
          [1913 Webster]

                In private draw your poultry, clean your tripe.
                                                  --King.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. To take into the lungs; to inhale; to inspire; hence,
      also, to utter or produce by an inhalation; to heave.
      ``Where I first drew air.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Drew, or seemed to draw, a dying groan. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To extend in length; to lengthen; to protract; to stretch;
      to extend, as a mass of metal into wire.
      [1913 Webster]

            How long her face is drawn!           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the huge Offa's dike which he drew from the
            mouth of Wye to that of Dee.          --J. R. Green.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To run, extend, or produce, as a line on any surface;
      hence, also, to form by marking; to make by an instrument
      of delineation; to produce, as a sketch, figure, or
      picture.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To represent by lines drawn; to form a sketch or a picture
      of; to represent by a picture; to delineate; hence, to
      represent by words; to depict; to describe.
      [1913 Webster]

            A flattering painter who made it his care
            To draw men as they ought to be, not as they are.
                                                  --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

            Can I, untouched, the fair one's passions move,
            Or thou draw beauty and not feel its power? --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To write in due form; to prepare a draught of; as, to draw
      a memorial, a deed, or bill of exchange.
      [1913 Webster]

            Clerk, draw a deed of gift.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To require (so great a depth, as of water) for floating;
       -- said of a vessel; to sink so deep in (water); as, a
       ship draws ten feet of water.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To withdraw. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
       [1913 Webster]

             Go wash thy face, and draw the action. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To trace by scent; to track; -- a hunting term.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Games)
       (a) (Cricket) To play (a short-length ball directed at
           the leg stump) with an inclined bat so as to deflect
           the ball between the legs and the wicket.
       (b) (Golf) To hit (the ball) with the toe of the club so
           that it is deflected toward the left.
       (c) (Billiards) To strike (the cue ball) below the center
           so as to give it a backward rotation which causes it
           to take a backward direction on striking another
           ball.
       (d) (Curling) To throw up (the stone) gently.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   14. To leave (a contest) undecided; as, the battle or game
       was drawn. ``Win, lose, or draw.''
       [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   Note: Draw, in most of its uses, retains some shade of its
         original sense, to pull, to move forward by the
         application of force in advance, or to extend in
         length, and usually expresses an action as gradual or
         continuous, and leisurely. We pour liquid quickly, but
         we draw it in a continued stream. We force compliance
         by threats, but we draw it by gradual prevalence. We
         may write a letter with haste, but we draw a bill with
         slow caution and regard to a precise form. We draw a
         bar of metal by continued beating.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To draw a bow}, to bend the bow by drawing the string for
      discharging the arrow.

   {To draw a cover}, to clear a cover of the game it contains.
      

   {To draw a curtain}, to cause a curtain to slide or move,
      either closing or unclosing. ``Night draws the curtain,
      which the sun withdraws.'' --Herbert.

   {To draw a line}, to fix a limit or boundary.

   {To draw back}, to receive back, as duties on goods for
      exportation.

   {To draw breath}, to breathe. --Shak.

   {To draw cuts} or {To draw lots}. See under {Cut}, n.

   {To draw in}.
       (a) To bring or pull in; to collect.
       (b) To entice; to inveigle.

   {To draw interest}, to produce or gain interest.

   {To draw off}, to withdraw; to abstract. --Addison.

   {To draw on}, to bring on; to occasion; to cause. ``War which
      either his negligence drew on, or his practices
      procured.'' --Hayward.

   {To draw (one) out}, to elicit cunningly the thoughts and
      feelings of another.

   {To draw out}, to stretch or extend; to protract; to spread
      out. -- ``Wilt thou draw out thine anger to all
      generations?'' --Ps. lxxxv. 5. ``Linked sweetness long
      drawn out.'' --Milton.

   {To draw over}, to cause to come over, to induce to leave one
      part or side for the opposite one.

   {To draw the longbow}, to exaggerate; to tell preposterous
      tales.

   {To draw (one) to} or {To draw (one) on to} (something), to
      move, to incite, to induce. ``How many actions most
      ridiculous hast thou been drawn to by thy fantasy?''
      --Shak.

   {To draw up}.
       (a) To compose in due form; to draught; to form in
           writing.
       (b) To arrange in order, as a body of troops; to array.
           ``Drawn up in battle to receive the charge.''
           --Dryden.

   Syn: To {Draw}, {Drag}.

   Usage: Draw differs from drag in this, that drag implies a
          natural inaptitude for drawing, or positive
          resistance; it is applied to things pulled or hauled
          along the ground, or moved with toil or difficulty.
          Draw is applied to all bodies moved by force in
          advance, whatever may be the degree of force; it
          commonly implies that some kind of aptitude or
          provision exists for drawing. Draw is the more general
          or generic term, and drag the more specific. We say,
          the horses draw a coach or wagon, but they drag it
          through mire; yet draw is properly used in both cases.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Draw \Draw\, n.
   1. The act of drawing; draught.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lot or chance to be drawn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. the act of drawing a lot or chance. ``The luck of the
      draw.''
      [PJC]

   3. A drawn game or battle, etc; a tied game; a tie. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. That part of a bridge which may be raised, swung round, or
      drawn aside; the movable part of a drawbridge. See the
      Note under {Drawbridge}. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The result of drawing, or state of being drawn; specif.:
      (a) A drawn battle, game, or the like.
      (b) The spin or twist imparted to a ball, or the like, by
          a drawing stroke.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. That which is drawn or is subject to drawing.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Draw \Draw\, v. i.
   1. To pull; to exert strength in drawing anything; to have
      force to move anything by pulling; as, a horse draws well;
      the sails of a ship draw well.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A sail is said to draw when it is filled with wind.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw a liquid from some receptacle, as water from a
      well.
      [1913 Webster]

            The woman saith unto him, Sir, thou hast nothing to
            draw with, and the well is deep.      --John iv. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To exert an attractive force; to act as an inducement or
      enticement.
      [1913 Webster]

            Keep a watch upon the particular bias of their
            minds, that it may not draw too much. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Med.) To have efficiency as an epispastic; to act as a
      sinapism; -- said of a blister, poultice, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To have draught, as a chimney, flue, or the like; to
      furnish transmission to smoke, gases, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To unsheathe a weapon, especially a sword.
      [1913 Webster]

            So soon as ever thou seest him, draw; and as thou
            drawest, swear horrible.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To perform the act, or practice the art, of delineation;
      to sketch; to form figures or pictures. ``Skill in
      drawing.'' --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To become contracted; to shrink. ``To draw into less
      room.'' --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To move; to come or go; literally, to draw one's self; --
      with prepositions and adverbs; as, to draw away, to move
      off, esp. in racing, to get in front; to obtain the lead
      or increase it; to draw back, to retreat; to draw level,
      to move up even (with another); to come up to or overtake
      another; to draw off, to retire or retreat; to draw on, to
      advance; to draw up, to form in array; to draw near, draw
      nigh, or draw towards, to approach; to draw together, to
      come together, to collect.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To make a draft or written demand for payment of money
       deposited or due; -- usually with on or upon.
       [1913 Webster]

             You may draw on me for the expenses of your
             journey.                             --Jay.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To admit the action of pulling or dragging; to undergo
       draught; as, a carriage draws easily.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To sink in water; to require a depth for floating.
       ``Greater hulks draw deep.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To draw to a head}.
       (a) (Med.) To begin to suppurate; to ripen, as a boil.
       (b) Fig.: To ripen, to approach the time for action; as,
           the plot draws to a head.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>draw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>draw
     n 1: a gully that is shallower than a ravine
     2: an entertainer who attracts large audiences; "he was the
        biggest drawing card they had" [syn: {drawing card}, {attraction},
         {attractor}, {attracter}]
     3: the finish of a contest in which the score is tied and the
        winner is undecided; "the game ended in a draw"; "their
        record was 3 wins, 6 losses and a tie" [syn: {standoff}, {tie}]
     4: anything (straws or pebbles etc.) taken or chosen at random;
        "the luck of the draw"; "they drew lots for it" [syn: {lot}]
     5: a playing card or cards dealt or taken from the pack; "he
        got a pair of kings in the draw"
     6: a golf shot that curves to the left for a right-handed
        golfer; "he tooks lessons to cure his hooking" [syn: {hook},
         {hooking}]
     7: (American football) the quarterback moves back as if to pass
        and then hands the ball to the fullback who is running
        toward the line of scrimmage [syn: {draw play}]
     8: poker in which a player can discard cards and receive
        substitutes from the dealer; "he played only draw and
        stud" [syn: {draw poker}]
     9: the act of drawing or hauling something; "the haul up the
        hill went very slowly" [syn: {haul}, {haulage}]
     v 1: cause to move along the ground by pulling; "draw a wagon";
          "pull a sled" [syn: {pull}, {force}] [ant: {push}]
     2: get or derive; "He drew great benefits from his membership
        in the association" [syn: {reap}]
     3: make a mark or lines on a surface; "draw a line"; "trace the
        outline of a figure in the sand" [syn: {trace}, {line}, {describe},
         {delineate}]
     4: make, formulate, or derive in the mind; "I draw a line
        here"; "draw a conclusion"; "draw parallels"; "make an
        estimate"; "What do you make of his remarks?" [syn: {make}]
     5: bring, take, or pull out of a container or from under a
        cover; "draw a weapon"; "pull out a gun"; "The mugger
        pulled a knife on his victim" [syn: {pull}, {pull out}, {get
        out}, {take out}]
     6: represent by making a drawing of, as with a pencil, chalk,
        etc. on a surface; "She drew an elephant"; "Draw me a
        horse"
     7: take liquid out of a container or well; "She drew water from
        the barrel" [syn: {take out}]
     8: give a description of; "He drew an elaborate plan of attack"
        [syn: {describe}, {depict}]
     9: select or take in from a given group or region; "The
        participants in the experiment were drawn from a
        representative population"
     10: elicit responses, such as objections, criticism, applause,
         etc.; "The President's comments drew sharp criticism from
         the Republicans"; "The comedian drew a lot of laughter"
     11: suck in or take (air); "draw a deep breath"; "draw on a
         cigarette" [syn: {puff}, {drag}]
     12: move or go steadily or gradually; "The ship drew near the
         shore"
     13: remove (a commodity) from (a supply source); "She drew
         $2,000 from the account"; "The doctors drew medical
         supplies from the hospital's emergency bank" [syn: {withdraw},
          {take out}, {draw off}] [ant: {deposit}]
     14: choose at random; "draw a card"; "cast lots" [syn: {cast}]
     15: in baseball: earn or achieve a base by being walked by the
         pitcher; "He drew a base on balls" [syn: {get}]
     16: bring or lead someone to a certain action or condition; "She
         was drawn to despair"; "The President refused to be drawn
         into delivering an ultimatum"; "The session was drawn to
         a close"
     17: cause to flow; "The nurse drew blood"
     18: write a legal document or paper; "The deed was drawn in the
         lawyer's office"
     19: engage in drawing; "He spent the day drawing in the garden"
     20: move or pull so as to cover or uncover something; "draw the
         shades"; "draw the curtains"
     21: allow a draft; "This chimney draws very well"
     22: require a specified depth for floating; "This boat draws 70
         inches"
     23: pull (a person) apart with four horses tied to his
         extremities, so as to execute him; "in the old days,
         people were drawn and quartered for certain crimes" [syn:
          {quarter}, {draw and quarter}]
     24: take in, also metaphorically; "The sponge absorbs water
         well"; "She drew strength from the minister's words"
         [syn: {absorb}, {suck}, {imbibe}, {soak up}, {sop up}, {suck
         up}, {take in}, {take up}]
     25: direct toward itself or oneself by means of some
         psychological power or physical attributes; "Her good
         looks attract the stares of many men"; "The ad pulled in
         many potential customers"; "This pianist pulls huge
         crowds"; "The store owner was happy that the ad drew in
         many new customers" [syn: {attract}, {pull}, {pull in}, {draw
         in}] [ant: {repel}]
     26: thread on or as if on a string; "string pearls on a string";
         "the child drew glass beads on a string"; "thread dried
         cranberries" [syn: {string}, {thread}]
     27: pull back the sling of (a bow); "The archers were drawing
         their bows" [syn: {pull back}]
     28: guide or pass over something; "He ran his eyes over her
         body"; "She ran her fingers along the carved figurine";
         "He drew her hair through his fingers" [syn: {guide}, {run},
          {pass}]
     29: finish a game with an equal number of points, goals, etc.;
         "The teams drew a tie" [syn: {tie}]
     30: contract; "The material drew after it was washed in hot
         water"
     31: reduce the diameter of (a wire or metal rod) by pulling it
         through a die; "draw wire"
     32: steep; pass through a strainer; "draw pulp from the fruit"
     33: remove the entrails of; "draw a chicken" [syn: {disembowel},
          {eviscerate}]
     34: flatten, stretch, or mold metal or glass, by rolling or by
         pulling it through a die or by stretching; "draw steel"
     35: cause to localize at one point; "Draw blood and pus"
     [also: {drew}, {drawn}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
