<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>drawing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drawing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>draw \draw\ (dr[add]), v. t. [imp. {Drew} (dr[udd]); p. p.
   {Drawn} (dr[add]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Drawing}.] [OE.
   dra[yogh]en, drahen, draien, drawen, AS. dragan; akin to
   Icel. &amp; Sw. draga, Dan. drage to draw, carry, and prob. to
   OS. dragan to bear, carry, D. dragen, G. tragen, Goth.
   dragan; cf. Skr. dhraj to move along, glide; and perh. akin
   to Skr. dhar to hold, bear. [root]73. Cf. 2d {Drag}, {Dray} a
   cart, 1st {Dredge}.]
   1. To cause to move continuously by force applied in advance
      of the thing moved; to pull along; to haul; to drag; to
      cause to follow.
      [1913 Webster]

            He cast him down to ground, and all along
            Drew him through dirt and mire without remorse.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hastened to draw the stranger into a private
            room.                                 --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Do not rich men oppress you, and draw you before the
            judgment seats?                       --James ii. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            The arrow is now drawn to the head.   --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To influence to move or tend toward one's self; to
      exercise an attracting force upon; to call towards itself;
      to attract; hence, to entice; to allure; to induce.
      [1913 Webster]

            The poet
            Did feign that Orpheus drew trees, stones, and
            floods.                               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All eyes you draw, and with the eyes the heart.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to come out for one's use or benefit; to extract;
      to educe; to bring forth; as:
      (a) To bring or take out, or to let out, from some
          receptacle, as a stick or post from a hole, water from
          a cask or well, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

                The drew out the staves of the ark. --2 Chron.
                                                  v. 9.
          [1913 Webster]

                Draw thee waters for the siege.   --Nahum iii.
                                                  14.
          [1913 Webster]

                I opened the tumor by the point of a lancet
                without drawing one drop of blood. --Wiseman.
      (b) To pull from a sheath, as a sword.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will draw my sword, my hand shall destroy
                them.                             --Ex. xv. 9.
      (c) To extract; to force out; to elicit; to derive.
          [1913 Webster]

                Spirits, by distillations, may be drawn out of
                vegetable juices, which shall flame and fume of
                themselves.                       --Cheyne.
          [1913 Webster]

                Until you had drawn oaths from him. --Shak.
      (d) To obtain from some cause or origin; to infer from
          evidence or reasons; to deduce from premises; to
          derive.
          [1913 Webster]

                We do not draw the moral lessons we might from
                history.                          --Burke.
      (e) To take or procure from a place of deposit; to call
          for and receive from a fund, or the like; as, to draw
          money from a bank.
      (f) To take from a box or wheel, as a lottery ticket; to
          receive from a lottery by the drawing out of the
          numbers for prizes or blanks; hence, to obtain by good
          fortune; to win; to gain; as, he drew a prize.
      (g) To select by the drawing of lots.
          [1913 Webster]

                Provided magistracies were filled by men freely
                chosen or drawn.                  --Freeman.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. To remove the contents of; as:
      (a) To drain by emptying; to suck dry.
          [1913 Webster]

                Sucking and drawing the breast dischargeth the
                milk as fast as it can generated. --Wiseman.
      (b) To extract the bowels of; to eviscerate; as, to draw a
          fowl; to hang, draw, and quarter a criminal.
          [1913 Webster]

                In private draw your poultry, clean your tripe.
                                                  --King.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. To take into the lungs; to inhale; to inspire; hence,
      also, to utter or produce by an inhalation; to heave.
      ``Where I first drew air.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Drew, or seemed to draw, a dying groan. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To extend in length; to lengthen; to protract; to stretch;
      to extend, as a mass of metal into wire.
      [1913 Webster]

            How long her face is drawn!           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the huge Offa's dike which he drew from the
            mouth of Wye to that of Dee.          --J. R. Green.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To run, extend, or produce, as a line on any surface;
      hence, also, to form by marking; to make by an instrument
      of delineation; to produce, as a sketch, figure, or
      picture.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To represent by lines drawn; to form a sketch or a picture
      of; to represent by a picture; to delineate; hence, to
      represent by words; to depict; to describe.
      [1913 Webster]

            A flattering painter who made it his care
            To draw men as they ought to be, not as they are.
                                                  --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

            Can I, untouched, the fair one's passions move,
            Or thou draw beauty and not feel its power? --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To write in due form; to prepare a draught of; as, to draw
      a memorial, a deed, or bill of exchange.
      [1913 Webster]

            Clerk, draw a deed of gift.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To require (so great a depth, as of water) for floating;
       -- said of a vessel; to sink so deep in (water); as, a
       ship draws ten feet of water.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To withdraw. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
       [1913 Webster]

             Go wash thy face, and draw the action. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To trace by scent; to track; -- a hunting term.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Games)
       (a) (Cricket) To play (a short-length ball directed at
           the leg stump) with an inclined bat so as to deflect
           the ball between the legs and the wicket.
       (b) (Golf) To hit (the ball) with the toe of the club so
           that it is deflected toward the left.
       (c) (Billiards) To strike (the cue ball) below the center
           so as to give it a backward rotation which causes it
           to take a backward direction on striking another
           ball.
       (d) (Curling) To throw up (the stone) gently.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   14. To leave (a contest) undecided; as, the battle or game
       was drawn. ``Win, lose, or draw.''
       [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   Note: Draw, in most of its uses, retains some shade of its
         original sense, to pull, to move forward by the
         application of force in advance, or to extend in
         length, and usually expresses an action as gradual or
         continuous, and leisurely. We pour liquid quickly, but
         we draw it in a continued stream. We force compliance
         by threats, but we draw it by gradual prevalence. We
         may write a letter with haste, but we draw a bill with
         slow caution and regard to a precise form. We draw a
         bar of metal by continued beating.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To draw a bow}, to bend the bow by drawing the string for
      discharging the arrow.

   {To draw a cover}, to clear a cover of the game it contains.
      

   {To draw a curtain}, to cause a curtain to slide or move,
      either closing or unclosing. ``Night draws the curtain,
      which the sun withdraws.'' --Herbert.

   {To draw a line}, to fix a limit or boundary.

   {To draw back}, to receive back, as duties on goods for
      exportation.

   {To draw breath}, to breathe. --Shak.

   {To draw cuts} or {To draw lots}. See under {Cut}, n.

   {To draw in}.
       (a) To bring or pull in; to collect.
       (b) To entice; to inveigle.

   {To draw interest}, to produce or gain interest.

   {To draw off}, to withdraw; to abstract. --Addison.

   {To draw on}, to bring on; to occasion; to cause. ``War which
      either his negligence drew on, or his practices
      procured.'' --Hayward.

   {To draw (one) out}, to elicit cunningly the thoughts and
      feelings of another.

   {To draw out}, to stretch or extend; to protract; to spread
      out. -- ``Wilt thou draw out thine anger to all
      generations?'' --Ps. lxxxv. 5. ``Linked sweetness long
      drawn out.'' --Milton.

   {To draw over}, to cause to come over, to induce to leave one
      part or side for the opposite one.

   {To draw the longbow}, to exaggerate; to tell preposterous
      tales.

   {To draw (one) to} or {To draw (one) on to} (something), to
      move, to incite, to induce. ``How many actions most
      ridiculous hast thou been drawn to by thy fantasy?''
      --Shak.

   {To draw up}.
       (a) To compose in due form; to draught; to form in
           writing.
       (b) To arrange in order, as a body of troops; to array.
           ``Drawn up in battle to receive the charge.''
           --Dryden.

   Syn: To {Draw}, {Drag}.

   Usage: Draw differs from drag in this, that drag implies a
          natural inaptitude for drawing, or positive
          resistance; it is applied to things pulled or hauled
          along the ground, or moved with toil or difficulty.
          Draw is applied to all bodies moved by force in
          advance, whatever may be the degree of force; it
          commonly implies that some kind of aptitude or
          provision exists for drawing. Draw is the more general
          or generic term, and drag the more specific. We say,
          the horses draw a coach or wagon, but they drag it
          through mire; yet draw is properly used in both cases.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drawing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drawing \Draw"ing\, n.
   1. The act of pulling, or attracting.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act or the art of representing any object by means of
      lines and shades; especially, such a representation when
      in one color, or in tints used not to represent the colors
      of natural objects, but for effect only, and produced with
      hard material such as pencil, chalk, etc.; delineation;
      also, the figure or representation drawn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The process of stretching or spreading metals as by
      hammering, or, as in forming wire from rods or tubes and
      cups from sheet metal, by pulling them through dies.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Textile Manuf.) The process of pulling out and elongating
      the sliver from the carding machine, by revolving rollers,
      to prepare it for spinning.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The distribution of prizes and blanks in a lottery.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Drawing is used adjectively or as the first part of
         compounds in the sense of pertaining to drawing, for
         drawing (in the sense of pulling, and of pictorial
         representation); as, drawing master or drawing-master,
         drawing knife or drawing-knife, drawing machine,
         drawing board, drawing paper, drawing pen, drawing
         pencil, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {A drawing of tea}, a small portion of tea for steeping.

   {Drawing knife}. See in the {Vocabulary}.

   {Drawing paper} (Fine Arts), a thick, sized paper for
      draughtsman and for water-color painting.

   {Drawing slate}, a soft, slaty substance used in crayon
      drawing; -- called also {black chalk}, or {drawing chalk}.
      

   {Free-hand drawing}, a style of drawing made without the use
      of guiding or measuring instruments, as distinguished from
      mechanical or geometrical drawing; also, a drawing thus
      executed.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drawing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>drawing
     n 1: an illustration that is drawn by hand and published in a
          book or magazine; "it is shown by the drawing in Fig. 7"
     2: a representation of forms or objects on a surface by means
        of lines; "drawings of abstract forms"; "he did
        complicated pen-and-ink drawings like medieval miniatures"
     3: the creation of artistic drawings; "he learned drawing from
        his father" [syn: {draftsmanship}, {drafting}]
     4: players buy (or are given) chances and prizes are
        distributed according to the drawing of lots [syn: {lottery}]
     5: act of getting or draining something such as electricity or
        a liquid from a source; "the drawing of water from the
        well" [syn: {drawing off}]
     6: the act of moving a load by drawing or pulling [syn: {draft},
         {draught}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
