<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dress</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dress
   (1.) Materials used. The earliest and simplest an apron of
   fig-leaves sewed together (Gen. 3:7); then skins of animals
   (3:21). Elijah's dress was probably the skin of a sheep (2 Kings
   1:8). The Hebrews were early acquainted with the art of weaving
   hair into cloth (Ex. 26:7; 35:6), which formed the sackcloth of
   mourners. This was the material of John the Baptist's robe
   (Matt. 3:4). Wool was also woven into garments (Lev. 13:47;
   Deut. 22:11; Ezek. 34:3; Job 31:20; Prov. 27:26). The Israelites
   probably learned the art of weaving linen when they were in
   Egypt (1 Chr. 4:21). Fine linen was used in the vestments of the
   high priest (Ex. 28:5), as well as by the rich (Gen. 41:42;
   Prov. 31:22; Luke 16:19). The use of mixed material, as wool and
   flax, was forbidden (Lev. 19:19; Deut. 22:11).
   
     (2.) Colour. The prevailing colour was the natural white of
   the material used, which was sometimes rendered purer by the
   fuller's art (Ps. 104:1, 2; Isa. 63:3; Mark 9:3). The Hebrews
   were acquainted with the art of dyeing (Gen. 37:3, 23). Various
   modes of ornamentation were adopted in the process of weaving
   (Ex. 28:6; 26:1, 31; 35:25), and by needle-work (Judg. 5:30; Ps.
   45:13). Dyed robes were imported from foreign countries,
   particularly from Phoenicia (Zeph. 1:8). Purple and scarlet
   robes were the marks of the wealthy (Luke 16:19; 2 Sam. 1:24).
   
     (3.) Form. The robes of men and women were not very much
   different in form from each other.
   
     (a) The "coat" (kethoneth), of wool, cotton, or linen, was
   worn by both sexes. It was a closely-fitting garment, resembling
   in use and form our shirt (John 19:23). It was kept close to the
   body by a girdle (John 21:7). A person wearing this "coat" alone
   was described as naked (1 Sam. 19:24; Isa. 20:2; 2 Kings 6:30;
   John 21:7); deprived of it he would be absolutely naked.
   
     (b) A linen cloth or wrapper (sadin) of fine linen, used
   somewhat as a night-shirt (Mark 14:51). It is mentioned in Judg.
   14:12, 13, and rendered there "sheets."
   
     (c) An upper tunic (meil), longer than the "coat" (1 Sam.
   2:19; 24:4; 28:14). In 1 Sam. 28:14 it is the mantle in which
   Samuel was enveloped; in 1 Sam. 24:4 it is the "robe" under
   which Saul slept. The disciples were forbidden to wear two
   "coats" (Matt. 10:10; Luke 9:3).
   
     (d) The usual outer garment consisted of a piece of woollen
   cloth like a Scotch plaid, either wrapped round the body or
   thrown over the shoulders like a shawl, with the ends hanging
   down in front, or it might be thrown over the head so as to
   conceal the face (2 Sam. 15:30; Esther 6:12). It was confined to
   the waist by a girdle, and the fold formed by the overlapping of
   the robe served as a pocket (2 Kings 4:39; Ps. 79:12; Hag. 2:12;
   Prov. 17:23; 21:14).
   
     Female dress. The "coat" was common to both sexes (Cant. 5:3).
   But peculiar to females were (1) the "veil" or "wimple," a kind
   of shawl (Ruth 3:15; rendered "mantle," R.V., Isa. 3:22); (2)
   the "mantle," also a species of shawl (Isa. 3:22); (3) a "veil,"
   probably a light summer dress (Gen. 24:65); (4) a "stomacher," a
   holiday dress (Isa. 3:24). The outer garment terminated in an
   ample fringe or border, which concealed the feet (Isa. 47:2;
   Jer. 13:22).
   
     The dress of the Persians is described in Dan. 3:21.
   
     The reference to the art of sewing are few, inasmuch as the
   garments generally came forth from the loom ready for being
   worn, and all that was required in the making of clothes
   devolved on the women of a family (Prov. 31:22; Acts 9:39).
   
     Extravagance in dress is referred to in Jer. 4:30; Ezek.
   16:10; Zeph. 1:8 (R.V., "foreign apparel"); 1 Tim. 2:9; 1 Pet.
   3:3. Rending the robes was expressive of grief (Gen. 37:29, 34),
   fear (1 Kings 21:27), indignation (2 Kings 5:7), or despair
   (Judg. 11:35; Esther 4:1).
   
     Shaking the garments, or shaking the dust from off them, was a
   sign of renunciation (Acts 18:6); wrapping them round the head,
   of awe (1 Kings 19:13) or grief (2 Sam. 15:30; casting them off,
   of excitement (Acts 22:23); laying hold of them, of supplication
   (1 Sam. 15:27). In the case of travelling, the outer garments
   were girded up (1 Kings 18:46). They were thrown aside also when
   they would impede action (Mark 10:50; John 13:4; Acts 7:58).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dress \Dress\ (dr[e^]s), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dressed}
   (dr[e^]st) or {Drest}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Dressing}.] [OF.
   drecier to make straight, raise, set up, prepare, arrange, F.
   dresser, (assumed) LL. directiare, fr. L. dirigere, directum,
   to direct; dis- + regere to rule. See {Right}, and cf.
   {Address}, {Adroit}, {Direct}, {Dirge}.]
   1. To direct; to put right or straight; to regulate; to
      order. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            At all times thou shalt bless God and pray Him to
            dress thy ways.                       --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Dress is used reflexively in Old English, in sense of
         ``to direct one's step; to address one's self.''
         [1913 Webster]

               To Grisild again will I me dresse. --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) To arrange in exact continuity of line, as
      soldiers; commonly to adjust to a straight line and at
      proper distance; to align; as, to dress the ranks.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Med.) To treat methodically with remedies, bandages, or
      curative appliances, as a sore, an ulcer, a wound, or a
      wounded or diseased part.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To adjust; to put in good order; to arrange; specifically:
      (a) To prepare for use; to fit for any use; to render
          suitable for an intended purpose; to get ready; as, to
          dress a slain animal; to dress meat; to dress leather
          or cloth; to dress or trim a lamp; to dress a garden;
          to dress a horse, by currying and rubbing; to dress
          grain, by cleansing it; in mining and metallurgy, to
          dress ores, by sorting and separating them.
          [1913 Webster]

                And the Lord God took the man, and put him into
                the garden of Eden to dress it.   --Gen. ii. 15.
          [1913 Webster]

                When he dresseth the lamps he shall burn
                incense.                          --Ex. xxx. 7.
          [1913 Webster]

                Three hundred horses . . . smoothly dressed.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

                Dressing their hair with the white sea flower.
                                                  --Tennyson
          .
          [1913 Webster]

                If he felt obliged to expostulate, he might have
                dressed his censures in a kinder form.
                                                  --Carlyle.
      (b) To cut to proper dimensions, or give proper shape to,
          as to a tool by hammering; also, to smooth or finish.
      (c) To put in proper condition by appareling, as the body;
          to put clothes upon; to apparel; to invest with
          garments or rich decorations; to clothe; to deck.
          [1913 Webster]

                Dressed myself in such humility.  -- Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                Prove that ever Idress myself handsome till thy
                return.                           --Shak.
      (d) To break and train for use, as a horse or other
          animal.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To dress up} or {To dress out}, to dress elaborately,
      artificially, or pompously. ``You see very often a king of
      England or France dressed up like a Julius C[ae]sar.''
      --Addison.

   {To dress a ship} (Naut.), to ornament her by hoisting the
      national colors at the peak and mastheads, and setting the
      jack forward; when dressed full, the signal flags and
      pennants are added. --Ham. Nav. Encyc.

   Syn: To attire; apparel; clothe; accouter; array; robe; rig;
        trim; deck; adorn; embellish.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dress \Dress\, v. i.
   1. (Mil.) To arrange one's self in due position in a line of
      soldiers; -- the word of command to form alignment in
      ranks; as, Dress right, dress!
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To clothe or apparel one's self; to put on one's garments;
      to pay particular regard to dress; as, to dress quickly.
      ``To dress for a ball.'' --Latham.
      [1913 Webster]

            To flaunt, to dress, to dance, to thrum. --Tennyson
      .
      [1913 Webster]

   {To dress to the right}, {To dress to the left}, {To dress on
   the center} (Mil.), to form alignment with reference to the
      soldier on the extreme right, or in the center, of the
      rank, who serves as a guide.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dress \Dress\, n.
   1. That which is used as the covering or ornament of the
      body; clothes; garments; habit; apparel. ``In your
      soldier's dress.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lady's gown; as, silk or a velvet dress.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Attention to apparel, or skill in adjusting it.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men of pleasure, dress, and gallantry. -- Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Milling) The system of furrows on the face of a
      millstone. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Dress parade} (Mil.), a parade in full uniform for review.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dress

Casual, vaguely post-hippie; T-shirts, jeans, running shoes, Birkenstocks
(or bare feet). Long hair, beards, and moustaches are common. High
incidence of tie-dye and intellectual or humorous `slogan' T-shirts. Until
the mid-1990s such T-shirts were seldom computer-related, as that would
have been too obvious - but the hacker culture has since developed its own
icons, and J. Random Hacker now often wears a Linux penguin or BSD daemon
or a DeCSS protest shirt.

A substantial minority prefers `outdoorsy' clothing -- hiking boots ("in
case a mountain should suddenly spring up in the machine room", as one
famous parody put it), khakis, lumberjack or chamois shirts, and the like.

After about 1995 hacker dress styles assimilated some influence from
punk, gothic, and rave subcultures. This was relatively mild and has
manifested mostly as a tendency to wear a lot of black, especially when
`dressed up' to the limit of formality. Other markers of those subcultures
such as piercings, chains, and dyed hair remain relatively uncommon.

Very few hackers actually fit the "National Lampoon" Nerd stereotype,
though it lingers on at MIT and may have been more common before 1975. At
least since the late Seventies backpacks have been more common than
briefcases, and the hacker `look' has been more whole-earth than
whole-polyester.

Hackers dress for comfort, function, and minimal maintenance hassles
rather than for appearance (some, perhaps unfortunately, take this to
extremes and neglect personal hygiene). They have a very low tolerance of
suits and other `business' attire; in fact, it is not uncommon for hackers
to quit a job rather than conform to a dress code. When they are somehow
backed into conforming to a dress code, they will find ways to subvert it,
for example by wearing absurd novelty ties.

Female hackers almost never wear visible makeup, and many use none at
all.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dress</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dress
     adj 1: suitable for formal occasions; "formal wear"; "a full-dress
            uniform"; "dress shoes" [syn: {full-dress}]
     2: (of an occasion) requiring formal clothes; "a dress dinner";
        "a full-dress ceremony" [syn: {full-dress}]
     n 1: a one-piece garment for a woman; has skirt and bodice [syn:
          {frock}]
     2: clothing of a distinctive style or for a particular
        occasion; "formal attire"; "battle dress" [syn: {attire},
        {garb}]
     3: clothing in general; "she was refined in her choice of
        apparel"; "he always bought his clothes at the same
        store"; "fastidious about his dress" [syn: {apparel}, {wearing
        apparel}, {clothes}]
     v 1: put on clothes; "we had to dress quickly"; "dress the
          patient"; "Can the child dress by herself?" [syn: {get
          dressed}] [ant: {undress}]
     2: provide with clothes or put clothes on; "Parents must feed
        and dress their child" [syn: {clothe}, {enclothe}, {garb},
         {raiment}, {tog}, {garment}, {habilitate}, {fit out}, {apparel}]
        [ant: {undress}]
     3: put a finish on; "dress the surface smooth"
     4: dress in a certain manner; "She dresses in the latest Paris
        fashion"; "he dressed up in a suit and tie" [syn: {dress
        up}]
     5: dress or groom with elaborate care; "She likes to dress when
        going to the opera" [syn: {preen}, {primp}, {plume}]
     6: kill and prepare for market or consumption; "dress a turkey"
        [syn: {dress out}]
     7: arrange in ranks; "dress troops" [syn: {line up}]
     8: decorate (food), as with parsley or other ornamental foods
        [syn: {trim}, {garnish}]
     9: provide with decoration; "dress the windows" [syn: {decorate}]
     10: put a dressing on; "dress the salads"
     11: cultivate, tend, and cut back the growth of; "dress the
         plants in the garden" [syn: {snip}, {clip}, {crop}, {trim},
          {lop}, {prune}, {cut back}]
     12: cut down rough-hewn (lumber) to standard thickness and width
     13: convert into leather; "dress the tanned skins"
     14: apply a bandage or medication to; "dress the victim's
         wounds"
     15: give a neat appearance to; "groom the dogs"; "dress the
         horses" [syn: {groom}, {curry}]
     16: arrange attractively; "dress my hair for the wedding" [syn:
         {arrange}, {set}, {do}, {coif}, {coiffe}, {coiffure}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
