<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>drift</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Adit \Ad"it\, n. [L. aditus, fr. adire, ?aitum, to go to; ad +
   ire to go.]
   1. An entrance or passage. Specifically: The nearly
      horizontal opening by which a mine is entered, or by which
      water and ores are carried away; -- called also {drift}
      and {tunnel}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Admission; approach; access. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Yourself and yours shall have
            Free adit.                            --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drift \Drift\, n. [From {drive}; akin to LG. &amp; D. drift a
   driving, Icel. drift snowdrift, Dan. drift, impulse, drove,
   herd, pasture, common, G. trift pasturage, drove. See
   {Drive}.]
   1. A driving; a violent movement.
      [1913 Webster]

            The dragon drew him [self] away with drift of his
            wings.                                --King
                                                  Alisaunder
                                                  (1332).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act or motion of drifting; the force which impels or
      drives; an overpowering influence or impulse.
      [1913 Webster]

            A bad man, being under the drift of any passion,
            will follow the impulse of it till something
            interpose.                            --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Course or direction along which anything is driven;
      setting. ``Our drift was south.'' --Hakluyt.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The tendency of an act, argument, course of conduct, or
      the like; object aimed at or intended; intention; hence,
      also, import or meaning of a sentence or discourse; aim.
      [1913 Webster]

            He has made the drift of the whole poem a compliment
            on his country in general.            -- Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now thou knowest my drift.            --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is driven, forced, or urged along; as:
      (a) Anything driven at random. ``Some log . . . a useless
          drift.'' --Dryden.
      (b) A mass of matter which has been driven or forced
          onward together in a body, or thrown together in a
          heap, etc., esp. by wind or water; as, a drift of
          snow, of ice, of sand, and the like.
          [1913 Webster]

                Drifts of rising dust involve the sky. -- Pope.
          [1913 Webster]

                We got the brig a good bed in the rushing drift
                [of ice].                         --Kane.
      (c) A drove or flock, as of cattle, sheep, birds. [Obs.]
          [1913 Webster]

                Cattle coming over the bridge (with their great
                drift doing much damage to the high ways). --
                                                  Fuller.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Arch.) The horizontal thrust or pressure of an arch or
      vault upon the abutments. [R.] --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Geol.) A collection of loose earth and rocks, or
      boulders, which have been distributed over large portions
      of the earth's surface, especially in latitudes north of
      forty degrees, by the agency of ice.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. In South Africa, a ford in a river.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mech.) A slightly tapered tool of steel for enlarging or
      shaping a hole in metal, by being forced or driven into or
      through it; a broach.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mil.)
       (a) A tool used in driving down compactly the composition
           contained in a rocket, or like firework.
       (b) A deviation from the line of fire, peculiar to oblong
           projectiles.
           [1913 Webster]

   11. (Mining) A passage driven or cut between shaft and shaft;
       a driftway; a small subterranean gallery; an adit or
       tunnel.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Naut.)
       (a) The distance through which a current flows in a given
           time.
       (b) The angle which the line of a ship's motion makes
           with the meridian, in drifting.
       (c) The distance to which a vessel is carried off from
           her desired course by the wind, currents, or other
           causes.
       (d) The place in a deep-waisted vessel where the sheer is
           raised and the rail is cut off, and usually
           terminated with a scroll, or driftpiece.
       (e) The distance between the two blocks of a tackle.
           [1913 Webster]

   13. The difference between the size of a bolt and the hole
       into which it is driven, or between the circumference of
       a hoop and that of the mast on which it is to be driven.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Phys. Geog.) One of the slower movements of oceanic
       circulation; a general tendency of the water, subject to
       occasional or frequent diversion or reversal by the wind;
       as, the easterly drift of the North Pacific.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   15. (A["e]ronautics) The horizontal component of the pressure
       of the air on the sustaining surfaces of a flying
       machine. The lift is the corresponding vertical
       component, which sustains the machine in the air.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: Drift is used also either adjectively or as the first
         part of a compound. See {Drift}, a.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Drift of the forest} (O. Eng. Law), an examination or view
      of the cattle in a forest, in order to see whose they are,
      whether they are commonable, and to determine whether or
      not the forest is surcharged. --Burrill. [1913 Webster]

   {continental drift} (Geology), the very slow (ca. 1-5 cm per
      year) movement of the continents and parts of continents
      relative to each other and to the points of upwelling of
      magma in the viscous layers beneath the continents; --
      causing, for example, the opening of the South Atlantic
      Ocean by the movement of Africa and South America away
      from each other. See also {plate tectonics}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drift \Drift\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Drifted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Drifting}.]
   1. To float or be driven along by, or as by, a current of
      water or air; as, the ship drifted astern; a raft drifted
      ashore; the balloon drifts slowly east.
      [1913 Webster]

            We drifted o'er the harbor bar.       -- Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To accumulate in heaps by the force of wind; to be driven
      into heaps; as, snow or sand drifts.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (mining) to make a drift; to examine a vein or ledge for
      the purpose of ascertaining the presence of metals or
      ores; to follow a vein; to prospect. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drift \Drift\, v. t.
   1. To drive or carry, as currents do a floating body. --J. H.
      Newman.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To drive into heaps; as, a current of wind drifts snow or
      sand.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.) To enlarge or shape, as a hole, with a drift.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drift \Drift\, a.
   That causes drifting or that is drifted; movable by wind or
   currents; as, drift currents; drift ice; drift mud. --Kane.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Drift anchor}. See {Sea anchor}, and also {Drag sail}, under
      {Drag}, n.

   {Drift epoch} (Geol.), the glacial epoch.

   {Drift net}, a kind of fishing net.

   {Drift sail}. Same as {Drag sail}. See under {Drag}, n.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>drift
     n 1: a force that moves something along [syn: {impetus}, {impulsion}]
     2: the gradual departure from an intended course due to
        external influences (as a ship or plane)
     3: a process of linguistic change over a period of time
     4: something that is heaped up by the wind or by water currents
     5: a general tendency to change (as of opinion); "not openly
        liberal but that is the trend of the book"; "a broad
        movement of the electorate to the right" [syn: {trend}, {movement}]
     6: general meaning or tenor; "caught the drift of the
        conversation" [syn: {purport}]
     7: a horizontal (or nearly horizontal) passageway in a mine;
        "they dug a drift parallel with the vein" [syn: {heading},
         {gallery}]
     v 1: be in motion due to some air or water current; "The leaves
          were blowing in the wind"; "the boat drifted on the
          lake"; "The sailboat was adrift on the open sea"; "the
          shipwrecked boat drifted away from the shore" [syn: {float},
           {be adrift}, {blow}]
     2: wander from a direct course or at random; "The child strayed
        from the path and her parents lost sight of her"; "don't
        drift from the set course" [syn: {stray}, {err}]
     3: move about aimlessly or without any destination, often in
        search of food or employment; "The gypsies roamed the
        woods"; "roving vagabonds"; "the wandering Jew"; "The
        cattle roam across the prairie"; "the laborers drift from
        one town to the next"; "They rolled from town to town"
        [syn: {roll}, {wander}, {swan}, {stray}, {tramp}, {roam},
        {cast}, {ramble}, {rove}, {range}, {vagabond}]
     4: vary or move from a fixed point or course; "stock prices are
        drifting higher"
     5: live unhurriedly, irresponsibly, or freely; "My son drifted
        around for years in California before going to law school"
        [syn: {freewheel}]
     6: move in an unhurried fashion; "The unknown young man drifted
        among the invited guests"
     7: cause to be carried by a current; "drift the boats
        downstream"
     8: drive slowly and far afield for grazing; "drift the cattle
        herds westwards"
     9: be subject to fluctuation; "The stock market drifted upward"
     10: be piled up in banks or heaps by the force of wind or a
         current; "snow drifting several feet high"; "sand
         drifting like snow"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
