<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>drinking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drinking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drink \Drink\ (dr[i^][ng]k), v. i. [imp. {Drank} (dr[a^][ng]k),
   formerly {Drunk} (dr[u^][ng]k); &amp; p. p. {Drunk}, {Drunken}
   (-'n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Drinking}. Drunken is now rarely
   used, except as a verbal adj. in sense of habitually
   intoxicated; the form drank, not infrequently used as a p.
   p., is not so analogical.] [AS. drincan; akin to OS. drinkan,
   D. drinken, G. trinken, Icel. drekka, Sw. dricka, Dan.
   drikke, Goth. drigkan. Cf. {Drench}, {Drunken}, {Drown}.]
   1. To swallow anything liquid, for quenching thirst or other
      purpose; to imbibe; to receive or partake of, as if in
      satisfaction of thirst; as, to drink from a spring.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gird thyself, and serve me, till have eaten and
            drunken; and afterward thou shalt eat and drink.
                                                  --Luke xvii.
                                                  8.
      [1913 Webster]

            He shall drink of the wrath the Almighty. --Job xxi.
                                                  20.
      [1913 Webster]

            Drink of the cup that can not cloy.   --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To quaff exhilarating or intoxicating liquors, in
      merriment or feasting; to carouse; to revel; hence, to
      lake alcoholic liquors to excess; to be intemperate in the
      ?se of intoxicating or spirituous liquors; to tipple.
      --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            And they drank, and were merry with him. --Gem.
                                                  xliii. 34.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bolingbroke always spoke freely when he had drunk
            freely.                               --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To drink to}, to salute in drinking; to wish well to, in the
      act of taking the cup; to pledge in drinking.
      [1913 Webster]

            I drink to the general joy of the whole table,
            And to our dear friend Banquo.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drinking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drinking \Drink"ing\, n.
   1. The act of one who drinks; the act of imbibing.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The practice of partaking to excess of intoxicating
      liquors.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An entertainment with liquors; a carousal.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Drinking is used adjectively, or as the first part of a
         compound; as, a drinking song, drinking cup, drinking
         glass, drinking house, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Drinking horn}, a drinking vessel made of a horn.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drinking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>drinking
     n 1: the act of consuming liquids [syn: {imbibing}, {imbibition}]
     2: the act of drinking alcoholic beverages to excess; "drink
        was his downfall" [syn: {drink}, {boozing}, {drunkenness},
         {crapulence}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
