<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>driver</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>driver</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>driver
     
        1. &lt;operating system&gt; {device driver}.
     
        2. &lt;programming&gt; The {main loop} of an event-processing
        program; the code that gets commands and dispatches them for
        execution.
     
        3. &lt;tool&gt; In the {TeX} world and the computerised typesetting
        world in general, a program that translates some
        device-independent or other common format to something a real
        device can actually understand.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>driver</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Driver, AR
  Zip code(s): 72329
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>driver</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Spanker \Spank"er\ (sp[a^][ng]k"[~e]r), n.
   1. One who spanks, or anything used as an instrument for
      spanking.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) The after sail of a ship or bark, being a
      fore-and-aft sail attached to a boom and gaff; --
      sometimes called {driver}. See Illust. under {Sail}.
      --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who takes long, quick strides in walking; also, a fast
      horse. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Something very large, or larger than common; a whopper, as
      a stout or tall person. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Spanker boom} (Naut.), a boom to which a spanker sail is
      attached. See Illust. of {Ship}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>driver</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Driver \Driv"er\, n. [From {Drive}.]
   1. One who, or that which, drives; the person or thing that
      urges or compels anything else to move onward.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The person who drives beasts or a carriage; a coachman; a
      charioteer, etc.; hence, also, one who controls the
      movements of a any vehicle.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. An overseer of a gang of slaves or gang of convicts at
      their work.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mach.) A part that transmits motion to another part by
      contact with it, or through an intermediate relatively
      movable part, as a gear which drives another, or a lever
      which moves another through a link, etc. Specifically:
      (a) The driving wheel of a locomotive.
      (b) An attachment to a lathe, spindle, or face plate to
          turn a carrier.
      (c) A crossbar on a grinding mill spindle to drive the
          upper stone.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) The after sail in a ship or bark, being a
      fore-and-aft sail attached to a gaff; a spanker. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An implement used for driving; as:
      (a) A mallet.
      (b) A tamping iron.
      (c) A cooper's hammer for driving on barrel hoops.
      (d) A wooden-headed golf club with a long shaft, for
          playing the longest strokes.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Driver ant} (Zo["o]l.), a species of African stinging ant;
      one of the visiting ants ({Anomma arcens}); -- so called
      because they move about in vast armies, and drive away or
      devour all insects and other small animals.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>driver</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>driver n. 1. The {main loop} of an event-processing program; the code
   that gets commands and dispatches them for execution. 2. [techspeak] In
   `device driver', code designed to handle a particular peripheral device
   such as a magnetic disk or tape unit. 3. In the TeX world and the
   computerized typesetting world in general, a program that translates
   some device-independent or other common format to something a real
   device can actually understand.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>driver</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>driver
     n 1: the operator of a motor vehicle [ant: {nondriver}]
     2: someone who drives animals that pull a vehicle
     3: a golfer who hits the golf ball with a driver
     4: (computer science) a program that determines how a computer
        will communicate with a peripheral device [syn: {device
        driver}]
     5: a golf club (a wood) with a near vertical face that is used
        for hitting long shots from the tee [syn: {number one wood}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
