<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>droid</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>droid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>droid
     
        &lt;robotics&gt; (From "android") The robots of the Star Wars
        universe.  While androids look somewhat human-like, Star Wars'
        droids are typically fashioned in the likeness of their
        creators or in a utilitarian design that stresses function
        over appearance.  Droids are equipped with artificial
        intelligence, though some are naturally created smarter than
        others depending on the function they are designed to serve.
     
        "Droid" is a Lucasfilm Ltd. trademark.
     
        {starwars.com (http://www.starwars.com/databank/droid/)}.
     
        ["A Guide to the Star Wars Universe", Bill Slavicsek, 1994,
        Lucasfilm Ltd.]
     
        [Was George Lucas really the first to use the abbreviation?]
     
        (2003-05-11)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>droid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>droid n. [from `android', SF terminology for a humanoid robot of
   essentially biological (as opposed to mechanical/electronic)
   construction] A person (esp. a low-level bureaucrat or service-business
   employee) exhibiting most of the following characteristics: (a) naive
   trust in the wisdom of the parent organization or `the system'; (b) a
   blind-faith propensity to believe obvious nonsense emitted by authority
   figures (or computers!); (c) a rule-governed mentality, one unwilling or
   unable to look beyond the `letter of the law' in exceptional situations;
   (d) a paralyzing fear of official reprimand or worse if Procedures are
   not followed No Matter What; and (e) no interest in doing anything above
   or beyond the call of a very narrowly-interpreted duty, or in particular
   in fixing that which is broken; an "It's not my job, man" attitude.

   Typical droid positions include supermarket checkout assistant and
   bank clerk; the syndrome is also endemic in low-level government
   employees. The implication is that the rules and official procedures
   constitute software that the droid is executing; problems arise when the
   software has not been properly debugged. The term `droid mentality' is
   also used to describe the mindset behind this behavior. Compare {suit},
   {marketroid}; see {-oid}.

   In England there is equivalent mainstream slang; a `jobsworth' is an
   obstructive, rule-following bureaucrat, often of the uniformed or suited
   variety. Named for the habit of denying a reasonable request by sucking
   his teeth and saying "Oh no, guv, sorry I can't help you: that's more
   than my job's worth".


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
