<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>drop</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gutta \Gut"ta\, n.; pl. {Gutt[AE]}. [L.]
   1. A drop.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.) One of a series of ornaments, in the form of a
      frustum of a cone, attached to the lower part of the
      triglyphs, and also to the lower faces of the mutules, in
      the Doric order; -- called also {campana}, and {drop}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Gutta serena} [L., lit. serene or clear drop] (Med.),
      amaurosis.

   {Gutt[ae] band} (Arch.), the listel or band from which the
      gutt[ae] hang.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drop \Drop\ (dr[o^]p), n. [OE. drope, AS. dropa; akin to OS.
   dropo, D. drop, OHG. tropo, G. tropfen, Icel. dropi, Sw.
   droppe; and Fr. AS. dre['o]pan to drip, drop; akin to OS.
   driopan, D. druipen, OHG. triofan, G. triefen, Icel.
   drj[=u]pa. Cf. {Drip}, {Droop}.]
   1. The quantity of fluid which falls in one small spherical
      mass; a liquid globule; a minim; hence, also, the smallest
      easily measured portion of a fluid; a small quantity; as,
      a drop of water.
      [1913 Webster]

            With minute drops from off the eaves. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            As dear to me as are the ruddy drops
            That visit my sad heart.              -- Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            That drop of peace divine.            --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which resembles, or that which hangs like, a liquid
      drop; as a hanging diamond ornament, an earring, a glass
      pendant on a chandelier, a sugarplum (sometimes
      medicated), or a kind of shot or slug.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.)
      (a) Same as {Gutta}.
      (b) Any small pendent ornament.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. Whatever is arranged to drop, hang, or fall from an
      elevated position; also, a contrivance for lowering
      something; as:
      (a) A door or platform opening downward; a trap door; that
          part of the gallows on which a culprit stands when he
          is to be hanged; hence, the gallows itself.
      (b) A machine for lowering heavy weights, as packages,
          coal wagons, etc., to a ship's deck.
      (c) A contrivance for temporarily lowering a gas jet.
      (d) A curtain which drops or falls in front of the stage
          of a theater, etc.
      (e) A drop press or drop hammer.
      (f) (Mach.) The distance of the axis of a shaft below the
          base of a hanger.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. Any medicine the dose of which is measured by drops;
      as, lavender drops.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) The depth of a square sail; -- generally applied
      to the courses only. --Ham. Nav. Encyc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Act of dropping; sudden fall or descent.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ague drop}, {Black drop}. See under {Ague}, {Black}.

   {Drop by drop}, in small successive quantities; in repeated
      portions. ``Made to taste drop by drop more than the
      bitterness of death.'' --Burke.

   {Drop curtain}. See {Drop}, n., 4.
      (d) .

   {Drop forging}. (Mech.)
      (a) A forging made in dies by a drop hammer.
      (b) The process of making drop forgings.

   {Drop hammer} (Mech.), a hammer for forging, striking up
      metal, etc., the weight being raised by a strap or similar
      device, and then released to drop on the metal resting on
      an anvil or die.

   {Drop kick} (Football), a kick given to the ball as it
      rebounds after having been dropped from the hands.

   {Drop lake}, a pigment obtained from Brazil wood. --Mollett.

   {Drop letter}, a letter to be delivered from the same office
      where posted.

   {Drop press} (Mech.), a drop hammer; sometimes, a dead-stroke
      hammer; -- also called drop.

   {Drop scene}, a drop curtain on which a scene is painted. See
      {Drop}, n., 4.
      (d) .

   {Drop seed}. (Bot.) See the List under {Glass}.

   {Drop serene}. (Med.) See {Amaurosis}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drop \Drop\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dropped}or {Dropt}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Dropping}.] [OE. droppen, AS. dropan, v. i. See
   {Drop}, n.]
   1. To pour or let fall in drops; to pour in small globules;
      to distill. ``The trees drop balsam.'' --Creech.
      [1913 Webster]

            The recording angel, as he wrote it down, dropped a
            tear upon the word and blotted it out forever.
                                                  --Sterne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to fall in one portion, or by one motion, like a
      drop; to let fall; as, to drop a line in fishing; to drop
      a courtesy.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To let go; to dismiss; to set aside; to have done with; to
      discontinue; to forsake; to give up; to omit.
      [1913 Webster]

            They suddenly drop't the pursuit.     --S. Sharp.
      [1913 Webster]

            That astonishing ease with which fine ladies drop
            you and pick you up again.            --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

            The connection had been dropped many years. -- Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Dropping the too rough H in Hell and Heaven.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To bestow or communicate by a suggestion; to let fall in
      an indirect, cautious, or gentle manner; as, to drop hint,
      a word of counsel, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To lower, as a curtain, or the muzzle of a gun, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To send, as a letter; as, please drop me a line, a letter,
      word.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To give birth to; as, to drop a lamb.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To cover with drops; to variegate; to bedrop.
      [1913 Webster]

            Show to the sun their waved coats dropped with gold.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To drop a vessel} (Naut.), to leave it astern in a race or a
      chase; to outsail it.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Drop \Drop\, v. i.
   1. To fall in drops.
      [1913 Webster]

            The kindly dew drops from the higher tree,
            And wets the little plants that lowly dwell.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fall, in general, literally or figuratively; as, ripe
      fruit drops from a tree; wise words drop from the lips.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mutilations of which the meaning has dropped out of
            memory.                               --H. Spencer.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the sound of dropping nuts is heard. --Bryant.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To let drops fall; to discharge itself in drops.
      [1913 Webster]

            The heavens . . . dropped at the presence of God.
                                                  --Ps. lxviii.
                                                  8.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To fall dead, or to fall in death; as, dropping like
      flies.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing, says Seneca, so soon reconciles us to the
            thoughts of our own death, as the prospect of one
            friend after another dropping round us. --Digby.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To come to an end; to cease; to pass out of mind; as, the
      affair dropped. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To come unexpectedly; -- with in or into; as, my old
      friend dropped in a moment. --Steele.
      [1913 Webster]

            Takes care to drop in when he thinks you are just
            seated.                               --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To fall or be depressed; to lower; as, the point of the
      spear dropped a little.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To fall short of a mark. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Often it drops or overshoots by the disproportion of
            distance.                             --Collier.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To be deep in extent; to descend perpendicularly; as, her
      main topsail drops seventeen yards.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To drop astern} (Naut.), to go astern of another vessel; to
      be left behind; to slacken the speed of a vessel so as to
      fall behind and to let another pass a head.

   {To drop down} (Naut.), to sail, row, or move down a river,
      or toward the sea.

   {To drop off}, to fall asleep gently; also, to die. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>drop</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>drop
     n 1: a small quantity (especially of a liquid); "one drop of each
          sample was analyzed"; "any child with a drop of negro
          blood was legally a negro"; "there is not a drop of pity
          in that man" [syn: {driblet}]
     2: a shape that is small and round; "he studied the shapes of
        low-viscosity drops"; "beads of sweat on his forehead"
        [syn: {bead}, {pearl}]
     3: a sudden sharp decrease in some quantity; "a drop of 57
        points on the Dow Jones index"; "there was a drop in
        pressure in the pulmonary artery"; "a dip in prices";
        "when that became known the price of their stock went into
        free fall" [syn: {dip}, {fall}, {free fall}]
     4: a steep high face of rock; "he stood on a high cliff
        overlooking the town"; "a steep drop" [syn: {cliff}, {drop-off}]
     5: a predetermined hiding place for the deposit and
        distribution of illicit goods (such as drugs or stolen
        property)
     6: a free and rapid descent by the force of gravity; "it was a
        miracle that he survived the drop from that height" [syn:
        {fall}]
     7: a curtain that can be lowered and raised onto a stage from
        the flies; often used as background scenery [syn: {drop
        curtain}, {drop cloth}]
     8: a central depository where things can be left or picked up
     9: the act of dropping something; "they expected the drop would
        be successful"
     v 1: let fall to the ground; "Don't drop the dishes"
     2: to fall vertically; "the bombs are dropping on enemy
        targets"
     3: go down in value; "Stock prices dropped"
     4: fall or drop to a lower place or level; "He sank to his
        knees" [syn: {sink}, {drop down}]
     5: terminate an association with; "drop him from the Republican
        ticket"
     6: utter casually; "drop a hint"
     7: stop pursuing or acting; "drop a lawsuit"; "knock it off!"
        [syn: {knock off}]
     8: leave or unload, especially of passengers or cargo; [syn: {set
        down}, {put down}, {unload}, {discharge}]
     9: cause to fall by or as if by delivering a blow; "strike down
        a tree"; "Lightning struck down the hikers" [syn: {fell},
        {strike down}, {cut down}]
     10: lose (a game); "The Giants dropped 11 of their first 13"
     11: pay out; "spend money" [syn: {spend}, {expend}]
     12: lower the pitch of (musical notes) [syn: {flatten}] [ant: {sharpen}]
     13: hang freely; "the ornaments dangled from the tree"; "The
         light dropped from the ceiling" [syn: {dangle}, {swing}]
     14: stop associating with; "They dropped her after she had a
         child out of wedlock" [syn: {dismiss}, {send packing}, {send
         away}]
     15: let or cause to fall in drops; "dribble oil into the
         mixture" [syn: {dribble}, {drip}]
     16: get rid of; "he shed his image as a pushy boss"; "shed your
         clothes" [syn: {shed}, {cast}, {cast off}, {shake off}, {throw},
          {throw off}, {throw away}]
     17: leave undone or leave out; "How could I miss that typo?";
         "The workers on the conveyor belt miss one out of ten"
         [syn: {neglect}, {pretermit}, {omit}, {miss}, {leave out},
          {overlook}, {overleap}] [ant: {attend to}]
     18: change from one level to another; "She dropped into army
         jargon"
     19: grow worse; "Her condition deteriorated"; "Conditions in the
         slums degenerated"; "The discussion devolved into a
         shouting match" [syn: {devolve}, {deteriorate}, {degenerate}]
         [ant: {recuperate}]
     20: give birth; used for animals; "The cow dropped her calf this
         morning"
     [also: {dropping}, {dropped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
