<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dry</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wine \Wine\, n. [OE. win, AS. win, fr. L. vinum (cf. Icel.
   v[=i]n; all from the Latin); akin to Gr. o'i^nos, ?, and E.
   withy. Cf. {Vine}, {Vineyard}, {Vinous}, {Withy}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The expressed juice of grapes, esp. when fermented; a
      beverage or liquor prepared from grapes by squeezing out
      their juice, and (usually) allowing it to ferment. ``Red
      wine of Gascoigne.'' --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wine is a mocker, strong drink is raging, and
            whosoever is deceived thereby is not wise. --Prov.
                                                  xx. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bacchus, that first from out the purple grape
            Crushed the sweet poison of misused wine. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Wine is essentially a dilute solution of ethyl alcohol,
         containing also certain small quantities of ethers and
         ethereal salts which give character and bouquet.
         According to their color, strength, taste, etc., wines
         are called {red}, {white}, {spirituous}, {dry},
         {light}, {still}, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A liquor or beverage prepared from the juice of any fruit
      or plant by a process similar to that for grape wine; as,
      currant wine; gooseberry wine; palm wine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The effect of drinking wine in excess; intoxication.
      [1913 Webster]

            Noah awoke from his wine.             --Gen. ix. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Birch wine}, {Cape wine}, etc. See under {Birch}, {Cape},
      etc.

   {Spirit of wine}. See under {Spirit}.

   {To have drunk wine of ape} or {To have drunk wine ape}, to
      be so drunk as to be foolish. [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {Wine acid}. (Chem.) See {Tartaric acid}, under {Tartaric}.
      [Colloq.]

   {Wine apple} (Bot.), a large red apple, with firm flesh and a
      rich, vinous flavor.

   {Wine fly} (Zo["o]l.), small two-winged fly of the genus
      {Piophila}, whose larva lives in wine, cider, and other
      fermented liquors.

   {Wine grower}, one who cultivates a vineyard and makes wine.
      

   {Wine measure}, the measure by which wines and other spirits
      are sold, smaller than beer measure.

   {Wine merchant}, a merchant who deals in wines.

   {Wine of opium} (Pharm.), a solution of opium in aromatized
      sherry wine, having the same strength as ordinary
      laudanum; -- also {Sydenham's laudanum}.

   {Wine press}, a machine or apparatus in which grapes are
      pressed to extract their juice.

   {Wine skin}, a bottle or bag of skin, used, in various
      countries, for carrying wine.

   {Wine stone}, a kind of crust deposited in wine casks. See
      1st {Tartar}, 1.

   {Wine vault}.
      (a) A vault where wine is stored.
      (b) A place where wine is served at the bar, or at tables;
          a dramshop. --Dickens.

   {Wine vinegar}, vinegar made from wine.

   {Wine whey}, whey made from milk coagulated by the use of
      wine.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dry \Dry\ (dr[imac]), a. [Compar. {Drier}; superl. {Driest}.]
   [OE. dru[yogh]e, druye, drie, AS. dryge; akin to LG.
   dr["o]ge, D. droog, OHG. trucchan, G. trocken, Icel. draugr a
   dry log. Cf. {Drought}, {Drouth}, 3d {Drug}.]
   1. Free from moisture; having little humidity or none; arid;
      not wet or moist; deficient in the natural or normal
      supply of moisture, as rain or fluid of any kind; -- said
      especially:
      (a) Of the weather: Free from rain or mist.
          [1913 Webster]

                The weather, we agreed, was too dry for the
                season.                           --Addison.
      (b) Of vegetable matter: Free from juices or sap; not
          succulent; not green; as, dry wood or hay.
      (c) Of animals: Not giving milk; as, the cow is dry.
      (d) Of persons: Thirsty; needing drink.
          [1913 Webster]

                Give the dry fool drink.          -- Shak
      (e) Of the eyes: Not shedding tears.
          [1913 Webster]

                Not a dry eye was to be seen in the assembly. --
                                                  Prescott.
      (f) (Med.) Of certain morbid conditions, in which there is
          entire or comparative absence of moisture; as, dry
          gangrene; dry catarrh.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Destitute of that which interests or amuses; barren;
      unembellished; jejune; plain.
      [1913 Webster]

            These epistles will become less dry, more
            susceptible of ornament.              --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Characterized by a quality somewhat severe, grave, or
      hard; hence, sharp; keen; shrewd; quaint; as, a dry tone
      or manner; dry wit.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was rather a dry, shrewd kind of body. --W.
                                                  Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Fine Arts) Exhibiting a sharp, frigid preciseness of
      execution, or the want of a delicate contour in form, and
      of easy transition in coloring.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Dry area} (Arch.), a small open space reserved outside the
      foundation of a building to guard it from damp.

   {Dry blow}.
      (a) (Med.) A blow which inflicts no wound, and causes no
          effusion of blood.
      (b) A quick, sharp blow.

   {Dry bone} (Min.), Smithsonite, or carbonate of zinc; -- a
      miner's term.

   {Dry castor} (Zo["o]l.) a kind of beaver; -- called also
      {parchment beaver}.

   {Dry cupping}. (Med.) See under {Cupping}.

   {Dry dock}. See under {Dock}.

   {Dry fat}. See {Dry vat} (below).

   {Dry light}, pure unobstructed light; hence, a clear,
      impartial view. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The scientific man must keep his feelings under
            stern control, lest they obtrude into his
            researches, and color the dry light in which alone
            science desires to see its objects.   -- J. C.
                                                  Shairp.

   {Dry masonry}. See {Masonry}.

   {Dry measure}, a system of measures of volume for dry or
      coarse articles, by the bushel, peck, etc.

   {Dry pile} (Physics), a form of the Voltaic pile, constructed
      without the use of a liquid, affording a feeble current,
      and chiefly useful in the construction of electroscopes of
      great delicacy; -- called also {Zamboni's}, from the names
      of the two earliest constructors of it.

   {Dry pipe} (Steam Engine), a pipe which conducts dry steam
      from a boiler.

   {Dry plate} (Photog.), a glass plate having a dry coating
      sensitive to light, upon which photographic negatives or
      pictures can be made, without moistening.

   {Dry-plate process}, the process of photographing with dry
      plates.

   {Dry point}. (Fine Arts)
      (a) An engraving made with the needle instead of the
          burin, in which the work is done nearly as in etching,
          but is finished without the use acid.
      (b) A print from such an engraving, usually upon paper.
      (c) Hence: The needle with which such an engraving is
          made.

   {Dry rent} (Eng. Law), a rent reserved by deed, without a
      clause of distress. --Bouvier.

   {Dry rot}, a decay of timber, reducing its fibers to the
      condition of a dry powdery dust, often accompanied by the
      presence of a peculiar fungus ({Merulius lacrymans}),
      which is sometimes considered the cause of the decay; but
      it is more probable that the real cause is the
      decomposition of the wood itself. --D. C. Eaton. Called
      also {sap rot}, and, in the United States, {powder post}.
      --Hebert.

   {Dry stove}, a hothouse adapted to preserving the plants of
      arid climates. --Brande &amp; C.

   {Dry vat}, a vat, basket, or other receptacle for dry
      articles.

   {Dry wine}, that in which the saccharine matter and
      fermentation were so exactly balanced, that they have
      wholly neutralized each other, and no sweetness is
      perceptible; -- opposed to {sweet wine}, in which the
      saccharine matter is in excess.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dry \Dry\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dried}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Drying}.] [AS. drygan; cf. drugian to grow dry. See {Dry},
   a.]
   To make dry; to free from water, or from moisture of any
   kind, and by any means; to exsiccate; as, to dry the eyes; to
   dry one's tears; the wind dries the earth; to dry a wet
   cloth; to dry hay.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To dry up}.
   (a) To scorch or parch with thirst; to deprive utterly of
       water; to consume.
       [1913 Webster]

             Their honorable men are famished, and their
             multitude dried up with thirst.      -- Is. v. 13.
       [1913 Webster]

             The water of the sea, which formerly covered it,
             was in time exhaled and dried up by the sun.
                                                  --Woodward.
   (b) To make to cease, as a stream of talk.
       [1913 Webster]

             Their sources of revenue were dried up. -- Jowett
                                                  (Thucyd. )
       

   {To dry a cow}, or {To dry up a cow}, to cause a cow to cease
      secreting milk. --Tylor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dry \Dry\, v. i.
   1. To grow dry; to become free from wetness, moisture, or
      juice; as, the road dries rapidly.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To evaporate wholly; to be exhaled; -- said of moisture,
      or a liquid; -- sometimes with up; as, the stream dries,
      or dries up.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To shrivel or wither; to lose vitality.
      [1913 Webster]

            And his hand, which he put forth against him, dried
            up, so that he could not pull it in again to him.
                                                  --I Kings
                                                  xiii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dry
     adj 1: free from liquid or moisture; lacking natural or normal
            moisture or depleted of water; or no longer wet; "dry
            land"; "dry clothes"; "a dry climate"; "dry splintery
            boards"; "a dry river bed"; "the paint is dry" [ant: {wet}]
     2: humorously sarcastic or mocking; "dry humor"; "an ironic
        remark often conveys an intended meaning obliquely"; "an
        ironic novel"; "an ironical smile"; "with a wry Scottish
        wit" [syn: {ironic}, {ironical}, {wry}]
     3: opposed to or prohibiting the production and sale of
        alcoholic beverages; "the dry vote led by preachers and
        bootleggers"; "a dry state" [ant: {wet}]
     4: not producing milk; "a dry cow" [ant: {wet}]
     5: (of wines) not sweet because of decomposition of sugar
        during fermentation; "a dry white burgundy" [ant: {sweet}]
     6: without a mucous or watery discharge; "a dry cough"; "that
        rare thing in the wintertime; a small child with a dry
        nose" [ant: {phlegmy}]
     7: not shedding tears; "dry sobs"; "with dry eyes"
     8: lacking interest or stimulation; dull and lifeless; "a dry
        book"; "a dry lecture filled with trivial details"; "dull
        and juiceless as only book knowledge can be when it is
        unrelated to...life"- John Mason Brown [syn: {juiceless}]
     9: used of solid substances in contrast with liquid ones; "dry
        weight"
     10: unproductive especially of the expected results; "a dry
         run"; "a mind dry of new ideas"
     11: having no adornment or coloration; "dry facts"; "rattled off
         the facts in a dry mechanical manner"
     12: (of food) eaten without a spread or sauce or other garnish;
         "dry toast"; "dry meat"
     13: suffering from fluid deprivation; "his mouth was dry"
     14: having a large proportion of strong liquor; "a very dry
         martini is almost straight gin"
     15: lacking warmth or emotional involvement; "a dry greeting";
         "a dry reading of the lines"; "a dry critique"
     16: practicing complete abstinence from alcoholic beverages;
         "he's been dry for ten years"; "no thank you; I happen to
         be teetotal" [syn: {teetotal}]
     n : a reformer who opposes the use of intoxicating beverages
         [syn: {prohibitionist}]
     v 1: remove the moisture from and make dry; "dry clothes"; "dry
          hair" [syn: {dry out}] [ant: {wet}]
     2: become dry or drier; "The laundry dries in the sun" [syn: {dry
        out}]
     [also: {dried}, {dryest}, {dryer}, {driest}, {drier}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
