<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>duel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>duel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DUEL, n.  A formal ceremony preliminary to the reconciliation of two
enemies.  Great skill is necessary to its satisfactory observance; if
awkwardly performed the most unexpected and deplorable consequences
sometimes ensue.  A long time ago a man lost his life in a duel.

    That dueling's a gentlemanly vice
        I hold; and wish that it had been my lot
        To live my life out in some favored spot --
    Some country where it is considered nice
    To split a rival like a fish, or slice
        A husband like a spud, or with a shot
        Bring down a debtor doubled in a knot
    And ready to be put upon the ice.
    Some miscreants there are, whom I do long
        To shoot, to stab, or some such way reclaim
    The scurvy rogues to better lives and manners,
    I seem to see them now -- a mighty throng.
        It looks as if to challenge _me_ they came,
    Jauntily marching with brass bands and banners!
                                                          Xamba Q. Dar


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>duel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>DUEL
     
        A front end to {gdb} by Michael Golan &lt;mg@cs.princeton.edu&gt;.
        DUEL implements a language designed for debugging {C}
        programs.  It mainly features efficient ways to select and
        display data items.  It is normally linked into the gdb
        executable, but could stand alone.  It interprets a subset of
        {C} in addition to its own language.
     
        Version 1.10.
     
        {(ftp://ftp.cs.princeton.edu/duel/)}.
     
        (1993-03-20)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>duel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Duel \Du"el\, v. i. &amp; t.
   To fight in single combat. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>duel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Duel \Du"el\, n. [It. duello, fr. L. duellum, orig., a contest
   between two, which passed into the common form bellum war,
   fr. duo two: cf. F. duel. See {Bellicose}, {Two}, and cf.
   {Duello}.]
   A combat between two persons, fought with deadly weapons, by
   agreement. It usually arises from an injury done or an
   affront given by one to the other.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Trial by duel} (Old Law), a combat between two persons for
      proving a cause; trial by battel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>duel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>duel
     n 1: a prearranged fight with deadly weapons by two people
          (accompanied by seconds) in order to settle a quarrel
          over a point of honor [syn: {affaire d'honneur}]
     2: any struggle between two skillful opponents (individuals or
        groups)
     v : fight a duel, as over one's honor or a woman; "In the 19th
         century, men often dueled over small matters"
     [also: {duelling}, {duelled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
