<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dumpling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dumpling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Crust \Crust\ (kr?st), n. [L. crusta: cf. OF. crouste, F.
   cro[^u]te; prob. akin to Gr. ????? ice, E. crystal, from the
   same root as E. crude, raw. See {Raw}, and cf. {Custard}.]
   1. The hard external coat or covering of anything; the hard
      exterior surface or outer shell; an incrustation; as, a
      crust of snow.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have known the statute of an emperor quite hid
            under a crust of dross.               --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Below this icy crust of conformity, the waters of
            infidelity lay dark and deep as ever. --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Cookery)
      (a) The hard exterior or surface of bread, in distinction
          from the soft part or crumb; or a piece of bread grown
          dry or hard.
      (b) The cover or case of a pie, in distinction from the
          soft contents.
      (c) The dough, or mass of doughy paste, cooked with a
          potpie; -- also called {dumpling}.
          [1913 Webster]

                Th' impenetrable crust thy teeth defies.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

                He that keeps nor crust nor crumb. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                They . . . made the crust for the venison pasty.
                                                  --Macaulay.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Geol.) The exterior portion of the earth, formerly
      universally supposed to inclose a molten interior.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) The shell of crabs, lobsters, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Med.) A hard mass, made up of dried secretions blood, or
      pus, occurring upon the surface of the body.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An incrustation on the interior of wine bottles, the
      result of the ripening of the wine; a deposit of tartar,
      etc. See {Beeswing}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dumpling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dumpling \Dump"ling\, n. [Dimin. of dump an illshapen piece; cf.
   D. dompelen to plunge, dip, duck, Scot. to dump in to plunge
   into, and E. dump, v. t.]
   A roundish mass of dough boiled in soup, or as a sort of
   pudding; often, a cover of paste inclosing an apple or other
   fruit, and boiled or baked; as, an apple dumpling.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dumpling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dumpling
     n 1: small balls or strips of boiled or steamed dough [syn: {dumplings}]
     2: dessert made by baking fruit wrapped in pastry
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
