<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>dust</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dust
   Storms of sand and dust sometimes overtake Eastern travellers.
   They are very dreadful, many perishing under them. Jehovah
   threatens to bring on the land of Israel, as a punishment for
   forsaking him, a rain of "powder and dust" (Deut. 28:24).
   
     To cast dust on the head was a sign of mourning (Josh. 7:6);
   and to sit in dust, of extreme affliction (Isa. 47:1). "Dust" is
   used to denote the grave (Job 7:21). "To shake off the dust from
   one's feet" against another is to renounce all future
   intercourse with him (Matt. 10:14; Acts 13:51). To "lick the
   dust" is a sign of abject submission (Ps. 72:9); and to throw
   dust at one is a sign of abhorrence (2 Sam. 16:13; comp. Acts
   22:23).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dust \Dust\ (d[u^]st), n. [AS. dust; cf. LG. dust, D. duist meal
   dust, OD. doest, donst, and G. dunst vapor, OHG. tunist,
   dunist, a blowing, wind, Icel. dust dust, Dan. dyst mill
   dust; perh. akin to L. fumus smoke, E. fume. [root]71.]
   1. Fine, dry particles of earth or other matter, so
      comminuted that they may be raised and wafted by the wind;
      that which is crumbled to minute portions; fine powder;
      as, clouds of dust; bone dust.
      [1913 Webster]

            Dust thou art, and unto dust shalt thou return.
                                                  --Gen. iii.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

            Stop! -- for thy tread is on an empire's dust.
                                                  --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A single particle of earth or other matter. [R.] ``To
      touch a dust of England's ground.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The earth, as the resting place of the dead.
      [1913 Webster]

            For now shall sleep in the dust.      --Job vii. 21.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The earthy remains of bodies once alive; the remains of
      the human body.
      [1913 Webster]

            And you may carve a shrine about my dust.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Figuratively, a worthless thing.
      [1913 Webster]

            And by the merit of vile gold, dross, dust. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Figuratively, a low or mean condition.
      [1913 Webster]

            [God] raiseth up the poor out of the dust. --1 Sam.
                                                  ii. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Gold dust; hence: (Slang) Coined money; cash.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Down with the dust}, deposit the cash; pay down the money.
      [Slang] ``My lord, quoth the king, presently deposit your
      hundred pounds in gold, or else no going hence all the
      days of your life. . . . The Abbot down with his dust, and
      glad he escaped so, returned to Reading.'' --Fuller.

   {Dust brand} (Bot.), a fungous plant ({Ustilago Carbo}); --
      called also {smut}.

   {Gold dust}, fine particles of gold, such as are obtained in
      placer mining; -- often used as money, being transferred
      by weight.

   {In dust and ashes}. See under {Ashes}.

   {To bite the dust}. See under {Bite}, v. t.

   {To raise dust}, or

   {To kick up dust}, to make a commotion. [Colloq.]

   {To throw dust in one's eyes}, to mislead; to deceive.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dust \Dust\ (d[u^]st), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Dusted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Dusting}.]
   1. To free from dust; to brush, wipe, or sweep away dust
      from; as, to dust a table or a floor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To sprinkle with dust.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To reduce to a fine powder; to levigate. --Sprat.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To dyst one's jacket}, to give one a flogging. [Slang.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>dust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>dust
     n 1: fine powdery material such as dry earth or pollen that can
          be blown about in the air; "the furniture was covered
          with dust"
     2: the remains of something that has been destroyed or broken
        up [syn: {debris}, {junk}, {rubble}, {detritus}]
     3: free microscopic particles of solid material; "astronomers
        say that the empty space between planets actually contains
        measurable amounts of dust"
     v 1: remove the dust from; "dust the cabinets"
     2: rub the dust over a surface so as to blur the outlines of a
        shape; "The artist dusted the charcoal drawing down to a
        faint image"
     3: cover with a light dusting of a substance; "dust the bread
        with flour"
     4: distribute loosely; "He scattered gun powder under the
        wagon" [syn: {scatter}, {sprinkle}, {dot}, {disperse}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
