<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>l</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>l</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>L \L\ ([e^]l) n.
   1. L is the twelfth letter of the English alphabet, and a
      vocal consonant. It is usually called a semivowel or
      liquid. Its form and value are from the Greek, through the
      Latin, the form of the Greek letter being from the
      Ph[oe]nician, and the ultimate origin prob. Egyptian.
      Etymologically, it is most closely related to r and u; as
      in pilgrim, peregrine, couch (fr. collocare), aubura (fr.
      LL. alburnus).
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: At the end of monosyllables containing a single vowel,
         it is often doubled, as in fall, full, bell; but not
         after digraphs, as in foul, fool, prowl, growl, foal.
         In English words, the terminating syllable le is
         unaccented, the e is silent, and l is preceded by a
         voice glide, as in able, eagle, pronounced [=a]"b'l,
         [=e]"g'l. See Guide to Pronunciation, [sect]241.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. As a numeral, L stands for fifty in the English, as in the
      Latin language.
      [1913 Webster]

            For 50 the Romans used the Chalcidian chi, ?, which
            assumed the less difficult lapidary type, ?, and was
            then easily assimilated to L.         --I. Taylor
                                                  (The
                                                  Alphabet).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>l</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>L \L\, a.
   1. Having the general shape of the (capital) letter L; as, an
      L beam, or L-beam.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. Elevated; -- a symbol for {el.} as an abbreviation of
      elevated in elevated road or railroad. -- n. An elevated
      road; as, to ride on the L. [Colloq., U. S.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>l</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>L \L\ ([e^]l), n.
   1. An extension at right angles to the length of a main
      building, giving to the ground plan a form resembling the
      letter L; sometimes less properly applied to a narrower,
      or lower, extension in the direction of the length of the
      main building; a wing. [Written also {ell}.]
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mech.) A short right-angled pipe fitting, used in
      connecting two pipes at right angles. [Written also
      {ell}.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>l</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>l
     adj : being ten more than forty [syn: {fifty}, {50}]
     n 1: a metric unit of capacity equal to the volume of 1 kilogram
          of pure water at 4 degrees centigrade and 760 mm of
          mercury (or approximately 1.76 pints) [syn: {liter}, {litre},
           {cubic decimeter}, {cubic decimetre}]
     2: the cardinal number that is the product of ten and five
        [syn: {fifty}, {50}]
     3: a cgs unit of illumination equal to the brightness of a
        perfectly diffusing surface that emits or reflects one
        lumen per square centimeter [syn: {lambert}]
     4: the 12th letter of the Roman alphabet
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
