<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>label</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>label</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Label \La"bel\ (l[=a]"b[e^]l), n. [OF. label sort of ribbon or
   fringe, label in heraldry, F. lambeau shred, strip, rag; of
   uncertain origin; cf. L. labellum, dim. of labrum lip, edge,
   margin, G. lappen flap, patch, rag, tatter (cf. {Lap} of a
   dress), W. llab, llabed, label, flap, Gael. leab, leob,
   slice, shred, hanging lip.]
   1. A tassel. [Obs.] --Huloet. --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A slip of silk, paper, parchment, etc., affixed to
      anything, and indicating, usually by an inscription, the
      contents, ownership, destination, etc.; as, the label of a
      bottle or a package.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A slip of ribbon, parchment, etc., attached to a document
      to hold the appended seal; also, the seal.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A writing annexed by way of addition, as a codicil added
      to a will.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Her.) A barrulet, or, rarely, a bendlet, with pendants,
      or points, usually three, especially used as a mark of
      cadency to distinguish an eldest or only son while his
      father is still living.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A brass rule with sights, formerly used, in connection
      with a circumferentor, to take altitudes. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Gothic Arch.) The name now generally given to the
      projecting molding by the sides, and over the tops, of
      openings in medi[ae]val architecture. It always has a
      square form, as in the illustration. --Arch. Pub. Soc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. In medi[ae]val art, the representation of a band or scroll
      containing an inscription. --Fairholt.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>label</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Label \La"bel\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Labeled} (l[=a]"b[e^]ld) or
   {Labelled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Labeling} or {Labelling}.]
   1. To affix a label to; to mark with a name, etc.; as, to
      label a bottle or a package.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To affix in or on a label. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>label</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>label
     n 1: a brief description given for purposes of identification;
          "the label Modern is applied to many different kinds of
          architecture"
     2: trade name of a company that produces musical recordings;
        "the artists and repertoire department of a recording
        label is responsible for finding new talent" [syn: {recording
        label}]
     3: a radioactive isotope that is used in a compound in order to
        trace the mechanism of a chemical reaction
     4: an identifying or descriptive marker that is attached to an
        object
     v 1: assign a label to; designate with a label; "These students
          were labelled `learning disabled'"
     2: attach a tag or label to; "label these bottles" [syn: {tag},
         {mark}]
     3: pronounce judgment on; "They labeled him unfit to work here"
        [syn: {pronounce}, {judge}]
     4: distinguish (as a compound or molecule) by introducing a
        labeled atom
     5: distinguish (an element or atom) by using a radioactive
        isotope or an isotope of unusual mass for tracing through
        chemical reactions
     [also: {labelling}, {labelled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
