<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>labor</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>labor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LABOR, n.  One of the processes by which A acquires property for B.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>labor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Labor \La"bor\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Labored}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Laboring}.] [OE. labouren, F. labourer, L. laborare. See
   {Labor}, n.] [Written also {labour}.]
   1. To exert muscular strength; to exert one's strength with
      painful effort, particularly in servile occupations; to
      work; to toil.
      [1913 Webster]

            Adam, well may we labor still to dress
            This garden.                          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To exert one's powers of mind in the prosecution of any
      design; to strive; to take pains.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be oppressed with difficulties or disease; to do one's
      work under conditions which make it especially hard,
      wearisome; to move slowly, as against opposition, or under
      a burden; to be burdened; -- often with under, and
      formerly with of.
      [1913 Webster]

            The stone that labors up the hill.    --Granville.
      [1913 Webster]

            The line too labors, and the words move slow.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            To cure the disorder under which he labored. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden,
            and I will give you rest.             --Matt. xi. 28
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be in travail; to suffer the pangs of childbirth; to be
      in labor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) To pitch or roll heavily, as a ship in a turbulent
      sea. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>labor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Labor \La"bor\ (l[=a]"b[~e]r), n. [OE. labour, OF. labour,
   laber, labur, F. labeur, L. labor; cf. Gr. lamba`nein to
   take, Skr. labh to get, seize.] [Written also {labour}.]
   1. Physical toil or bodily exertion, especially when
      fatiguing, irksome, or unavoidable, in distinction from
      sportive exercise; hard, muscular effort directed to some
      useful end, as agriculture, manufactures, and like;
      servile toil; exertion; work.
      [1913 Webster]

            God hath set
            Labor and rest, as day and night, to men
            Successive.                           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Intellectual exertion; mental effort; as, the labor of
      compiling a history.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which requires hard work for its accomplishment; that
      which demands effort.
      [1913 Webster]

            Being a labor of so great a difficulty, the exact
            performance thereof we may rather wish than look
            for.                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Travail; the pangs and efforts of childbirth.
      [1913 Webster]

            The queen's in labor,
            They say, in great extremity; and feared
            She'll with the labor end.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Any pang or distress. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) The pitching or tossing of a vessel which results
      in the straining of timbers and rigging.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. [Sp.] A measure of land in Mexico and Texas, equivalent to
      an area of 1771/7 acres. --Bartlett.

   8. (Mining.) A stope or set of stopes. [Sp. Amer.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Syn: Work; toil; drudgery; task; exertion; effort; industry;
        painstaking. See {Toll}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>labor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Labor \La"bor\, v. t. [F. labourer, L. laborare.]
   1. To work at; to work; to till; to cultivate by toil.
      [1913 Webster]

            The most excellent lands are lying fallow, or only
            labored by children.                  --W. Tooke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form or fabricate with toil, exertion, or care. ``To
      labor arms for Troy.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To prosecute, or perfect, with effort; to urge
      strenuously; as, to labor a point or argument.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To belabor; to beat. [Obs.] --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>labor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>labor
     n 1: productive work (especially physical work done for wages);
          "his labor did not require a great deal of skill" [syn:
          {labour}, {toil}]
     2: a social class comprising those who do manual labor or work
        for wages; "there is a shortage of skilled labor in this
        field" [syn: {labour}, {working class}, {proletariat}]
     3: concluding state of pregnancy; from the onset of labor to
        the birth of a child; "she was in labor for six hours"
        [syn: {parturiency}, {labour}, {confinement}, {lying-in},
        {travail}, {childbed}]
     4: an organized attempt by workers to improve their status by
        united action especially via labor unions (especially the
        leaders of this movement) [syn: {labor movement}, {trade
        union movement}]
     5: a political party formed in Great Britain in 1900;
        characterized by the promotion of labor's interests and
        the socialization of key industries [syn: {Labour Party},
        {Labour}, {Labor Party}]
     6: the federal department responsible for promoting the working
        conditions of wage earners in the United States; created
        in 1913 [syn: {Department of Labor}, {Labor Department}, {DoL}]
     7: any piece of work that is undertaken or attempted; "he
        prepared for great undertakings" [syn: {undertaking}, {project},
         {task}]
     v 1: strive and make an effort to reach a goal; "She tugged for
          years to make a decent living"; "We have to push a
          little to make the deadline!"; "She is driving away at
          her doctoral thesis" [syn: {tug}, {labour}, {push}, {drive}]
     2: work hard; "She was digging away at her math homework";
        "Lexicographers drudge all day long" [syn: {labour}, {toil},
         {fag}, {travail}, {grind}, {drudge}, {dig}, {moil}]
     3: undergo the efforts of childbirth [syn: {labour}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
