<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>laboring</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>laboring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Labor \La"bor\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Labored}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Laboring}.] [OE. labouren, F. labourer, L. laborare. See
   {Labor}, n.] [Written also {labour}.]
   1. To exert muscular strength; to exert one's strength with
      painful effort, particularly in servile occupations; to
      work; to toil.
      [1913 Webster]

            Adam, well may we labor still to dress
            This garden.                          --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To exert one's powers of mind in the prosecution of any
      design; to strive; to take pains.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be oppressed with difficulties or disease; to do one's
      work under conditions which make it especially hard,
      wearisome; to move slowly, as against opposition, or under
      a burden; to be burdened; -- often with under, and
      formerly with of.
      [1913 Webster]

            The stone that labors up the hill.    --Granville.
      [1913 Webster]

            The line too labors, and the words move slow.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            To cure the disorder under which he labored. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden,
            and I will give you rest.             --Matt. xi. 28
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be in travail; to suffer the pangs of childbirth; to be
      in labor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) To pitch or roll heavily, as a ship in a turbulent
      sea. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>laboring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Laboring \La"bor*ing\, a.
   1. That labors; performing labor; esp., performing coarse,
      heavy work, not requiring skill also, set apart for labor;
      as, laboring days.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sleep of a laboring man is sweet. --Eccl. v. 12.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Suffering pain or grief. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Laboring oar}, the oar which requires most strength and
      exertion; often used figuratively; as, to have, or pull,
      the laboring oar in some difficult undertaking.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>laboring</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>laboring
     adj : doing arduous or unpleasant work; "drudging peasants"; "the
           bent backs of laboring slaves picking cotton"; "toiling
           coal miners in the black deeps" [syn: {drudging}, {labouring},
            {toiling}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
