<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lace</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lace
     
        Language for Assembling Classes in Eiffel.  Specifies how to
        assemble an Eiffel system : in which directories to find the
        clusters, which class to use as the root, permits class
        renaming to avoid name clashes.  "Eiffel: The Language",
        Bertrand Meyer, P-H 1992.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lace \Lace\ (l[=a]s), n. [OE. las, OF. laz, F. lacs, dim. lacet,
   fr. L. laqueus noose, snare; prob. akin to lacere to entice.
   Cf. {Delight}, {Elicit}, {Lasso}, {Latchet}.]
   1. That which binds or holds, especially by being interwoven;
      a string, cord, or band, usually one passing through
      eyelet or other holes, and used in drawing and holding
      together parts of a garment, of a shoe, of a machine belt,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            His hat hung at his back down by a lace. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            For striving more, the more in laces strong
            Himself he tied.                      --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A snare or gin, especially one made of interwoven cords; a
      net. [Obs.] --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

            Vulcanus had caught thee [Venus] in his lace.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A fabric of fine threads of linen, silk, cotton, etc.,
      often ornamented with figures; a delicate tissue of
      thread, much worn as an ornament of dress.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our English dames are much given to the wearing of
            costly laces.                         --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Spirits added to coffee or some other beverage. [Old
      Slang] --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Alen[,c]on lace}, a kind of point lace, entirely of
      needlework, first made at Alen[,c]on in France, in the
      17th century. It is very durable and of great beauty and
      cost.

   {Bone lace}, {Brussels lace}, etc. See under {Bone},
      {Brussels}, etc.

   {Gold lace}, or {Silver lace}, lace having warp threads of
      silk, or silk and cotton, and a weft of silk threads
      covered with gold (or silver), or with gilt.

   {Lace leather}, thin, oil-tanned leather suitable for cutting
      into lacings for machine belts.

   {Lace lizard} (Zo["o]l.), a large, aquatic, Australian lizard
      ({Hydrosaurus giganteus}), allied to the monitors.

   {Lace paper}, paper with an openwork design in imitation of
      lace.

   {Lace piece} (Shipbuilding), the main piece of timber which
      supports the beak or head projecting beyond the stem of a
      ship.

   {Lace pillow}, and {Pillow lace}. See under {Pillow}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lace \Lace\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Laced} ([=a]st); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Lacing}.]
   1. To fasten with a lace; to draw together with a lace passed
      through eyelet holes; to unite with a lace or laces, or,
      figuratively. with anything resembling laces. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Jenny's stays are newly laced.   --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To adorn with narrow strips or braids of some decorative
      material; as, cloth laced with silver. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To beat; to lash; to make stripes on. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll lace your coat for ye.           --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To add something to (a food or beverage) so as to impart
      flavor, pungency, or some special quality; as, to lace a
      punch with alcohol; to lace the Kool-Aid with LSD. [Old
      Slang]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   5. To twine or draw as a lace; to interlace; to intertwine.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

            The Gond . . . picked up a trail of the Karela, the
            vine that bears the bitter wild gourd, and laced it
            to and fro across the temple door.    --Kipling.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lace \Lace\, v. i.
   To be fastened with a lace, or laces; as, these boots lace.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lace
     n 1: a cord that is drawn through eyelets or around hooks in
          order to draw together two edges (as of a shoe or
          garment) [syn: {lacing}]
     2: a delicate decorative fabric woven in an open web of
        symmetrical patterns
     v 1: spin or twist together so as to form a cord; "intertwine the
          ribbons"; "Twine the threads into a rope" [syn: {intertwine},
           {twine}, {entwine}, {enlace}, {interlace}] [ant: {untwine}]
     2: make by braiding or interlacing; "lace a tablecloth" [syn: {braid},
         {plait}]
     3: do lacework; "The Flemish women were lacing in front of the
        cathedral"
     4: draw through eyes or holes; "lace the shoelaces" [syn: {lace
        up}]
     5: add alcohol beverages [syn: {spike}, {fortify}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
