<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lacing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lacing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lace \Lace\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Laced} ([=a]st); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Lacing}.]
   1. To fasten with a lace; to draw together with a lace passed
      through eyelet holes; to unite with a lace or laces, or,
      figuratively. with anything resembling laces. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            When Jenny's stays are newly laced.   --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To adorn with narrow strips or braids of some decorative
      material; as, cloth laced with silver. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To beat; to lash; to make stripes on. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll lace your coat for ye.           --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To add something to (a food or beverage) so as to impart
      flavor, pungency, or some special quality; as, to lace a
      punch with alcohol; to lace the Kool-Aid with LSD. [Old
      Slang]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   5. To twine or draw as a lace; to interlace; to intertwine.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

            The Gond . . . picked up a trail of the Karela, the
            vine that bears the bitter wild gourd, and laced it
            to and fro across the temple door.    --Kipling.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lacing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lacing \La"cing\ (l[=a]"s[i^]ng), n.
   1. The act of securing, fastening, or tightening, with a lace
      or laces.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lace; specifically (Mach.), a thong of thin leather for
      uniting the ends of belts.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) A rope or line passing through eyelet holes in the
      edge of a sail or an awning to attach it to a yard, gaff,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bridge Building) A system of bracing bars, not crossing
      each other in the middle, connecting the channel bars of a
      compound strut. --Waddell.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A quantity of a substance, such as an alcoholic liquor,
      added to a food or a drink; as, punch with a lacing of
      rum.
      [PJC]

   6. A beating, especially with a lash.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lacing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lacing
     n 1: a small amount of liquor added to a food or beverage
     2: a cord that is drawn through eyelets or around hooks in
        order to draw together two edges (as of a shoe or garment)
        [syn: {lace}]
     3: the act of inflicting corporal punishment with repeated
        blows [syn: {beating}, {thrashing}, {licking}, {drubbing},
         {trouncing}, {whacking}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
