<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ladies</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ladies</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lady \La"dy\ (l[=a]"d[y^]), n.; pl. {Ladies} (l[=a]"d[i^]z).
   [OE. ladi, l[ae]fdi, AS. hl[=ae]fdige, hl[=ae]fdie; AS.
   hl[=a]f loaf + a root of uncertain origin, possibly akin to
   E. dairy. See {Loaf}, and cf. {Lord}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A woman who looks after the domestic affairs of a family;
      a mistress; the female head of a household.
      [1913 Webster]

            Agar, the handmaiden of Sara, whence comest thou,
            and whither goest thou? The which answered, Fro the
            face of Sara my lady.                 --Wyclif (Gen.
                                                  xvi. 8.).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A woman having proprietary rights or authority; mistress;
      -- a feminine correlative of lord. ``Lord or lady of high
      degree.'' --Lowell.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of all these bounds, even from this line to this, .
            . .
            We make thee lady.                    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A woman to whom the particular homage of a knight was
      paid; a woman to whom one is devoted or bound; a
      sweetheart.
      [1913 Webster]

            The soldier here his wasted store supplies,
            And takes new valor from his lady's eyes. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A woman of social distinction or position. In England, a
      title prefixed to the name of any woman whose husband is
      not of lower rank than a baron, or whose father was a
      nobleman not lower than an earl. The wife of a baronet or
      knight has the title of Lady by courtesy, but not by
      right.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A woman of refined or gentle manners; a well-bred woman;
      -- the feminine correlative of {gentleman}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A wife; -- not now in approved usage. --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence: Any woman; as, a lounge for ladies; a cleaning
      lady; also used in combination; as, saleslady.
      [PJC]

   8. (Zo["o]l.) The triturating apparatus in the stomach of a
      lobster; -- so called from a fancied resemblance to a
      seated female figure. It consists of calcareous plates.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ladies' man}, a man who affects the society of ladies.

   {Lady altar}, an altar in a lady chapel. --Shipley.

   {Lady chapel}, a chapel dedicated to the Virgin Mary.

   {Lady court}, the court of a lady of the manor.

   {Lady crab} (Zo["o]l.), a handsomely spotted swimming crab
      ({Platyonichus ocellatus}) very common on the sandy shores
      of the Atlantic coast of the United States.

   {Lady fern}. (Bot.) See {Female fern}, under {Female}, and
      Illust. of {Fern}.

   {Lady in waiting}, a lady of the queen's household, appointed
      to wait upon or attend the queen.

   {Lady Mass}, a Mass said in honor of the Virgin Mary.
      --Shipley.

   {Lady of the manor}, a lady having jurisdiction of a manor;
      also, the wife of a manor lord.

   {Lady's maid}, a maidservant who dresses and waits upon a
      lady. --Thackeray.

   {Our Lady}, the Virgin Mary.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
