<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lakers</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lakers</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lake \Lake\, n. [AS. lac, L. lacus; akin to AS. lagu lake, sea,
   Icel. l["o]gr; OIr. loch; cf. Gr. la`kkos pond, tank. Cf.
   {Loch}, {Lough}.]
   A large body of water contained in a depression of the
   earth's surface, and supplied from the drainage of a more or
   less extended area.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Lakes are for the most part of fresh water; the salt
         lakes, like the Great Salt Lake of Utah, have usually
         no outlet to the ocean.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Lake dwellers} (Ethnol.), people of a prehistoric race, or
      races, which inhabited different parts of Europe. Their
      dwellings were built on piles in lakes, a short distance
      from the shore. Their relics are common in the lakes of
      Switzerland.

   {Lake dwellings} (Arch[ae]ol.), dwellings built over a lake,
      sometimes on piles, and sometimes on rude foundations kept
      in place by piles; specifically, such dwellings of
      prehistoric times. Lake dwellings are still used by many
      savage tribes. Called also {lacustrine dwellings}. See
      {Crannog}.

   {Lake fly} (Zo["o]l.), any one of numerous species of
      dipterous flies of the genus {Chironomus}. In form they
      resemble mosquitoes, but they do not bite. The larv[ae]
      live in lakes.

   {Lake herring} (Zo["o]l.), the cisco ({Coregonus Artedii}).
      

   {Lake poets}, {Lake school}, a collective name originally
      applied in contempt, but now in honor, to Southey,
      Coleridge, and Wordsworth, who lived in the lake country
      of Cumberland, England, Lamb and a few others were classed
      with these by hostile critics. Called also {lakers} and
      {lakists}.

   {Lake sturgeon} (Zo["o]l.), a sturgeon ({Acipenser
      rubicundus}), of moderate size, found in the Great Lakes
      and the Mississippi River. It is used as food.

   {Lake trout} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of trout
      and salmon; in Europe, esp. {Salmo fario}; in the United
      States, esp. {Salvelinus namaycush} of the Great Lakes,
      and of various lakes in New York, Eastern Maine, and
      Canada. A large variety of brook trout ({Salvelinus
      fontinalis}), inhabiting many lakes in New England, is
      also called lake trout. See {Namaycush}.

   {Lake whitefish}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Whitefish}.

   {Lake whiting} (Zo["o]l.), an American whitefish ({Coregonus
      Labradoricus}), found in many lakes in the Northern United
      States and Canada. It is more slender than the common
      whitefish.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
