<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lamp</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lamp
   (1.) That part of the candle-sticks of the tabernacle and the
   temple which bore the light (Ex. 25:37; 1 Kings 7:49; 2 Chr.
   4:20; 13:11; Zech. 4:2). Their form is not described. Olive oil
   was generally burned in them (Ex. 27:20).
   
     (2.) A torch carried by the soliders of Gideon (Judg. 7:16,
   20). (R.V., "torches.")
   
     (3.) Domestic lamps (A.V., "candles") were in common use among
   the Hebrews (Matt. 5:15; Mark 4:21, etc.).
   
     (4.) Lamps or torches were used in connection with marriage
   ceremonies (Matt. 25:1).
   
     This word is also frequently metaphorically used to denote
   life, welfare, guidance, etc. (2 Sam. 21:17; Ps. 119:105; Prov.
   6:23; 13:9).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lamp \Lamp\ (l[a^]mp), n. [OE. (with excrescent p), fr. F. lame,
   L. lamina. See {Lamina}.]
   A thin plate or lamina. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lamp \Lamp\ (l[a^]mp), n. [F. lampe, L. lampas, -adis, fr. Gr.
   ?, ?, torch, fr. ? to give light, to shine. Cf. {Lampad},
   {Lantern}.]
   1. A light-producing vessel, device, instrument or apparatus;
      formerly referring especially to a vessel with a wick used
      for the combustion of oil or other inflammable liquid, for
      the purpose of producing artificial light; also, a similar
      device using a gas as the combustible fuel; now referring
      mainly to an electric lamp. See sense [3].
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. Figuratively, anything which enlightens intellectually or
      morally; anything regarded metaphorically a performing the
      uses of a lamp.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy word is a lamp unto my feet, and a light unto my
            path.                                 --Ps. cxix.
                                                  105.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ages elapsed ere Homer's lamp appeared. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Elec.) A device or mechanism for producing light by
      electricity, usually having a glass bulb or tube
      containing the light-emitting element. Most lamps belong
      to one of two categories, the {Incandescent lamp} (See
      under {Incandescent}) or the {fluorescent lamp}. However,
      see also {arc lamp}, below.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. A device that emits radiant energy in the form of heat,
      infrared, or ultraviolet rays; as, a heat lamp.
      [PJC]

   {[AE]olipile lamp}, a hollow ball of copper containing
      alcohol which is converted into vapor by a lamp beneath,
      so as to make a powerful blowpipe flame when the vapor is
      ignited. --Weale.

   {Arc lamp} (Elec.), a form of lamp in which the voltaic arc
      is used as the source of light.

   {D["e]bereiner's lamp}, an apparatus for the instantaneous
      production of a flame by the spontaneous ignition of a jet
      of hydrogen on being led over platinum sponge; -- named
      after the German chemist D["o]bereiner, who invented it.
      Called also {philosopher's lamp}.

   {Flameless lamp}, an aphlogistic lamp.

   {Lamp burner}, the part of a lamp where the wick is exposed
      and ignited. --Knight.

   {Lamp fount}, a reservoir for oil, in a lamp.

   {Lamp jack}. See 2d {Jack}, n., 4
      (l) &amp;
      (n) .

   {Lamp shade}, a screen, as of paper, glass, or tin, for
      softening or obstructing the light of a lamp.

   {Lamp shell} (Zo["o]l.), any brachiopod shell of the genus
      {Terebratula} and allied genera. The name refers to the
      shape, which is like that of an antique lamp. See
      {Terebratula}.

   {Safety lamp}, a miner's lamp in which the flame is
      surrounded by fine wire gauze, preventing the kindling of
      dangerous explosive gases; -- called also, from Sir
      Humphry Davy the inventor, {Davy lamp}.

   {To smell of the lamp}, to bear marks of great study and
      labor, as a literary composition.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LAMP
     Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP (Linux, Apache, PHP)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lamp</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lamp
     n 1: an artificial source of visible illumination
     2: a piece of furniture holding one or more electric light
        bulbs
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
