<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>land</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>land</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LAND, n.  A part of the earth's surface, considered as property.  The
theory that land is property subject to private ownership and control
is the foundation of modern society, and is eminently worthy of the
superstructure.  Carried to its logical conclusion, it means that some
have the right to prevent others from living; for the right to own
implies the right exclusively to occupy; and in fact laws of trespass
are enacted wherever property in land is recognized.  It follows that
if the whole area of _terra firma_ is owned by A, B and C, there will
be no place for D, E, F and G to be born, or, born as trespassers, to
exist.

    A life on the ocean wave,
        A home on the rolling deep,
    For the spark the nature gave
        I have there the right to keep.

    They give me the cat-o'-nine
        Whenever I go ashore.
    Then ho! for the flashing brine --
        I'm a natural commodore!
                                                                 Dodle


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>land</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Land \Land\ (l[a^]nd), n.
   Urine. See {Lant}. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>land</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Land \Land\, n. [AS. land, lond; akin to D., G., Icel., Sw.,
   Dan., and Goth. land. ]
   1. The solid part of the surface of the earth; -- opposed to
      water as constituting a part of such surface, especially
      to oceans and seas; as, to sight land after a long voyage.
      [1913 Webster]

            They turn their heads to sea, their sterns to land.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any portion, large or small, of the surface of the earth,
      considered by itself, or as belonging to an individual or
      a people, as a country, estate, farm, or tract.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go view the land, even Jericho.       --Josh. ii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ill fares the land, to hastening ills a prey,
            Where wealth accumulates and men decay. --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the expressions ``to be, or dwell, upon land,'' ``to
         go, or fare, on land,'' as used by Chaucer, land
         denotes the country as distinguished from the town.
         [1913 Webster]

               A poor parson dwelling upon land [i.e., in the
               country].                          --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. Ground, in respect to its nature or quality; soil; as, wet
      land; good or bad land.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The inhabitants of a nation or people.
      [1913 Webster]

            These answers, in the silent night received,
            The king himself divulged, the land believed.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The mainland, in distinction from islands.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The ground or floor. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Herself upon the land she did prostrate. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Agric.) The ground left unplowed between furrows; any one
      of several portions into which a field is divided for
      convenience in plowing.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Law) Any ground, soil, or earth whatsoever, as meadows,
      pastures, woods, etc., and everything annexed to it,
      whether by nature, as trees, water, etc., or by the hand
      of man, as buildings, fences, etc.; real estate. --Kent.
      Bouvier. Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) The lap of the strakes in a clinker-built boat;
      the lap of plates in an iron vessel; -- called also
      {landing}. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. In any surface prepared with indentations, perforations,
       or grooves, that part of the surface which is not so
       treated, as the level part of a millstone between the
       furrows, or the surface of the bore of a rifled gun
       between the grooves.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Land agent}, a person employed to sell or let land, to
      collect rents, and to attend to other money matters
      connected with land.

   {Land boat}, a vehicle on wheels propelled by sails.

   {Land blink}, a peculiar atmospheric brightness seen from sea
      over distant snow-covered land in arctic regions. See {Ice
      blink}.

   {Land breeze}. See under {Breeze}.

   {Land chain}. See {Gunter's chain}.

   {Land crab} (Zo["o]l.), any one of various species of crabs
      which live much on the land, and resort to the water
      chiefly for the purpose of breeding. They are abundant in
      the West Indies and South America. Some of them grow to a
      large size.

   {Land fish} a fish on land; a person quite out of place.
      --Shak.

   {Land force}, a military force serving on land, as
      distinguished from a naval force.

   {Land, ho!} (Naut.), a sailor's cry in announcing sight of
      land.

   {Land ice}, a field of ice adhering to the coast, in
      distinction from a floe.

   {Land leech} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      blood-sucking leeches, which, in moist, tropical regions,
      live on land, and are often troublesome to man and beast.
      

   {Land measure}, the system of measurement used in determining
      the area of land; also, a table of areas used in such
      measurement.

   {Land of bondage} or {House of bondage}, in Bible history,
      Egypt; by extension, a place or condition of special
      oppression.

   {Land o' cakes}, Scotland.

   {Land of Nod}, sleep.

   {Land of promise}, in Bible history, Canaan: by extension, a
      better country or condition of which one has expectation.
      

   {Land of steady habits}, a nickname sometimes given to the
      State of Connecticut.

   {Land office}, a government office in which the entries upon,
      and sales of, public land are registered, and other
      business respecting the public lands is transacted. [U.S.]
      

   {Land pike}. (Zo["o]l.)
       (a) The gray pike, or sauger.
       (b) The Menobranchus.

   {Land service}, military service as distinguished from naval
      service.

   {Land rail}. (Zo["o]l)
       (a) The crake or corncrake of Europe. See {Crake}.
       (b) An Australian rail ({Hypot[ae]nidia Phillipensis});
           -- called also {pectoral rail}.

   {Land scrip}, a certificate that the purchase money for a
      certain portion of the public land has been paid to the
      officer entitled to receive it. [U.S.]

   {Land shark}, a swindler of sailors on shore. [Sailors' Cant]
      

   {Land side}
       (a) That side of anything in or on the sea, as of an
           island or ship, which is turned toward the land.
       (b) The side of a plow which is opposite to the moldboard
           and which presses against the unplowed land.

   {Land snail} (Zo["o]l.), any snail which lives on land, as
      distinguished from the aquatic snails are Pulmonifera, and
      belong to the Geophila; but the operculated land snails of
      warm countries are Di[oe]cia, and belong to the
      T[ae]nioglossa. See {Geophila}, and {Helix}.

   {Land spout}, a descent of cloud and water in a conical form
      during the occurrence of a tornado and heavy rainfall on
      land.

   {Land steward}, a person who acts for another in the
      management of land, collection of rents, etc.

   {Land tortoise}, {Land turtle} (Zo["o]l.), any tortoise that
      habitually lives on dry land, as the box tortoise. See
      {Tortoise}.

   {Land warrant}, a certificate from the Land Office,
      authorizing a person to assume ownership of a public land.
      [U.S.]

   {Land wind}. Same as {Land breeze} (above).

   {To make land} (Naut.), to sight land.

   {To set the land}, to see by the compass how the land bears
      from the ship.

   {To shut in the land}, to hide the land, as when fog, or an
      intervening island, obstructs the view.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>land</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Land \Land\, v. i.
   1. To come to the end of a course; to arrive at a
      destination, literally or figuratively; as, he landed in
      trouble; after hithchiking for a week, he landed in Los
      Angeles.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. Specifically: To go on shore from a ship or boat; to
      disembark.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically: To reach and come to rest on land after
      having been in the air; as, the arrow landed in a flower
      bed; the golf ball landed in a sand trap; our airplane
      landed in Washington.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>land</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Land \Land\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Landed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Landing}.]
   1. To set or put on shore from a ship or other water craft;
      to disembark; to debark.
      [1913 Webster]

            I 'll undertake to land them on our coast. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To catch and bring to shore; to capture; as, to land a
      fish.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To set down after conveying; to cause to fall, alight, or
      reach; to bring to the end of a course; as, he landed the
      quoit near the stake; to be thrown from a horse and landed
      in the mud; to land one in difficulties or mistakes.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically: (Aeronautics) To pilot (an airplane) from
      the air onto the land; as, to land the plane on a highway.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>land</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>land
     adj 1: relating to or characteristic of or occurring on land; "land
            vehicles" [syn: {land(a)}] [ant: {sea(a)}, {air(a)}]
     2: operating or living or growing on land [syn: {terrestrial},
        {land(a)}] [ant: {amphibious}, {aquatic}]
     n 1: the land on which real estate is located; "he built the
          house on land leased from the city"
     2: material in the top layer of the surface of the earth in
        which plants can grow (especially with reference to its
        quality or use); "the land had never been plowed"; "good
        agricultural soil" [syn: {ground}, {soil}]
     3: the solid part of the earth's surface; "the plane turned
        away from the sea and moved back over land"; "the earth
        shook for several minutes"; "he dropped the logs on the
        ground" [syn: {dry land}, {earth}, {ground}, {solid ground},
         {terra firma}]
     4: territory over which rule or control is exercised; "his
        domain extended into Europe"; "he made it the law of the
        land" [syn: {domain}, {demesne}]
     5: the territory occupied by a nation; "he returned to the land
        of his birth"; "he visited several European countries"
        [syn: {country}, {state}]
     6: a domain in which something is dominant; "the untroubled
        kingdom of reason"; "a land of make-believe"; "the rise of
        the realm of cotton in the south" [syn: {kingdom}, {realm}]
     7: extensive landed property (especially in the country)
        retained by the owner for his own use; "the family owned a
        large estate on Long Island" [syn: {estate}, {landed
        estate}, {acres}, {demesne}]
     8: the people who live in a nation or country; "a statement
        that sums up the nation's mood"; "the news was announced
        to the nation"; "the whole country worshipped him" [syn: {nation},
         {country}, {a people}]
     9: a politically organized body of people under a single
        government; "the state has elected a new president";
        "African nations"; "students who had come to the nation's
        capitol"; "the country's largest manufacturer"; "an
        industrialized land" [syn: {state}, {nation}, {country}, {commonwealth},
         {res publica}, {body politic}]
     10: United States inventor who incorporated Polaroid film into
         lenses and invented the one-step photographic process
         (1909-1991) [syn: {Din Land}, {Edwin Herbert Land}]
     11: working the land as an occupation or way of life; "farming
         is a strenuous life"; "there's no work on the land any
         more" [syn: {farming}]
     v 1: reach or come to rest; "The bird landed on the highest
          branch"; "The plane landed in Istanbul" [syn: {set down}]
     2: cause to come to the ground; "the pilot managed to land the
        airplane safely" [syn: {put down}, {bring down}]
     3: bring into a different state; "this may land you in jail"
        [syn: {bring}]
     4: bring ashore; "The drug smugglers landed the heroin on the
        beach of the island"
     5: deliver (a blow); "He landed several blows on his opponent's
        head"
     6: arrive on shore; "The ship landed in Pearl Harbor" [syn: {set
        ashore}, {shore}]
     7: shoot at and force to come down; "the enemy landed several
        of our aircraft" [syn: {down}, {shoot down}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
