<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>landing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>landing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Landing, NJ
  Zip code(s): 07850
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>landing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Halfpace \Half"pace`\ (-p[=a]s`), n. (Arch.)
   A platform of a staircase where the stair turns back in
   exactly the reverse direction of the lower flight. See
   {Quarterpace}.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: This term and {quarterpace} are rare or unknown in the
         United States, {platform} or {landing} being used
         instead.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>landing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Land \Land\, n. [AS. land, lond; akin to D., G., Icel., Sw.,
   Dan., and Goth. land. ]
   1. The solid part of the surface of the earth; -- opposed to
      water as constituting a part of such surface, especially
      to oceans and seas; as, to sight land after a long voyage.
      [1913 Webster]

            They turn their heads to sea, their sterns to land.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any portion, large or small, of the surface of the earth,
      considered by itself, or as belonging to an individual or
      a people, as a country, estate, farm, or tract.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go view the land, even Jericho.       --Josh. ii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ill fares the land, to hastening ills a prey,
            Where wealth accumulates and men decay. --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the expressions ``to be, or dwell, upon land,'' ``to
         go, or fare, on land,'' as used by Chaucer, land
         denotes the country as distinguished from the town.
         [1913 Webster]

               A poor parson dwelling upon land [i.e., in the
               country].                          --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. Ground, in respect to its nature or quality; soil; as, wet
      land; good or bad land.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The inhabitants of a nation or people.
      [1913 Webster]

            These answers, in the silent night received,
            The king himself divulged, the land believed.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The mainland, in distinction from islands.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The ground or floor. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Herself upon the land she did prostrate. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Agric.) The ground left unplowed between furrows; any one
      of several portions into which a field is divided for
      convenience in plowing.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Law) Any ground, soil, or earth whatsoever, as meadows,
      pastures, woods, etc., and everything annexed to it,
      whether by nature, as trees, water, etc., or by the hand
      of man, as buildings, fences, etc.; real estate. --Kent.
      Bouvier. Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) The lap of the strakes in a clinker-built boat;
      the lap of plates in an iron vessel; -- called also
      {landing}. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. In any surface prepared with indentations, perforations,
       or grooves, that part of the surface which is not so
       treated, as the level part of a millstone between the
       furrows, or the surface of the bore of a rifled gun
       between the grooves.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Land agent}, a person employed to sell or let land, to
      collect rents, and to attend to other money matters
      connected with land.

   {Land boat}, a vehicle on wheels propelled by sails.

   {Land blink}, a peculiar atmospheric brightness seen from sea
      over distant snow-covered land in arctic regions. See {Ice
      blink}.

   {Land breeze}. See under {Breeze}.

   {Land chain}. See {Gunter's chain}.

   {Land crab} (Zo["o]l.), any one of various species of crabs
      which live much on the land, and resort to the water
      chiefly for the purpose of breeding. They are abundant in
      the West Indies and South America. Some of them grow to a
      large size.

   {Land fish} a fish on land; a person quite out of place.
      --Shak.

   {Land force}, a military force serving on land, as
      distinguished from a naval force.

   {Land, ho!} (Naut.), a sailor's cry in announcing sight of
      land.

   {Land ice}, a field of ice adhering to the coast, in
      distinction from a floe.

   {Land leech} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      blood-sucking leeches, which, in moist, tropical regions,
      live on land, and are often troublesome to man and beast.
      

   {Land measure}, the system of measurement used in determining
      the area of land; also, a table of areas used in such
      measurement.

   {Land of bondage} or {House of bondage}, in Bible history,
      Egypt; by extension, a place or condition of special
      oppression.

   {Land o' cakes}, Scotland.

   {Land of Nod}, sleep.

   {Land of promise}, in Bible history, Canaan: by extension, a
      better country or condition of which one has expectation.
      

   {Land of steady habits}, a nickname sometimes given to the
      State of Connecticut.

   {Land office}, a government office in which the entries upon,
      and sales of, public land are registered, and other
      business respecting the public lands is transacted. [U.S.]
      

   {Land pike}. (Zo["o]l.)
       (a) The gray pike, or sauger.
       (b) The Menobranchus.

   {Land service}, military service as distinguished from naval
      service.

   {Land rail}. (Zo["o]l)
       (a) The crake or corncrake of Europe. See {Crake}.
       (b) An Australian rail ({Hypot[ae]nidia Phillipensis});
           -- called also {pectoral rail}.

   {Land scrip}, a certificate that the purchase money for a
      certain portion of the public land has been paid to the
      officer entitled to receive it. [U.S.]

   {Land shark}, a swindler of sailors on shore. [Sailors' Cant]
      

   {Land side}
       (a) That side of anything in or on the sea, as of an
           island or ship, which is turned toward the land.
       (b) The side of a plow which is opposite to the moldboard
           and which presses against the unplowed land.

   {Land snail} (Zo["o]l.), any snail which lives on land, as
      distinguished from the aquatic snails are Pulmonifera, and
      belong to the Geophila; but the operculated land snails of
      warm countries are Di[oe]cia, and belong to the
      T[ae]nioglossa. See {Geophila}, and {Helix}.

   {Land spout}, a descent of cloud and water in a conical form
      during the occurrence of a tornado and heavy rainfall on
      land.

   {Land steward}, a person who acts for another in the
      management of land, collection of rents, etc.

   {Land tortoise}, {Land turtle} (Zo["o]l.), any tortoise that
      habitually lives on dry land, as the box tortoise. See
      {Tortoise}.

   {Land warrant}, a certificate from the Land Office,
      authorizing a person to assume ownership of a public land.
      [U.S.]

   {Land wind}. Same as {Land breeze} (above).

   {To make land} (Naut.), to sight land.

   {To set the land}, to see by the compass how the land bears
      from the ship.

   {To shut in the land}, to hide the land, as when fog, or an
      intervening island, obstructs the view.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>landing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Land \Land\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Landed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Landing}.]
   1. To set or put on shore from a ship or other water craft;
      to disembark; to debark.
      [1913 Webster]

            I 'll undertake to land them on our coast. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To catch and bring to shore; to capture; as, to land a
      fish.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To set down after conveying; to cause to fall, alight, or
      reach; to bring to the end of a course; as, he landed the
      quoit near the stake; to be thrown from a horse and landed
      in the mud; to land one in difficulties or mistakes.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically: (Aeronautics) To pilot (an airplane) from
      the air onto the land; as, to land the plane on a highway.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>landing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Landing \Land"ing\, a.
   Of, pertaining to, or used for, setting, bringing, or going,
   on shore.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Landing charges}, charges or fees paid on goods unloaded
      from a vessel.

   {Landing net}, a small, bag-shaped net, used in fishing to
      take the fish from the water after being hooked.

   {Landing stage}, a floating platform attached at one end to a
      wharf in such a manner as to rise and fall with the tide,
      and thus facilitate passage between the wharf and a vessel
      lying beside the stage.

   {Landing waiter}, a customhouse officer who oversees the
      landing of goods, etc., from vessels; a landwaiter.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>landing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Landing \Land"ing\, n.
   1. A going or bringing on shore.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A place for landing, as from a ship, a carriage. etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.) The level part of a staircase, at the top of a
      flight of stairs, or connecting one flight with another.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Aeronautics) The act or process of bringing an aircraft
      to land after having been in the air; as, the pilot made a
      perfect three-point landing. Contrasted with {take-off}.
      [PJC]

   {Landing place}. me as {Landing}, n., 2 and 3.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>landing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>landing
     n 1: an intermediate platform in a staircase
     2: structure providing a place where boats can land people or
        goods [syn: {landing place}]
     3: the act of coming down to the earth (or other surface); "the
        plane made a smooth landing"; "his landing on his feet was
        catlike"
     4: the act of coming to land after a voyage
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
