<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>larger</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>larger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Large \Large\ (l[aum]rj), a. [Compar. {Larger} (l[aum]r"j[~e]r);
   superl. {Largest}.] [F., fr. L. largus. Cf. {Largo}.]
   1. Exceeding most other things of like kind in bulk,
      capacity, quantity, superficial dimensions, or number of
      constituent units; big; great; capacious; extensive; --
      opposed to {small}; as, a large horse; a large house or
      room; a large lake or pool; a large jug or spoon; a large
      vineyard; a large army; a large city.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: For linear dimensions, and mere extent, great, and not
         large, is used as a qualifying word; as, great length,
         breadth, depth; a great distance; a great height.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Abundant; ample; as, a large supply of provisions.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have yet large day.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Full in statement; diffuse; full; profuse.
      [1913 Webster]

            I might be very large upon the importance and
            advantages of education.              --Felton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Having more than usual power or capacity; having broad
      sympathies and generous impulses; comprehensive; -- said
      of the mind and heart.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Free; unembarrassed. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Of burdens all he set the Paynims large. --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Unrestrained by decorum; -- said of language. [Obs.]
      ``Some large jests he will make.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Prodigal in expending; lavish. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Naut.) Crossing the line of a ship's course in a
      favorable direction; -- said of the wind when it is abeam,
      or between the beam and the quarter.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At large}.
      (a) Without restraint or confinement; as, to go at large;
          to be left at large.
      (b) Diffusely; fully; in the full extent; as, to discourse
          on a subject at large.

   {Common at large}. See under {Common}, n.

   {Electors at large}, {Representative at large}, electors, or
      a representative, as in Congress, chosen to represent the
      whole of a State, in distinction from those chosen to
      represent particular districts in a State. [U. S.]

   {To give large}, {To go large}, {To run large}, or {To sail
   large} (Naut.), to have the wind crossing the direction of a
      vessel's course in such a way that the sails feel its full
      force, and the vessel gains its highest speed. See
      {Large}, a., 8.

   Syn: Big; bulky; huge; capacious; comprehensive; ample;
        abundant; plentiful; populous; copious; diffusive;
        liberal.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>larger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>larger
     adj : large or big relative to something else [syn: {bigger}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
