<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>latter</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>latter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Late \Late\ (l[=a]t), a. [Compar. {Later} (l[=a]t"[~e]r), or
   {latter} (l[a^]t"t[~e]r); superl. {Latest} (l[=a]t"[e^]st) or
   {Last} (l[.a]st).] [OE. lat slow, slack, AS. l[ae]t; akin to
   OS. lat, D. laat late, G. lass weary, lazy, slack, Icel.
   latr, Sw. lat, Dan. lad, Goth. lats, and to E. let, v. See
   {Let} to permit, and cf. {Alas}, {Lassitude}.]
   1. Coming after the time when due, or after the usual or
      proper time; not early; slow; tardy; long delayed; as, a
      late spring.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Far advanced toward the end or close; as, a late hour of
      the day; a late period of life.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Existing or holding some position not long ago, but not
      now; recently deceased, departed, or gone out of office;
      as, the late bishop of London; the late administration.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Not long past; happening not long ago; recent; as, the
      late rains; we have received late intelligence.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Continuing or doing until an advanced hour of the night;
      as, late revels; a late watcher.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>latter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Latter \Lat"ter\, a. [OE. later, l[ae]tter, compar. of lat late.
   See {Late}, and cf. {Later}.]
   1. Later; more recent; coming or happening after something
      else; -- opposed to {former}; as, the former and latter
      rain.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of two things, the one mentioned second.
      [1913 Webster]

            The difference between reason and revelation, and in
            what sense the latter is superior.    --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Recent; modern.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hath not navigation discovered in these latter ages,
            whole nations at the bay of Soldania? --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Last; latest; final. [R.] ``My latter gasp.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Latter harvest}, the last part of the harvest.

   {Latter spring}, the last part of the spring of the year.
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>latter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>latter
     adj : referring to the second of two things or persons mentioned
           (or the last one or ones of several); "in the latter
           case" [syn: {latter(a)}] [ant: {former(a)}]
     n : the second of two or the second mentioned of two; "Tom and
         Dick were both heroes but only the latter is remembered
         today" [ant: {former}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
