<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>leading</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>leading
     
        &lt;text&gt; /ledding/ The spacing between lines of {text}.  This is
        defined when a {font} is designed but can often be altered in
        order to change the appearance of the text or for special
        effects.  It is measured in {points} and is normally 120% of
        the height of the text.
     
        See also {kerning}, {tracking}.
     
        (1996-06-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lead \Lead\ (l[e^]d), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Leaded}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Leading}.]
   1. To cover, fill, or affect with lead; as, continuous firing
      leads the grooves of a rifle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Print.) To place leads between the lines of; as, to lead
      a page; leaded matter.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lead \Lead\ (l[=e]d), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Led} (l[e^]d); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Leading}.] [OE. leden, AS. l[=ae]dan (akin to OS.
   l[=e]dian, D. leiden, G. leiten, Icel. le[imac][eth]a, Sw.
   leda, Dan. lede), properly a causative fr. AS. li[eth]an to
   go; akin to OHG. l[imac]dan, Icel. l[imac][eth]a, Goth.
   lei[thorn]an (in comp.). Cf. {Lode}, {Loath}.]
   1. To guide or conduct with the hand, or by means of some
      physical contact or connection; as, a father leads a
      child; a jockey leads a horse with a halter; a dog leads a
      blind man.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a blind man lead a blind man, both fall down in
            the ditch.                            --Wyclif
                                                  (Matt. xv.
                                                  14.)
      [1913 Webster]

            They thrust him out of the city, and led him unto
            the brow of the hill.                 --Luke iv. 29.
      [1913 Webster]

            In thy right hand lead with thee
            The mountain nymph, sweet Liberty.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To guide or conduct in a certain course, or to a certain
      place or end, by making the way known; to show the way,
      esp. by going with or going in advance of. Hence,
      figuratively: To direct; to counsel; to instruct; as, to
      lead a traveler; to lead a pupil.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord went before them by day in a pillar of a
            cloud, to lead them the way.          --Ex. xiii.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

            He leadeth me beside the still waters. --Ps. xxiii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

            This thought might lead me through the world's vain
            mask.
            Content, though blind, had I no better guide.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To conduct or direct with authority; to have direction or
      charge of; as, to lead an army, an exploring party, or a
      search; to lead a political party.
      [1913 Webster]

            Christ took not upon him flesh and blood that he
            might conquer and rule nations, lead armies, or
            possess places.                       --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To go or to be in advance of; to precede; hence, to be
      foremost or chief among; as, the big sloop led the fleet
      of yachts; the Guards led the attack; Demosthenes leads
      the orators of all ages.
      [1913 Webster]

            As Hesperus, that leads the sun his way. --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

            And lo ! Ben Adhem's name led all the rest. --Leigh
                                                  Hunt.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To draw or direct by influence, whether good or bad; to
      prevail on; to induce; to entice; to allure; as, to lead
      one to espouse a righteous cause.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was driven by the necessities of the times, more
            than led by his own disposition, to any rigor of
            actions.                              --Eikon
                                                  Basilike.
      [1913 Webster]

            Silly women, laden with sins, led away by divers
            lusts.                                --2 Tim. iii.
                                                  6 (Rev. Ver.).
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To guide or conduct one's self in, through, or along (a
      certain course); hence, to proceed in the way of; to
      follow the path or course of; to pass; to spend. Also, to
      cause (one) to proceed or follow in (a certain course).
      [1913 Webster]

            That we may lead a quiet and peaceable life. --1
                                                  Tim. ii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor thou with shadowed hint confuse
            A life that leads melodious days.     --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            You remember . . . the life he used to lead his wife
            and daughter.                         --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Cards &amp; Dominoes) To begin a game, round, or trick, with;
      as, to lead trumps; the double five was led.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To lead astray}, to guide in a wrong way, or into error; to
      seduce from truth or rectitude.

   {To lead captive}, to carry or bring into captivity.

   {To lead the way}, to show the way by going in front; to act
      as guide. --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Leading \Lead"ing\, a.
   Guiding; directing; controlling; foremost; as, a leading
   motive; a leading man; a leading example. -- {Lead"ing*ly},
   adv.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Leading case} (Law), a reported decision which has come to
      be regarded as settling the law of the question involved.
      --Abbott.

   {Leading motive} [a translation of G. leitmotif] (Mus.), a
      guiding theme; in the musical drama of Wagner, a marked
      melodic phrase or short passage which always accompanies
      the reappearance of a certain person, situation, abstract
      idea, or allusion in the course of the play; a sort of
      musical label. Also called {leitmotif} or {leitmotiv}.

   {Leading note} (Mus.), the seventh note or tone in the
      ascending major scale; the sensible note.

   {Leading question}, a question so framed as to guide the
      person questioned in making his reply.

   {Leading strings}, strings by which children are supported
      when beginning to walk.

   {To be in leading strings}, to be in a state of infancy or
      dependence, or under the guidance of others.

   {Leading wheel}, a wheel situated before the driving wheels
      of a locomotive engine.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Leading \Lead"ing\, n.
   1. The act of guiding, directing, governing, or enticing;
      guidance. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Suggestion; hint; example. [Archaic] --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leading</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>leading
     adj 1: indicating the most important performer or role; "the
            leading man"; "prima ballerina"; "prima donna"; "a
            star figure skater"; "the starring role"; "a stellar
            role"; "a stellar performance" [syn: {leading(p)}, {prima(p)},
             {star(p)}, {starring(p)}, {stellar(a)}]
     2: going or proceeding or going in advance; showing the way;
        "we rode in the leading car"; "the leading edge of
        technology" [ant: {following}]
     3: greatest in importance or degree or significance or
        achievement; "our greatest statesmen"; "the country's
        leading poet"; "a preeminent archeologist" [syn: {greatest},
         {leading(a)}, {preeminent}]
     4: having the leading position or higher score in a contest;
        "he is ahead by a pawn"; "the leading team in the pennant
        race" [syn: {ahead(p)}, {in the lead}]
     5: purposefully formulated to elicit a desired response; "a
        leading question"
     n 1: thin strip of metal used to separate lines of type in
          printing [syn: {lead}]
     2: the activity of leading; "his leadership inspired the team"
        [syn: {leadership}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
