<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lease</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lease</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lease \Lease\ (l[=e]z), v. i. [AS. lesan to gather; akin to D.
   lezen to gather, read, G. lesen, Goth. lisan to gather; cf.
   Lith lesti to peck.]
   To gather what harvesters have left behind; to glean. [Obs.]
   --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lease</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lease \Lease\ (l[=e]s), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Leased}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Leasing}.] [F. laisser, OF. laissier, lessier, to
   leave, transmit, L. laxare to loose, slacken, from laxus
   loose, wide. See {Lax}, and cf. {Lesser}.]
   1. To grant to another by lease the possession of, as of
      lands, tenements, and hereditaments; to let; to demise;
      as, a landowner leases a farm to a tenant; -- sometimes
      with out.
      [1913 Webster]

            There were some [houses] that were leased out for
            three lives.                          --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To hold under a lease; to take lease of; as, a tenant
      leases his land from the owner.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lease</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lease \Lease\ (l[=e]s), n. [Cf. OF. lais. See {Lease}, v. t.]
   1. The temporary transfer of a possession to another person
      in return for a fee or other valuable consideration paid
      for the transfer; especially, A demise or letting of
      lands, tenements, or hereditaments to another for life,
      for a term of years, or at will, or for any less interest
      than that which the lessor has in the property, usually
      for a specified rent or compensation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The contract for such letting.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any tenure by grant or permission; the time for which such
      a tenure holds good; allotted time.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our high-placed Macbeth
            Shall live the lease of nature.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Lease and release} a mode of conveyance of freehold estates,
      formerly common in England and in New York. its place is
      now supplied by a simple deed of grant. --Burrill.
      --Warren's Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lease</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Record \Re*cord"\ (r?*k?rd"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Recorded}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Recording}.] [OE. recorden to repeat, remind,
   F. recorder, fr. L. recordari to remember; pref. re- re- +
   cor, cordis, the heart or mind. See {Cordial}, {Heart}.]
   1. To recall to mind; to recollect; to remember; to meditate.
      [Obs.] ``I it you record.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To repeat; to recite; to sing or play. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They longed to see the day, to hear the lark
            Record her hymns, and chant her carols blest.
                                                  --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To preserve the memory of, by committing to writing, to
      printing, to inscription, or the like; to make note of; to
      write or enter in a book or on parchment, for the purpose
      of preserving authentic evidence of; to register; to
      enroll; as, to record the proceedings of a court; to
      record historical events.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those things that are recorded of him . . . are
            written in the chronicles of the kings. --1 Esd. i.
                                                  42.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To record a deed}, {mortgage}, {lease}, etc., to have a copy
      of the same entered in the records of the office
      designated by law, for the information of the public.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lease</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lease
     n 1: property that is leased or rented out or let [syn: {rental},
           {letting}]
     2: a contract granting use or occupation of property during a
        specified time for a specified payment
     3: the period of time during which a contract conveying
        property to a person is in effect [syn: {term of a
        contract}]
     v 1: let for money; "We rented our apartment to friends while we
          were abroad" [syn: {rent}]
     2: hold under a lease or rental agreement; of goods and
        services [syn: {rent}, {hire}, {charter}]
     3: grant use or occupation of under a term of contract; "I am
        leasing my country estate to some foreigners" [syn: {let},
         {rent}]
     4: engage for service under a term of contract; "We took an
        apartment on a quiet street"; "Let's rent a car"; "Shall
        we take a guide in Rome?" [syn: {rent}, {hire}, {charter},
         {engage}, {take}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
