<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>leaving</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leaving</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Leave \Leave\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Left} (l[e^]ft); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Leaving}.] [OE. leven, AS. l?fan, fr. l[=a]f remnant,
   heritage; akin to lifian, libban, to live, orig., to remain;
   cf. bel[=i]fan to remain, G. bleiben, Goth. bileiban.
   [root]119. See {Live}, v.]
   1. To withdraw one's self from; to go away from; to depart
      from; as, to leave the house.
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore shall a man leave his father and his
            mother, and shall cleave unto his wife. --Gen. ii.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To let remain unremoved or undone; to let stay or
      continue, in distinction from what is removed or changed.
      [1913 Webster]

            If grape gatherers come to thee, would they not
            leave some gleaning grapes ?          --Jer. xlix.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

            These ought ye to have done, and not to leave the
            other undone.                         --Matt. xxiii.
                                                  23.
      [1913 Webster]

            Besides it leaveth a suspicion, as if more might be
            said than is expressed.               --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cease from; to desist from; to abstain from.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now leave complaining and begin your tea. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To desert; to abandon; to forsake; hence, to give up; to
      relinquish.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lo, we have left all, and have followed thee. --Mark
                                                  x. 28.
      [1913 Webster]

            The heresies that men do leave.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To let be or do without interference; as, I left him to
      his reflections; I leave my hearers to judge.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will leave you now to your gossiplike humor.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To put; to place; to deposit; to deliver; to commit; to
      submit -- with a sense of withdrawing one's self from; as,
      leave your hat in the hall; we left our cards; to leave
      the matter to arbitrators.
      [1913 Webster]

            Leave there thy gift before the altar and go thy
            way.                                  --Matt. v. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

            The foot
            That leaves the print of blood where'er it walks.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To have remaining at death; hence, to bequeath; as, he
      left a large estate; he left a good name; he left a legacy
      to his niece.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. to cause to be; -- followed by an adjective or adverb
      describing a state or condition; as, the losses due to
      fire leave me penniless; The cost of defending himself
      left Bill Clinton with a mountain of lawyers' bills.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   {To leave alone}.
      (a) To leave in solitude.
      (b) To desist or refrain from having to do with; as, to
          leave dangerous chemicals alone.

   {To leave off}.
      (a) To desist from; to forbear; to stop; as, to leave off
          work at six o'clock.
      (b) To cease wearing or using; to omit to put in the usual
          position; as, to leave off a garment; to leave off the
          tablecloth.
      (c) To forsake; as, to leave off a bad habit.

   {To leave out}, to omit; as, to leave out a word or name in
      writing.

   {To leave to one's self}, to let (one) be alone; to cease
      caring for (one).

   Syn: Syn&gt;- To quit; depart from; forsake; abandon;
        relinquish; deliver; bequeath; give up; forego; resign;
        surrender; forbear. See {Quit}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leaving</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Leave \Leave\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Leaved}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Leaving}]
   To send out leaves; to leaf; -- often with out. --G.
   Fletcher.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leaving</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>leaving
     n : act of departing [syn: {departure}, {going}, {going away}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
