<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>led</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>led</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LED
     
        &lt;electronics&gt; {Light-Emitting Diode}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>led</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Led \Led\ (l[e^]d), imp. &amp; p. p.
   of {Lead}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Led captain}. An obsequious follower or attendant. [Obs.]
      --Swift.

   {Led horse}, a sumpter horse, or a spare horse, that is led
      along.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>led</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lead \Lead\ (l[=e]d), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Led} (l[e^]d); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Leading}.] [OE. leden, AS. l[=ae]dan (akin to OS.
   l[=e]dian, D. leiden, G. leiten, Icel. le[imac][eth]a, Sw.
   leda, Dan. lede), properly a causative fr. AS. li[eth]an to
   go; akin to OHG. l[imac]dan, Icel. l[imac][eth]a, Goth.
   lei[thorn]an (in comp.). Cf. {Lode}, {Loath}.]
   1. To guide or conduct with the hand, or by means of some
      physical contact or connection; as, a father leads a
      child; a jockey leads a horse with a halter; a dog leads a
      blind man.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a blind man lead a blind man, both fall down in
            the ditch.                            --Wyclif
                                                  (Matt. xv.
                                                  14.)
      [1913 Webster]

            They thrust him out of the city, and led him unto
            the brow of the hill.                 --Luke iv. 29.
      [1913 Webster]

            In thy right hand lead with thee
            The mountain nymph, sweet Liberty.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To guide or conduct in a certain course, or to a certain
      place or end, by making the way known; to show the way,
      esp. by going with or going in advance of. Hence,
      figuratively: To direct; to counsel; to instruct; as, to
      lead a traveler; to lead a pupil.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord went before them by day in a pillar of a
            cloud, to lead them the way.          --Ex. xiii.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

            He leadeth me beside the still waters. --Ps. xxiii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

            This thought might lead me through the world's vain
            mask.
            Content, though blind, had I no better guide.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To conduct or direct with authority; to have direction or
      charge of; as, to lead an army, an exploring party, or a
      search; to lead a political party.
      [1913 Webster]

            Christ took not upon him flesh and blood that he
            might conquer and rule nations, lead armies, or
            possess places.                       --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To go or to be in advance of; to precede; hence, to be
      foremost or chief among; as, the big sloop led the fleet
      of yachts; the Guards led the attack; Demosthenes leads
      the orators of all ages.
      [1913 Webster]

            As Hesperus, that leads the sun his way. --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

            And lo ! Ben Adhem's name led all the rest. --Leigh
                                                  Hunt.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To draw or direct by influence, whether good or bad; to
      prevail on; to induce; to entice; to allure; as, to lead
      one to espouse a righteous cause.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was driven by the necessities of the times, more
            than led by his own disposition, to any rigor of
            actions.                              --Eikon
                                                  Basilike.
      [1913 Webster]

            Silly women, laden with sins, led away by divers
            lusts.                                --2 Tim. iii.
                                                  6 (Rev. Ver.).
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To guide or conduct one's self in, through, or along (a
      certain course); hence, to proceed in the way of; to
      follow the path or course of; to pass; to spend. Also, to
      cause (one) to proceed or follow in (a certain course).
      [1913 Webster]

            That we may lead a quiet and peaceable life. --1
                                                  Tim. ii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor thou with shadowed hint confuse
            A life that leads melodious days.     --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            You remember . . . the life he used to lead his wife
            and daughter.                         --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Cards &amp; Dominoes) To begin a game, round, or trick, with;
      as, to lead trumps; the double five was led.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To lead astray}, to guide in a wrong way, or into error; to
      seduce from truth or rectitude.

   {To lead captive}, to carry or bring into captivity.

   {To lead the way}, to show the way by going in front; to act
      as guide. --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>led</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LED
     Light-Emitting Diode
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>led</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lead
     n 1: a soft heavy toxic malleable metallic element; bluish white
          when freshly cut but tarnishes readily to dull gray;
          "the children were playing with lead soldiers" [syn: {Pb},
           {atomic number 82}]
     2: an advantage held by a competitor in a race; "he took the
        lead at the last turn"
     3: evidence pointing to a possible solution; "the police are
        following a promising lead"; "the trail led straight to
        the perpetrator" [syn: {track}, {trail}]
     4: a position of leadership (especially in the phrase `take the
        lead'); "he takes the lead in any group"; "we were just
        waiting for someone to take the lead"; "they didn't follow
        our lead"
     5: the angle between the direction a gun is aimed and the
        position of a moving target (correcting for the flight
        time of the missile)
     6: the introductory section of a story; "it was an amusing
        lead-in to a very serious matter" [syn: {lead-in}]
     7: an actor who plays a principal role [syn: {star}, {principal}]
     8: (baseball) the position taken by a base runner preparing to
        advance to the next base; "he took a long lead off first"
     9: an indication of potential opportunity; "he got a tip on the
        stock market"; "a good lead for a job" [syn: {tip}, {steer},
         {confidential information}, {wind}, {hint}]
     10: a news story of major importance [syn: {lead story}]
     11: the timing of ignition relative to the position of the
         piston in an internal-combustion engine [syn: {spark
         advance}]
     12: restraint consisting of a rope (or light chain) used to
         restrain an animal [syn: {leash}, {tether}]
     13: thin strip of metal used to separate lines of type in
         printing [syn: {leading}]
     14: mixture of graphite with clay in different degrees of
         hardness; the marking substance in a pencil [syn: {pencil
         lead}]
     15: a jumper that consists of a short piece of wire; "it was a
         tangle of jumper cables and clip leads" [syn: {jumper
         cable}, {jumper lead}]
     16: the playing of a card to start a trick in bridge; "the lead
         was in the dummy"
     v 1: take somebody somewhere; "We lead him to our chief"; "can
          you take me to the main entrance?"; "He conducted us to
          the palace" [syn: {take}, {direct}, {conduct}, {guide}]
     2: result in; "The water left a mark on the silk dress"; "Her
        blood left a stain on the napkin" [syn: {leave}, {result}]
     3: tend to or result in; "This remark lead to further arguments
        among the guests"
     4: travel in front of; go in advance of others; "The procession
        was headed by John" [syn: {head}]
     5: cause to undertake a certain action; "Her greed led her to
        forge the checks"
     6: stretch out over a distance, space, time, or scope; run or
        extend between two points or beyond a certain point;
        "Service runs all the way to Cranbury"; "His knowledge
        doesn't go very far"; "My memory extends back to my fourth
        year of life"; "The facts extend beyond a consideration of
        her personal assets" [syn: {run}, {go}, {pass}, {extend}]
     7: be in charge of; "Who is heading this project?" [syn: {head}]
     8: be ahead of others; be the first; "she topped her class
        every year" [syn: {top}]
     9: be conducive to; "The use of computers in the classroom lead
        to better writing" [syn: {contribute}, {conduce}]
     10: lead, as in the performance of a composition; "conduct an
         orchestra; Bairenboim conducted the Chicago symphony for
         years" [syn: {conduct}, {direct}]
     11: pass or spend; "lead a good life"
     12: lead, extend, or afford access; "This door goes to the
         basement"; "The road runs South" [syn: {go}]
     13: move ahead (of others) in time or space [syn: {precede}]
         [ant: {follow}]
     14: cause something to pass or lead somewhere; "Run the wire
         behind the cabinet" [syn: {run}]
     15: preside over; "John moderated the discussion" [syn: {moderate},
          {chair}]
     [also: {led}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>led</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LED
     n : diode such that light emitted at a p-n junction is
         proportional to the bias current; color depends on the
         material used [syn: {light-emitting diode}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>led</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>led
     See {lead}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
