<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>left</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>left</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Left \Left\, n.
   1. That part of surrounding space toward which the left side
      of one's body is turned; as, the house is on the left when
      you face North.
      [1913 Webster]

            Put that rose a little more to the left. --Ld.
                                                  Lytton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Those members of a legislative assembly (as in France) who
      are in the opposition; the advanced republicans and
      extreme radicals. They have their seats at the left-hand
      side of the presiding officer. See {Center}, and {Right}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>left</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Left \Left\ (l[e^]ft), imp. &amp; p. p.
   of {Leave}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>left</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Left \Left\, a. [OE. left, lift, luft; akin to Fries. leeft, OD.
   lucht, luft; cf. AS. left (equiv. to L. inanis), lyft[=a]dl
   palsy; or cf. AS. l[=e]f weak.]
   1. Of or pertaining to that side of the body in man on which
      the muscular action of the limbs is usually weaker than on
      the other side; -- opposed to {right}, when used in
      reference to a part of the body; as, the left hand, or
      arm; the left ear. Also said of the corresponding side of
      the lower animals.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Situated so that the left side of the body is toward it;
      as, the left side of a deliberative meeting is that to the
      left of the presiding officer; the left wing of an army is
      that to the left of the center to one facing an enemy.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Left bank of a river}, that which is on the left hand of a
      person whose face is turned downstream.

   {Left bower}. See under 2d {Bower}.

   {Left center}, the members whose sympathies are, in the main,
      with the members of the Left, but who do not favor extreme
      courses, and on occasions vote with the government. They
      sit between the Center and the extreme Left.

   {Over the left shoulder}, or {Over the left}, an old but
      still current colloquialism, or slang expression, used as
      an aside to indicate insincerity, negation, or disbelief;
      as, he said it, and it is true, -- over the left.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>left</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Leave \Leave\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Left} (l[e^]ft); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Leaving}.] [OE. leven, AS. l?fan, fr. l[=a]f remnant,
   heritage; akin to lifian, libban, to live, orig., to remain;
   cf. bel[=i]fan to remain, G. bleiben, Goth. bileiban.
   [root]119. See {Live}, v.]
   1. To withdraw one's self from; to go away from; to depart
      from; as, to leave the house.
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore shall a man leave his father and his
            mother, and shall cleave unto his wife. --Gen. ii.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To let remain unremoved or undone; to let stay or
      continue, in distinction from what is removed or changed.
      [1913 Webster]

            If grape gatherers come to thee, would they not
            leave some gleaning grapes ?          --Jer. xlix.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

            These ought ye to have done, and not to leave the
            other undone.                         --Matt. xxiii.
                                                  23.
      [1913 Webster]

            Besides it leaveth a suspicion, as if more might be
            said than is expressed.               --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cease from; to desist from; to abstain from.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now leave complaining and begin your tea. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To desert; to abandon; to forsake; hence, to give up; to
      relinquish.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lo, we have left all, and have followed thee. --Mark
                                                  x. 28.
      [1913 Webster]

            The heresies that men do leave.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To let be or do without interference; as, I left him to
      his reflections; I leave my hearers to judge.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will leave you now to your gossiplike humor.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To put; to place; to deposit; to deliver; to commit; to
      submit -- with a sense of withdrawing one's self from; as,
      leave your hat in the hall; we left our cards; to leave
      the matter to arbitrators.
      [1913 Webster]

            Leave there thy gift before the altar and go thy
            way.                                  --Matt. v. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

            The foot
            That leaves the print of blood where'er it walks.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To have remaining at death; hence, to bequeath; as, he
      left a large estate; he left a good name; he left a legacy
      to his niece.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. to cause to be; -- followed by an adjective or adverb
      describing a state or condition; as, the losses due to
      fire leave me penniless; The cost of defending himself
      left Bill Clinton with a mountain of lawyers' bills.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   {To leave alone}.
      (a) To leave in solitude.
      (b) To desist or refrain from having to do with; as, to
          leave dangerous chemicals alone.

   {To leave off}.
      (a) To desist from; to forbear; to stop; as, to leave off
          work at six o'clock.
      (b) To cease wearing or using; to omit to put in the usual
          position; as, to leave off a garment; to leave off the
          tablecloth.
      (c) To forsake; as, to leave off a bad habit.

   {To leave out}, to omit; as, to leave out a word or name in
      writing.

   {To leave to one's self}, to let (one) be alone; to cease
      caring for (one).

   Syn: Syn&gt;- To quit; depart from; forsake; abandon;
        relinquish; deliver; bequeath; give up; forego; resign;
        surrender; forbear. See {Quit}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>left</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>left
     adj 1: being or located on or directed toward the side of the body
            to the west when facing north; "my left hand"; "left
            center field"; "the left bank of a river is bank on
            your left side when you are facing downstream" [ant: {right}]
     2: not used up; "leftover meatloaf"; "she had a little money
        left over so she went to a movie"; "some odd dollars
        left"; "saved the remaining sandwiches for supper";
        "unexpended provisions" [syn: {leftover}, {left over(p)},
        {left(p)}, {odd}, {remaining}, {unexpended}]
     3: intended for the left hand; "I rarely lose a left-hand
        glove" [syn: {left(a)}, {left-hand(a)}]
     4: of or belonging to the political or intellectual left [ant:
        {center}, {right}]
     n 1: location near or direction toward the left side; i.e. the
          side to the north when a person or object faces east;
          "she stood on the left" [ant: {right}]
     2: those who support varying degrees of social or political or
        economic change designed to promote the public welfare
        [syn: {left wing}]
     3: the hand that is on the left side of the body; "jab with
        your left" [syn: {left hand}]
     4: the piece of ground in the outfield on the catcher's left
        [syn: {left field}]
     5: a turn to the left; "take a left at the corner"
     adv : toward or on the left; also used figuratively; "he looked
           right and left"; "the political party has moved left"
           [ant: {right}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>left</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>leave
     n 1: the period of time during which you are absent from work or
          duty; "a ten day's leave to visit his mother" [syn: {leave
          of absence}]
     2: permission to do something; "she was granted leave to speak"
     3: the act of departing politely; "he disliked long farewells";
        "he took his leave"; "parting is such sweet sorrow" [syn:
        {farewell}, {leave-taking}, {parting}]
     v 1: go away from a place; "At what time does your train leave?";
          "She didn't leave until midnight"; "The ship leaves at
          midnight" [syn: {go forth}, {go away}] [ant: {arrive}]
     2: go and leave behind, either intentionally or by neglect or
        forgetfulness; "She left a mess when she moved out"; "His
        good luck finally left him"; "her husband left her after
        20 years of marriage"; "she wept thinking she had been
        left behind"
     3: act or be so as to become in a specified state; "The
        inflation left them penniless"; "The president's remarks
        left us speechless"
     4: leave unchanged or undisturbed or refrain from taking;
        "leave it as is"; "leave the young fawn alone"; "leave the
        flowers that you see in the park behind" [syn: {leave
        alone}, {leave behind}]
     5: move out of or depart from; "leave the room"; "the fugitive
        has left the country" [syn: {exit}, {go out}, {get out}]
        [ant: {enter}]
     6: make a possibility or provide opportunity for; permit to be
        attainable or cause to remain; "This leaves no room for
        improvement"; "The evidence allows only one conclusion";
        "allow for mistakes"; "leave lots of time for the trip";
        "This procedure provides for lots of leeway" [syn: {allow
        for}, {allow}, {provide}]
     7: result in; "The water left a mark on the silk dress"; "Her
        blood left a stain on the napkin" [syn: {result}, {lead}]
     8: remove oneself from an association with or participation in;
        "She wants to leave"; "The teenager left home"; "She left
        her position with the Red Cross"; "He left the Senate
        after two terms"; "after 20 years with the same company,
        she pulled up stakes" [syn: {depart}, {pull up stakes}]
     9: put into the care or protection of someone; "He left the
        decision to his deputy"; "leave your child the nurse's
        care" [syn: {entrust}]
     10: leave or give by will after one's death; "My aunt bequeathed
         me all her jewelry"; "My grandfather left me his entire
         estate" [syn: {bequeath}, {will}] [ant: {disinherit}]
     11: have left or have as a remainder; "That left the four of
         us"; "19 minus 8 leaves 11"
     12: be survived by after one's death; "He left six children";
         "At her death, she left behind her husband and 11 cats"
         [syn: {leave behind}]
     13: tell or deposit (information) knowledge; "give a secret to
         the Russians"; "leave your name and address here" [syn: {impart},
          {give}, {pass on}]
     14: leave behind unintentionally; "I forgot my umbrella in the
         restaurant"; "I left my keys inside the car and locked
         the doors" [syn: {forget}]
     [also: {left}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>left</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>left
     See {leave}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
