<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>leg</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Leg \Leg\ (l[e^]g), n. [Icel. leggr; akin to Dan. l[ae]g calf of
   the leg, Sw. l["a]gg.]
   1. A limb or member of an animal used for supporting the
      body, and in running, climbing, and swimming; esp., that
      part of the limb between the knee and foot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which resembles a leg in form or use; especially, any
      long and slender support on which any object rests; as,
      the leg of a table; the leg of a pair of compasses or
      dividers.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The part of any article of clothing which covers the leg;
      as, the leg of a stocking or of a pair of trousers.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A bow, esp. in the phrase to make a leg; probably from
      drawing the leg backward in bowing. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He that will give a cap and make a leg in thanks for
            a favor he never received.            --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A disreputable sporting character; a blackleg. [Slang,
      Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) The course and distance made by a vessel on one
      tack or between tacks.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Steam Boiler) An extension of the boiler downward, in the
      form of a narrow space between vertical plates, sometimes
      nearly surrounding the furnace and ash pit, and serving to
      support the boiler; -- called also {water leg}.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Grain Elevator) The case containing the lower part of the
      belt which carries the buckets.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Cricket) A fielder whose position is on the outside, a
      little in rear of the batter.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Math.) Either side of a triangle distinguished from the
       base or, in a right triangle, from the hypotenuse; also,
       an indefinitely extending branch of a curve, as of a
       hyperbola.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. (Telephony) A branch or lateral circuit connecting an
       instrument with the main line.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. (Elec.) A branch circuit; one phase of a polyphase
       system.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {A good leg} (Naut.), a course sailed on a tack which is near
      the desired course.

   {Leg bail}, escape from custody by flight. [Slang]

   {Legs of an hyperbola} (or other curve) (Geom.), the branches
      of the curve which extend outward indefinitely.

   {Legs of a triangle}, the sides of a triangle; -- a name
      seldom used unless one of the sides is first distinguished
      by some appropriate term; as, the hypothenuse and two legs
      of a right-angled triangle.

   {On one's legs}, standing to speak.

   {On one's last legs}. See under {Last}.

   {To have legs} (Naut.), to have speed.

   {To stand on one's own legs}, to support one's self; to be
      independent.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Leg \Leg\ (l[e^]g), v. t.
   To use as a leg, with it as object:
   (a) To bow. [Obs.]
   (b) To run. [Low]
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>leg</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>leg
     n 1: a human limb; commonly used to refer to a whole limb but
          technically only the part between the knee and ankle
     2: a structure in animals that is similar to a human leg and
        used for locomotion
     3: one of the supports for a piece of furniture
     4: a part of a forked or branching shape; "he broke off one of
        the branches"; "they took the south fork" [syn: {branch},
        {fork}, {ramification}]
     5: the limb of an animal used for food
     6: a prosthesis that replaces a missing leg [syn: {peg}, {wooden
        leg}, {pegleg}]
     7: cloth covering consisting of the part of a garment that
        covers the leg
     8: (nautical) the distance traveled by a sailing vessel on a
        single tack
     9: a section or portion of a journey or course; "then we
        embarked on the second stage of our Caribbean cruise"
        [syn: {stage}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
