<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>legal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>legal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>legal
     
        Loosely used to mean "in accordance with all the relevant
        rules", especially in connection with some set of constraints
        defined by software.  "The older =+ alternate for += is no
        longer legal syntax in ANSI C."  "This parser processes each
        line of legal input the moment it sees the trailing linefeed."
        Hackers often model their work as a sort of game played with
        the environment in which the objective is to maneuver through
        the thicket of "natural laws" to achieve a desired objective.
        Their use of "legal" is flavoured as much by this game-playing
        sense as by the more conventional one having to do with courts
        and lawyers.  Compare {language lawyer}, {legalese}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>legal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Legal \Le"gal\ (l[=e]"gal), a. [L. legalis, fr. lex, legis, law;
   prob. orig., that which lies or is fixed (cf. L. lectus bed),
   and if so akin to E. lie, law: cf. F. l['e]gal. Cf. {Lie} to
   be prostrate, {Loyal}, {Leal}.]
   1. Created by, permitted by, in conformity with, or relating
      to, law; as, a legal obligation; a legal standard or test;
      a legal procedure; a legal claim; a legal trade; anything
      is legal which the laws do not forbid.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Theol.)
      (a) According to the law of works, as distinguished from
          free grace; or resting on works for salvation.
      (b) According to the old or Mosaic dispensation; in
          accordance with the law of Moses.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) Governed by the rules of law as distinguished from
      the rules of equity; as, legal estate; legal assets.
      --Bouvier. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Legal cap}. See under {Cap}.

   {Legal tender}.
      (a) The act of tendering in the performance of a contract
          or satisfaction of a claim that which the law
          prescribes or permits, and at such time and place as
          the law prescribes or permits.
      (b) That currency, or money, which the law authorizes a
          debtor to tender and requires a creditor to receive.
          It differs in different countries.

   Syn: Lawful; constitutional; legitimate; licit; authorized.
        See {Lawful}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>legal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>legal adj. Loosely used to mean `in accordance with all the relevant
   rules', esp. in connection with some set of constraints defined by
   software. "The older =+ alternate for += is no longer legal syntax in
   ANSI C." "This parser processes each line of legal input the moment it
   sees the trailing linefeed." Hackers often model their work as a sort of
   game played with the environment in which the objective is to maneuver
   through the thicket of `natural laws' to achieve a desired objective.
   Their use of `legal' is flavored as much by this game-playing sense as
   by the more conventional one having to do with courts and lawyers.
   Compare {language lawyer}, {legalese}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>legal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>legal
     adj 1: established by or founded upon law or official or accepted
            rules [ant: {illegal}]
     2: of or relating to jurisprudence; "legal loophole"
     3: having legal efficacy or force; "a sound title to the
        property" [syn: {sound}]
     4: relating to or characteristic of the profession of law; "the
        legal profession"
     5: allowed by official rules; "a legal pass receiver"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
