<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>length</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>length</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Length \Length\ (l[e^]ngth), n. [OE. lengthe, AS. leng[eth], fr.
   lang, long, long; akin to D. lengte, Dan. l[ae]ngde, Sw.
   l["a]ngd, Icel. lengd. See {Long}, a. ]
   1. The longest, or longer, dimension of any object, in
      distinction from {breadth} or {width}; extent of anything
      from end to end; the longest line which can be drawn
      through a body, parallel to its sides; as, the length of a
      church, or of a ship; the length of a rope or line.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A portion of space or of time considered as measured by
      its length; -- often in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            Large lengths of seas and shores.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The future but a length behind the past. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The quality or state of being long, in space or time;
      extent; duration; as, some sea birds are remarkable for
      the length of their wings; he was tired by the length of
      the sermon, and the length of his walk.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A single piece or subdivision of a series, or of a number
      of long pieces which may be connected together; as, a
      length of pipe; a length of fence.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Detail or amplification; unfolding; continuance as, to
      pursue a subject to a great length.
      [1913 Webster]

            May Heaven, great monarch, still augment your bliss
            With length of days, and every day like this.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Distance. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He had marched to the length of Exeter. --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At length}.
      (a) At or in the full extent; without abbreviation; as,
          let the name be inserted at length.
      (b) At the end or conclusion; after a long period. See
          Syn. of At last, under {Last}.

   {At arm's length}. See under {Arm}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>length</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Length \Length\, v. t.
   To lengthen. [Obs.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>length</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>length
     n 1: the linear extent in space from one end to the other; the
          longest horizontal dimension of something that is fixed
          in place; "the length of the table was 5 feet"
     2: continuance in time; "the ceremony was of short duration";
        "he complained about the length of time required" [syn: {duration}]
     3: the property of being the extent of something from beginning
        to end; "the editor limited the length of my article to
        500 words"
     4: size of the gap between two places; "the distance from New
        York to Chicago"; "he determined the length of the
        shortest line segment joining the two points" [syn: {distance}]
     5: a section of something that is long and narrow; "a length of
        timber"; "a length of tubing"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
