<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>letting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Let \Let\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Let} ({Letted} (l[e^]t"t[e^]d),
   [Obs].); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Letting}.] [OE. leten, l[ae]ten
   (past tense lat, let, p. p. laten, leten, lete), AS.
   l[=ae]tan (past tense l[=e]t, p. p. l[=ae]ten); akin to
   OFries. l[=e]ta, OS. l[=a]tan, D. laten, G. lassen, OHG.
   l[=a]zzan, Icel. l[=a]ta, Sw. l[*a]ta, Dan. lade, Goth.
   l[=e]tan, and L. lassus weary. The original meaning seems to
   have been, to let loose, let go, let drop. Cf. {Alas},
   {Late}, {Lassitude}, {Let} to hinder.]
   1. To leave; to relinquish; to abandon. [Obs. or Archaic,
      except when followed by alone or be.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . prayed him his voyage for to let.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet neither spins nor cards, ne cares nor frets,
            But to her mother Nature all her care she lets.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let me alone in choosing of my wife.  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To consider; to think; to esteem. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause; to make; -- used with the infinitive in the
      active form but in the passive sense; as, let make, i. e.,
      cause to be made; let bring, i. e., cause to be brought.
      [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            This irous, cursed wretch
            Let this knight's son anon before him fetch.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . thus let do slay hem all three. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Anon he let two coffers make.         --Gower.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To permit; to allow; to suffer; -- either affirmatively,
      by positive act, or negatively, by neglecting to restrain
      or prevent.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense, when followed by an infinitive, the
         latter is commonly without the sign to; as to let us
         walk, i. e., to permit or suffer us to walk. Sometimes
         there is entire omission of the verb; as, to let [to be
         or to go] loose.
         [1913 Webster]

               Pharaoh said, I will let you go.   --Ex. viii.
                                                  28.
         [1913 Webster]

               If your name be Horatio, as I am let to know it
               is.                                --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. To allow to be used or occupied for a compensation; to
      lease; to rent; to hire out; -- often with out; as, to let
      a farm; to let a house; to let out horses.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To give, grant, or assign, as a work, privilege, or
      contract; -- often with out; as, to let the building of a
      bridge; to let out the lathing and the plastering.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The active form of the infinitive of let, as of many
         other English verbs, is often used in a passive sense;
         as, a house to let (i. e., for letting, or to be let).
         This form of expression conforms to the use of the
         Anglo-Saxon gerund with to (dative infinitive) which
         was commonly so employed. See {Gerund}, 2. `` Your
         elegant house in Harley Street is to let.''
         --Thackeray. In the imperative mood, before the first
         person plural, let has a hortative force. `` Rise up,
         let us go.'' --Mark xiv. 42. `` Let us seek out some
         desolate shade.'' --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To let alone}, to leave; to withdraw from; to refrain from
      interfering with.

   {To let blood}, to cause blood to flow; to bleed.

   {To let down}.
      (a) To lower.
      (b) To soften in tempering; as, to let down tools,
          cutlery, and the like.

   {To let fly} or {To let drive}, to discharge with violence,
      as a blow, an arrow, or stone. See under {Drive}, and
      {Fly}.

   {To let in} or {To let into}.
      (a) To permit or suffer to enter; to admit.
      (b) To insert, or imbed, as a piece of wood, in a recess
          formed in a surface for the purpose.

   {To let loose}, to remove restraint from; to permit to wander
      at large.

   {To let off}.
      (a) To discharge; to let fly, as an arrow; to fire the
          charge of, as a gun.
      (b) To release, as from an engagement or obligation.
          [Colloq.]

   {To let out}.
      (a) To allow to go forth; as, to let out a prisoner.
      (b) To extend or loosen, as the folds of a garment; to
          enlarge; to suffer to run out, as a cord.
      (c) To lease; to give out for performance by contract, as
          a job.
      (d) To divulge.

   {To let slide}, to let go; to cease to care for. [Colloq.] ``
      Let the world slide.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>letting
     n : property that is leased or rented out or let [syn: {lease},
         {rental}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>letting
     See {let}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
