<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>letter</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Letter
   in Rom. 2:27, 29 means the outward form. The "oldness of the
   letter" (7:6) is a phrase which denotes the old way of literal
   outward obedience to the law as a system of mere external rules
   of conduct. In 2 Cor. 3:6, "the letter" means the Mosaic law as
   a written law. (See {WRITING}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Letter \Let"ter\, n. [From {Let} to hinder.]
   One who retards or hinders. [Archaic.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Letter \Let"ter\, n. [OE. lettre, F. lettre, OF. letre, fr. L.
   littera, litera, a letter; pl., an epistle, a writing,
   literature, fr. linere, litum, to besmear, to spread or rub
   over; because one of the earliest modes of writing was by
   graving the characters upon tablets smeared over or covered
   with wax. --Pliny, xiii. 11. See {Liniment}, and cf.
   {Literal}.]
   1. A mark or character used as the representative of a sound,
      or of an articulation of the human organs of speech; a
      first element of written language.
      [1913 Webster]

            And a superscription also was written over him in
            letters of Greek, and Latin, and Hebrew. --Luke
                                                  xxiii. 38.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A written or printed communication; a message expressed in
      intelligible characters on something adapted to
      conveyance, as paper, parchment, etc.; an epistle.
      [1913 Webster]

            The style of letters ought to be free, easy, and
            natural.                              --Walsh.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A writing; an inscription. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            None could expound what this letter meant.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Verbal expression; literal statement or meaning; exact
      signification or requirement.
      [1913 Webster]

            We must observe the letter of the law, without doing
            violence to the reason of the law and the intention
            of the lawgiver.                      --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            I broke the letter of it to keep the sense.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Print.) A single type; type, collectively; a style of
      type.
      [1913 Webster]

            Under these buildings . . . was the king's printing
            house, and that famous letter so much esteemed.
                                                  --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. pl. Learning; erudition; as, a man of letters.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. A letter; an epistle. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Teleg.) A telegram longer than an ordinary message sent
      at rates lower than the standard message rate in
      consideration of its being sent and delivered subject to
      priority in service of regular messages. Such telegrams
      are called by the Western Union Company {day letters}, or
      {night letters} according to the time of sending, and by
      The Postal Telegraph Company {day lettergrams}, or {night
      lettergrams}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Dead letter}, {Drop letter}, etc. See under {Dead}, {Drop},
      etc.

   {Letter book}, a book in which copies of letters are kept.

   {Letter box}, a box for the reception of letters to be mailed
      or delivered.

   {Letter carrier}, a person who carries letters; a postman;
      specif., an officer of the post office who carries letters
      to the persons to whom they are addressed, and collects
      letters to be mailed.

   {Letter cutter}, one who engraves letters or letter punches.
      

   {Letter lock}, a lock that can not be opened when fastened,
      unless certain movable lettered rings or disks forming a
      part of it are in such a position (indicated by a
      particular combination of the letters) as to permit the
      bolt to be withdrawn.
      [1913 Webster]

            A strange lock that opens with AMEN.  --Beau. &amp; Fl.

   {Letter paper}, paper for writing letters on; especially, a
      size of paper intermediate between note paper and
      foolscap. See {Paper}.

   {Letter punch}, a steel punch with a letter engraved on the
      end, used in making the matrices for type.

   {Letters of administration} (Law), the instrument by which an
      administrator or administratrix is authorized to
      administer the goods and estate of a deceased person.

   {Letter of attorney}, {Letter of credit}, etc. See under
      {Attorney}, {Credit}, etc.

   {Letter of license}, a paper by which creditors extend a
      debtor's time for paying his debts.

   {Letters close} or {Letters clause} (Eng. Law.), letters or
      writs directed to particular persons for particular
      purposes, and hence closed or sealed on the outside; --
      distinguished from {letters patent}. --Burrill.

   {Letters of orders} (Eccl.), a document duly signed and
      sealed, by which a bishop makes it known that he has
      regularly ordained a certain person as priest, deacon,
      etc.

   {Letters patent}, {Letters overt}, or {Letters open} (Eng.
      Law), a writing executed and sealed, by which power and
      authority are granted to a person to do some act, or enjoy
      some right; as, letters patent under the seal of England.
      The common commercial {patent} is a derivative form of
      such a right.

   {Letter-sheet envelope}, a stamped sheet of letter paper
      issued by the government, prepared to be folded and sealed
      for transmission by mail without an envelope.

   {Letters testamentary} (Law), an instrument granted by the
      proper officer to an executor after probate of a will,
      authorizing him to act as executor.

   {Letter writer}.
      (a) One who writes letters.
      (b) A machine for copying letters.
      (c) A book giving directions and forms for the writing of
          letters.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Letter \Let"ter\ (l[e^]t"t[~e]r), n. [From {Let} to permit.]
   One who lets or permits; one who lets anything for hire.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Letter \Let"ter\ (l[e^]t"t[~e]r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lettered}
   (-t[~e]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Lettering}.]
   To impress with letters; to mark with letters or words; as, a
   book gilt and lettered.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Attorney \At*tor"ney\, n.; pl. {Attorneys}. [OE. aturneye, OF.
   atorn['e], p. p. of atorner: cf. LL. atturnatus, attornatus,
   fr. attornare. See {Attorn}.]
   1. A substitute; a proxy; an agent. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            And will have no attorney but myself. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law)
      (a) One who is legally appointed by another to transact
          any business for him; an attorney in fact.
      (b) A legal agent qualified to act for suitors and
          defendants in legal proceedings; an attorney at law.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: An attorney is either public or private. A private
         attorney, or an attorney in fact, is a person appointed
         by another, by a letter or power of attorney, to
         transact any business for him out of court; but in a
         more extended sense, this class includes any agent
         employed in any business, or to do any act in pais, for
         another. A public attorney, or attorney at law, is a
         practitioner in a court of law, legally qualified to
         prosecute and defend actions in such court, on the
         retainer of clients. --Bouvier. -- The attorney at law
         answers to the procurator of the civilians, to the
         solicitor in chancery, and to the proctor in the
         ecclesiastical and admiralty courts, and all of these
         are comprehended under the more general term lawyer. In
         Great Britain and in some states of the United States,
         attorneys are distinguished from counselors in that the
         business of the former is to carry on the practical and
         formal parts of the suit. In many states of the United
         States however, no such distinction exists. In England,
         since 1873, attorneys at law are by statute called
         solicitors.
         [1913 Webster]

   {A power}, {letter}, or {warrant}, {of attorney}, a written
      authority from one person empowering another to transact
      business for him.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>letter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>letter
     n 1: a written message addressed to a person or organization;
          "mailed an indignant letter to the editor" [syn: {missive}]
     2: the conventional characters of the alphabet used to
        represent speech; "his grandmother taught him his letters"
        [syn: {letter of the alphabet}, {alphabetic character}]
     3: a strictly literal interpretation (as distinct from the
        intention); "he followed instructions to the letter"; "he
        obeyed the letter of the law"
     4: an award earned by participation in a school sport; "he won
        letters in three sports" [syn: {varsity letter}]
     5: owner who lets another person use something (housing
        usually) for hire
     v 1: win an athletic letter
     2: set down or print with letters
     3: mark letters on or mark with letters
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
