<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>level</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>level</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Level \Lev"el\ (l[e^]v"[e^]l), n. [OE. level, livel, OF. livel,
   F. niveau, fr. L. libella level, water level, a plumb level,
   dim. of libra pound, measure for liquids, balance, water
   poise, level. Cf. {Librate}, {Libella}.]
   1. A line or surface to which, at every point, a vertical or
      plumb line is perpendicular; a line or surface which is
      everywhere parallel to the surface of still water; -- this
      is the true level, and is a curve or surface in which all
      points are equally distant from the center of the earth,
      or rather would be so if the earth were an exact sphere.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A horizontal line or plane; that is, a straight line or a
      plane which is tangent to a true level at a given point
      and hence parallel to the horizon at that point; -- this
      is the apparent level at the given point.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An approximately horizontal line or surface at a certain
      degree of altitude, or distance from the center of the
      earth; as, to climb from the level of the coast to the
      level of the plateau and then descend to the level of the
      valley or of the sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            After draining of the level in Northamptonshire.
                                                  --Sir M. Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shot from the deadly level of a gun.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, figuratively, a certain position, rank, standard,
      degree, quality, character, etc., conceived of as in one
      of several planes of different elevation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Providence, for the most part, sets us on a level.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Somebody there of his own level.      --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            Be the fair level of thy actions laid
            As temperance wills and prudence may persuade.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A uniform or average height; a normal plane or altitude; a
      condition conformable to natural law or which will secure
      a level surface; as, moving fluids seek a level.
      [1913 Webster]

            When merit shall find its level.      --F. W.
                                                  Robertson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mech. &amp; Surv.)
      (a) An instrument by which to find a horizontal line, or
          adjust something with reference to a horizontal line.
      (b) A measurement of the difference of altitude of two
          points, by means of a level; as, to take a level.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. A horizontal passage, drift, or adit, in a mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Air level}, {a spirit level}. See {Spirit level} (below).

   {Box level}, a spirit level in which a glass-covered box is
      used instead of a tube.

   {Carpenter's level}, {Mason's level}, either the plumb level
      or a straight bar of wood, in which is imbedded a small
      spirit level.

   {Level of the sea}, the imaginary level from which heights
      and depths are calculated, taken at a mean distance
      between high and low water.

   {Line of levels}, a connected series of measurements, by
      means of a level, along a given line, as of a railroad, to
      ascertain the profile of the ground.

   {Plumb level}, one in which a horizontal bar is placed in
      true position by means of a plumb line, to which it is at
      right angles.

   {Spirit level}, one in which the adjustment to the horizon is
      shown by the position of a bubble in alcohol or ether
      contained in a nearly horizontal glass tube, or a circular
      box with a glass cover.

   {Surveyor's level}, a telescope, with a spirit level
      attached, and with suitable screws, etc., for accurate
      adjustment, the whole mounted on a tripod, for use in
      leveling; -- called also {leveling instrument}.

   {Water level}, an instrument to show the level by means of
      the surface of water in a trough, or in upright tubes
      connected by a pipe.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>level</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Level \Lev"el\ (l[e^]v"[e^]l), a.
   1. Even; flat; having no part higher than another; having, or
      conforming to, the curvature which belongs to the
      undisturbed liquid parts of the earth's surface; as, a
      level field; level ground; the level surface of a pond or
      lake.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ample spaces o'er the smooth
            And level pavement.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Coinciding or parallel with the plane of the horizon;
      horizontal; as, the telescope is now level.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Even with anything else; of the same height; on the same
      line or plane; on the same footing; of equal importance;
      -- followed by with, sometimes by to.
      [1913 Webster]

            Young boys and girls
            Are level now with men; the odds is gone. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Everything lies level to our wish.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Straightforward; direct; clear; open.
      [1913 Webster]

            A very plain and level account.       --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Well balanced; even; just; steady; impartial; as, a level
      head; a level understanding. [Colloq.] `` A level
      consideration.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Phonetics) Of even tone; without rising or falling
      inflection. --H. Sweet.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Level line} (Shipbuilding), the outline of a section which
      is horizontal crosswise, and parallel with the rabbet of
      the keel lengthwise.

   {Level surface} (Physics), an equipotential surface at right
      angles at every point to the lines of force.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>level</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Level \Lev"el\, v. i.
   1. To be level; to be on a level with, or on an equality
      with, something; hence, to accord; to agree; to suit.
      [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            With such accommodation and besort
            As levels with her breeding.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To aim a gun, spear, etc., horizontally; hence, to aim or
      point a weapon in direct line with the mark; fig., to
      direct the eye, mind, or effort, directly to an object;
      as, he leveled a gun at the bandit and fired.
      [1913 Webster]

            The foeman may with as great aim level at the edge
            of a penknife.                        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The glory of God and the good of his church . . .
            ought to be the mark whereat we also level.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            She leveled at our purposes.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>level</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Level \Lev"el\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Leveled} (-[e^]ld) or
   {Levelled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Leveling} or {Levelling}.]
   1. To make level; to make horizontal; to bring to the
      condition of a level line or surface; hence, to make flat
      or even; as, to level a road, a walk, or a garden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring to a lower level; to overthrow; to topple down;
      to reduce to a flat surface; to lower.
      [1913 Webster]

            And their proud structures level with the ground.
                                                  --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

            He levels mountains and he raises plains. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bring to a horizontal position, as a gun; hence, to
      point in taking aim; to aim; to direct.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bertram de Gordon, standing on the castle wall,
            leveled a quarrel out of a crossbow.  --Stow.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Figuratively, to bring to a common level or plane, in
      respect of rank, condition, character, privilege, etc.;
      as, to level all the ranks and conditions of men.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To adjust or adapt to a certain level; as, to level
      remarks to the capacity of children.
      [1913 Webster]

            For all his mind on honor fixed is,
            To which he levels all his purposes.  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>level</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>level
     adj 1: having a horizontal surface in which no part is higher or
            lower than another; "a flat desk"; "acres of level
            farmland"; "a plane surface" [syn: {flat}, {plane}]
     2: not showing abrupt variations; "spoke in a level voice";
        "she gave him a level look"- Louis Auchincloss [syn: {unwavering}]
     3: being on a precise horizontal plane; "a billiard table must
        be level"
     4: oriented at right angles to the plumb; "the picture is
        level"
     5: of the score in a contest; "the score is tied" [syn: {tied(p)},
         {even}, {level(p)}]
     n 1: a position on a scale of intensity or amount or quality; "a
          moderate degree of intelligence"; "a high level of care
          is required"; "it is all a matter of degree" [syn: {degree},
           {grade}]
     2: a relative position or degree of value in a graded group;
        "lumber of the highest grade" [syn: {grade}, {tier}]
     3: a specific identifiable position in a continuum or series or
        especially in a process; "a remarkable degree of
        frankness"; "at what stage are the social sciences?" [syn:
         {degree}, {stage}, {point}]
     4: height above ground; "the water reached ankle level"; "the
        pictures were at the same level"
     5: indicator that establishes the horizontal when a bubble is
        centered in a tube of liquid [syn: {spirit level}]
     6: a flat surface at right angles to a plumb line; "park the
        car on the level" [syn: {horizontal surface}]
     7: structure consisting of a room or set of rooms comprising a
        single level of a multilevel building; "what level is the
        office on?" [syn: {floor}, {storey}, {story}]
     8: an abstract place usually conceived as having depth; "a good
        actor communicates on several levels"; "a simile has at
        least two layers of meaning"; "the mind functions on many
        strata simultaneously" [syn: {layer}, {stratum}]
     v 1: aim at; "level criticism or charges at somebody"
     2: tear down so as to make flat with the ground; "The building
        was levelled" [syn: {raze}, {rase}, {dismantle}, {tear
        down}, {take down}, {pull down}] [ant: {raise}]
     3: make level or straight; "level the ground" [syn: {flush}, {even
        out}, {even}]
     4: direct into a position for use; "point a gun"; "He charged
        his weapon at me" [syn: {charge}, {point}]
     5: talk frankly with; lay it on the line; "I have to level with
        you"
     6: become level or even; "The ground levelled off" [syn: {level
        off}]
     [also: {levelling}, {levelled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
