<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>life</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LIFE, n.  A spiritual pickle preserving the body from decay.  We live
in daily apprehension of its loss; yet when lost it is not missed. 
The question, "Is life worth living?" has been much discussed;
particularly by those who think it is not, many of whom have written
at great length in support of their view and by careful observance of
the laws of health enjoyed for long terms of years the honors of
successful controversy.

    "Life's not worth living, and that's the truth,"
    Carelessly caroled the golden youth.
    In manhood still he maintained that view
    And held it more strongly the older he grew.
    When kicked by a jackass at eighty-three,
    "Go fetch me a surgeon at once!" cried he.
                                                             Han Soper


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Life
   generally of physical life (Gen. 2:7; Luke 16:25, etc.); also
   used figuratively (1) for immortality (Heb. 7:16); (2) conduct
   or manner of life (Rom. 6:4); (3) spiritual life or salvation
   (John 3:16, 17, 18, 36); (4) eternal life (Matt. 19:16, 17; John
   3:15); of God and Christ as the absolute source and cause of all
   life (John 1:4; 5:26, 39; 11:25; 12:50).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Life
     
        &lt;games&gt; The first popular {cellular automata} based
        {artificial life} "game".  Life was invented by British
        mathematician {John Horton Conway} in 1970 and was first
        introduced publicly in "Scientific American" later that year.
     
        Conway first devised what he called "The Game of Life" and
        "ran" it using plates placed on floor tiles in his house.
        Because of he ran out of floor space and kept stepping on the
        plates, he later moved to doing it on paper or on a
        checkerboard, and then moved to running Life as a computer
        program on a {PDP-7}.  That first implementation of Life as a
        computer program was written by M. J. T. Guy and
        {S. R. Bourne} (the author of {Unix}'s {Bourne shell}).
     
        Life uses a rectangular grid of binary (live or dead) cells
        each of which is updated at each step according to the
        previous state of its eight neighbours as follows: a live cell
        with less than two, or more than three, live neighbours dies.
        A dead cell with exactly three neighbours becomes alive.
        Other cells do not change.
     
        While the rules are fairly simple, the patterns that can arise
        are of a complexity resembling that of organic systems -- hence
        the name "Life".
     
        Many hackers pass through a stage of fascination with Life,
        and hackers at various places contributed heavily to the
        mathematical analysis of this game (most notably {Bill Gosper}
        at {MIT}, who even implemented Life in {TECO}!; see
        {Gosperism}).  When a hacker mentions "life", he is more
        likely to mean this game than the magazine, the breakfast
        cereal, the 1950s-era board game or the human state of
        existence.
     
        {Yahoo!
        (http://www.yahoo.com/Science/Artificial_Life/Conway_s_Game_of_Life/)}.
     
        {Demonstration
        (http://www.research.digital.com/nsl/projects/life/)}.
     
        ["Scientific American" 223, October 1970, p120-123, 224;
        February 1971 p121-117, Martin Gardner].
     
        ["The Garden in The Machine: the Emerging Science of
        Artificial Life", Claus Emmeche, 1994].
     
        ["Winning Ways, For Your Mathematical Plays", Elwyn
        R. Berlekamp, John Horton Conway and Richard K. Guy, 1982].
     
        ["The Recursive Universe: Cosmic Complexity and the Limits of
        Scientific Knowledge", William Poundstone, 1985].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1997-09-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LIFE
     
        &lt;language&gt; Logic of Inheritance, Functions and Equations.
     
        An {object-oriented}, {functional}, {constraint}-based
        language by Hassan Ait-Kacy &lt;hak@prl.dec.com&gt; et al of {MCC},
        Austin TX, 1987.  LIFE integrates ideas from {LOGIN} and
        {LeFun}.
     
        Mailing list: life-users@prl.dec.com.
     
        See also {Wild_LIFE}.
     
        ["Is There a Meaning to LIFE?", H. Ait-Kacy et al, Intl Conf
        on Logic Prog, 1991].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-04-21)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>life
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; The opposite of {Usenet}.  As in "{Get a life!}"
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-04-21)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Life \Life\ (l[imac]f), n.; pl. {Lives} (l[imac]vz). [AS.
   l[imac]f; akin to D. lijf body, G. leib body, MHG. l[imac]p
   life, body, OHG. l[imac]b life, Icel. l[imac]f, life, body,
   Sw. lif, Dan. liv, and E. live, v. [root]119. See {Live}, and
   cf. {Alive}.]
   1. The state of being which begins with generation, birth, or
      germination, and ends with death; also, the time during
      which this state continues; that state of an animal or
      plant in which all or any of its organs are capable of
      performing all or any of their functions; -- used of all
      animal and vegetable organisms.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of human beings: The union of the soul and body; also, the
      duration of their union; sometimes, the deathless quality
      or existence of the soul; as, man is a creature having an
      immortal life.
      [1913 Webster]

            She shows a body rather than a life.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Philos) The potential principle, or force, by which the
      organs of animals and plants are started and continued in
      the performance of their several and co["o]perative
      functions; the vital force, whether regarded as physical
      or spiritual.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Figuratively: The potential or animating principle, also,
      the period of duration, of anything that is conceived of
      as resembling a natural organism in structure or
      functions; as, the life of a state, a machine, or a book;
      authority is the life of government.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A certain way or manner of living with respect to
      conditions, circumstances, character, conduct, occupation,
      etc.; hence, human affairs; also, lives, considered
      collectively, as a distinct class or type; as, low life; a
      good or evil life; the life of Indians, or of miners.
      [1913 Webster]

            That which before us lies in daily life. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            By experience of life abroad in the world. --Ascham.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lives of great men all remind us
            We can make our lives sublime.        --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is from high life high characters are drawn.
                                                  --Pope
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Animation; spirit; vivacity; vigor; energy.
      [1913 Webster]

            No notion of life and fire in fancy and in words.
                                                  --Felton.
      [1913 Webster]

            That gives thy gestures grace and life.
                                                  --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. That which imparts or excites spirit or vigor; that upon
      which enjoyment or success depends; as, he was the life of
      the company, or of the enterprise.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. The living or actual form, person, thing, or state; as, a
      picture or a description from, the life.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A person; a living being, usually a human being; as, many
      lives were sacrificed.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The system of animal nature; animals in general, or
       considered collectively.
       [1913 Webster]

             Full nature swarms with life.        --Thomson.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. An essential constituent of life, esp: the blood.
       [1913 Webster]

             The words that I speak unto you . . . they are
             life.                                --John vi. 63.
       [1913 Webster]

             The warm life came issuing through the wound.
                                                  --Pope
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A history of the acts and events of a life; a biography;
       as, Johnson wrote the life of Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Enjoyment in the right use of the powers; especially, a
       spiritual existence; happiness in the favor of God;
       heavenly felicity.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Something dear to one as one's existence; a darling; --
       used as a term of endearment.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Life forms the first part of many compounds, for the
         most part of obvious meaning; as, life-giving,
         life-sustaining, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Life annuity}, an annuity payable during one's life.

   {Life arrow}, {Life rocket}, {Life shot}, an arrow, rocket,
      or shot, for carrying an attached line to a vessel in
      distress in order to save life.

   {Life assurance}. See {Life insurance}, below.

   {Life buoy}. See {Buoy}.

   {Life car}, a water-tight boat or box, traveling on a line
      from a wrecked vessel to the shore. In it person are
      hauled through the waves and surf.

   {Life drop}, a drop of vital blood. --Byron.

   {Life estate} (Law), an estate which is held during the term
      of some certain person's life, but does not pass by
      inheritance.

   {Life everlasting} (Bot.), a plant with white or yellow
      persistent scales about the heads of the flowers, as
      {Antennaria}, and {Gnaphalium}; cudweed.

   {Life of an execution} (Law), the period when an execution is
      in force, or before it expires.

   {Life guard}. (Mil.) See under {Guard}.

   {Life insurance}, the act or system of insuring against
      death; a contract by which the insurer undertakes, in
      consideration of the payment of a premium (usually at
      stated periods), to pay a stipulated sum in the event of
      the death of the insured or of a third person in whose
      life the insured has an interest.

   {Life interest}, an estate or interest which lasts during
      one's life, or the life of another person, but does not
      pass by inheritance.

   {Life land} (Law), land held by lease for the term of a life
      or lives.

   {Life line}.
       (a) (Naut.) A line along any part of a vessel for the
           security of sailors.
       (b) A line attached to a life boat, or to any life saving
           apparatus, to be grasped by a person in the water.

   {Life rate}, rate of premium for insuring a life.

   {Life rent}, the rent of a life estate; rent or property to
      which one is entitled during one's life.

   {Life school}, a school for artists in which they model,
      paint, or draw from living models.

   {Lifetable}, a table showing the probability of life at
      different ages.

   {To lose one's life}, to die.

   {To seek the life of}, to seek to kill.

   {To the life}, so as closely to resemble the living person or
      the subject; as, the portrait was drawn to the life.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>life n. 1. A cellular-automata game invented by John Horton Conway and
   first introduced publicly by Martin Gardner ("Scientific American",
   October 1970); the game's popularity had to wait a few years for
   computers on which it could reasonably be played, as it's no fun to
   simulate the cells by hand. Many hackers pass through a stage of
   fascination with it, and hackers at various places contributed heavily
   to the mathematical analysis of this game (most notably Bill Gosper at
   MIT, who even implemented life in {TECO}!; see {Gosperism}). When a
   hacker mentions `life', he is much more likely to mean this game than
   the magazine, the breakfast cereal, or the human state of existence. 2.
   The opposite of {Usenet}. As in "{Get a life!}"


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LIFE
     Laboratory for International Fuzzy Engineering [research] (MITI)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LIFE
     Logistics Interface For manufacturing Environment
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>life</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>life
     n 1: a characteristic state or mode of living; "social life";
          "city life"; "real life"
     2: the course of existence of an individual; the actions and
        events that occur in living; "he hoped for a new life in
        Australia"; "he wanted to live his own life without
        interference from others"
     3: the experience of living; the course of human events and
        activities; "he could no longer cope with the complexities
        of life" [syn: {living}]
     4: the condition of living or the state of being alive; "while
        there's life there's hope"; "life depends on many chemical
        and physical processes" [syn: {animation}, {living}, {aliveness}]
     5: the period during which something is functional (as between
        birth and death); "the battery had a short life"; "he
        lived a long and happy life" [syn: {lifetime}, {lifespan}]
     6: the period between birth and the present time; "I have known
        him all his life"
     7: animation and energy in action or expression; "it was a
        heavy play and the actors tried in vain to give life to
        it" [syn: {liveliness}, {spirit}, {sprightliness}]
     8: an account of the series of events making up a person's life
        [syn: {biography}, {life story}, {life history}]
     9: the period from the present until death; "he appointed
        himself emperor for life"
     10: a living person; "his heroism saved a life"
     11: living things collectively; "the oceans are teeming with
         life"
     12: a motive for living; "pottery was his life"
     13: the organic phenomenon that distinguishes living organisms
         from nonliving ones; "there is no life on the moon"
     14: a prison term lasting as long as the prisoner lives; "he got
         life for killing the guard" [syn: {life sentence}]
     [also: {lives} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
