<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lift</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lift \Lift\ (l[i^]ft), n. [AS. lyft air. See {Loft}.]
   The sky; the atmosphere; the firmament. [Obs. or Scot.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lift \Lift\ (l[i^]ft), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lifted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Lifting}.] [Icel. lypta, fr. lopt air; akin to Sw.
   lyfta to lift, Dan. l["o]fte, G. l["u]ften; -- prop., to
   raise into the air. See {Loft}, and cf. 1st {Lift}.]
   1. To move in a direction opposite to that of gravitation; to
      raise; to elevate; to bring up from a lower place to a
      higher; to upheave; sometimes implying a continued support
      or holding in the higher place; -- said of material
      things; as, to lift the foot or the hand; to lift a chair
      or a burden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To raise, elevate, exalt, improve, in rank, condition,
      estimation, character, etc.; -- often with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Roman virtues lift up mortal man. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lest, being lifted up with pride.     --1 Tim. iii.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bear; to support. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To collect, as moneys due; to raise.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [Perh. a different word, and akin to Goth. hliftus thief,
      hlifan to steal, L. clepere, Gr. kle`ptein. Cf.
      {Shoplifter}.] To steal; to carry off by theft (esp.
      cattle); as, to lift a drove of cattle.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In old writers, lift is sometimes used for lifted.
         [1913 Webster]

               He ne'er lift up his hand but conquered. --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   {To lift up}, to raise or elevate; in the Scriptures,
      specifically, to elevate upon the cross. --John viii. 28.

   {To lift up the eyes}. To look up; to raise the eyes, as in
      prayer. --Ps. cxxi. 1.

   {To lift up the feet}, to come speedily to one's relief.
      --Ps. lxxiv. 3.

   {To lift up the hand}.
      (a) To take an oath. --Gen. xiv. 22.
      (b) To pray. --Ps. xxviii. 2.
      (c) To engage in duty. --Heb. xii. 12.

   {To lift up the hand against}, to rebel against; to assault;
      to attack; to injure; to oppress. --Job xxxi. 21.

   {To lift up one's head}, to cause one to be exalted or to
      rejoice. --Gen. xl. 13. --Luke xxi. 28.

   {To lift up the heel against}, to treat with insolence or
      unkindness. --John xiii.18.

   {To lift up the voice}, to cry aloud; to call out. --Gen.
      xxi. 16.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lift \Lift\ (l[i^]ft), v. i.
   1. To try to raise something; to exert the strength for
      raising or bearing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Strained by lifting at a weight too heavy. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To rise; to become or appear raised or elevated; as, the
      fog lifts; the land lifts to a ship approaching it.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. [See {Lift}, v. t., 5.] To steal; also, to live by theft.
      --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lift \Lift\, n.
   1. Act of lifting; also, that which is lifted.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The space or distance through which anything is lifted;
      as, a long lift. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Help; assistance, as by lifting. Hence: A ride in a
      vehicle, given by the vehicle's owner to another person as
      a favor -- usually in ``give a lift'' or ``got a lift'';
      as, to give one a lift in a wagon; Jack gave me a lift
      into town. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            The goat gives the fox a lift.        --L'Estrange.

   4. That by means of which a person or thing lifts or is
      lifted; as:
      (a) A hoisting machine; an elevator; a dumb waiter.
          [Chiefly Brit.]
      (b) An exercising machine.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. A rise; a degree of elevation; as, the lift of a lock in
      canals.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A lift gate. See {Lift gate}, below. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Naut.) A rope leading from the masthead to the extremity
      of a yard below; -- used for raising or supporting the end
      of the yard.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mach.) One of the steps of a cone pulley.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Shoemaking) A layer of leather in the heel.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Horology) That portion of the vibration of a balance
       during which the impulse is given. --Saunier.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A brightening of the spirits; encouragement; as, the
       campaign workers got a lift from the President's
       endorsement.
       [PJC]

   {Dead lift}. See under {Dead}. --Swift.

   {Lift bridge}, a kind of drawbridge, the movable part of
      which is lifted, instead of being drawn aside.

   {Lift gate}, a gate that is opened by lifting.

   {Lift hammer}. See {Tilt hammer}.

   {Lift lock}, a canal lock.

   {Lift pump}, a lifting pump.

   {Lift tenter} (Windmills), a governor for regulating the
      speed by adjusting the sails, or for adjusting the action
      of grinding machinery according to the speed.

   {Lift wall} (Canal Lock), the cross wall at the head of the
      lock.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Elevator \El"e*va`tor\, n. [L., one who raises up, a deliverer:
   cf. F. ['e]l['e]vateur.]
   1. One who, or that which, raises or lifts up anything.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A mechanical contrivance, usually an endless belt or chain
      with a series of scoops or buckets, for transferring grain
      to an upper loft for storage.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A cage or platform (called an elevator car) and the
      hoisting machinery in a hotel, warehouse, mine, etc., for
      conveying persons, goods, etc., to or from different
      floors or levels; -- called in England a {lift}; the cage
      or platform itself.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A building for elevating, storing, and discharging, grain.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Anat.) A muscle which serves to raise a part of the body,
      as the leg or the eye.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Surg.) An instrument for raising a depressed portion of a
      bone.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (A["e]ronautics) A movable plane or group of planes used
      to control the altitude or fore-and-aft poise or
      inclination of an airship or flying machine.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Elevator head}, {Elevator leg}, &amp; {Elevator boot}, the boxes
      in which the upper pulley, belt, and lower pulley,
      respectively, run in a grain elevator. [1913 Webster]

   {Elevator shoes}, shoes having unusually thick soles and
      heels, designed to make a person appear taller than he or
      she actually is. [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lift</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lift
     n 1: the act of giving temporary assistance
     2: the component of the aerodynamic forces acting on an airfoil
        that opposes gravity [syn: {aerodynamic lift}]
     3: the event of something being raised upward; "an elevation of
        the temperature in the afternoon"; "a raising of the land
        resulting from volcanic activity" [syn: {elevation}, {raising}]
     4: a wave that lifts the surface of the water or ground [syn: {rise}]
     5: a powered conveyance that carries skiers up a hill [syn: {ski
        tow}, {ski lift}]
     6: a device worn in a shoe or boot to make the wearer look
        taller or to correct a shortened leg
     7: one of the layers forming the heel of a shoe or boot
     8: lifting device consisting of a platform or cage that is
        raised and lowered mechanically in a vertical shaft in
        order to move people from one floor to another in a
        building [syn: {elevator}]
     9: plastic surgery to remove wrinkles and other signs of aging
        from your face; an incision is made near the hair line and
        skin is pulled back and excess tissue is excised; "some
        actresses have more than one face lift" [syn: {face lift},
         {facelift}, {face lifting}, {cosmetic surgery}, {rhytidectomy},
         {rhytidoplasty}, {nip and tuck}]
     10: transportation of people or goods by air (especially when
         other means of access are unavailable) [syn: {airlift}]
     11: a ride in a car; "he gave me a lift home"
     12: the act of raising something; "he responded with a lift of
         his eyebrow"; "fireman learn several different raises for
         getting ladders up" [syn: {raise}, {heave}]
     v 1: raise from a lower to a higher position; "Raise your hands";
          "Lift a load" [syn: {raise}, {elevate}, {get up}, {bring
          up}] [ant: {lower}]
     2: take hold of something and move it to a different location;
        "lift the box onto the table"
     3: move upwards; "lift one's eyes" [syn: {raise}]
     4: move upward; "The fog lifted"; "The smoke arose from the
        forest fire"; "The mist uprose from the meadows" [syn: {rise},
         {arise}, {move up}, {go up}, {come up}, {uprise}] [ant: {descend}]
     5: make audible; "He lifted a war whoop"
     6: annul by recalling or rescinding; "He revoked the ban on
        smoking"; "lift an embargo"; "vacate a death sentence"
        [syn: {revoke}, {annul}, {countermand}, {reverse}, {repeal},
         {overturn}, {rescind}, {vacate}]
     7: make off with belongings of others [syn: {pilfer}, {cabbage},
         {purloin}, {pinch}, {abstract}, {snarf}, {swipe}, {hook},
         {sneak}, {filch}, {nobble}]
     8: raise or haul up with or as if with mechanical help; "hoist
        the bicycle onto the roof of the car" [syn: {hoist}, {wind}]
     9: invigorate or heighten; "lift my spirits"; "lift his ego"
        [syn: {raise}]
     10: raise in rank or condition; "The new law lifted many people
         from poverty" [syn: {raise}, {elevate}]
     11: take off or away by decreasing; "lift the pressure"
     12: rise up; "The building rose before them" [syn: {rise}, {rear}]
     13: pay off (a mortgage)
     14: take without referencing from someone else's writing or
         speech; of intellectual property [syn: {plagiarize}, {plagiarise}]
     15: take illegally; "rustle cattle" [syn: {rustle}]
     16: fly people or goods to or from places not accessible by
         other means; "Food is airlifted into Bosnia" [syn: {airlift}]
     17: take (root crops) out of the ground; "lift potatoes"
     18: call to stop the hunt or to retire, as of hunting dogs
     19: rise upward, as from pressure or moisture; "The floor is
         lifting slowly"
     20: put an end to; "lift a ban"; "raise a siege" [syn: {raise}]
     21: remove (hair) by scalping
     22: remove from a seedbed or from a nursery; "lift the tulip
         bulbs"
     23: remove from a surface; "the detective carefully lifted some
         fingerprints from the table"
     24: perform cosmetic surgery on someone's face [syn: {face-lift}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
