<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lighting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lighting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lighted} (l[imac]t"[e^]d) or
   {Lit} (l[i^]t); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Lighting}.] [AS. l[=i]htan
   to alight orig., to relieve (a horse) of the rider's burden,
   to make less heavy, fr. l[=i]ht light. See {Light} not heavy,
   and cf. {Alight}, {Lighten} to make light.]
   1. To dismount; to descend, as from a horse or carriage; to
      alight; -- with from, off, on, upon, at, in.
      [1913 Webster]

            When she saw Isaac, she lighted off the camel.
                                                  --Gen. xxiv.
                                                  64.
      [1913 Webster]

            Slowly rode across a withered heath,
            And lighted at a ruined inn.          --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To feel light; to be made happy. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            It made all their hearts to light.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To descend from flight, and rest, perch, or settle, as a
      bird or insect.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The bee] lights on that, and this, and tasteth all.
                                                  --Sir. J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

            On the tree tops a crested peacock lit. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To come down suddenly and forcibly; to fall; -- with on or
      upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            On me, me only, as the source and spring
            Of all corruption, all the blame lights due.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To come by chance; to happen; -- with on or upon; formerly
      with into.
      [1913 Webster]

            The several degrees of vision, which the assistance
            of glasses (casually at first lit on) has taught us
            to conceive.                          --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shall light into atheistical company. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            And here we lit on Aunt Elizabeth,
            And Lilia with the rest.              --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lighting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lighted} (l[imac]t"[e^]d) or
   {Lit} (l[i^]t); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Lighting}.] [AS. l[=y]htan,
   l[=i]htan, to shine. [root]122. See {Light}, n.]
   1. To set fire to; to cause to burn; to set burning; to
      ignite; to kindle; as, to light a candle or lamp; to light
      the gas; -- sometimes with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a thousand candles be all lighted from one.
                                                  --Hakewill.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the largest lamp is lit.          --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Absence might cure it, or a second mistress
            Light up another flame, and put out this. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give light to; to illuminate; to fill with light; to
      spread over with light; -- often with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ah, hopeless, lasting flames! like those that burn
            To light the dead.                    --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            One hundred years ago, to have lit this theater as
            brilliantly as it is now lighted would have cost, I
            suppose, fifty pounds.                --F. Harrison.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sun has set, and Vesper, to supply
            His absent beams, has lighted up the sky. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To attend or conduct with a light; to show the way to by
      means of a light.
      [1913 Webster]

            His bishops lead him forth, and light him on.
                                                  --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To light a fire}, to kindle the material of a fire.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lighting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lighting \Light"ing\, n. (Metal.)
   A name sometimes applied to the process of annealing metals.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lighting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lighting
     n 1: having abundant light or illumination; "they played as long
          as it was light"; "as long as the lighting was good"
          [syn: {light}] [ant: {dark}]
     2: apparatus for supplying artificial light effects for the
        stage or a film
     3: the craft of providing artificial light; "an interior
        decorator must understand lighting"
     4: the act of setting on fire or catching fire [syn: {ignition},
         {firing}, {kindling}, {inflammation}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
