<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lightest</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lightest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\ (l[imac]t), a. [AS. le['o]ht. See {Light}, n.]
   [Compar. {Lighter} (l[imac]t"[~e]r); superl. {Lightest}.]
   1. Having light; not dark or obscure; bright; clear; as, the
      apartment is light.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. White or whitish; not intense or very marked; not of a
      deep shade; moderately colored; as, a light color; a light
      brown; a light complexion.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lightest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, a. [Compar. {Lighter} (l[imac]t"[~e]r); superl.
   {Lightest}.] [OE. light, liht, AS. l[=i]ht, le['o]ht; akin to
   D. ligt, G. leicht, OHG. l[=i]hti, Icel. l[=e]ttr, Dan. let,
   Sw. l["a]tt, Goth. leihts, and perh. to L. levis (cf.
   {Levity}), Gr. 'elachy`s small, Skr. laghu light. [root]125.]
   1. Having little, or comparatively little, weight; not
      tending to be the center of gravity with force; not heavy.
      [1913 Webster]

            These weights did not exert their natural gravity, .
            . . insomuch that I could not guess which was light
            or heavy whilst I held them in my hand. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not burdensome; easy to be lifted, borne, or carried by
      physical strength; as, a light burden, or load.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye shall find rest unto your souls. For my yoke is
            easy, and my burden is light.         --Matt. xi.
                                                  29, 30.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Easy to be endured or performed; not severe; not
      difficult; as, a light affliction or task. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Light sufferings give us leisure to complain.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Easy to be digested; not oppressive to the stomach; as,
      light food; also, containing little nutriment.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Not heavily armed; armed with light weapons; as, light
      troops; a troop of light horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Not encumbered; unembarrassed; clear of impediments;
      hence, active; nimble; swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            Unmarried men are best friends, best masters . . .
            but not always best subjects, for they are light to
            run away.                             --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Not heavily burdened; not deeply laden; not sufficiently
      ballasted; as, the ship returned light.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Slight; not important; as, a light error. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Well leavened; not heavy; as, light bread.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Not copious or heavy; not dense; not inconsiderable; as,
       a light rain; a light snow; light vapors.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Not strong or violent; moderate; as, a light wind.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Not pressing heavily or hard upon; hence, having an easy,
       graceful manner; delicate; as, a light touch; a light
       style of execution.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Easy to admit influence; inconsiderate; easily influenced
       by trifling considerations; unsteady; unsettled;
       volatile; as, a light, vain person; a light mind.
       [1913 Webster]

             There is no greater argument of a light and
             inconsiderate person than profanely to scoff at
             religion.                            --Tillotson.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Indulging in, or inclined to, levity; wanting dignity or
       solemnity; trifling; gay; frivolous; airy; unsubstantial.
       [1913 Webster]

             Seneca can not be too heavy, nor Plautus too light.
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             Specimens of New England humor laboriously light
             and lamentably mirthful.             --Hawthorne.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. Not quite sound or normal; somewhat impaired or deranged;
       dizzy; giddy.
       [1913 Webster]

             Are his wits safe? Is he not light of brain ?
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. Easily bestowed; inconsiderately rendered.
       [1913 Webster]

             To a fair semblance doth light faith annex.
                                                  --Spenser.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. Wanton; unchaste; as, a woman of light character.
       [1913 Webster]

             A light wife doth make a heavy husband. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. Not of the legal, standard, or usual weight; clipped;
       diminished; as, light coin.
       [1913 Webster]

   19. Loose; sandy; easily pulverized; as, a light soil.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Light cavalry}, {Light horse} (Mil.), light-armed soldiers
      mounted on strong and active horses.

   {Light eater}, one who eats but little.

   {Light infantry}, infantry soldiers selected and trained for
      rapid evolutions.

   {Light of foot}.
       (a) Having a light step.
       (b) Fleet.

   {Light of heart}, gay, cheerful.

   {Light oil} (Chem.), the oily product, lighter than water,
      forming the chief part of the first distillate of coal
      tar, and consisting largely of benzene and toluene.

   {Light sails} (Naut.), all the sails above the topsails,
      with, also, the studding sails and flying jib. --Dana.

   {Light sleeper}, one easily wakened.

   {Light weight}, a prize fighter, boxer, wrestler, or jockey,
      who is below a standard medium weight. Cf. {Feather
      weight}, under {Feather}. [Cant]

   {To make light of}, to treat as of little consequence; to
      slight; to disregard.

   {To set light by}, to undervalue; to slight; to treat as of
      no importance; to despise.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
