<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>light</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light
   the offspring of the divine command (Gen. 1:3). "All the more
   joyous emotions of the mind, all the pleasing sensations of the
   frame, all the happy hours of domestic intercourse were
   habitually described among the Hebrews under imagery derived
   from light" (1 Kings 11:36; Isa. 58:8; Esther 8:16; Ps. 97:11).
   Light came also naturally to typify true religion and the
   felicity it imparts (Ps. 119:105; Isa. 8:20; Matt. 4:16, etc.),
   and the glorious inheritance of the redeemed (Col. 1:12; Rev.
   21:23-25). God is said to dwell in light inaccessible (1 Tim.
   6:16). It frequently signifies instruction (Matt. 5:16; John
   5:35). In its highest sense it is applied to Christ as the "Sun
   of righteousness" (Mal. 4:2; Luke 2:32; John 1:7-9). God is
   styled "the Father of lights" (James 1:17). It is used of angels
   (2 Cor. 11:14), and of John the Baptist, who was a "burning and
   a shining light" (John 5:35), and of all true disciples, who are
   styled "the light of the world" (Matt. 5:14).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LIGHT
     
        LIfecycle Global HyperText.
     
        A project in the CERN ECP/TP group whereby documents resulting
        from the {software life cycle} are available as {hypertext}.
     
        (1995-02-03)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lighted} (l[imac]t"[e^]d) or
   {Lit} (l[i^]t); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Lighting}.] [AS. l[=i]htan
   to alight orig., to relieve (a horse) of the rider's burden,
   to make less heavy, fr. l[=i]ht light. See {Light} not heavy,
   and cf. {Alight}, {Lighten} to make light.]
   1. To dismount; to descend, as from a horse or carriage; to
      alight; -- with from, off, on, upon, at, in.
      [1913 Webster]

            When she saw Isaac, she lighted off the camel.
                                                  --Gen. xxiv.
                                                  64.
      [1913 Webster]

            Slowly rode across a withered heath,
            And lighted at a ruined inn.          --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To feel light; to be made happy. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            It made all their hearts to light.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To descend from flight, and rest, perch, or settle, as a
      bird or insect.
      [1913 Webster]

            [The bee] lights on that, and this, and tasteth all.
                                                  --Sir. J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

            On the tree tops a crested peacock lit. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To come down suddenly and forcibly; to fall; -- with on or
      upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            On me, me only, as the source and spring
            Of all corruption, all the blame lights due.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To come by chance; to happen; -- with on or upon; formerly
      with into.
      [1913 Webster]

            The several degrees of vision, which the assistance
            of glasses (casually at first lit on) has taught us
            to conceive.                          --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shall light into atheistical company. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            And here we lit on Aunt Elizabeth,
            And Lilia with the rest.              --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\ (l[imac]t), n. [OE. light, liht, AS. le['o]ht;
   akin to OS. lioht, D. &amp; G. licht, OHG. lioht, Goth.
   liuha[thorn], Icel. lj[=o]s, L. lux light, lucere to shine,
   Gr. leyko`s white, Skr. ruc to shine. [root]122. Cf. {Lucid},
   {Lunar}, {Luminous}, {Lynx}.]
   1. That agent, force, or action in nature by the operation of
      which upon the organs of sight, objects are rendered
      visible or luminous.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Light was regarded formerly as consisting of material
         particles, or corpuscules, sent off in all directions
         from luminous bodies, and traversing space, in right
         lines, with the known velocity of about 186,300 miles
         per second; but it is now generally understood to
         consist, not in any actual transmission of particles or
         substance, but in the propagation of vibrations or
         undulations in a subtile, elastic medium, or ether,
         assumed to pervade all space, and to be thus set in
         vibratory motion by the action of luminous bodies, as
         the atmosphere is by sonorous bodies. This view of the
         nature of light is known as the undulatory or wave
         theory; the other, advocated by Newton (but long since
         abandoned), as the corpuscular, emission, or Newtonian
         theory. A more recent theory makes light to consist in
         electrical oscillations, and is known as the
         electro-magnetic theory of light.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. That which furnishes, or is a source of, light, as the
      sun, a star, a candle, a lighthouse, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then he called for a light, and sprang in. --Acts
                                                  xvi. 29.
      [1913 Webster]

            And God made two great lights; the greater light to
            rule the day, and the lesser light to rule the
            night.                                --Gen. i. 16.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The time during which the light of the sun is visible;
      day; especially, the dawn of day.
      [1913 Webster]

            The murderer, rising with the light, killeth the
            poor and needy.                       --Job xxiv.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The brightness of the eye or eyes.
      [1913 Webster]

            He seemed to find his way without his eyes;
            For out o'door he went without their helps,
            And, to the last, bended their light on me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The medium through which light is admitted, as a window,
      or window pane; a skylight; in architecture, one of the
      compartments of a window made by a mullion or mullions.
      [1913 Webster]

            There were windows in three rows, and light was
            against light in three ranks.         --I Kings
                                                  vii.4.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Life; existence.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, spring to light, auspicious Babe, be born !
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Open view; a visible state or condition; public
      observation; publicity.
      [1913 Webster]

            The duke yet would have dark deeds darkly answered;
            he would never bring them to light.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. The power of perception by vision.
      [1913 Webster]

            My strength faileth me; as for the light of my eyes,
            it also is gone from me.              --Ps. xxxviii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. That which illumines or makes clear to the mind; mental or
      spiritual illumination; enlightenment; knowledge;
      information.
      [1913 Webster]

            He shall never know
            That I had any light of this from thee. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Prosperity; happiness; joy; felicity.
       [1913 Webster]

             Then shall thy light break forth as the morning,
             and thy health shall spring forth speedily. --Is.
                                                  lviii. 8.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Paint.) The manner in which the light strikes upon a
       picture; that part of a picture which represents those
       objects upon which the light is supposed to fall; the
       more illuminated part of a landscape or other scene; --
       opposed to {shade}. Cf. {Chiaroscuro}.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Appearance due to the particular facts and circumstances
       presented to view; point of view; as, to state things
       fairly and put them in the right light.
       [1913 Webster]

             Frequent consideration of a thing . . . shows it in
             its several lights and various ways of appearance.
                                                  --South.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. One who is conspicuous or noteworthy; a model or example;
       as, the lights of the age or of antiquity.
       [1913 Webster]

             Joan of Arc,
             A light of ancient France.           --Tennyson.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Pyrotech.) A firework made by filling a case with a
       substance which burns brilliantly with a white or colored
       flame; as, a Bengal light.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Light is used figuratively to denote that which
         resembles physical light in any respect, as
         illuminating, benefiting, enlightening, or enlivening
         mankind.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Ancient lights} (Law), {Calcium light}, {Flash light}, etc.
      See under {Ancient}, {Calcium}, etc.

   {Light ball} (Mil.), a ball of combustible materials, used to
      afford light; -- sometimes made so as to be fired from a
      cannon or mortar, or to be carried up by a rocket.

   {Light barrel} (Mil.), an empty power barrel pierced with
      holes and filled with shavings soaked in pitch, used to
      light up a ditch or a breach.

   {Light dues} (Com.), tolls levied on ships navigating certain
      waters, for the maintenance of lighthouses.

   {Light iron}, a candlestick. [Obs.]

   {Light keeper}, a person appointed to take care of a
      lighthouse or light-ship.

   {Light money}, charges laid by government on shipping
      entering a port, for the maintenance of lighthouses and
      light-ships.

   {The light of the countenance}, favor; kindness; smiles.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lord, lift thou up the light of thy countenance upon
            us.                                   --Ps. iv. 6.

   {Northern lights}. See {Aurora borealis}, under {Aurora}.

   {To bring to light}, to cause to be disclosed.

   {To come to light}, to be disclosed.

   {To see the light}, to come into the light; hence, to come
      into the world or into public notice; as, his book never
      saw the light.

   {To stand in one's own light}, to take a position which is
      injurious to one's own interest.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\ (l[imac]t), a. [AS. le['o]ht. See {Light}, n.]
   [Compar. {Lighter} (l[imac]t"[~e]r); superl. {Lightest}.]
   1. Having light; not dark or obscure; bright; clear; as, the
      apartment is light.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. White or whitish; not intense or very marked; not of a
      deep shade; moderately colored; as, a light color; a light
      brown; a light complexion.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lighted} (l[imac]t"[e^]d) or
   {Lit} (l[i^]t); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Lighting}.] [AS. l[=y]htan,
   l[=i]htan, to shine. [root]122. See {Light}, n.]
   1. To set fire to; to cause to burn; to set burning; to
      ignite; to kindle; as, to light a candle or lamp; to light
      the gas; -- sometimes with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            If a thousand candles be all lighted from one.
                                                  --Hakewill.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the largest lamp is lit.          --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            Absence might cure it, or a second mistress
            Light up another flame, and put out this. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give light to; to illuminate; to fill with light; to
      spread over with light; -- often with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ah, hopeless, lasting flames! like those that burn
            To light the dead.                    --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            One hundred years ago, to have lit this theater as
            brilliantly as it is now lighted would have cost, I
            suppose, fifty pounds.                --F. Harrison.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sun has set, and Vesper, to supply
            His absent beams, has lighted up the sky. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To attend or conduct with a light; to show the way to by
      means of a light.
      [1913 Webster]

            His bishops lead him forth, and light him on.
                                                  --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To light a fire}, to kindle the material of a fire.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, v. i.
   1. To become ignited; to take fire; as, the match will not
      light.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be illuminated; to receive light; to brighten; -- with
      up; as, the room light up very well.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, a. [Compar. {Lighter} (l[imac]t"[~e]r); superl.
   {Lightest}.] [OE. light, liht, AS. l[=i]ht, le['o]ht; akin to
   D. ligt, G. leicht, OHG. l[=i]hti, Icel. l[=e]ttr, Dan. let,
   Sw. l["a]tt, Goth. leihts, and perh. to L. levis (cf.
   {Levity}), Gr. 'elachy`s small, Skr. laghu light. [root]125.]
   1. Having little, or comparatively little, weight; not
      tending to be the center of gravity with force; not heavy.
      [1913 Webster]

            These weights did not exert their natural gravity, .
            . . insomuch that I could not guess which was light
            or heavy whilst I held them in my hand. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not burdensome; easy to be lifted, borne, or carried by
      physical strength; as, a light burden, or load.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye shall find rest unto your souls. For my yoke is
            easy, and my burden is light.         --Matt. xi.
                                                  29, 30.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Easy to be endured or performed; not severe; not
      difficult; as, a light affliction or task. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Light sufferings give us leisure to complain.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Easy to be digested; not oppressive to the stomach; as,
      light food; also, containing little nutriment.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Not heavily armed; armed with light weapons; as, light
      troops; a troop of light horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Not encumbered; unembarrassed; clear of impediments;
      hence, active; nimble; swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            Unmarried men are best friends, best masters . . .
            but not always best subjects, for they are light to
            run away.                             --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Not heavily burdened; not deeply laden; not sufficiently
      ballasted; as, the ship returned light.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Slight; not important; as, a light error. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Well leavened; not heavy; as, light bread.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Not copious or heavy; not dense; not inconsiderable; as,
       a light rain; a light snow; light vapors.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. Not strong or violent; moderate; as, a light wind.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Not pressing heavily or hard upon; hence, having an easy,
       graceful manner; delicate; as, a light touch; a light
       style of execution.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. Easy to admit influence; inconsiderate; easily influenced
       by trifling considerations; unsteady; unsettled;
       volatile; as, a light, vain person; a light mind.
       [1913 Webster]

             There is no greater argument of a light and
             inconsiderate person than profanely to scoff at
             religion.                            --Tillotson.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Indulging in, or inclined to, levity; wanting dignity or
       solemnity; trifling; gay; frivolous; airy; unsubstantial.
       [1913 Webster]

             Seneca can not be too heavy, nor Plautus too light.
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             Specimens of New England humor laboriously light
             and lamentably mirthful.             --Hawthorne.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. Not quite sound or normal; somewhat impaired or deranged;
       dizzy; giddy.
       [1913 Webster]

             Are his wits safe? Is he not light of brain ?
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. Easily bestowed; inconsiderately rendered.
       [1913 Webster]

             To a fair semblance doth light faith annex.
                                                  --Spenser.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. Wanton; unchaste; as, a woman of light character.
       [1913 Webster]

             A light wife doth make a heavy husband. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. Not of the legal, standard, or usual weight; clipped;
       diminished; as, light coin.
       [1913 Webster]

   19. Loose; sandy; easily pulverized; as, a light soil.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Light cavalry}, {Light horse} (Mil.), light-armed soldiers
      mounted on strong and active horses.

   {Light eater}, one who eats but little.

   {Light infantry}, infantry soldiers selected and trained for
      rapid evolutions.

   {Light of foot}.
       (a) Having a light step.
       (b) Fleet.

   {Light of heart}, gay, cheerful.

   {Light oil} (Chem.), the oily product, lighter than water,
      forming the chief part of the first distillate of coal
      tar, and consisting largely of benzene and toluene.

   {Light sails} (Naut.), all the sails above the topsails,
      with, also, the studding sails and flying jib. --Dana.

   {Light sleeper}, one easily wakened.

   {Light weight}, a prize fighter, boxer, wrestler, or jockey,
      who is below a standard medium weight. Cf. {Feather
      weight}, under {Feather}. [Cant]

   {To make light of}, to treat as of little consequence; to
      slight; to disregard.

   {To set light by}, to undervalue; to slight; to treat as of
      no importance; to despise.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\ (l[imac]t), adv.
   Lightly; cheaply. --Hooker.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Light \Light\, v. t. [See {Light} not heavy, and cf. {Light} to
   alight, and {Lighten} to make less heavy.]
   To lighten; to ease of a burden; to take off. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         From his head the heavy burgonet did light. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Wine \Wine\, n. [OE. win, AS. win, fr. L. vinum (cf. Icel.
   v[=i]n; all from the Latin); akin to Gr. o'i^nos, ?, and E.
   withy. Cf. {Vine}, {Vineyard}, {Vinous}, {Withy}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The expressed juice of grapes, esp. when fermented; a
      beverage or liquor prepared from grapes by squeezing out
      their juice, and (usually) allowing it to ferment. ``Red
      wine of Gascoigne.'' --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wine is a mocker, strong drink is raging, and
            whosoever is deceived thereby is not wise. --Prov.
                                                  xx. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bacchus, that first from out the purple grape
            Crushed the sweet poison of misused wine. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Wine is essentially a dilute solution of ethyl alcohol,
         containing also certain small quantities of ethers and
         ethereal salts which give character and bouquet.
         According to their color, strength, taste, etc., wines
         are called {red}, {white}, {spirituous}, {dry},
         {light}, {still}, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A liquor or beverage prepared from the juice of any fruit
      or plant by a process similar to that for grape wine; as,
      currant wine; gooseberry wine; palm wine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The effect of drinking wine in excess; intoxication.
      [1913 Webster]

            Noah awoke from his wine.             --Gen. ix. 24.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Birch wine}, {Cape wine}, etc. See under {Birch}, {Cape},
      etc.

   {Spirit of wine}. See under {Spirit}.

   {To have drunk wine of ape} or {To have drunk wine ape}, to
      be so drunk as to be foolish. [Obs.] --Chaucer.

   {Wine acid}. (Chem.) See {Tartaric acid}, under {Tartaric}.
      [Colloq.]

   {Wine apple} (Bot.), a large red apple, with firm flesh and a
      rich, vinous flavor.

   {Wine fly} (Zo["o]l.), small two-winged fly of the genus
      {Piophila}, whose larva lives in wine, cider, and other
      fermented liquors.

   {Wine grower}, one who cultivates a vineyard and makes wine.
      

   {Wine measure}, the measure by which wines and other spirits
      are sold, smaller than beer measure.

   {Wine merchant}, a merchant who deals in wines.

   {Wine of opium} (Pharm.), a solution of opium in aromatized
      sherry wine, having the same strength as ordinary
      laudanum; -- also {Sydenham's laudanum}.

   {Wine press}, a machine or apparatus in which grapes are
      pressed to extract their juice.

   {Wine skin}, a bottle or bag of skin, used, in various
      countries, for carrying wine.

   {Wine stone}, a kind of crust deposited in wine casks. See
      1st {Tartar}, 1.

   {Wine vault}.
      (a) A vault where wine is stored.
      (b) A place where wine is served at the bar, or at tables;
          a dramshop. --Dickens.

   {Wine vinegar}, vinegar made from wine.

   {Wine whey}, whey made from milk coagulated by the use of
      wine.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>light</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>light
     adj 1: of comparatively little physical weight or density; "a light
            load"; "magnesium is a light metal--having a specific
            gravity of 1.74 at 20 degrees C" [ant: {heavy}]
     2: (used of color) having a relatively small amount of coloring
        agent; "light blue"; "light colors such as pastels"; "a
        light-colored powder" [syn: {light-colored}] [ant: {dark}]
     3: of the military or industry; using (or being) relatively
        small or light arms or equipment; "light infantry"; "light
        cavalry"; "light industry"; "light weapons" [ant: {heavy}]
     4: not great in degree or quantity or number; "a light
        sentence"; "a light accent"; "casualties were light";
        "light snow was falling"; "light misty rain"; "light smoke
        from the chimney" [ant: {heavy}]
     5: psychologically light; especially free from sadness or
        troubles; "a light heart" [ant: {heavy}]
     6: characterized by or emitting light; "a room that is light
        when the shutters are open"; "the inside of the house was
        airy and light" [ant: {dark}]
     7: used of vowels or syllables; pronounced with little or no
        stress; "a syllable that ends in a short vowel is a light
        syllable"; "a weak stress on the second syllable" [syn: {unaccented},
         {weak}]
     8: easily assimilated in the alimentary canal; not rich or
        heavily seasoned; "a light diet"
     9: (used of soil) loose and large-grained in consistency;
        "light sandy soil" [syn: {friable}, {sandy}]
     10: (of sound or color) free from anything that dulls or dims;
         "efforts to obtain a clean bass in orchestral
         recordings"; "clear laughter like a waterfall"; "clear
         reds and blues"; "a light lilting voice like a silver
         bell" [syn: {clean}, {clear}, {unclouded}]
     11: moving easily and quickly; nimble; "the dancer was light and
         graceful"; "a lightsome buoyant step"; "walked with a
         light tripping step" [syn: {lightsome}, {tripping}]
     12: demanding little effort; not burdensome; "light housework";
         "light exercise"
     13: of little intensity or power or force; "the light touch of
         her fingers"; "a light breeze" [ant: {heavy}]
     14: (physics, chemistry) not having atomic weight greater than
         average; "light water is ordinary water" [ant: {heavy}]
     15: weak and likely to lose consciousness; "suddenly felt faint
         from the pain"; "was sick and faint from hunger"; "felt
         light in the head"; "a swooning fit"; "light-headed with
         wine"; "light-headed from lack of sleep" [syn: {faint}, {swooning},
          {light-headed}, {lightheaded}]
     16: very thin and insubstantial; "thin paper"; "flimsy voile";
         "light summer dresses" [syn: {flimsy}]
     17: marked by temperance in indulgence; "abstemious meals"; "a
         light eater"; "a light smoker"; "ate a light supper"
         [syn: {abstemious}, {light(a)}]
     18: less than the correct or legal or full amount often
         deliberately so; "a light pound"; "a scant cup of sugar";
         "regularly gives short weight" [syn: {scant(p)}, {short}]
     19: having little importance; "losing his job was no light
         matter"
     20: intended primarily as entertainment; not serious or
         profound; "light verse"; "a light comedy"
     21: silly or trivial; "idle pleasure"; "light banter"; "light
         idle chatter" [syn: {idle}]
     22: having a spongy or flaky texture; well-leavened; "light
         pastries"
     23: designed for ease of movement or to carry little weight;
         "light aircraft"; "a light truck"
     24: having relatively few calories; "diet cola"; "light (or
         lite) beer"; "lite (or light) mayonnaise"; "a low-cal
         diet" [syn: {lite}, {low-cal}]
     25: (of sleep) easily disturbed; "in a light doze"; "a light
         sleeper"; "a restless wakeful night" [syn: {wakeful}]
     26: casual and unrestrained in sexual behavior; "her easy
         virtue"; "he was told to avoid loose (or light) women";
         "wanton behavior" [syn: {easy}, {loose}, {promiscuous}, {sluttish},
          {wanton}]
     n 1: (physics) electromagnetic radiation that can produce a
          visual sensation; "the light was filtered through a soft
          glass window" [syn: {visible light}, {visible radiation}]
     2: any device serving as a source of illumination; "he stopped
        the car and turned off the lights" [syn: {light source}]
     3: a particular perspective or aspect of a situation; "although
        he saw it in a different light, he still did not
        understand"
     4: the quality of being luminous; emitting or reflecting light;
        "its luminosity is measured relative to that of our sun"
        [syn: {luminosity}, {brightness}, {brightness level}, {luminance},
         {luminousness}]
     5: an illuminated area; "he stepped into the light"
     6: a condition of spiritual awareness; divine illumination;
        "follow God's light" [syn: {illumination}]
     7: the visual effect of illumination on objects or scenes as
        created in pictures; "he could paint the lightest light
        and the darkest dark" [syn: {lightness}]
     8: a person regarded very fondly; "the light of my life"
     9: mental understanding as an enlightening experience; "he
        finally saw the light"; "can you shed light on this
        problem?"
     10: having abundant light or illumination; "they played as long
         as it was light"; "as long as the lighting was good"
         [syn: {lighting}] [ant: {dark}]
     11: public awareness; "it brought the scandal to light"
     12: brightness and animation of countenance; "he had a sparkle
         in his eye" [syn: {sparkle}, {spark}]
     13: a divine presence believed by Quakers to enlighten and guide
         the soul [syn: {Inner Light}, {Light Within}, {Christ
         Within}]
     14: a visual warning signal; "they saw the light of the beacon";
         "there was a light at every corner"
     15: a device for lighting or igniting fuel or charges or fires;
         "do you have a light?" [syn: {lighter}, {igniter}, {ignitor}]
     adv : with few burdens; "experienced travellers travel light"
           [syn: {lightly}]
     v 1: make lighter or brighter; "This lamp lightens the room a
          bit" [syn: {illume}, {illumine}, {light up}, {illuminate}]
     2: begin to smoke; "After the meal, some of the diners lit up"
        [syn: {light up}, {fire up}]
     3: to come to rest, settle; "Misfortune lighted upon him" [syn:
         {alight}, {perch}]
     4: cause to start burning; subject to fire or great heat;
        "Great heat can ignite almost any dry matter"; "Light a
        cigarette" [syn: {ignite}] [ant: {snuff out}]
     5: fall to somebody by assignment or lot; "The task fell to
        me"; "It fell to me to notify the parents of the victims"
        [syn: {fall}]
     6: get off (a horse) [syn: {unhorse}, {dismount}, {get off}, {get
        down}]
     [also: {lit}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
