<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>limb</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LIMB, n.  The branch of a tree or the leg of an American woman.

    'Twas a pair of boots that the lady bought,
        And the salesman laced them tight
        To a very remarkable height --
    Higher, indeed, than I think he ought --
        Higher than _can_ be right.
    For the Bible declares -- but never mind:
        It is hardly fit
    To censure freely and fault to find
    With others for sins that I'm not inclined
        Myself to commit.
    Each has his weakness, and though my own
        Is freedom from every sin,
        It still were unfair to pitch in,
    Discharging the first censorious stone.
    Besides, the truth compels me to say,
    The boots in question were _made_ that way.
    As he drew the lace she made a grimace,
        And blushingly said to him:
    "This boot, I'm sure, is too high to endure,
    It hurts my -- hurts my -- limb."
    The salesman smiled in a manner mild,
    Like an artless, undesigning child;
    Then, checking himself, to his face he gave
    A look as sorrowful as the grave,
        Though he didn't care two figs
    For her paints and throes,
    As he stroked her toes,
    Remarking with speech and manner just
    Befitting his calling:  "Madam, I trust
        That it doesn't hurt your twigs."
                                                      B. Percival Dike


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Limb \Limb\, v. t.
   1. To supply with limbs. [R.] --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To dismember; to tear off the limbs of.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Limb \Limb\, n. [L. limbus border. Cf. {Limbo}, {Limbus}.]
   A border or edge, in certain special uses.
   (a) (Bot.) The border or upper spreading part of a
       monopetalous corolla, or of a petal, or sepal; blade.
   (b) (Astron.) The border or edge of the disk of a heavenly
       body, especially of the sun and moon.
   (c) The graduated margin of an arc or circle, in an
       instrument for measuring angles.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Limb \Limb\ (l[i^]m), n. [OE. lim, AS. lim; akin to Icel. limr
   limb, lim branch of a tree, Sw. &amp; Dan. lem limb; cf. also AS.
   li[eth], OHG. lid, gilid, G. glied, Goth. li[thorn]us. Cf.
   {Lith}, {Limber}.]
   1. A part of a tree which extends from the trunk and
      separates into branches and twigs; a large branch.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An arm or a leg of a human being; a leg, arm, or wing of
      an animal.
      [1913 Webster]

            A second Hector for his grim aspect,
            And large proportion of his strong-knit limbs.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A thing or person regarded as a part or member of, or
      attachment to, something else. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            That little limb of the devil has cheated the
            gallows.                              --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An elementary piece of the mechanism of a lock.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Limb of the law}, a lawyer or an officer of the law.
      [Colloq.] --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>limb
     n 1: one of the jointed appendages of an animal used for
          locomotion or grasping: arm; leg; wing; flipper
     2: any of the main branches arising from the trunk or a bough
        of a tree [syn: {tree branch}]
     3: (astronomy) the circumferential edge of the apparent disc of
        the sun or the moon or a planet
     4: either of the two halves of a bow from handle to tip; "the
        upper limb of the bow"
     5: the graduated arc that is attached to an instrument for
        measuring angles; "the limb of the sextant"
     6: any projection that is thought to resemble an arm; "the arm
        of the record player"; "an arm of the sea"; "a branch of
        the sewer" [syn: {arm}, {branch}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
