<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>limbo</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limbo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Limbo \Lim"bo\ (l[i^]m"b[-o]), Limbus \Lim"bus\ (l[i^]m"b[u^]s),
   n. [L. limbus border, edge in limbo on the border. Cf. {Limb}
   border.]
   1. (Scholastic Theol.) An spiritual region where certain
      classes of souls were supposed to await the last judgment.
      [1913 Webster]

            As far from help as Limbo is from bliss. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A Limbo large and broad, since called
            The Paradise of fools.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The limbus patrum was considered as a place for the
         souls of good men who lived before the coming of our
         Savior. The limbus infantium was said to be a similar
         place for the souls of unbaptized infants. To these was
         added, in the popular belief, the limbus fatuorum, or
         fool's paradise, regarded as a receptacle of all vanity
         and nonsense.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: Any real or imaginary place of restraint or
      confinement; a prison; as, to put a man in limbo.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: A state of waiting, or uncertainty, in which final
      judgment concerning the outcome of a decision is
      postponed, perhaps indefinitely; neglect for an indefinite
      time; as, the proposal was left in limbo while opponents
      and proponents refused to compromise.
      [PJC]

   4. (Anat.) A border or margin; as, the limbus of the cornea.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limbo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Limbo \Lim"bo\ (l[i^]m"b[-o]), n. [Jamaican E. limba to bend,
   fr. E. limber (1950) --MW10]
   A West Indian dance contest, in which participants must dance
   under a pole which is lowered successively until only one
   participant can successfully pass under, without falling. It
   is often performed at celebrations, such as weddings.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>limbo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>limbo
     n 1: the state of being disregarded or forgotten [syn: {oblivion}]
     2: an imaginary place for lost or neglected things
     3: (theology) in Roman Catholicism, the place of unbaptized but
        innocent or righteous souls (such as infants and virtuous
        individuals)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
