<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>line</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>line</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>line
     
        1. &lt;hardware&gt; An electrical conductor.  For distances larger
        than a breadbox, a single line may consist of two electrical
        conductors in twisted, parallel, or concentric arrangement
        used to transport one logical signal.
     
        By extension, a (usually physical) medium such as an {optical
        fibre} which carries a signal.
     
        (1995-09-29)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>line</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Shaft \Shaft\, n. [OE. shaft, schaft, AS. sceaft; akin to D.
   schacht, OHG. scaft, G. schaft, Dan. &amp; Sw. skaft handle,
   haft, Icel. skapt, and probably to L. scapus, Gr. ????, ????,
   a staff. Probably originally, a shaven or smoothed rod. Cf.
   {Scape}, {Scepter}, {Shave}.]
   1. The slender, smooth stem of an arrow; hence, an arrow.
      [1913 Webster]

            His sleep, his meat, his drink, is him bereft,
            That lean he wax, and dry as is a shaft. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            A shaft hath three principal parts, the stele
            [stale], the feathers, and the head.  --Ascham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The long handle of a spear or similar weapon; hence, the
      weapon itself; (Fig.) anything regarded as a shaft to be
      thrown or darted; as, shafts of light.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the thunder,
            Winged with red lightning and impetuous rage,
            Perhaps hath spent his shafts.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some kinds of literary pursuits . . . have been
            attacked with all the shafts of ridicule. --V. Knox.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which resembles in some degree the stem or handle of
      an arrow or a spear; a long, slender part, especially when
      cylindrical. Specifically: (a) (Bot.) The trunk, stem, or
      stalk of a plant.
      (b) (Zo["o]l.) The stem or midrib of a feather. See
          Illust. of {Feather}.
      (c) The pole, or tongue, of a vehicle; also, a thill.
      (d) The part of a candlestick which supports its branches.
          [1913 Webster]

                Thou shalt make a candlestick of pure gold . . .
                his shaft, and his branches, his bowls, his
                knops, and his flowers, shall be of the same.
                                                  --Ex. xxv. 31.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) The handle or helve of certain tools, instruments,
          etc., as a hammer, a whip, etc.
      (f) A pole, especially a Maypole. [Obs.] --Stow.
      (g) (Arch.) The body of a column; the cylindrical pillar
          between the capital and base (see Illust. of
          {Column}). Also, the part of a chimney above the roof.
          Also, the spire of a steeple. [Obs. or R.] --Gwilt.
      (h) A column, an obelisk, or other spire-shaped or
          columnar monument.
          [1913 Webster]

                Bid time and nature gently spare
                The shaft we raise to thee.       --Emerson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (i) (Weaving) A rod at the end of a heddle.
      (j) (Mach.) A solid or hollow cylinder or bar, having one
          or more journals on which it rests and revolves, and
          intended to carry one or more wheels or other
          revolving parts and to transmit power or motion; as,
          the shaft of a steam engine. See Illust. of
          {Countershaft}.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) A humming bird ({Thaumastura cora}) having two
      of the tail feathers next to the middle ones very long in
      the male; -- called also {cora humming bird}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [Cf. G. schacht.] (Mining) A well-like excavation in the
      earth, perpendicular or nearly so, made for reaching and
      raising ore, for raising water, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A long passage for the admission or outlet of air; an air
      shaft.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The chamber of a blast furnace.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Line shaft} (Mach.), a main shaft of considerable length, in
      a shop or factory, usually bearing a number of pulleys by
      which machines are driven, commonly by means of
      countershafts; -- called also {line}, or {main line}.

   {Shaft alley} (Naut.), a passage extending from the engine
      room to the stern, and containing the propeller shaft.

   {Shaft furnace} (Metal.), a furnace, in the form of a
      chimney, which is charged at the top and tapped at the
      bottom.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>line</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Line \Line\ (l[imac]n), n. [OE. lin. See {Linen}.]
   1. Flax; linen. [Obs.] ``Garments made of line.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The longer and finer fiber of flax.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>line</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Line \Line\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lined} (l[imac]nd); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Lining}.] [See {Line} flax.]
   1. To cover the inner surface of; as, to line a cloak with
      silk or fur; to line a box with paper or tin.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inside lined with rich carnation silk. --W.
                                                  Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put something in the inside of; to fill; to supply, as
      a purse with money.
      [1913 Webster]

            The charge amounteth very high for any one man's
            purse, except lined beyond ordinary, to reach unto.
                                                  --Carew.
      [1913 Webster]

            Till coffee has her stomach lined.    --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To place persons or things along the side of for security
      or defense; to strengthen by adding anything; to fortify;
      as, to line works with soldiers.
      [1913 Webster]

            Line and new repair our towns of war
            With men of courage and with means defendant.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To impregnate; -- applied to brute animals. --Creech.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Lined gold}, gold foil having a lining of another metal.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>line</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Line \Line\, n. [OE. line, AS. l[=i]ne cable, hawser, prob. from
   L. linea a linen thread, string, line, fr. linum flax,
   thread, linen, cable; but the English word was influenced by
   F. ligne line, from the same L. word linea. See {Linen}.]
   1. A linen thread or string; a slender, strong cord; also, a
      cord of any thickness; a rope; a hawser; as, a fishing
      line; a line for snaring birds; a clothesline; a towline.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who so layeth lines for to latch fowls. --Piers
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A more or less threadlike mark of pen, pencil, or graver;
      any long mark; as, a chalk line.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The course followed by anything in motion; hence, a road
      or route; as, the arrow descended in a curved line; the
      place is remote from lines of travel.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Direction; as, the line of sight or vision.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A row of letters, words, etc., written or printed; esp., a
      row of words extending across a page or column.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A short letter; a note; as, a line from a friend.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Poet.) A verse, or the words which form a certain number
      of feet, according to the measure.
      [1913 Webster]

            In the preceding line Ulysses speaks of Nausicaa.
                                                  --Broome.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Course of conduct, thought, occupation, or policy; method
      of argument; department of industry, trade, or
      intellectual activity.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is uncommonly powerful in his own line, but it is
            not the line of a first-rate man.     --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Math.) That which has length, but not breadth or
      thickness.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The exterior limit of a figure, plat, or territory;
       boundary; contour; outline.
       [1913 Webster]

             Eden stretched her line
             From Auran eastward to the royal towers
             Of great Seleucia.                   --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A threadlike crease marking the face or the hand; hence,
       characteristic mark.
       [1913 Webster]

             Though on his brow were graven lines austere.
                                                  --Byron.
       [1913 Webster]

             He tipples palmistry, and dines
             On all her fortune-telling lines.    --Cleveland.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Lineament; feature; figure. ``The lines of my boy's
       face.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. A straight row; a continued series or rank; as, a line of
       houses, or of soldiers; a line of barriers.
       [1913 Webster]

             Unite thy forces and attack their lines. --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. A series or succession of ancestors or descendants of a
       given person; a family or race; as, the ascending or
       descending line; the line of descent; the male line; a
       line of kings.
       [1913 Webster]

             Of his lineage am I, and his offspring
             By very line, as of the stock real.  --Chaucer.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. A connected series of public conveyances, and hence, an
       established arrangement for forwarding merchandise, etc.;
       as, a line of stages; an express line.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. (Geog.)
       (a) A circle of latitude or of longitude, as represented
           on a map.
       (b) The equator; -- usually called the line, or
           equinoctial line; as, to cross the line.
           [1913 Webster]

   17. A long tape, or a narrow ribbon of steel, etc., marked
       with subdivisions, as feet and inches, for measuring; a
       tapeline.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. (Script.)
       (a) A measuring line or cord.
           [1913 Webster]

                 He marketh it out with a line.   --Is. xliv.
                                                  13.
       (b) That which was measured by a line, as a field or any
           piece of land set apart; hence, allotted place of
           abode.
           [1913 Webster]

                 The lines are fallen unto me in pleasant
                 places; yea, I have a goodly heritage. --Ps.
                                                  xvi. 6.
       (c) Instruction; doctrine.
           [1913 Webster]

                 Their line is gone out through all the earth.
                                                  --Ps. xix. 4.
           [1913 Webster]

   19. (Mach.) The proper relative position or adjustment of
       parts, not as to design or proportion, but with reference
       to smooth working; as, the engine is in line or out of
       line.
       [1913 Webster]

   20. The track and roadbed of a railway; railroad.
       [1913 Webster]

   21. (Mil.)
       (a) A row of men who are abreast of one another, whether
           side by side or some distance apart; -- opposed to
           {column}.
       (b) The regular infantry of an army, as distinguished
           from militia, guards, volunteer corps, cavalry,
           artillery, etc.
           [1913 Webster]

   22. (Fort.)
       (a) A trench or rampart.
       (b) pl. Dispositions made to cover extended positions,
           and presenting a front in but one direction to an
           enemy.
           [1913 Webster]

   23. pl. (Shipbuilding) Form of a vessel as shown by the
       outlines of vertical, horizontal, and oblique sections.
       [1913 Webster]

   24. (Mus.) One of the straight horizontal and parallel
       prolonged strokes on and between which the notes are
       placed.
       [1913 Webster]

   25. (Stock Exchange) A number of shares taken by a jobber.
       [1913 Webster]

   26. (Trade) A series of various qualities and values of the
       same general class of articles; as, a full line of
       hosiery; a line of merinos, etc. --McElrath.
       [1913 Webster]

   27. The wire connecting one telegraphic station with another,
       or the whole of a system of telegraph wires under one
       management and name.
       [1913 Webster]

   28. pl. The reins with which a horse is guided by his driver.
       [U. S.]
       [1913 Webster]

   29. A measure of length; one twelfth of an inch.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Hard lines}, hard lot. --C. Kingsley. [See Def. 18.]

   {Line breeding} (Stockbreeding), breeding by a certain family
      line of descent, especially in the selection of the dam or
      mother.

   {Line conch} (Zo["o]l.), a spiral marine shell ({Fasciolaria
      distans}), of Florida and the West Indies. It is marked by
      narrow, dark, revolving lines.

   {Line engraving}.
       (a) Engraving in which the effects are produced by lines
           of different width and closeness, cut with the burin
           upon copper or similar material; also, a plate so
           engraved.
       (b) A picture produced by printing from such an
           engraving.

   {Line of battle}.
       (a) (Mil. Tactics) The position of troops drawn up in
           their usual order without any determined maneuver.
       (b) (Naval) The line or arrangement formed by vessels of
           war in an engagement.

   {Line of battle ship}. See {Ship of the line}, below.

   {Line of beauty} (Fine Arts),an abstract line supposed to be
      beautiful in itself and absolutely; -- differently
      represented by different authors, often as a kind of
      elongated S (like the one drawn by Hogarth).

   {Line of centers}. (Mach.)
       (a) A line joining two centers, or fulcra, as of wheels
           or levers.
       (b) A line which determines a dead center. See {Dead
           center}, under {Dead}.

   {Line of dip} (Geol.), a line in the plane of a stratum, or
      part of a stratum, perpendicular to its intersection with
      a horizontal plane; the line of greatest inclination of a
      stratum to the horizon.

   {Line of fire} (Mil.), the direction of fire.

   {Line of force} (Physics), any line in a space in which
      forces are acting, so drawn that at every point of the
      line its tangent is the direction of the resultant of all
      the forces. It cuts at right angles every equipotential
      surface which it meets. Specifically (Magnetism), a line
      in proximity to a magnet so drawn that any point in it is
      tangential with the direction of a short compass needle
      held at that point. --Faraday.

   {Line of life} (Palmistry), a line on the inside of the hand,
      curving about the base of the thumb, supposed to indicate,
      by its form or position, the length of a person's life.

   {Line of lines}. See {Gunter's line}.

   {Line of march}. (Mil.)
       (a) Arrangement of troops for marching.
       (b) Course or direction taken by an army or body of
           troops in marching.

   {Line of operations}, that portion of a theater of war which
      an army passes over in attaining its object. --H. W.
      Halleck.

   {Line of sight} (Firearms), the line which passes through the
      front and rear sight, at any elevation, when they are
      sighted at an object.

   {Line tub} (Naut.), a tub in which the line carried by a
      whaleboat is coiled.

   {Mason and Dixon's line}, {Mason-Dixon line}, the boundary
      line between Pennsylvania and Maryland, as run before the
      Revolution (1764-1767) by two English astronomers named
      Charles Mason and Jeremiah Dixon. In an extended sense,
      the line between the free and the slave States; as, below
      the Mason-Dixon line, i.e. in the South.

   {On the line},
       (a) on a level with the eye of the spectator; -- said of
           a picture, as hung in an exhibition of pictures.
       (b) at risk (dependent upon success) in a contest or
           enterprise; as, the survival of the company is on the
           line in this project.

   {Right line}, a straight line; the shortest line that can be
      drawn between two points.

   {Ship of the line}, formerly, a ship of war large enough to
      have a place in the line of battle; a vessel superior to a
      frigate; usually, a seventy-four, or three-decker; --
      called also {line of battle ship} or {battleship}.
      --Totten.

   {To cross the line}, to cross the equator, as a vessel at
      sea.

   {To give a person line}, to allow him more or less liberty
      until it is convenient to stop or check him, like a hooked
      fish that swims away with the line.

   {Water line} (Shipbuilding), the outline of a horizontal
      section of a vessel, as when floating in the water.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>line</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Line \Line\ (l[imac]n), v. t.
   1. To mark with a line or lines; to cover with lines; as, to
      line a copy book.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had a healthy color in his cheeks, and his face,
            though lined, bore few traces of anxiety. --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To represent by lines; to delineate; to portray. [R.]
      ``Pictures fairest lined.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To read or repeat line by line; as, to line out a hymn.
      [1913 Webster]

            This custom of reading or lining, or, as it was
            frequently called ``deaconing'' the hymn or psalm in
            the churches, was brought about partly from
            necessity.                            --N. D. Gould.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To form into a line; to align; as, to line troops.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To line bees}, to track wild bees to their nest by following
      their line of flight.

   {To line up} (Mach.), to put in alignment; to put in correct
      adjustment for smooth running. See 3d {Line}, 19.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>line</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>line
     n 1: a formation of people or things one beside another; "the
          line of soldiers advanced with their bayonets fixed";
          "they were arrayed in line of battle"; "the cast stood
          in line for the curtain call"
     2: a mark that is long relative to its width; "He drew a line
        on the chart"; "The substance produced characteristic
        lines on the spectroscope"
     3: a formation of people or things one behind another; "the
        line stretched clear around the corner"; "you must wait in
        a long line at the checkout counter"
     4: a length (straight or curved) without breadth or thickness;
        the trace of a moving point
     5: text consisting of a row of words written across a page or
        computer screen; "the letter consisted of three short
        lines"; "there are six lines in every stanza"
     6: a single frequency (or very narrow band) of radiation in a
        spectrum
     7: a fortified position (especially one marking the most
        forward position of troops); "they attacked the enemy's
        line"
     8: the methodical process of logical reasoning; "I can't follow
        your line of reasoning" [syn: {argumentation}, {logical
        argument}, {line of reasoning}]
     9: a conductor for transmitting electrical or optical signals
        or electric power [syn: {cable}, {transmission line}]
     10: a connected series of events or actions or developments;
         "the government took a firm course"; "historians can only
         point out those lines for which evidence is available"
         [syn: {course}]
     11: a spatial location defined by a real or imaginary
         unidimensional extent
     12: a slight depression in the smoothness of a surface; "his
         face has many lines"; "ironing gets rid of most wrinkles"
         [syn: {wrinkle}, {furrow}, {crease}, {crinkle}, {seam}]
     13: a pipe used to transport liquids or gases; "a pipeline runs
         from the wells to the seaport" [syn: {pipeline}]
     14: the road consisting of railroad track and roadbed [syn: {railway
         line}, {rail line}]
     15: a telephone connection [syn: {telephone line}, {phone line},
          {telephone circuit}, {subscriber line}]
     16: acting in conformity; "in line with"; "he got out of line";
         "toe the line"
     17: the descendants of one individual; "his entire lineage has
         been warriors" [syn: {lineage}, {line of descent}, {descent},
          {bloodline}, {blood line}, {blood}, {pedigree}, {ancestry},
          {origin}, {parentage}, {stemma}, {stock}]
     18: something (as a cord or rope) that is long and thin and
         flexible; "a washing line"
     19: the principal activity in your life that you do to earn
         money; "he's not in my line of business" [syn: {occupation},
          {business}, {job}, {line of work}]
     20: in games or sports; a mark indicating positions or bounds of
         the playing area
     21: (often plural) a means of communication or access; "it must
         go through official channels"; "lines of communication
         were set up between the two firms" [syn: {channel}, {communication
         channel}]
     22: a particular kind of product or merchandise; "a nice line of
         shoes" [syn: {product line}, {line of products}, {line of
         merchandise}, {business line}, {line of business}]
     23: a commercial organization serving as a common carrier
     24: space for one line of print (one column wide and 1/14 inch
         deep) used to measure advertising [syn: {agate line}]
     25: the maximum credit that a customer is allowed [syn: {credit
         line}, {line of credit}, {bank line}, {personal credit
         line}, {personal line of credit}]
     26: a succession of notes forming a distinctive sequence; "she
         was humming an air from Beethoven" [syn: {tune}, {melody},
          {air}, {strain}, {melodic line}, {melodic phrase}]
     27: a short personal letter; "drop me a line when you get there"
         [syn: {note}, {short letter}, {billet}]
     28: a conceptual separation or demarcation; "there is a narrow
         line between sanity and insanity" [syn: {dividing line},
         {demarcation}, {contrast}]
     29: mechanical system in a factory whereby an article is
         conveyed through sites at which successive operations are
         performed on it [syn: {production line}, {assembly line}]
     v 1: be in line with; form a line along; "trees line the
          riverbank" [syn: {run along}]
     2: cover the interior of (garments); "line the gloves"
     3: make a mark or lines on a surface; "draw a line"; "trace the
        outline of a figure in the sand" [syn: {trace}, {draw}, {describe},
         {delineate}]
     4: mark with lines; "sorrow had lined his face"
     5: fill plentifully; "line one's pockets"
     6: reinforce with fabric; "lined books are more enduring"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
