<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lining</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lining</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lining \Lin"ing\ (l[imac]n"[i^]ng), n. [See {Line} to cover the
   in side.]
   1. The act of one who lines; the act or process of making
      lines, or of inserting a lining.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which covers the inner surface of anything, as of a
      garment or a box; also, the contents of anything.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lining of his coffers shall make coats
            To deck our soldiers.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lining</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Line \Line\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lined} (l[imac]nd); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Lining}.] [See {Line} flax.]
   1. To cover the inner surface of; as, to line a cloak with
      silk or fur; to line a box with paper or tin.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inside lined with rich carnation silk. --W.
                                                  Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put something in the inside of; to fill; to supply, as
      a purse with money.
      [1913 Webster]

            The charge amounteth very high for any one man's
            purse, except lined beyond ordinary, to reach unto.
                                                  --Carew.
      [1913 Webster]

            Till coffee has her stomach lined.    --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To place persons or things along the side of for security
      or defense; to strengthen by adding anything; to fortify;
      as, to line works with soldiers.
      [1913 Webster]

            Line and new repair our towns of war
            With men of courage and with means defendant.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To impregnate; -- applied to brute animals. --Creech.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Lined gold}, gold foil having a lining of another metal.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lining</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lining
     n 1: a protective covering that protects an inside surface
     2: a piece of cloth that is used as the inside surface of a
        garment [syn: {liner}]
     3: providing something with a surface of a different material
        [syn: {facing}]
     4: the act of attaching an inside lining (to a garment or
        curtain etc.)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
