<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>link</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>link</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>link
     
        1. &lt;file system&gt; {hard link} or {symbolic link}.
     
        2. &lt;hypertext&gt; {hyperlink}.
     
        (1997-10-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>link</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Link \Link\ (l[i^][ng]k), n. [Prob. corrupted from lint and this
   for lunt a torch, match, D. lont match; akin to G. lunte, cf.
   MHG. l["u]nden to burn. Cf. {Lunt}, {Linstock}.]
   A torch made of tow and pitch, or the like. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>link</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Link \Link\, n. [OE. linke, AS. hlence; akin to Sw. l["a]nk ring
   of a chain, Dan. l[ae]nke chain, Icel. hlekkr; cf. G. gelenk
   joint, link, ring of a chain, lenken to bend.]
   1. A single ring or division of a chain.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: Anything, whether material or not, which binds
      together, or connects, separate things; a part of a
      connected series; a tie; a bond. ``Links of iron.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The link of brotherhood, by which
            One common Maker bound me to the kind. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

            And so by double links enchained themselves in
            lover's life.                         --Gascoigne.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything doubled and closed like a link; as, a link of
      horsehair. --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Kinematics) Any one of the several elementary pieces of a
      mechanism, as the fixed frame, or a rod, wheel, mass of
      confined liquid, etc., by which relative motion of other
      parts is produced and constrained.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mach.) Any intermediate rod or piece for transmitting
      force or motion, especially a short connecting rod with a
      bearing at each end; specifically (Steam Engine), the
      slotted bar, or connecting piece, to the opposite ends of
      which the eccentric rods are jointed, and by means of
      which the movement of the valve is varied, in a link
      motion.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Surveying) The length of one joint of Gunter's chain,
      being the hundredth part of it, or 7.92 inches, the chain
      being 66 feet in length. Cf. {Chain}, n., 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Chem.) A bond of affinity, or a unit of valence between
      atoms; -- applied to a unit of chemical force or
      attraction.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. pl. Sausages; -- because linked together. [Colloq.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>link</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Link \Link\, v. i.
   To be connected.
   [1913 Webster]

         No one generation could link with the other. --Burke.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>link</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Link \Link\ (l[i^][ng]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Linked}
   (l[i^][ng]kt); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Linking}.]
   To connect or unite with a link or as with a link; to join;
   to attach; to unite; to couple.
   [1913 Webster]

         All the tribes and nations that composed it [the Roman
         Empire] were linked together, not only by the same laws
         and the same government, but by all the facilities of
         commodious intercourse, and of frequent communication.
                                                  --Eustace.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>link</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Link \Link\ (l[i^][ng]k), n. [See {Linch}.]
   1. A hill or ridge, as a sand hill, or a wooded or turfy bank
      between cultivated fields, etc. [Scot. &amp; Prov. Eng.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. A winding of a river; also, the ground along such a
      winding; a meander; -- usually in pl. [Scot.]

            The windings or ``links'' of the Forth above and
            below Stirling are extremely tortuous. --Encyc.
                                                  Brit.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. pl. Sand hills with the surrounding level or undulating
      land, such as occur along the seashore, a river bank, etc.
      [Scot.]

            Golf may be played on any park or common, but its
            original home is the ``links'' or common land which
            is found by the seashore, where the short close
            tuft, the sandy subsoil, and the many natural
            obstacles in the shape of bents, whins, sand holes,
            and banks, supply the conditions which are essential
            to the proper pursuit of the game.    --Encyc. of
                                                  Sport.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. pl. Hence, any such piece of ground where golf is played;
      a golf course.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>link</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>link
     n 1: the means of connection between things linked in series
          [syn: {nexus}]
     2: a fastener that serves to join or link; "the walls are held
        together with metal links placed in the wet mortar during
        construction" [syn: {linkup}, {tie}, {tie-in}]
     3: the state of being connected; "the connection between church
        and state is inescapable" [syn: {connection}, {connectedness}]
        [ant: {disjunction}]
     4: a connecting shape [syn: {connection}, {connexion}]
     5: a unit of length equal to 1/100 of a chain
     6: (computing) an instruction that connects one part of a
        program or an element on a list to another program or list
     7: a channel for communication between groups; "he provided a
        liaison with the guerrillas" [syn: {liaison}, {contact}, {inter-group
        communication}]
     8: a two-way radio communication system (usually microwave);
        part of a more extensive telecommunication network [syn: {radio
        link}]
     9: an interconnecting circuit between two or more locations for
        the purpose of transmitting and receiving data [syn: {data
        link}]
     v 1: make a logical or causal connection; "I cannot connect these
          two pieces of evidence in my mind"; "colligate these
          facts"; "I cannot relate these events at all" [syn: {associate},
           {tie in}, {relate}, {colligate}, {link up}, {connect}]
          [ant: {decouple}]
     2: connect, fasten, or put together two or more pieces; "Can
        you connect the two loudspeakers?"; "Tie the ropes
        together"; "Link arms" [syn: {connect}, {tie}, {link up}]
        [ant: {disconnect}]
     3: be or become joined or united or linked; "The two streets
        connect to become a highway"; "Our paths joined"; "The
        travelers linked up again at the airport" [syn: {connect},
         {link up}, {join}, {unite}]
     4: link with or as with a yoke; "yoke the oxen together" [syn:
        {yoke}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
