<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>list</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>list
     
        &lt;data&gt; A data structure holding many values, possibly of
        different types, which is usually accessed sequentially,
        working from the head to the end of the tail - an "ordered
        list".  This contrasts with a (one-dimensional) {array}, any
        element of which can be accessed equally quickly.
     
        Lists are often stored using a cell and pointer arrangement
        where each value is stored in a cell along with an associated
        pointer to the next cell.  A special pointer, e.g. zero, marks
        the end of the list.  This is known as a (singlely) "linked
        list".  A doublely linked list has pointers from each cell to
        both next and previous cells.
     
        An unordered list is a {set}.
     
        (1998-11-12)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\, v. i. [OE. listen, lusten, AS. lystan, from lust
   pleasure. See {Lust}.]
   1. To desire or choose; to please.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wind bloweth where it listeth.    --John iii. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

            Them that add to the Word of God what them listeth.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let other men think of your devices as they list.
                                                  --Whitgift.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) To lean; to incline; as, the ship lists to port.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\, n.
   1. Inclination; desire. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) An inclination to one side; as, the ship has a
      list to starboard.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\ (l[i^]st), n. [F. lice, LL. liciae, pl., from L.
   licium thread, girdle.]
   A line inclosing or forming the extremity of a piece of
   ground, or field of combat; hence, in the plural (lists), the
   ground or field inclosed for a race or combat. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

         In measured lists to toss the weighty lance. --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To enter the lists}, to accept a challenge, or engage in
      contest.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\, n. [AS. l[=i]st a list of cloth; akin to D. lijst,
   G. leiste, OHG. l[=i]sta, Icel. lista, listi, Sw. list, Dan.
   liste. In sense 5 from F. liste, of German origin, and thus
   ultimately the same word.]
   1. A strip forming the woven border or selvedge of cloth,
      particularly of broadcloth, and serving to strengthen it;
      hence, a strip of cloth; a fillet. ``Gartered with a red
      and blue list.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A limit or boundary; a border.
      [1913 Webster]

            The very list, the very utmost bound,
            Of all our fortunes.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The lobe of the ear; the ear itself. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A stripe. [Obs.] --Sir T. Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A roll or catalogue, that is, row or line; a record of
      names; as, a list of names, books, articles; a list of
      ratable estate.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was the ablest emperor of all the list. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Arch.) A little square molding; a fillet; -- called also
      {listel}.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Carp.) A narrow strip of wood, esp. sapwood, cut from the
      edge of a plank or board.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Rope Making) A piece of woolen cloth with which the yarns
      are grasped by a workman.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Tin-plate Manuf.)
      (a) The first thin coat of tin.
      (b) A wirelike rim of tin left on an edge of the plate
          after it is coated.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Civil list} (Great Britain &amp; U.S.), the civil officers of
      government, as judges, ambassadors, secretaries, etc.
      Hence, the revenues or appropriations of public money for
      the support of the civil officers. More recently, the
      civil list, in England, embraces only the expenses of the
      reigning monarch's household.

   {Free list}.
      (a) A list of articles admitted to a country free of duty.
      (b) A list of persons admitted to any entertainment, as a
          theater or opera, without payment, or to whom a
          periodical, or the like, is furnished without cost.

   Syn: Roll; catalogue; register; inventory; schedule.

   Usage: {List}, {Roll}, {Catalogue}, {Register}, {Inventory},
          {Schedule}. A list is properly a simple series of
          names, etc., in a brief form, such as might naturally
          be entered in a narrow strip of paper. A roll was
          originally a list containing the names of persons
          belonging to a public body (as Parliament, etc.),
          which was rolled up and laid aside among its archives.
          A catalogue is a list of persons or things arranged in
          order, and usually containing some description of the
          same, more or less extended. A register is designed
          for record or preservation. An inventory is a list of
          articles, found on hand in a store of goods, or in the
          estate of a deceased person, or under similar
          circumstances. A schedule is a formal list or
          inventory prepared for legal or business purposes.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\, v. t.
   To inclose for combat; as, to list a field.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\, v. i. [See {Listen}.]
   To hearken; to attend; to listen. [Obs. except in poetry.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Stand close, and list to him.            --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\, v. t.
   To listen or hearken to.
   [1913 Webster]

         Then weigh what loss your honor may sustain,
         If with too credent ear you list his songs. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\, v. i.
   To engage in public service by enrolling one's name; to
   enlist.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\ (l[i^]st), v. t.
   1. To plow and plant with a lister.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. In cotton culture, to prepare, as land, for the crop by
      making alternating beds and alleys with the hoe. [Southern
      U. S.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>List \List\ (l[i^]st), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Listed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Listing}.] [From list a roll.]
   1. To sew together, as strips of cloth, so as to make a show
      of colors, or form a border. --Sir H. Wotton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover with list, or with strips of cloth; to put list
      on; as, to list a door; to stripe as if with list.
      [1913 Webster]

            The tree that stood white-listed through the gloom.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To enroll; to place or register in a list.
      [1913 Webster]

            Listed among the upper serving men.   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To engage, as a soldier; to enlist.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will list you for my soldier.       --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Carp.) To cut away a narrow strip, as of sapwood, from
      the edge of; as, to list a board.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To list a stock} (Stock Exchange), to put it in the list of
      stocks called at the meeting of the board.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>list</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>list
     n 1: a database containing an ordered array of items (names or
          topics) [syn: {listing}]
     2: the property possessed by a line or surface that departs
        from the vertical; "the tower had a pronounced tilt"; "the
        ship developed a list to starboard"; "he walked with a
        heavy inclination to the right" [syn: {tilt}, {inclination},
         {lean}, {leaning}]
     v 1: give or make a list of; name individually; give the names
          of; "List the states west of the Mississippi" [syn: {name}]
     2: include in a list; "Am I listed in your register?"
     3: enumerate; "We must number the names of the great
        mathematicians" [syn: {number}]
     4: cause to lean to the side; "Erosion listed the old tree"
        [syn: {lean}]
     5: tilt to one side; "The balloon heeled over"; "the wind made
        the vessel heel"; "The ship listed to starboard" [syn: {heel}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
