<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>litter</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>litter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Litter
   (Heb. tsab, as being lightly and gently borne), a sedan or
   palanquin for the conveyance of persons of rank (Isa. 66:20). In
   Num. 7:3, the words "covered wagons" are more literally "carts
   of the litter kind." There they denote large and commodious
   vehicles drawn by oxen, and fitted for transporting the
   furniture of the temple.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>litter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Litter \Lit"ter\ (l[i^]t"t[~e]r), n. [F. liti[`e]re, LL.
   lectaria, fr. L. lectus couch, bed. See {Lie} to be
   prostrated, and cf. {Coverlet}.]
   1. A bed or stretcher so arranged that a person, esp. a sick
      or wounded person, may be easily carried in or upon it.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is a litter ready; lay him in 't. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Straw, hay, etc., scattered on a floor, as bedding for
      animals to rest on; also, a covering of straw for plants.
      [1913 Webster]

            To crouch in litter of your stable planks. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Take off the litter from your kernel beds. --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Things lying scattered about in a manner indicating
      slovenliness; scattered rubbish.
      [1913 Webster]

            Strephon, who found the room was void.
            Stole in, and took a strict survey
            Of all the litter as it lay.          --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Disorder or untidiness resulting from scattered rubbish,
      or from thongs lying about uncared for; as, a room in a
      state of litter.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The young brought forth at one time, by a cat, dog, sow or
      other multiparous animal, taken collectively. Also Fig.
      [1913 Webster]

            A wolf came to a sow, and very kindly offered to
            take care of her litter.              --D. Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            Reflect upon that numerous litter of strange,
            senseless opinions that crawl about the world.
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>litter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Litter \Lit"ter\ (l[i^]t"t[~e]r), v. i.
   1. To be supplied with litter as bedding; to sleep or make
      one's bed in litter. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The inn
            Where he and his horse littered.      --Habington.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To produce a litter.
      [1913 Webster]

            A desert . . . where the she-wolf still littered.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>litter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Litter \Lit"ter\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Littered}
   (l[i^]t"t[~e]rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Littering}.]
   1. To supply with litter, as cattle; to cover with litter, as
      the floor of a stall.
      [1913 Webster]

            Tell them how they litter their jades. --Bp.
                                                  Hackett.
      [1913 Webster]

            For his ease, well littered was the floor. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put into a confused or disordered condition; to strew
      with scattered articles; as, to litter a room.
      [1913 Webster]

            The room with volumes littered round. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give birth to; to bear; -- said of brutes, esp. those
      which produce more than one at a birth, and also of human
      beings, in abhorrence or contempt.
      [1913 Webster]

            We might conceive that dogs were created blind,
            because we observe they were littered so with us.
                                                  --Sir T.
                                                  Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

            The son that she did litter here,
            A freckled whelp hagborn.             --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>litter</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>litter
     n 1: the offspring at one birth of a multiparous mammal
     2: rubbish carelessly dropped or left about (especially in
        public places)
     3: conveyance consisting of a chair or bed carried on two poles
        by bearers
     4: material used to provide a bed for animals [syn: {bedding
        material}, {bedding}]
     v 1: strew; "Cigar butts littered the ground"
     2: make a place messy by strewing garbage around
     3: give birth to a litter of animals
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
