<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lived</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lived</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Live \Live\ (l[i^]v), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lived} (l[i^]vd); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Living}.] [OE. liven, livien, AS. libban,
   lifian; akin to OS. libbian, D. leven, G. leben, OHG.
   leb[=e]n, Dan. leve, Sw. lefva, Icel. lifa to live, to be
   left, to remain, Goth. liban to live; akin to E. leave to
   forsake, and life, Gr. liparei^n to persist, liparo`s oily,
   shining, sleek, li`pos fat, lard, Skr. lip to anoint, smear;
   -- the first sense prob. was, to cleave to, stick to; hence,
   to remain, stay; and hence, to live.]
   1. To be alive; to have life; to have, as an animal or a
      plant, the capacity of assimilating matter as food, and to
      be dependent on such assimilation for a continuance of
      existence; as, animals and plants that live to a great age
      are long in reaching maturity.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus saith the Lord God unto these bones; Behold, I
            will . . . lay sinews upon you, and will bring up
            flesh upon you, and cover you with skin, and put
            breath in you, and ye shall live.     --Ezek.
                                                  xxxvii. 5, 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pass one's time; to pass life or time in a certain
      manner, as to habits, conduct, or circumstances; as, to
      live in ease or affluence; to live happily or usefully.
      [1913 Webster]

            O death, how bitter is the remembrance of thee to a
            man that liveth at rest in his possessions!
                                                  --Ecclus. xli.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make one's abiding place or home; to abide; to dwell;
      to reside; as, to live in a cottage by the sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jacob lived in the land of Egypt seventeen years.
                                                  --Gen. xlvii.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be or continue in existence; to exist; to remain; to be
      permanent; to last; -- said of inanimate objects, ideas,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men's evil manners live in brass; their virtues
            We write in water.                    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To enjoy or make the most of life; to be in a state of
      happiness; as, people want not just to exist, but to live.
      [1913 Webster]

            What greater curse could envious fortune give
            Than just to die when I began to live? --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To feed; to subsist; to be nourished or supported; -- with
      on; as, horses live on grass and grain.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To have a spiritual existence; to be quickened, nourished,
      and actuated by divine influence or faith.
      [1913 Webster]

            The just shall live by faith.         --Gal. iii.
                                                  ll.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To be maintained in life; to acquire a livelihood; to
      subsist; -- with on or by; as, to live on spoils.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those who live by labor.              --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To outlast danger; to float; -- said of a ship, boat,
      etc.; as, no ship could live in such a storm.
      [1913 Webster]

            A strong mast that lived upon the sea. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To live out}, to be at service; to live away from home as a
      servant. [U. S.]

   {To live with}.
      (a) To dwell or to be a lodger with.
      (b) To cohabit with; to have intercourse with, as male
          with female.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lived</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lived \Lived\ (l[imac]vd), a.
   Having life; -- used only in composition; as, long-lived;
   short-lived.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
