<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>live</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>live</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Live \Live\ (l[i^]v), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lived} (l[i^]vd); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Living}.] [OE. liven, livien, AS. libban,
   lifian; akin to OS. libbian, D. leven, G. leben, OHG.
   leb[=e]n, Dan. leve, Sw. lefva, Icel. lifa to live, to be
   left, to remain, Goth. liban to live; akin to E. leave to
   forsake, and life, Gr. liparei^n to persist, liparo`s oily,
   shining, sleek, li`pos fat, lard, Skr. lip to anoint, smear;
   -- the first sense prob. was, to cleave to, stick to; hence,
   to remain, stay; and hence, to live.]
   1. To be alive; to have life; to have, as an animal or a
      plant, the capacity of assimilating matter as food, and to
      be dependent on such assimilation for a continuance of
      existence; as, animals and plants that live to a great age
      are long in reaching maturity.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus saith the Lord God unto these bones; Behold, I
            will . . . lay sinews upon you, and will bring up
            flesh upon you, and cover you with skin, and put
            breath in you, and ye shall live.     --Ezek.
                                                  xxxvii. 5, 6.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pass one's time; to pass life or time in a certain
      manner, as to habits, conduct, or circumstances; as, to
      live in ease or affluence; to live happily or usefully.
      [1913 Webster]

            O death, how bitter is the remembrance of thee to a
            man that liveth at rest in his possessions!
                                                  --Ecclus. xli.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make one's abiding place or home; to abide; to dwell;
      to reside; as, to live in a cottage by the sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jacob lived in the land of Egypt seventeen years.
                                                  --Gen. xlvii.
                                                  28.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To be or continue in existence; to exist; to remain; to be
      permanent; to last; -- said of inanimate objects, ideas,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men's evil manners live in brass; their virtues
            We write in water.                    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To enjoy or make the most of life; to be in a state of
      happiness; as, people want not just to exist, but to live.
      [1913 Webster]

            What greater curse could envious fortune give
            Than just to die when I began to live? --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To feed; to subsist; to be nourished or supported; -- with
      on; as, horses live on grass and grain.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To have a spiritual existence; to be quickened, nourished,
      and actuated by divine influence or faith.
      [1913 Webster]

            The just shall live by faith.         --Gal. iii.
                                                  ll.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To be maintained in life; to acquire a livelihood; to
      subsist; -- with on or by; as, to live on spoils.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those who live by labor.              --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To outlast danger; to float; -- said of a ship, boat,
      etc.; as, no ship could live in such a storm.
      [1913 Webster]

            A strong mast that lived upon the sea. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To live out}, to be at service; to live away from home as a
      servant. [U. S.]

   {To live with}.
      (a) To dwell or to be a lodger with.
      (b) To cohabit with; to have intercourse with, as male
          with female.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>live</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Live \Live\ (l[i^]v), v. t.
   1. To spend, as one's life; to pass; to maintain; to continue
      in, constantly or habitually; as, to live an idle or a
      useful life.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To act habitually in conformity with; to practice.
      [1913 Webster]

            To live the Gospel.                   --Foxe.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To live down}, to live so as to subdue or refute; as, to
      live down slander.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>live</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Live \Live\ (l[imac]v), a. [Abbreviated from alive. See {Alive},
   {Life}.]
   1. Having life; alive; living; not dead.
      [1913 Webster]

            If one man's ox hurt another's, that he die; then
            they shall sell the live ox, and divide the money of
            it.                                   --Ex. xxi. 35.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Being in a state of ignition; burning; having active
      properties; as, a live coal; live embers. `` The live
      ether.'' --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Full of earnestness; active; wide awake; glowing; as, a
      live man, or orator.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Vivid; bright. `` The live carnation.'' --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Engin.) Imparting power; having motion; as, the live
      spindle of a lathe; live steam.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Elec.) Connected to a voltage source; as, a live wire.
      [PJC]

   7. (Broadcasting) Being transmitted instantaneously, as
      events occur, in contrast to {recorded}.
      [PJC]

   8. (Sport) Still in active play; -- of a ball being used in a
      game; as, a live ball.
      [PJC]

   9. Pertaining to an entertainment event which was performed
      (and possibly recorded) in front of an audience;
      contrasted to performances recorded in a studio without an
      audience.
      [PJC]

   {Live birth}, the condition of being born in such a state
      that acts of life are manifested after the extrusion of
      the whole body. --Dunglison.

   {Live box}, a cell for holding living objects under
      microscopical examination. --P. H. Gosse.

   {Live feathers}, feathers which have been plucked from the
      living bird, and are therefore stronger and more elastic.
      

   {Live gang}. (Sawing) See under {Gang}.

   {Live grass} (Bot.), a grass of the genus {Eragrostis}.

   {Live load} (Engin.), a suddenly applied load; a varying
      load; a moving load; as a moving train of cars on a
      bridge, or wind pressure on a roof.

   {Live oak} (Bot.), a species of oak ({Quercus virens}),
      growing in the Southern States, of great durability, and
      highly esteemed for ship timber. In California the
      {Quercus chrysolepis} and some other species are also
      called live oaks.

   {Live ring} (Engin.), a circular train of rollers upon which
      a swing bridge, or turntable, rests, and which travels
      around a circular track when the bridge or table turns.

   {Live steam}, steam direct from the boiler, used for any
      purpose, in distinction from {exhaust steam}.

   {Live stock}, horses, cattle, and other domestic animals kept
      on a farm. whole body.

   {live wire}
      (a) (Elec.) a wire connected to a power source, having a
          voltage potential; -- used esp. of a power line with a
          high potential relative to ground, capable of harming
          a person who touches it.
      (b) (Fig.) a person who is unusually active, alert, or
          aggressive.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>live</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Live \Live\ (l[imac]v), n.
   Life. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

   {On live}, in life; alive. [Obs.] See {Alive}. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>live</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>live /li:v/ adj.,adv. [common] Opposite of `test'. Refers to actual
   real-world data or a program working with it. For example, the response
   to "I think the record deleter is finished" might be "Is it live yet?"
   or "Have you tried it out on live data?" This usage usually carries the
   connotation that live data is more fragile and must not be corrupted, or
   bad things will happen. So a more appropriate response might be: "Well,
   make sure it works perfectly before we throw live data at it." The
   implication here is that record deletion is something pretty
   significant, and a haywire record-deleter running amok live would
   probably cause great harm.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>live</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LIVE
     LInux VErband (Linux, org.)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>live</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>live
     adj 1: actually being performed at the time of hearing or viewing;
            "a live television program"; "brought to you live from
            Lincoln Center"; "live entertainment involves
            performers actually in the physical presence of a live
            audience" [syn: {unrecorded}] [ant: {recorded}]
     2: showing characteristics of life; exerting force or
        containing energy; "live coals"; "tossed a live cigarette
        out the window"; "got a shock from a live wire"; "live ore
        is unmined ore"; "a live bomb"; "a live ball is one in
        play" [ant: {dead}]
     3: highly reverberant; "a live concert hall" [syn: {live(a)}]
     4: charged with an explosive; "live ammunition"; "a live bomb"
     5: rebounds readily; "clean bouncy hair"; "a lively tennis
        ball"; "as resiliant as seasoned hickory"; "springy turf"
        [syn: {bouncy}, {lively}, {resilient}, {springy}, {whippy}]
     6: abounding with life and energy; "the club members are a
        really live bunch"
     7: in current use or ready for use; "live copy is ready to be
        set in type or already set but not yet proofread"
     8: of current relevance; "a live issue"; "still a live option"
     9: charged or energized with electricity; "a hot wire"; "a live
        wire" [syn: {hot}]
     10: having life; "a live canary"; "hit a live nerve"; "famous
         living painters"; "living tissue";
     11: capable of erupting; "a live volcano"; "the volcano is very
         much alive" [syn: {alive(p)}, {live(a)}]
     adv : not recorded; "the opera was broadcast live"
     v 1: make one's home or live in; "She resides officially in
          Iceland"; "I live in a 200-year old house"; "These
          people inhabited all the islands that are now deserted";
          "The plains are sparsely populated" [syn: {dwell}, {shack},
           {reside}, {inhabit}, {people}, {populate}, {domicile},
          {domiciliate}]
     2: lead a certain kind of life; live in a certain style; "we
        had to live frugally after the war"
     3: continue to live; endure or last; "We went without water and
        food for 3 days"; "These superstitions survive in the
        backwaters of America"; "The racecar driver lived through
        several very serious accidents" [syn: {survive}, {last}, {live
        on}, {go}, {endure}, {hold up}, {hold out}]
     4: support oneself; "he could barely exist on such a low wage";
        "Can you live on $2000 a month in New York City?"; "Many
        people in the world have to subsist on $1 a day" [syn: {exist},
         {survive}, {subsist}]
     5: have life, be alive; "Our great leader is no more"; "My
        grandfather lived until the end of war" [syn: {be}]
     6: have firsthand knowledge of states, situations, emotions, or
        sensations; "I know the feeling!"; "have you ever known
        hunger?"; "I have lived a kind of hell when I was a drug
        addict"; "The holocaust survivors have lived a nightmare";
        "I lived through two divorces" [syn: {know}, {experience}]
     7: pursue a positive and satisfying existence; "You must accept
        yourself and others if you really want to live"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
