<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lobby</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lobby</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lobby \Lob"by\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lobbied}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Lobbying}.]
   To address or solicit members of a legislative body in the
   lobby or elsewhere, with the purpose to influence their
   votes; in an extended sense, to try to influence
   decision-makers in any circumstance. [U.S.] --Bartlett.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lobby</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lobby \Lob"by\, n.; pl. {Lobbies}. [LL. lobium, lobia, laubia, a
   covered portico fit for walking, fr. OHG. louba, G. laube,
   arbor. See {Lodge}.]
   1. (Arch.) A passage or hall of communication, especially
      when large enough to serve also as a waiting room. It
      differs from an antechamber in that a lobby communicates
      between several rooms, an antechamber to one only; but
      this distinction is not carefully preserved.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That part of a hall of legislation not appropriated to the
      official use of the assembly; hence, the persons,
      collectively, who frequent such a place to transact
      business with the legislators; hence: any persons, not
      members of a legislative body, who strive to influence its
      proceedings by personal agency; a group of lobbyists for a
      particular cause; as, the drug industry lobby. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   3. (Naut.) An apartment or passageway in the fore part of an
      old-fashioned cabin under the quarter-deck.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Agric.) A confined place for cattle, formed by hedges.
      trees, or other fencing, near the farmyard.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Lobby member}, a lobbyist. [Humorous cant, U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lobby</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lobby \Lob"by\, v. t.
   To urge the adoption or passage of by soliciting members of a
   legislative body; as, to lobby a bill; -- also used with the
   legislators as object; as, to lobby the state legislatuire
   for protection. [U.S.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lobby</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lobby
     n 1: a large entrance or reception room or area [syn: {anteroom},
           {antechamber}, {entrance hall}, {hall}, {foyer}, {vestibule}]
     2: a group of people who try actively to influence legislation
        [syn: {pressure group}, {third house}]
     v : detain in conversation by or as if by holding on to the
         outer garments of; as for political or economic favors
         [syn: {buttonhole}]
     [also: {lobbied}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
