<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lock</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LOCK-:AND:-:KEY:, n.  The distinguishing device of civilization and
enlightenment.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lock
   The Hebrews usually secured their doors by bars of wood or iron
   (Isa. 45:2; 1 Kings 4:3). These were the locks originally used,
   and were opened and shut by large keys applied through an
   opening in the outside (Judg. 3:24). (See {KEY}.)
   
     Lock of hair (Judg. 16:13, 19; Ezek. 8:3; Num. 6:5, etc.).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lock \Lock\ (l[o^]k), n. [AS. locc; akin to D. lok, G. locke,
   OHG. loc, Icel. lokkr, and perh. to Gr. ? to bend, twist.]
   A tuft of hair; a flock or small quantity of wool, hay, or
   other like substance; a tress or ringlet of hair.
   [1913 Webster]

         These gray locks, the pursuivants of death. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lock \Lock\, n. [AS. loc inclosure, an inclosed place, the
   fastening of a door, fr. l[=u]can to lock, fasten; akin to
   OS. l[=u]kan (in comp.), D. luiken, OHG. l[=u]hhan, Icel.
   l[=u]ka, Goth. l[=u]kan (in comp.); cf. Skr. ruj to break.
   Cf. {Locket}.]
   1. Anything that fastens; specifically, a fastening, as for a
      door, a lid, a trunk, a drawer, and the like, in which a
      bolt is moved by a key so as to hold or to release the
      thing fastened.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A fastening together or interlacing; a closing of one
      thing upon another; a state of being fixed or immovable.
      [1913 Webster]

            Albemarle Street closed by a lock of carriages. --De
                                                  Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A place from which egress is prevented, as by a lock.
      --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The barrier or works which confine the water of a stream
      or canal.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An inclosure in a canal with gates at each end, used in
      raising or lowering boats as they pass from one level to
      another; -- called also {lift lock}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That part or apparatus of a firearm by which the charge is
      exploded; as, a matchlock, flintlock, percussion lock,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A device for keeping a wheel from turning.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A grapple in wrestling. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Detector lock}, a lock containing a contrivance for showing
      whether it as has been tampered with.

   {Lock bay} (Canals), the body of water in a lock chamber.

   {Lock chamber}, the inclosed space between the gates of a
      canal lock.

   {Lock nut}. See {Check nut}, under {Check}.

   {Lock plate}, a plate to which the mechanism of a gunlock is
      attached.

   {Lock rail} (Arch.), in ordinary paneled doors, the rail
      nearest the lock.

   {Lock rand} (Masonry), a range of bond stone. --Knight.

   {Mortise lock}, a door lock inserted in a mortise.

   {Rim lock}, a lock fastened to the face of a door, thus
      differing from a {mortise lock}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lock \Lock\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Locked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Locking}.]
   1. To fasten with a lock, or as with a lock; to make fast; to
      prevent free movement of; as, to lock a door, a carriage
      wheel, a river, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To prevent ingress or access to, or exit from, by
      fastening the lock or locks of; -- often with up; as, to
      lock or lock up, a house, jail, room, trunk. etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To fasten in or out, or to make secure by means of, or as
      with, locks; to confine, or to shut in or out -- often
      with up; as, to lock one's self in a room; to lock up the
      prisoners; to lock up one's silver; to lock intruders out
      of the house; to lock money into a vault; to lock a child
      in one's arms; to lock a secret in one's breast.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To link together; to clasp closely; as, to lock arms. ``
      Lock hand in hand.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Canals) To furnish with locks; also, to raise or lower (a
      boat) in a lock.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Fencing) To seize, as the sword arm of an antagonist, by
      turning the left arm around it, to disarm him.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lock \Lock\, v. i.
   To become fast, as by means of a lock or by interlacing; as,
   the door locks close.
   [1913 Webster]

         When it locked none might through it pass. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To lock into}, to fit or slide into; as, they lock into each
      other. --Boyle.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Safety \Safe"ty\, n. [Cf. F. sauvet['e].]
   1. The condition or state of being safe; freedom from danger
      or hazard; exemption from hurt, injury, or loss.
      [1913 Webster]

            Up led by thee,
            Into the heaven I have presumed,
            An earthly guest . . . With like safety guided down,
            Return me to my native element.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Freedom from whatever exposes one to danger or from
      liability to cause danger or harm; safeness; hence, the
      quality of making safe or secure, or of giving confidence,
      justifying trust, insuring against harm or loss, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Would there were any safety in thy sex,
            That I might put a thousand sorrows off,
            And credit thy repentance!            --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Preservation from escape; close custody.
      [1913 Webster]

            Imprison him, . . .
            Deliver him to safety; and return.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Amer. Football) the act or result of a ball-carrier on
      the offensive team being tackled behind his own goal line,
      or the downing of a ball behind the offensive team's own
      goal line when it had been carried or propelled behind
      that goal line by a player on the offensive tream; such a
      play causes a score of two points to be awarded to the
      defensive team; -- it is distinguished from {touchback},
      when the ball is downed behind the goal after being
      propelled there or last touched by a player of the
      defending team. See {Touchdown}. Same as {Safety
      touchdown}, below.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   5. Short for {Safety bicycle}. [archaic]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. a switch on a firearm that locks the trigger and prevents
      the firearm from being discharged unintentionally; -- also
      called {safety catch}, {safety lock}, or {lock}. [archaic]
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lock</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lock
     n 1: a fastener fitted to a door or drawer to keep it firmly
          closed
     2: a strand or cluster of hair [syn: {curl}, {ringlet}, {whorl}]
     3: a mechanism that detonates the charge of a gun
     4: enclosure consisting of a section of canal that can be
        closed to control the water level; used to raise or lower
        vessels that pass through it [syn: {lock chamber}]
     5: a restraint incorporated into the ignition switch to prevent
        the use of a vehicle by persons who do not have the key
        [syn: {ignition lock}]
     6: any wrestling hold in which some part of the opponent's body
        is twisted or pressured
     v 1: fasten with a lock; "lock the bike to the fence" [ant: {unlock},
           {unlock}]
     2: keep engaged; "engaged the gears" [syn: {engage}, {mesh}, {operate}]
        [ant: {disengage}]
     3: become rigid or immoveable; "The therapist noticed that the
        patient's knees tended to lock in this exercise" [ant: {unlock}]
     4: hold in a locking position; "He locked his hands around her
        neck" [syn: {interlock}, {interlace}]
     5: become engaged or intermeshed with one another; "They were
        locked in embrace" [syn: {interlock}]
     6: hold fast (in a certain state); "He was locked in a laughing
        fit"
     7: place in a place where something cannot be removed or
        someone cannot escape; "The parents locked her daughter up
        for the weekend"; "She locked her jewels in the safe"
        [syn: {lock in}, {lock away}, {put away}, {shut up}, {shut
        away}, {lock up}]
     8: pass by means through a lock in a waterway
     9: build locks in order to facilitate the navigation of vessels
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
