<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>locust</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>locust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Locust
   There are ten Hebrew words used in Scripture to signify locust.
   In the New Testament locusts are mentioned as forming part of
   the food of John the Baptist (Matt. 3:4; Mark 1:6). By the
   Mosaic law they were reckoned "clean," so that he could lawfully
   eat them. The name also occurs in Rev. 9:3, 7, in allusion to
   this Oriental devastating insect.
   
     Locusts belong to the class of Orthoptera, i.e.,
   straight-winged. They are of many species. The ordinary Syrian
   locust resembles the grasshopper, but is larger and more
   destructive. "The legs and thighs of these insects are so
   powerful that they can leap to a height of two hundred times the
   length of their bodies. When so raised they spread their wings
   and fly so close together as to appear like one compact moving
   mass." Locusts are prepared as food in various ways. Sometimes
   they are pounded, and then mixed with flour and water, and baked
   into cakes; "sometimes boiled, roasted, or stewed in butter, and
   then eaten." They were eaten in a preserved state by the ancient
   Assyrians.
   
     The devastations they make in Eastern lands are often very
   appalling. The invasions of locusts are the heaviest calamites
   that can befall a country. "Their numbers exceed computation:
   the hebrews called them 'the countless,' and the Arabs knew them
   as 'the darkeners of the sun.' Unable to guide their own flight,
   though capable of crossing large spaces, they are at the mercy
   of the wind, which bears them as blind instruments of Providence
   to the doomed region given over to them for the time.
   Innumerable as the drops of water or the sands of the seashore,
   their flight obscures the sun and casts a thick shadow on the
   earth (Ex. 10:15; Judg. 6:5; 7:12; Jer. 46:23; Joel 2:10). It
   seems indeed as if a great aerial mountain, many miles in
   breadth, were advancing with a slow, unresting progress. Woe to
   the countries beneath them if the wind fall and let them alight!
   They descend unnumbered as flakes of snow and hide the ground.
   It may be 'like the garden of Eden before them, but behind them
   is a desolate wilderness. At their approach the people are in
   anguish; all faces lose their colour' (Joel 2:6). No walls can
   stop them; no ditches arrest them; fires kindled in their path
   are forthwith extinguished by the myriads of their dead, and the
   countless armies march on (Joel 2:8, 9). If a door or a window
   be open, they enter and destroy everything of wood in the house.
   Every terrace, court, and inner chamber is filled with them in a
   moment. Such an awful visitation swept over Egypt (Ex. 10:1-19),
   consuming before it every green thing, and stripping the trees,
   till the land was bared of all signs of vegetation. A strong
   north-west wind from the Mediterranean swept the locusts into
   the Red Sea.", Geikie's Hours, etc., ii., 149.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>locust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Locust, NC (city, FIPS 38860)
  Location: 35.25814 N, 80.43060 W
  Population (1990): 1940 (739 housing units)
  Area: 9.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 28097
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>locust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Harvest \Har"vest\ (h[aum]r"v[e^]st), n. [OE. harvest, hervest,
   AS. h[ae]rfest autumn; akin to LG. harfst, D. herfst, OHG.
   herbist, G. herbst, and prob. to L. carpere to pluck, Gr.
   karpo`s fruit. Cf. {Carpet}.]
   1. The gathering of a crop of any kind; the ingathering of
      the crops; also, the season of gathering grain and fruits,
      late summer or early autumn.
      [1913 Webster]

            Seedtime and harvest . . . shall not cease. --Gen.
                                                  viii. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

            At harvest, when corn is ripe.        --Tyndale.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is reaped or ready to be reaped or gathered; a
      crop, as of grain (wheat, maize, etc.), or fruit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Put ye in the sickle, for the harvest is ripe.
                                                  --Joel iii.
                                                  13.
      [1913 Webster]

            To glean the broken ears after the man
            That the main harvest reaps.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The product or result of any exertion or labor; gain;
      reward.
      [1913 Webster]

            The pope's principal harvest was in the jubilee.
                                                  --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            The harvest of a quiet eye.           --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Harvest fish} (Zo["o]l.), a marine fish of the Southern
      United States ({Stromateus alepidotus}); -- called
      {whiting} in Virginia. Also applied to the dollar fish.

   {Harvest fly} (Zo["o]l.), an hemipterous insect of the genus
      {Cicada}, often called {locust}. See {Cicada}.

   {Harvest lord}, the head reaper at a harvest. [Obs.]
      --Tusser.

   {Harvest mite} (Zo["o]l.), a minute European mite ({Leptus
      autumnalis}), of a bright crimson color, which is
      troublesome by penetrating the skin of man and domestic
      animals; -- called also {harvest louse}, and {harvest
      bug}.

   {Harvest moon}, the moon near the full at the time of harvest
      in England, or about the autumnal equinox, when, by reason
      of the small angle that is made by the moon's orbit with
      the horizon, it rises nearly at the same hour for several
      days.

   {Harvest mouse} (Zo["o]l.), a very small European field mouse
      ({Mus minutus}). It builds a globular nest on the stems of
      wheat and other plants.

   {Harvest queen}, an image representing Ceres, formerly
      carried about on the last day of harvest. --Milton.

   {Harvest spider}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Daddy longlegs}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>locust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Locust \Lo"cust\, n. [L. locusta locust, grasshopper. Cf.
   {Lobster}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) Any one of numerous species of long-winged,
      migratory, orthopterous insects, of the family
      {Acridid[ae]}, allied to the grasshoppers; esp., ({Edipoda
      migratoria}, syn. {Pachytylus migratoria}, and {Acridium
      perigrinum}, of Southern Europe, Asia, and Africa. In the
      United States the related species with similar habits are
      usually called {grasshoppers}. See {Grasshopper}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: These insects are at times so numerous in Africa and
         the south of Asia as to devour every green thing; and
         when they migrate, they fly in an immense cloud. In the
         United States the harvest flies are improperly called
         locusts. See {Cicada}.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Locust beetle} (Zo["o]l.), a longicorn beetle ({Cyllene
      robini[ae]}), which, in the larval state, bores holes in
      the wood of the locust tree. Its color is brownish black,
      barred with yellow. Called also {locust borer}.

   {Locust bird} (Zo["o]l.) the rose-colored starling or pastor
      of India. See {Pastor}.

   {Locust hunter} (Zo["o]l.), an African bird; the beefeater.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [Etymol. uncertain.] (Bot.) The locust tree. See {Locust
      Tree} (definition, note, and phrases).
      [1913 Webster]

   {Locust bean} (Bot.), a commercial name for the sweet pod of
      the carob tree.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>locust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>locust
     n 1: migratory grasshoppers of warm regions having short antennae
     2: hardwood from any of various locust trees
     3: any of various hard-wooded trees of the family Leguminosae
        [syn: {locust tree}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
