<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lodge</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lodge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lodge
   a shed for a watchman in a garden (Isa. 1:8). The Hebrew name
   _melunah_ is rendered "cottage" (q.v.) in Isa. 24:20. It also
   denotes a hammock or hanging-bed.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lodge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lodge, SC (town, FIPS 42280)
  Location: 33.06752 N, 80.95456 W
  Population (1990): 147 (69 housing units)
  Area: 8.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 29082
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lodge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lodge \Lodge\ (l[o^]j), n. [OE. loge, logge, F. loge, LL. laubia
   porch, gallery, fr. OHG. louba, G. laube, arbor, bower, fr.
   lab foliage. See {Leaf}, and cf. {Lobby}, {Loggia}.]
   1. A shelter in which one may rest; as:
      (a) A shed; a rude cabin; a hut; as, an Indian's lodge.
          --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]

                Their lodges and their tentis up they gan bigge
                [to build].                       --Robert of
                                                  Brunne.
          [1913 Webster]

                O for a lodge in some vast wilderness! --Cowper.
      (b) A small dwelling house, as for a gamekeeper or
          gatekeeper of an estate. --Shak.
      (c) A den or cave.
      (d) The meeting room of an association; hence, the
          regularly constituted body of members which meets
          there; as, a masonic lodge.
      (c) The chamber of an abbot, prior, or head of a college.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mining) The space at the mouth of a level next the shaft,
      widened to permit wagons to pass, or ore to be deposited
      for hoisting; -- called also {platt}. --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A collection of objects lodged together.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Maldives, a famous lodge of islands. --De Foe.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A family of North American Indians, or the persons who
      usually occupy an Indian lodge, -- as a unit of
      enumeration, reckoned from four to six persons; as, the
      tribe consists of about two hundred lodges, that is, of
      about a thousand individuals.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Lodge gate}, a park gate, or entrance gate, near the lodge.
      See {Lodge}, n., 1
      (b) .
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lodge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lodge \Lodge\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lodged} (l[o^]jd); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Lodging} (l[o^]j"[i^]ng).]
   1. To rest or remain a lodge house, or other shelter; to
      rest; to stay; to abide; esp., to sleep at night; as, to
      lodge in York Street. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Stay and lodge by me this night.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Something holy lodges in that breast. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fall or lie down, as grass or grain, when overgrown or
      beaten down by the wind. --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To come to a rest; to stop and remain; to become stuck or
      caught; as, the bullet lodged in the bark of a tree; a
      piece of meat lodged in his throat.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lodge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lodge \Lodge\, v. t. [OE. loggen, OF. logier, F. loger. See
   {Lodge}, n. ]
   1. To give shelter or rest to; especially, to furnish a
      sleeping place for; to harbor; to shelter; hence, to
      receive; to hold.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every house was proud to lodge a knight. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The memory can lodge a greater store of images than
            all the senses can present at one time. --Cheyne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To drive to shelter; to track to covert.
      [1913 Webster]

            The deer is lodged; I have tracked her to her
            covert.                               --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To deposit for keeping or preservation; as, the men lodged
      their arms in the arsenal.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cause to stop or rest in; to implant.
      [1913 Webster]

            He lodged an arrow in a tender breast. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To lay down; to prostrate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though bladed corn be lodged, and trees blown down.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To present or bring (information, a complaint) before a
      court or other authority; as, to lodge a complaint.
      [PJC]

   {To lodge an information}, to enter a formal complaint.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lodge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lodge
     n 1: English physicist who studied electromagnetic radiation and
          was a pioneer of radiotelegraphy (1851-1940) [syn: {Sir
          Oliver Lodge}, {Sir Oliver Joseph Lodge}]
     2: a formal association of people with similar interests; "he
        joined a golf club"; "they formed a small lunch society";
        "men from the fraternal order will staff the soup kitchen
        today" [syn: {club}, {society}, {guild}, {gild}, {order}]
     3: small house at the entrance to the grounds of a country
        mansion; usually occupied by a gatekeeper or gardener
     4: a small (rustic) house used as a temporary shelter [syn: {hunting
        lodge}]
     5: any of various native American dwellings [syn: {indian lodge}]
     6: a hotel providing overnight lodging for travelers [syn: {hostel},
         {hostelry}, {inn}]
     v 1: be a lodger; stay temporarily; "Where are you lodging in
          Paris?"
     2: fix, force, or implant; "lodge a bullet in the table" [syn:
        {wedge}, {stick}, {deposit}] [ant: {dislodge}]
     3: file a formal charge against; "The suspect was charged with
        murdering his wife" [syn: {charge}, {file}]
     4: provide housing for; "We are lodging three foreign students
        this semester" [syn: {accommodate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
