<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>logical</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>logical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>logical
     
        (From the technical term "logical device", wherein a physical
        device is referred to by an arbitrary "logical" name) Having
        the role of.  If a person (say, Les Earnest at SAIL) who had
        long held a certain post left and were replaced, the
        replacement would for a while be known as the "logical" Les
        Earnest.  (This does not imply any judgment on the
        replacement).
     
        Compare {virtual}.
     
        At Stanford, "logical" compass directions denote a coordinate
        system in which "logical north" is toward San Francisco,
        "logical west" is toward the ocean, etc., even though logical
        north varies between physical (true) north near San Francisco
        and physical west near San Jose.  (The best rule of thumb here
        is that, by definition, El Camino Real always runs logical
        north-and-south.)  In giving directions, one might say: "To
        get to Rincon Tarasco restaurant, get onto {El Camino Bignum}
        going logical north."  Using the word "logical" helps to
        prevent the recipient from worrying about that the fact that
        the sun is setting almost directly in front of him.  The
        concept is reinforced by North American highways which are
        almost, but not quite, consistently labelled with logical
        rather than physical directions.
     
        A similar situation exists at MIT: Route 128 (famous for the
        electronics industry that has grown up along it) is a
        3-quarters circle surrounding Boston at a radius of 10 miles,
        terminating near the coastline at each end.  It would be most
        precise to describe the two directions along this highway as
        "clockwise" and "counterclockwise", but the road signs all say
        "north" and "south", respectively.  A hacker might describe
        these directions as "logical north" and "logical south", to
        indicate that they are conventional directions not
        corresponding to the usual denotation for those words.  (If
        you went logical south along the entire length of route 128,
        you would start out going northwest, curve around to the
        south, and finish headed due east, passing along one infamous
        stretch of pavement that is simultaneously route 128 south and
        Interstate 93 north, and is signed as such!)
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-01-24)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>logical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Logical \Log"ic*al\ (l[o^]j"[i^]*kal), a. [Cf. F. logique, L.
   logicus, Gr. logiko`s.]
   1. Of or pertaining to logic; used in logic; as, logical
      subtilties. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. According to the rules of logic; as, a logical argument or
      inference; the reasoning is logical; a logical argument; a
      logical impossibility. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Skilled in logic; versed in the art of thinking and
      reasoning; as, he is a logical thinker. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>logical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>logical adj. [from the technical term `logical device', wherein a
   physical device is referred to by an arbitrary `logical' name] Having
   the role of. If a person (say, Les Earnest at SAIL) who had long held a
   certain post left and were replaced, the replacement would for a while
   be known as the `logical' Les Earnest. (This does not imply any judgment
   on the replacement.) Compare {virtual}.

   At Stanford, `logical' compass directions denote a coordinate system
   relative to El Camino Real, in which `logical north' is always toward
   San Francisco and `logical south' is always toward San Jose-in spite of
   the fact that El Camino Real runs physical north/south near San
   Francisco, physical east/west near San Jose, and along a curve
   everywhere in between. (The best rule of thumb here is that, by
   definition, El Camino Real always runs logical north-south.)

   In giving directions, one might say: "To get to Rincon Tarasco
   restaurant, get onto {El Camino Bignum} going logical north." Using the
   word `logical' helps to prevent the recipient from worrying about that
   the fact that the sun is setting almost directly in front of him. The
   concept is reinforced by North American highways which are almost, but
   not quite, consistently labeled with logical rather than physical
   directions. A similar situation exists at MIT: Route 128 (famous for the
   electronics industry that grew up along it) wraps roughly 3 quarters
   around Boston at a radius of 10 miles, terminating near the coastline at
   each end. It would be most precise to describe the two directions along
   this highway as `clockwise' and `counterclockwise', but the road signs
   all say "north" and "south", respectively. A hacker might describe these
   directions as `logical north' and `logical south', to indicate that they
   are conventional directions not corresponding to the usual denotation
   for those words.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>logical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>logical
     adj 1: capable of or reflecting the capability for correct and
            valid reasoning; "a logical mind" [ant: {illogical}]
     2: in accordance with reason or logic; "a logical conclusion"
        [syn: {legitimate}]
     3: marked by an orderly, logical, and aesthetically consistent
        relation of parts; "a logical argument"; "the orderly
        presentation" [syn: {consistent}, {ordered}, {orderly}]
     4: based on known statements or events or conditions; "rain was
        a logical expectation, given the time of year"
     5: capable of thinking and expressing yourself in a clear and
        consistent manner; "a lucid thinker"; "she was more
        coherent than she had been just after the accident" [syn:
        {coherent}, {lucid}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
