<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>longer</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>longer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Long \Long\, a. [Compar. {Longer}; superl. {Longest}.] [AS.
   long, lang; akin to OS, OFries., D., &amp; G. lang, Icel. langr,
   Sw. l[*a]ng, Dan. lang, Goth. laggs, L. longus. [root]125.
   Cf. {Length}, {Ling} a fish, {Linger}, {Lunge}, {Purloin}.]
   1. Drawn out in a line, or in the direction of length;
      protracted; extended; as, a long line; -- opposed to
      short, and distinguished from broad or wide.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Drawn out or extended in time; continued through a
      considerable tine, or to a great length; as, a long series
      of events; a long debate; a long drama; a long history; a
      long book.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Slow in passing; causing weariness by length or duration;
      lingering; as, long hours of watching.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Occurring or coming after an extended interval; distant in
      time; far away.
      [1913 Webster]

            The we may us reserve both fresh and strong
            Against the tournament, which is not long.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Having a length of the specified measure; of a specified
      length; as, a span long; a yard long; a mile long, that
      is, extended to the measure of a mile, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Far-reaching; extensive. `` Long views.'' --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Phonetics) Prolonged, or relatively more prolonged, in
      utterance; -- said of vowels and syllables. See {Short},
      a., 13, and Guide to Pronunciation, [sect][sect] 22, 30.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Finance &amp; Com.) Having a supply of stocks or goods;
      prepared for, or depending for a profit upon, advance in
      prices; as, long of cotton. Hence, the phrases: to be, or
      go, long of the market, to be on the long side of the
      market, to hold products or securities for a rise in
      price, esp. when bought on a margin. Contrasted to
      {short}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: Long is used as a prefix in a large number of compound
         adjectives which are mostly of obvious meaning; as,
         long-armed, long-beaked, long-haired, long-horned,
         long-necked, long-sleeved, long-tailed, long- worded,
         etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {In the long run}, in the whole course of things taken
      together; in the ultimate result; eventually.

   {Long clam} (Zo["o]l.), the common clam ({Mya arenaria}) of
      the Northern United States and Canada; -- called also
      {soft-shell clam} and {long-neck clam}. See {Mya}.

   {Long cloth}, a kind of cotton cloth of superior quality.

   {Long clothes}, clothes worn by a young infant, extending
      below the feet.

   {Long division}. (Math.) See {Division}.

   {Long dozen}, one more than a dozen; thirteen.

   {Long home}, the grave.

   {Long measure}, {Long meter}. See under {Measure}, {Meter}.
      

   {Long Parliament} (Eng. Hist.), the Parliament which
      assembled Nov. 3, 1640, and was dissolved by Cromwell,
      April 20, 1653.

   {Long price}, the full retail price.

   {Long purple} (Bot.), a plant with purple flowers, supposed
      to be the {Orchis mascula}. --Dr. Prior.

   {Long suit}
      (a) (Whist), a suit of which one holds originally more
          than three cards. --R. A. Proctor.
      (b) One's most important resource or source of strength;
          as, as an entertainer, her voice was her long suit.

   {Long tom}.
      (a) A pivot gun of great length and range, on the dock of
          a vessel.
      (b) A long trough for washing auriferous earth. [Western
          U.S.]
      (c) (Zo["o]l.) The long-tailed titmouse.

   {Long wall} (Coal Mining), a working in which the whole seam
      is removed and the roof allowed to fall in, as the work
      progresses, except where passages are needed.

   {Of long}, a long time. [Obs.] --Fairfax.

   {To be long of the market}, or {To go long of the market},
   {To be on the long side of the market}, etc. (Stock
      Exchange), to hold stock for a rise in price, or to have a
      contract under which one can demand stock on or before a
      certain day at a stipulated price; -- opposed to {short}
      in such phrases as, to be short of stock, to sell short,
      etc. [Cant] See {Short}.

   {To have a long head}, to have a farseeing or sagacious mind.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>longer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Longer \Long"er\, n.
   One who longs for anything.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>longer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>longer
     adj : having the greater length of two or the greatest length of
           several; "the longer (or long) edge of the door"; "the
           hypotenuse is the longest (or long) side of a right
           triangle" [syn: {longest}]
     n : a person with a strong desire for something; "a longer for
         money"; "a thirster after blood"; "a yearner for
         knowledge" [syn: {thirster}, {yearner}]
     adv : for more time; "can I stay bit longer?"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
