<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>looking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>looking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LOOKING-:GLASS:, n.  A vitreous plane upon which to display a fleeting
show for man's disillusion given.
    The King of Manchuria had a magic looking-glass, whereon whoso
looked saw, not his own image, but only that of the king.  A certain
courtier who had long enjoyed the king's favor and was thereby
enriched beyond any other subject of the realm, said to the king: 
"Give me, I pray, thy wonderful mirror, so that when absent out of
thine august presence I may yet do homage before thy visible shadow,
prostrating myself night and morning in the glory of thy benign
countenance, as which nothing has so divine splendor, O Noonday Sun of
the Universe!"
    Please with the speech, the king commanded that the mirror be
conveyed to the courtier's palace; but after, having gone thither
without apprisal, he found it in an apartment where was naught but
idle lumber.  And the mirror was dimmed with dust and overlaced with
cobwebs.  This so angered him that he fisted it hard, shattering the
glass, and was sorely hurt.  Enraged all the more by this mischance,
he commanded that the ungrateful courtier be thrown into prison, and
that the glass be repaired and taken back to his own palace; and this
was done.  But when the king looked again on the mirror he saw not his
image as before, but only the figure of a crowned ass, having a bloody
bandage on one of its hinder hooves -- as the artificers and all who
had looked upon it had before discerned but feared to report.  Taught
wisdom and charity, the king restored his courtier to liberty, had the
mirror set into the back of the throne and reigned many years with
justice and humility; and one day when he fell asleep in death while
on the throne, the whole court saw in the mirror the luminous figure
of an angel, which remains to this day.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>looking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Look \Look\ (l[oo^]k), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Looked}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Looking}.] [OE. loken, AS. l[=o]cian; akin to G.
   lugen, OHG. luog[=e]n.]
   1. To direct the eyes for the purpose of seeing something; to
      direct the eyes toward an object; to observe with the eyes
      while keeping them directed; -- with various prepositions,
      often in a special or figurative sense. See Phrases below.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To direct the attention (to something); to consider; to
      examine; as, to look at an action.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To seem; to appear; to have a particular appearance; as,
      the patient looks better; the clouds look rainy.
      [1913 Webster]

            It would look more like vanity than gratitude.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Observe how such a practice looks in another person.
                                                  --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To have a particular direction or situation; to face; to
      front.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inner gate that looketh to north. --Ezek. viii.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

            The east gate . . . which looketh eastward. --Ezek.
                                                  xi. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. In the imperative: see; behold; take notice; take care;
      observe; -- used to call attention.
      [1913 Webster]

            Look, how much we thus expel of sin, so much we
            expel of virtue.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Look, in the imperative, may be followed by a dependent
         sentence, but see is oftener so used.
         [1913 Webster]

               Look that ye bind them fast.       --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

               Look if it be my daughter.         --Talfourd.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. To show one's self in looking, as by leaning out of a
      window; as, look out of the window while I speak to you.
      Sometimes used figuratively.
      [1913 Webster]

            My toes look through the overleather. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To await the appearance of anything; to expect; to
      anticipate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Looking each hour into death's mouth to fall.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To look about}, to look on all sides, or in different
      directions.

   {To look about one}, to be on the watch; to be vigilant; to
      be circumspect or guarded.

   {To look after}.
      (a) To attend to; to take care of; as, to look after
          children.
      (b) To expect; to be in a state of expectation.
          [1913 Webster]

                Men's hearts failing them for fear, and for
                looking after those things which are coming on
                the earth.                        --Luke xxi.
                                                  26.
      (c) To seek; to search.
          [1913 Webster]

                My subject does not oblige me to look after the
                water, or point forth the place where to it is
                now retreated.                    --Woodward.

   {To look at}, to direct the eyes toward so that one sees, or
      as if to see; as, to look at a star; hence, to observe,
      examine, consider; as, to look at a matter without
      prejudice.

   {To look black}, to frown; to scowl; to have a threatening
      appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bishops thereat repined, and looked black.
                                                  --Holinshed.
      

   {To look down on} or {To look down upon}, to treat with
      indifference or contempt; to regard as an inferior; to
      despise.

   {To look for}.
      (a) To expect; as, to look for news by the arrival of a
          ship. ``Look now for no enchanting voice.'' --Milton.
      (b) To seek for; to search for; as, to look for lost
          money, or lost cattle.

   {To look forth}.
      (a) To look out of something, as from a window.
      (b) To threaten to come out. --Jer. vi. 1. (Rev. Ver.).

   {To look forward to}. To anticipate with an expectation of
      pleasure; to be eager for; as, I am looking forward to
      your visit.

   {To look into}, to inspect closely; to observe narrowly; to
      examine; as, to look into the works of nature; to look
      into one's conduct or affairs.

   {To look on}.
      (a) To regard; to esteem.
          [1913 Webster]

                Her friends would look on her the worse.
                                                  --Prior.
      (b) To consider; to view; to conceive of; to think of.
          [1913 Webster]

                I looked on Virgil as a succinct, majestic
                writer.                           --Dryden.
      (c) To be a mere spectator.
          [1913 Webster]

                I'll be a candleholder, and look on. --Shak.

   {To look out}, to be on the watch; to be careful; as, the
      seaman looks out for breakers.

   {To look through}.
      (a) To see through.
      (b) To search; to examine with the eyes.

   {To look to} or {To look unto}.
      (a) To watch; to take care of. ``Look well to thy herds.''
          --Prov. xxvii. 23.
      (b) To resort to with expectation of receiving something;
          to expect to receive from; as, the creditor may look
          to surety for payment. ``Look unto me, and be ye
          saved.'' --Is. xlv. 22.

   {To look up}, to search for or find out by looking; as, to
      look up the items of an account.

   {To look up to}, to respect; to regard with deference.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>looking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Looking \Look"ing\, a.
   Having a certain look or appearance; -- often compounded with
   adjectives; as, good-looking, grand-looking, etc.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>looking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Looking \Look"ing\, n.
   1. The act of one who looks; a glance.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The manner in which one looks; appearance; countenance;
      face. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            All dreary was his cheer and his looking. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Looking for}, anticipation; expectation. ``A certain fearful
      looking for of judgment.'' --Heb. x. 27.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>looking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>looking
     adj : appearing to be as specified; usually used as combining
           forms; "left their clothes dirty looking"; "a most
           disagreeable looking character"; "angry-looking";
           "liquid-looking"; "severe-looking policemen on noble
           horses"; "fine-sounding phrases"; "taken in by
           high-sounding talk" [syn: {sounding}]
     n 1: the act of directing the eyes toward something and
          perceiving it visually; "he went out to have a look";
          "his look was fixed on her eyes"; "he gave it a good
          looking at"; "his camera does his looking for him" [syn:
           {look}, {looking at}]
     2: the act of searching visually [syn: {looking for}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
