<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>look</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>look</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LOOK
     
        A specification language.
     
        ["A Look at Algebraic Specifications", S.N. Zilles et al, IBM
        RR, 1982].
     
        (1994-11-16)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>look</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Look \Look\ (l[oo^]k), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Looked}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Looking}.] [OE. loken, AS. l[=o]cian; akin to G.
   lugen, OHG. luog[=e]n.]
   1. To direct the eyes for the purpose of seeing something; to
      direct the eyes toward an object; to observe with the eyes
      while keeping them directed; -- with various prepositions,
      often in a special or figurative sense. See Phrases below.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To direct the attention (to something); to consider; to
      examine; as, to look at an action.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To seem; to appear; to have a particular appearance; as,
      the patient looks better; the clouds look rainy.
      [1913 Webster]

            It would look more like vanity than gratitude.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Observe how such a practice looks in another person.
                                                  --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To have a particular direction or situation; to face; to
      front.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inner gate that looketh to north. --Ezek. viii.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

            The east gate . . . which looketh eastward. --Ezek.
                                                  xi. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. In the imperative: see; behold; take notice; take care;
      observe; -- used to call attention.
      [1913 Webster]

            Look, how much we thus expel of sin, so much we
            expel of virtue.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Look, in the imperative, may be followed by a dependent
         sentence, but see is oftener so used.
         [1913 Webster]

               Look that ye bind them fast.       --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

               Look if it be my daughter.         --Talfourd.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. To show one's self in looking, as by leaning out of a
      window; as, look out of the window while I speak to you.
      Sometimes used figuratively.
      [1913 Webster]

            My toes look through the overleather. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To await the appearance of anything; to expect; to
      anticipate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Looking each hour into death's mouth to fall.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To look about}, to look on all sides, or in different
      directions.

   {To look about one}, to be on the watch; to be vigilant; to
      be circumspect or guarded.

   {To look after}.
      (a) To attend to; to take care of; as, to look after
          children.
      (b) To expect; to be in a state of expectation.
          [1913 Webster]

                Men's hearts failing them for fear, and for
                looking after those things which are coming on
                the earth.                        --Luke xxi.
                                                  26.
      (c) To seek; to search.
          [1913 Webster]

                My subject does not oblige me to look after the
                water, or point forth the place where to it is
                now retreated.                    --Woodward.

   {To look at}, to direct the eyes toward so that one sees, or
      as if to see; as, to look at a star; hence, to observe,
      examine, consider; as, to look at a matter without
      prejudice.

   {To look black}, to frown; to scowl; to have a threatening
      appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bishops thereat repined, and looked black.
                                                  --Holinshed.
      

   {To look down on} or {To look down upon}, to treat with
      indifference or contempt; to regard as an inferior; to
      despise.

   {To look for}.
      (a) To expect; as, to look for news by the arrival of a
          ship. ``Look now for no enchanting voice.'' --Milton.
      (b) To seek for; to search for; as, to look for lost
          money, or lost cattle.

   {To look forth}.
      (a) To look out of something, as from a window.
      (b) To threaten to come out. --Jer. vi. 1. (Rev. Ver.).

   {To look forward to}. To anticipate with an expectation of
      pleasure; to be eager for; as, I am looking forward to
      your visit.

   {To look into}, to inspect closely; to observe narrowly; to
      examine; as, to look into the works of nature; to look
      into one's conduct or affairs.

   {To look on}.
      (a) To regard; to esteem.
          [1913 Webster]

                Her friends would look on her the worse.
                                                  --Prior.
      (b) To consider; to view; to conceive of; to think of.
          [1913 Webster]

                I looked on Virgil as a succinct, majestic
                writer.                           --Dryden.
      (c) To be a mere spectator.
          [1913 Webster]

                I'll be a candleholder, and look on. --Shak.

   {To look out}, to be on the watch; to be careful; as, the
      seaman looks out for breakers.

   {To look through}.
      (a) To see through.
      (b) To search; to examine with the eyes.

   {To look to} or {To look unto}.
      (a) To watch; to take care of. ``Look well to thy herds.''
          --Prov. xxvii. 23.
      (b) To resort to with expectation of receiving something;
          to expect to receive from; as, the creditor may look
          to surety for payment. ``Look unto me, and be ye
          saved.'' --Is. xlv. 22.

   {To look up}, to search for or find out by looking; as, to
      look up the items of an account.

   {To look up to}, to respect; to regard with deference.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>look</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Look \Look\, v. t.
   1. To look at; to turn the eyes toward.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To seek; to search for. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Looking my love, I go from place to place.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To expect. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To influence, overawe, or subdue by looks or presence as,
      to look down opposition.
      [1913 Webster]

            A spirit fit to start into an empire,
            And look the world to law.            --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To express or manifest by a look.
      [1913 Webster]

            Soft eyes looked love to eyes which spake again.
                                                  --Byron.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To look daggers}. See under {Dagger}.

   {To look in the face}, to face or meet with boldness or
      confidence; hence, sometimes, to meet for combat.

   {To look out}, to seek for; to search out; as, prudent
      persons look out associates of good reputation.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>look</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Look \Look\, n.
   1. The act of looking; a glance; a sight; a view; -- often in
      certain phrases; as, to have, get, take, throw, or cast, a
      look.
      [1913 Webster]

            Threw many a northward look to see his father
            Bring up his powers; but he did long in vain.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Expression of the eyes and face; manner; as, a proud or
      defiant look. ``Gentle looks.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Up ! up! my friends, and clear your looks.
                                                  --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence; Appearance; aspect; as, the house has a gloomy
      look; the affair has a bad look.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pain, disgrace, and poverty have frighted looks.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            There was something that reminded me of Dante's Hell
            in the look of this.                  --Carlyle.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>look</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>look
     n 1: the expression on a person's face; "a sad expression"; "a
          look of triumph"; "an angry face" [syn: {expression}, {aspect},
           {facial expression}, {face}]
     2: the act of directing the eyes toward something and
        perceiving it visually; "he went out to have a look"; "his
        look was fixed on her eyes"; "he gave it a good looking
        at"; "his camera does his looking for him" [syn: {looking},
         {looking at}]
     3: physical appearance; "I don't like the looks of this place"
     4: the general atmosphere of a place or situation and the
        effect that it has on people; "the feel of the city
        excited him"; "a clergyman improved the tone of the
        meeting"; "it had the smell of treason" [syn: {spirit}, {tone},
         {feel}, {feeling}, {flavor}, {flavour}, {smell}]
     v 1: perceive with attention; direct one's gaze towards; "She
          looked over the expanse of land"; "Look at your child!";
          "Look--a deer in the backyard!"
     2: give a certain impression or have a certain outward aspect;
        "She seems to be sleeping"; "This appears to be a very
        difficult problem"; "This project looks fishy"; "They
        appeared like people who had not eaten or slept for a long
        time" [syn: {appear}, {seem}]
     3: have a certain outward or facial expression; "How does she
        look?"; "The child looks unhappy"; "She looked pale after
        the surgery"
     4: search or seek; "We looked all day and finally found the
        child in the forest"; "Look elsewhere for the perfect
        gift!" [syn: {search}]
     5: be oriented in a certain direction, often with respect to
        another reference point; be opposite to; "The house looks
        north"; "My backyard look onto the pond"; "The building
        faces the park" [syn: {front}, {face}] [ant: {back}]
     6: take charge of or deal with; "Could you see about lunch?";
        "I must attend to this matter"; "She took care of this
        business" [syn: {attend}, {take care}, {see}]
     7: convey by one's expression; "She looked her devotion to me"
     8: look forward to the probable occurrence of; "We were
        expecting a visit from our relatives"; "She is looking to
        a promotion"; "he is waiting to be drafted" [syn: {expect},
         {await}, {wait}]
     9: accord in appearance with; "You don't look your age!"
     10: have faith or confidence in; "you can count on me to help
         you any time"; "Look to your friends for support"; "You
         can bet on that!"; "Depend on your family in times of
         crisis" [syn: {count}, {bet}, {depend}, {calculate}, {reckon}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
