<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lord</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LORD, n.  In American society, an English tourist above the state of a
costermonger, as, lord 'Aberdasher, Lord Hartisan and so forth.  The
traveling Briton of lesser degree is addressed as "Sir," as, Sir 'Arry
Donkiboi, or 'Amstead 'Eath.  The word "Lord" is sometimes used, also,
as a title of the Supreme Being; but this is thought to be rather
flattery than true reverence.

    Miss Sallie Ann Splurge, of her own accord,
    Wedded a wandering English lord --
    Wedded and took him to dwell with her "paw,"
    A parent who throve by the practice of Draw.
    Lord Cadde I don't hesitate to declare
    Unworthy the father-in-legal care
    Of that elderly sport, notwithstanding the truth
    That Cadde had renounced all the follies of youth;
    For, sad to relate, he'd arrived at the stage
    Of existence that's marked by the vices of age.
    Among them, cupidity caused him to urge
    Repeated demands on the pocket of Splurge,
    Till, wrecked in his fortune, that gentleman saw
    Inadequate aid in the practice of Draw,
    And took, as a means of augmenting his pelf,
    To the business of being a lord himself.
    His neat-fitting garments he wilfully shed
    And sacked himself strangely in checks instead;
    Denuded his chin, but retained at each ear
    A whisker that looked like a blasted career.
    He painted his neck an incarnadine hue
    Each morning and varnished it all that he knew.
    The moony monocular set in his eye
    Appeared to be scanning the Sweet Bye-and-Bye.
    His head was enroofed with a billycock hat,
    And his low-necked shoes were aduncous and flat.
    In speech he eschewed his American ways,
    Denying his nose to the use of his A's
    And dulling their edge till the delicate sense
    Of a babe at their temper could take no offence.
    His H's -- 'twas most inexpressibly sweet,
    The patter they made as they fell at his feet!
    Re-outfitted thus, Mr. Splurge without fear
    Began as Lord Splurge his recouping career.
    Alas, the Divinity shaping his end
    Entertained other views and decided to send
    His lordship in horror, despair and dismay
    From the land of the nobleman's natural prey.
    For, smit with his Old World ways, Lady Cadde
    Fell -- suffering Caesar! -- in love with her dad!
                                                                  G.J.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lord
   There are various Hebrew and Greek words so rendered.
   
     (1.) Heb. Jehovah, has been rendered in the English Bible
   LORD, printed in small capitals. This is the proper name of the
   God of the Hebrews. The form "Jehovah" is retained only in Ex.
   6:3; Ps. 83:18; Isa. 12:2; 26:4, both in the Authorized and the
   Revised Version.
   
     (2.) Heb. 'adon, means one possessed of absolute control. It
   denotes a master, as of slaves (Gen. 24:14, 27), or a ruler of
   his subjects (45:8), or a husband, as lord of his wife (18:12).
   
     The old plural form of this Hebrew word is _'adonai_. From a
   superstitious reverence for the name "Jehovah," the Jews, in
   reading their Scriptures, whenever that name occurred, always
   pronounced it _'Adonai_.
   
     (3.) Greek kurios, a supreme master, etc. In the LXX. this is
   invariably used for "Jehovah" and "'Adonai."
   
     (4.) Heb. ba'al, a master, as having domination. This word is
   applied to human relations, as that of husband, to persons
   skilled in some art or profession, and to heathen deities. "The
   men of Shechem," literally "the baals of Shechem" (Judg. 9:2,
   3). These were the Israelite inhabitants who had reduced the
   Canaanites to a condition of vassalage (Josh. 16:10; 17:13).
   
     (5.) Heb. seren, applied exclusively to the "lords of the
   Philistines" (Judg. 3:3). The LXX. render it by satrapies. At
   this period the Philistines were not, as at a later period (1
   Sam. 21:10), under a kingly government. (See Josh. 13:3; 1 Sam.
   6:18.) There were five such lordships, viz., Gath, Ashdod, Gaza,
   Ashkelon, and Ekron.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lord \Lord\ (l[^o]rd), n. [Cf. Gr. ? bent so as to be convex in
   front.]
   A hump-backed person; -- so called sportively. [Eng.]
   --Richardson (Dict.).
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lord \Lord\, n. [OE. lord, laverd, loverd, AS. hl[=a]ford, for
   hl[=a]fweard, i. e., bread keeper; hl[=a]f bread, loaf +
   weardian to look after, to take care of, to ward. See {Loaf},
   and {Ward} to guard, and cf. {Laird}, {Lady}.]
   1. One who has power and authority; a master; a ruler; a
      governor; a prince; a proprietor, as of a manor.
      [1913 Webster]

            But now I was the lord
            Of this fair mansion.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Man over men
            He made not lord.                     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A titled nobleman., whether a peer of the realm or not; a
      bishop, as a member of the House of Lords; by courtesy;
      the son of a duke or marquis, or the eldest son of an
      earl; in a restricted sense, a baron, as opposed to
      noblemen of higher rank. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A title bestowed on the persons above named; and also, for
      honor, on certain official persons; as, lord advocate,
      lord chamberlain, lord chancellor, lord chief justice,
      etc. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A husband. ``My lord being old also.'' --Gen. xviii. 12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou worthy lord
            Of that unworthy wife that greeteth thee. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Feudal Law) One of whom a fee or estate is held; the male
      owner of feudal land; as, the lord of the soil; the lord
      of the manor.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The Supreme Being; Jehovah.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When Lord, in the Old Testament, is printed in small
         capitals, it is usually equivalent to Jehovah, and
         might, with more propriety, be so rendered.
         [1913 Webster]

   7. (Christianity) The Savior; Jesus Christ.
      [1913 Webster]

   {House of Lords}, one of the constituent parts of the British
      Parliament, consisting of the lords spiritual and
      temporal.

   {Lord high chancellor}, {Lord high constable}, etc. See
      {Chancellor}, {Constable}, etc.

   {Lord justice clerk}, the second in rank of the two highest
      judges of the Supreme Court of Scotland.

   {Lord justice general}, or {Lord president}, the highest in
      rank of the judges of the Supreme Court of Scotland.

   {Lord keeper}, an ancient officer of the English crown, who
      had the custody of the king's great seal, with authority
      to affix it to public documents. The office is now merged
      in that of the chancellor.

   {Lord lieutenant}, a representative of British royalty: the
      {lord lieutenant of Ireland} being the representative of
      royalty there, and exercising supreme administrative
      authority; the {lord lieutenant of a county} being a
      deputy to manage its military concerns, and also to
      nominate to the chancellor the justices of the peace for
      that county.

   {Lord of misrule}, the master of the revels at Christmas in a
      nobleman's or other great house. --Eng. Cyc.

   {Lords spiritual}, the archbishops and bishops who have seats
      in the House of Lords.

   {Lords temporal}, the peers of England; also, sixteen
      representative peers of Scotland, and twenty-eight
      representatives of the Irish peerage.

   {Our lord}, Jesus Christ; the Savior.

   {The Lord's Day}, Sunday; the Christian Sabbath, on which the
      Lord Jesus rose from the dead.

   {The Lord's Prayer}, (Christianity) the prayer which Jesus
      taught his disciples, also called the {Our Father}.
      --Matt. vi. 9-13.

   {The Lord's Supper}.
      (a) The paschal supper partaken of by Jesus the night
          before his crucifixion.
      (b) The sacrament of the eucharist; the holy communion.

   {The Lord's Table}.
      (a) The altar or table from which the sacrament is
          dispensed.
      (b) The sacrament itself.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lord \Lord\, v. t.
   1. To invest with the dignity, power, and privileges of a
      lord. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To rule or preside over as a lord. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lord \Lord\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lorded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Lording}.]
   To play the lord; to domineer; to rule with arbitrary or
   despotic sway; -- sometimes with over; and sometimes with it
   in the manner of a transitive verb; as, rich students lording
   it over their classmates.
   [1913 Webster]

         The whiles she lordeth in licentious bliss. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]

         I see them lording it in London streets. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         And lorded over them whom now they serve. --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lord</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lord
     n 1: terms referring to the Judeo-Christian God [syn: {Godhead},
          {Creator}, {Maker}, {Divine}, {God Almighty}, {Almighty},
           {Jehovah}]
     2: a person who has general authority over others [syn: {overlord},
         {master}]
     3: a titled peer of the realm [syn: {noble}, {nobleman}] [ant:
        {Lady}, {Lady}]
     v : make a lord of someone
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
