<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>loss</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>loss</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>LOSS, n.  Privation of that which we had, or had not.  Thus, in the
latter sense, it is said of a defeated candidate that he "lost his
election"; and of that eminent man, the poet Gilder, that he has "lost
his mind."  It is in the former and more legitimate sense, that the
word is used in the famous epitaph:

    Here Huntington's ashes long have lain
    Whose loss is our eternal gain,
    For while he exercised all his powers
    Whatever he gained, the loss was ours.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>loss</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>loss
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; Something (not a person) that loses; a situation in
        which something is losing.  Emphatic forms include "moby
        loss", and "total loss", "complete loss".  Common
        interjections are "What a loss!"  and "What a moby loss!"
        Note that "moby loss" is OK even though **"moby loser" is not
        used; applied to an abstract noun, moby is simply a magnifier,
        whereas when applied to a person it implies substance and has
        positive connotations.
     
        Compare {lossage}.
     
        (1995-04-19)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>loss</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Loss \Loss\ (l[o^]s; 115), n. [AS. los loss, losing, fr.
   le['o]san to lose. [root]127. See {Lose}, v. t.]
   1. The act of losing; failure; destruction; privation; as,
      the loss of property; loss of money by gaming; loss of
      health or reputation.
      [1913 Webster]

            Assured loss before the match be played. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of losing or having lost; the privation, defect,
      misfortune, harm, etc., which ensues from losing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though thou repent, yet I have still the loss.
                                                  --Shak
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is lost or from which one has parted; waste; --
      opposed to {gain} or {increase}; as, the loss of liquor by
      leakage was considerable.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The state of being lost or destroyed; especially, the
      wreck or foundering of a ship or other vessel.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Failure to gain or win; as, loss of a race or battle.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Failure to use advantageously; as, loss of time.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mil.) Killed, wounded, and captured persons, or captured
      property.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Insurance) Destruction or diminution of value, if brought
      about in a manner provided for in the insurance contract
      (as destruction by fire or wreck, damage by water or
      smoke), or the death or injury of an insured person; also,
      the sum paid or payable therefor; as, the losses of the
      company this year amount to a million of dollars.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To bear a loss}, to make a loss good; also, to sustain a
      loss without sinking under it.

   {To be at a loss}, to be in a state of uncertainty.

   Syn: Privation; detriment; injury; damage.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>loss</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>loss n. Something (not a person) that loses; a situation in which
   something is losing. Emphatic forms include `moby loss', and `total
   loss', `complete loss'. Common interjections are "What a loss!" and
   "What a moby loss!" Note that `moby loss' is OK even though **`moby
   loser' is not used; applied to an abstract noun, moby is simply a
   magnifier, whereas when applied to a person it implies substance and has
   positive connotations. Compare {lossage}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>loss</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>loss
     n 1: the act of losing; "everyone expected him to win so his loss
          was a shock"
     2: something that is lost; "the car was a total loss"; "loss of
        livestock left the rancher bankrupt"
     3: the amount by which the cost of a business exceeds its
        revenue; "the company operated at a loss last year"; "the
        company operated in the red last year" [syn: {red ink}, {red}]
        [ant: {gain}]
     4: gradual decline in amount or activity; "weight loss"; "a
        serious loss of business"
     5: the disadvantage that results from losing something; "his
        loss of credibility led to his resignation"; "losing him
        is no great deprivation" [syn: {deprivation}]
     6: military personnel lost by death or capture [syn: {personnel
        casualty}]
     7: the experience of losing a loved one; "he sympathized on the
        loss of their grandfather"
     8: euphemistic expressions for death; "thousands mourned his
        passing" [syn: {passing}, {departure}, {exit}, {expiration},
         {going}, {release}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
