<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lot</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lot
   (Heb. goral, a "pebble"), a small stone used in casting lots
   (Num. 33:54; Jonah 1:7). The lot was always resorted to by the
   Hebrews with strictest reference to the interposition of God,
   and as a method of ascertaining the divine will (Prov. 16:33),
   and in serious cases of doubt (Esther 3:7). Thus the lot was
   used at the division of the land of Canaan among the serveral
   tribes (Num. 26:55; 34:13), at the detection of Achan (Josh.
   7:14, 18), the election of Saul to be king (1 Sam. 10:20, 21),
   the distribution of the priestly offices of the temple service
   (1 Chr. 24:3, 5, 19; Luke 1:9), and over the two goats at the
   feast of Atonement (Lev. 16:8). Matthias, who was "numbered with
   the eleven" (Acts 1:24-26), was chosen by lot.
   
     This word also denotes a portion or an inheritance (Josh.
   15:1; Ps. 125:3; Isa. 17:4), and a destiny, as assigned by God
   (Ps. 16:5; Dan. 12:13).
   
     Lot, (Heb. lot), a covering; veil, the son of Haran, and
   nephew of Abraham (Gen. 11:27). On the death of his father, he
   was left in charge of his grandfather Terah (31), after whose
   death he accompanied his uncle Abraham into Canaan (12:5),
   thence into Egypt (10), and back again to Canaan (13:1). After
   this he separated from him and settled in Sodom (13:5-13). There
   his righteous soul was "vexed" from day to day (2 Pet. 2:7), and
   he had great cause to regret this act. Not many years after the
   separation he was taken captive by Chedorlaomer, and was rescued
   by Abraham (Gen. 14). At length, when the judgment of God
   descended on the guilty cities of the plain (Gen. 19:1-20), Lot
   was miraculously delivered. When fleeing from the doomed city
   his wife "looked back from behind him, and became a pillar of
   salt." There is to this day a peculiar crag at the south end of
   the Dead Sea, near Kumran, which the Arabs call Bint Sheik Lot,
   i.e., Lot's wife. It is "a tall, isolated needle of rock, which
   really does bear a curious resemblance to an Arab woman with a
   child upon her shoulder." From the words of warning in Luke
   17:32, "Remember Lot's wife," it would seem as if she had gone
   back, or tarried so long behind in the desire to save some of
   her goods, that she became involved in the destruction which
   fell on the city, and became a stiffened corpse, fixed for a
   time in the saline incrustations. She became "a pillar of salt",
   i.e., as some think, of asphalt. (See {SALT}.)
   
     Lot and his daughters sought refuge first in Zoar, and then,
   fearing to remain there longer, retired to a cave in the
   neighbouring mountains (Gen. 19:30). Lot has recently been
   connected with the people called on the Egyptian monuments
   Rotanu or Lotanu, who is supposed to have been the hero of the
   Edomite tribe Lotan.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lot \Lot\ (l[o^]t), n. [AS. hlot; akin to hle['o]tan to cast
   lots, OS. hl[=o]t lot, D. lot, G. loos, OHG. l[=o]z, Icel.
   hlutr, Sw. lott, Dan. lod, Goth. hlauts. Cf. {Allot},
   {Lotto}, {Lottery}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. That which happens without human design or forethought;
      chance; accident; hazard; fortune; fate.
      [1913 Webster]

            But save my life, which lot before your foot doth
            lay.                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything (as a die, pebble, ball, or slip of paper) used
      in determining a question by chance, or without man's
      choice or will; as, to cast or draw lots.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lot is cast into the lap, but the whole
            disposing thereof is of the Lord.     --Prov. xvi.
                                                  33.
      [1913 Webster]

            If we draw lots, he speeds.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The part, or fate, which falls to one, as it were, by
      chance, or without his planning.
      [1913 Webster]

            O visions ill foreseen! Each day's lot's
            Enough to bear.                       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was but born to try
            The lot of man -- to suffer and to die. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A separate portion; a number of things taken collectively;
      all objects sold in a single purchase transaction; as, a
      lot of stationery; -- colloquially, sometimes of people;
      as, a sorry lot; a bad lot.
      [1913 Webster]

            I, this winter, met with a very large lot of English
            heads, chiefly of the reign of James I. --Walpole.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A distinct portion or plot of land, usually smaller than a
      field; as, a building lot in a city.
      [1913 Webster]

            The defendants leased a house and lot in the city of
            New York.                             --Kent.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A large quantity or number; a great deal; as, to spend a
      lot of money; to waste a lot of time on line; lots of
      people think so. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He wrote to her . . . he might be detained in London
            by a lot of business.                 --W. Black.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A prize in a lottery. [Obs.] --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To cast in one's lot with}, to share the fortunes of.

   {To cast lots}, to use or throw a die, or some other
      instrument, by the unforeseen turn or position of which,
      an event is by previous agreement determined.

   {To draw lots}, to determine an event, or make a decision, by
      drawing one thing from a number whose marks are concealed
      from the drawer.

   {To pay scot and lot}, to pay taxes according to one's
      ability. See {Scot}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lot \Lot\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lotted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Lotting}.]
   To allot; to sort; to portion. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

   {To lot on} or {To lot upon}, to count or reckon upon; to
      expect with pleasure. [Colloq. U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lot, Lotan, wrapt up; hidden; covered; myrrh; rosin

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lot</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lot
     n 1: (often followed by `of') a large number or amount or extent;
          "a batch of letters"; "a deal of trouble"; "a lot of
          money"; "he made a mint on the stock market"; "it must
          have cost plenty" [syn: {batch}, {deal}, {flock}, {good
          deal}, {great deal}, {hatful}, {heap}, {mass}, {mess}, {mickle},
           {mint}, {muckle}, {peck}, {pile}, {plenty}, {pot}, {quite
          a little}, {raft}, {sight}, {slew}, {spate}, {stack}, {tidy
          sum}, {wad}, {whole lot}, {whole slew}]
     2: a parcel of land having fixed boundaries; "he bought a lot
        on the lake"
     3: your overall circumstances or condition in life (including
        everything that happens to you); "whatever my fortune may
        be"; "deserved a better fate"; "has a happy lot"; "the
        luck of the Irish"; "a victim of circumstances"; "success
        that was her portion" [syn: {fortune}, {destiny}, {fate},
        {luck}, {circumstances}, {portion}]
     4: any collection in its entirety; "she bought the whole
        caboodle" [syn: {bunch}, {caboodle}]
     5: an unofficial association of people or groups; "the smart
        set goes there"; "they were an angry lot" [syn: {set}, {circle},
         {band}]
     6: anything (straws or pebbles etc.) taken or chosen at random;
        "the luck of the draw"; "they drew lots for it" [syn: {draw}]
     7: (Old Testament) nephew of Abraham; God destroyed Sodom and
        Gomorrah but chose to spare Lot and his family who were
        told to flee without looking back at the destruction
     v 1: divide into lots, as of land, for example
     2: administer or bestow, as in small portions; "administer
        critical remarks to everyone present"; "dole out some
        money"; "shell out pocket money for the children"; "deal a
        blow to someone" [syn: {distribute}, {administer}, {mete
        out}, {deal}, {parcel out}, {dispense}, {shell out}, {deal
        out}, {dish out}, {allot}, {dole out}]
     [also: {lotting}, {lotted}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
