<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>lowering</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lowering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lower \Low"er\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lowered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Lowering}.] [From {Low}, a.]
   1. To let descend by its own weight, as something suspended;
      to let down; as, to lower a bucket into a well; to lower a
      sail or a boat; sometimes, to pull down; as, to lower a
      flag.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lowered softly with a threefold cord of love
            Down to a silent grave.               --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To reduce the height of; as, to lower a fence or wall; to
      lower a chimney or turret.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To depress as to direction; as, to lower the aim of a gun;
      to make less elevated as to object; as, to lower one's
      ambition, aspirations, or hopes.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To reduce the degree, intensity, strength, etc., of; as,
      to lower the temperature of anything; to lower one's
      vitality; to lower distilled liquors.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To bring down; to humble; as, to lower one's pride.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To reduce in value, amount, etc.; as, to lower the price
      of goods, the rate of interest, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lowering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lowering \Low"er*ing\, a.
   Dark and threatening; gloomy; sullen; as, lowering clouds or
   sky.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lowering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lower \Low"er\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Lowered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Lowering}.] [OE. lowren, luren; cf. D. loeren, LG. luren. G.
   lauern to lurk, to be on the watch, and E. leer, lurk.]
   1. To be dark, gloomy, and threatening, as clouds; to be
      covered with dark and threatening clouds, as the sky; to
      show threatening signs of approach, as a tempest.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the clouds that lowered upon our house. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To frown; to look sullen.
      [1913 Webster]

            But sullen discontent sat lowering on her face.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>lowering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>lowering
     adj : darkened by clouds; "a heavy sky" [syn: {heavy}, {sullen}, {threatening}]
     n 1: the act of causing to become less
     2: the act of causing something to move to a lower level [syn:
        {letting down}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
