<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>luck</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Luck, WI (village, FIPS 46200)
  Location: 45.57517 N, 92.46729 W
  Population (1990): 1022 (501 housing units)
  Area: 4.3 sq km (land), 1.5 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 54853
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Luck \Luck\, n. [Akin to D. luk, geluk, G. gl["u]ck, Icel.
   lukka, Sw. lycka, Dan. lykke, and perh. to G. locken to
   entice. Cf. 3d {Gleck}.]
   That which happens to a person; an event, good or ill,
   affecting one's interests or happiness, and which is deemed
   casual; a course or series of such events regarded as
   occurring by chance; chance; hap; fate; fortune; often, one's
   habitual or characteristic fortune; as, good, bad, ill, or
   hard luck. Luck is often used by itself to mean good luck;
   as, luck is better than skill; a stroke of luck.
   [1913 Webster]

         If thou dost play with him at any game,
         Thou art sure to lose; and of that natural luck,
         He beats thee 'gainst the odds.          --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Luck penny}, a small sum given back for luck to one who pays
      money. [Prov. Eng.]

   {To be in luck}, to receive some good, or to meet with some
      success, in an unexpected manner, or as the result of
      circumstances beyond one's control; to be fortunate.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luck</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>luck
     n 1: your overall circumstances or condition in life (including
          everything that happens to you); "whatever my fortune
          may be"; "deserved a better fate"; "has a happy lot";
          "the luck of the Irish"; "a victim of circumstances";
          "success that was her portion" [syn: {fortune}, {destiny},
           {fate}, {lot}, {circumstances}, {portion}]
     2: an unknown and unpredictable phenomenon that causes an event
        to result one way rather than another; "bad luck caused
        his downfall"; "we ran into each other by pure chance"
        [syn: {fortune}, {chance}, {hazard}]
     3: an unknown and unpredictable phenomenon that leads to a
        favorable outcome; "it was my good luck to be there";
        "they say luck is a lady"; "it was as if fortune guided
        his hand" [syn: {fortune}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
