<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>luke</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Luke
   the evangelist, was a Gentile. The date and circumstances of his
   conversion are unknown. According to his own statement (Luke
   1:2), he was not an "eye-witness and minister of the word from
   the beginning." It is probable that he was a physician in Troas,
   and was there converted by Paul, to whom he attached himself. He
   accompanied him to Philippi, but did not there share his
   imprisonment, nor did he accompany him further after his release
   in his missionary journey at this time (Acts 17:1). On Paul's
   third visit to Philippi (20:5, 6) we again meet with Luke, who
   probably had spent all the intervening time in that city, a
   period of seven or eight years. From this time Luke was Paul's
   constant companion during his journey to Jerusalem (20:6-21:18).
   He again disappears from view during Paul's imprisonment at
   Jerusalem and Caesarea, and only reappears when Paul sets out
   for Rome (27:1), whither he accompanies him (28:2, 12-16), and
   where he remains with him till the close of his first
   imprisonment (Philemon 1:24; Col. 4:14). The last notice of the
   "beloved physician" is in 2 Tim. 4:11.
   
     There are many passages in Paul's epistles, as well as in the
   writings of Luke, which show the extent and accuracy of his
   medical knowledge.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Luke, MD (town, FIPS 48775)
  Location: 39.47556 N, 79.06037 W
  Population (1990): 184 (97 housing units)
  Area: 0.7 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 21540
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Luke \Luke\ (l[=u]k), a. [Prob. fr. lew, perh. influenced by AS.
   wl[ae]c warm, lukewarm, remiss. Cf. Lew.]
   Moderately warm; not hot; tepid; lukewarm. -- {Luke"ness}, n.
   [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Nine penn'orth o'brandy and water luke.  --Dickens.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Luke, luminous; white

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>luke</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Luke
     n 1: (New Testament) the Apostle closely associated with St Paul
          and traditionally assumed to be the author of the third
          Gospel [syn: {Saint Luke}, {St. Luke}]
     2: one of the four Gospels in the New Testament; contains
        details of Jesus's birth and early life [syn: {Gospel of
        Luke}, {Gospel According to Luke}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
