<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>e</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>e</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>E
     
        1. An extension of {C++} with {database} types and
        {persistent} {object}s.  E is a powerful and flexible
        {procedural} programming language.  It is used in the {Exodus}
        database system.
     
        See also {GNU E}.
     
        {(ftp://ftp.cs.wisc.edu/exodus/E/)}.
     
        ["Persistence in the E Language: Issues and Implementation",
        J.E. Richardson et al, Soft Prac &amp; Exp 19(12):1115-1150 (Dec
        1989)].
     
        2. &lt;language&gt; A {procedural language} by Wouter van
        Oortmerssen with {semantics} similar to {C}.  E features
        lists, low-level {polymorphism}, {exception} handling, quoted
        expressions, {pattern matching} and {object} {inheritance}.
        {Amiga E} is a version for the {Amiga}.
     
        (1999-10-05)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>e</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Notopodium \No`to*po"di*um\, n.; pl. L. {Notopodia}, {E}.
   {Notopodiums}. [NL., fr. Gr. nw^ton the back + poy`s, podo`s,
   the foot.] (Zo["o]l.)
   The dorsal lobe or branch of a parapodium. See {Parapodium}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>e</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Medium \Me"di*um\, n.; pl. L. {Media}, {E}. {Mediums}. [L.
   medium the middle, fr. medius middle. See {Mid}, and cf.
   {Medius}.]
   1. That which lies in the middle, or between other things;
      intervening body or quantity. Hence, specifically:
      (a) Middle place or degree; mean.
          [1913 Webster]

                The just medium . . . lies between pride and
                abjection.                        --L'Estrange.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) (Math.) See {Mean}.
      (c) (Logic) The mean or middle term of a syllogism; that
          by which the extremes are brought into connection.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A substance through which an effect is transmitted from
      one thing to another; as, air is the common medium of
      sound. Hence: The condition upon which any event or action
      occurs; necessary means of motion or action; that through
      or by which anything is accomplished, conveyed, or carried
      on; specifically, in animal magnetism, spiritualism, etc.,
      a person through whom the action of another being is said
      to be manifested and transmitted.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether any other liquors, being made mediums, cause
            a diversity of sound from water, it may be tried.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            I must bring together
            All these extremes; and must remove all mediums.
                                                  --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An average. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            A medium of six years of war, and six years of
            peace.                                --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A trade name for printing and writing paper of certain
      sizes. See {Paper}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Paint.) The liquid vehicle with which dry colors are
      ground and prepared for application.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Microbiology) A source of nutrients in which a
      microorganism is placed to permit its growth, cause it to
      produce substances, or observe its activity under defined
      conditions; also called {culture medium} or {growth
      medium}. The medium is usually a solution of nutrients in
      water, or a similar solution solidified with gelatin or
      agar.
      [PJC]

   7. A means of transmission of news, advertising, or other
      messages from an information source to the public, also
      called a {news medium}, such as a newspaper or radio; used
      mostly in the plural form, i. e. {news media} or {media}.
      See 1st {media}[2].
      [PJC]

   {Circulating medium}, a current medium of exchange, whether
      coin, bank notes, or government notes.

   {Ethereal medium} (Physics), the ether.

   {Medium of exchange}, that which is used for effecting an
      exchange of commodities -- money or current
      representatives of money.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>e</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Amt \Amt\, n.; pl. {Amter}, {E}. {Amts}. [Dan. &amp; Norw., fr. G.]
   An administrative territorial division in Denmark and Norway.
   [1913 Webster]

         Each of the provinces [of Denmark] is divided into
         several amts, answering . . . to the English hundreds.
                                                  --Encyc. Brit.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>e</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>E \E\ ([=e]).
   1. The fifth letter of the English alphabet.

   Note: It derives its form, name, and value from the Latin,
         the form and value being further derived from the
         Greek, into which it came from the Ph[oe]nician, and
         ultimately, probably, from the Egyptian. Its
         etymological relations are closest with the vowels i,
         a, and o, as illustrated by to fall, to fell; man, pl.
         men; drink, drank, drench; dint, dent; doom, deem;
         goose, pl. geese; beef, OF. boef, L. bos; and E. cheer,
         OF. chiere, LL. cara.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: The letter e has in English several vowel sounds, the
         two principal being its long or name sound, as in eve,
         me, and the short, as in end, best. Usually at the end
         of words it is silent, but serves to indicate that the
         preceding vowel has its long sound, where otherwise it
         would be short, as in m[=a]ne, c[=a]ne, m[=e]te, which
         without the final e would be pronounced m[a^]n, c[a^]n,
         m[e^]t. After c and g, the final e indicates that these
         letters are to be pronounced as s and j; respectively,
         as in lace, rage. See Guide to Pronunciation,
         [sect][sect] 74-97.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mus.) E is the third tone of the model diatonic scale.
      E[flat] (E flat) is a tone which is intermediate between D
      and E.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>e</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>E- \E-\
   A Latin prefix meaning out, out of, from; also, without. See
   {Ex-}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>e</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>E
     n 1: a fat-soluble vitamin that is essential for normal
          reproduction; an important antioxidant that neutralizes
          free radicals in the body [syn: {vitamin E}, {tocopherol}]
     2: a radioactive transuranic element produced by bombarding
        plutonium with neutrons [syn: {einsteinium}, {Es}, {atomic
        number 99}]
     3: the cardinal compass point that is at 90 degrees [syn: {east},
         {due east}]
     4: the base of the natural system of logarithms [syn: {2.718282...}]
     5: the 5th letter of the Roman alphabet
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
