<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>eagle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eagle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eagle
   (Herb. nesher; properly the griffon vulture or great vulture, so
   called from its tearing its prey with its beak), referred to for
   its swiftness of flight (Deut. 28:49; 2 Sam. 1:23), its mounting
   high in the air (Job 39:27), its strength (Ps. 103:5), its
   setting its nest in high places (Jer. 49:16), and its power of
   vision (Job 39:27-30).
   
     This "ravenous bird" is a symbol of those nations whom God
   employs and sends forth to do a work of destruction, sweeping
   away whatever is decaying and putrescent (Matt. 24:28; Isa.
   46:11; Ezek. 39:4; Deut. 28:49; Jer. 4:13; 48:40). It is said
   that the eagle sheds his feathers in the beginning of spring,
   and with fresh plumage assumes the appearance of youth. To this,
   allusion is made in Ps. 103:5 and Isa. 40:31. God's care over
   his people is likened to that of the eagle in training its young
   to fly (Ex. 19:4; Deut. 32:11, 12). An interesting illustration
   is thus recorded by Sir Humphry Davy:, "I once saw a very
   interesting sight above the crags of Ben Nevis. Two parent
   eagles were teaching their offspring, two young birds, the
   maneuvers of flight. They began by rising from the top of the
   mountain in the eye of the sun. It was about mid-day, and bright
   for the climate. They at first made small circles, and the young
   birds imitated them. They paused on their wings, waiting till
   they had made their flight, and then took a second and larger
   gyration, always rising toward the sun, and enlarging their
   circle of flight so as to make a gradually ascending spiral. The
   young ones still and slowly followed, apparently flying better
   as they mounted; and they continued this sublime exercise,
   always rising till they became mere points in the air, and the
   young ones were lost, and afterwards their parents, to our
   aching sight." (See Isa. 40:31.)
   
     There have been observed in Palestine four distinct species of
   eagles, (1) the golden eagle (Aquila chrysaetos); (2) the
   spotted eagle (Aquila naevia); (3) the common species, the
   imperial eagle (Aquila heliaca); and (4) the Circaetos gallicus,
   which preys on reptiles. The eagle was unclean by the Levitical
   law (Lev. 11:13; Deut. 14:12).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eagle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eagle
     
        A {dBASE}-like dialect bundled with {Emerald Bay}, sold by
        {Migent} from 1986-1988, later renamed {Vulcan} when {Wayne
        Ratliff} reacquired the product.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eagle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eagle, AK (city, FIPS 20380)
  Location: 64.77815 N, 141.20063 W
  Population (1990): 168 (146 housing units)
  Area: 3.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Eagle, CO (town, FIPS 22200)
  Location: 39.65564 N, 106.82544 W
  Population (1990): 1580 (624 housing units)
  Area: 2.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 81631
Eagle, ID (city, FIPS 23410)
  Location: 43.69353 N, 116.35478 W
  Population (1990): 3327 (1238 housing units)
  Area: 13.0 sq km (land), 0.1 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 83616
Eagle, MI (village, FIPS 23560)
  Location: 42.80978 N, 84.79052 W
  Population (1990): 120 (42 housing units)
  Area: 0.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 48822
Eagle, NE (village, FIPS 14100)
  Location: 40.81606 N, 96.43206 W
  Population (1990): 1047 (374 housing units)
  Area: 0.8 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 68347
Eagle, WI (village, FIPS 21425)
  Location: 42.87963 N, 88.47127 W
  Population (1990): 1182 (400 housing units)
  Area: 2.7 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 53119
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eagle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eagle \Ea"gle\, n. [OE. egle, F. aigle, fr. L. aquila; prob.
   named from its color, fr. aquilus dark-colored, brown; cf.
   Lith. aklas blind. Cf. {Aquiline}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) Any large, rapacious bird of the Falcon family,
      esp. of the genera {Aquila} and {Hali[ae]etus}. The eagle
      is remarkable for strength, size, graceful figure,
      keenness of vision, and extraordinary flight. The most
      noted species are the golden eagle ({Aquila
      chrysa["e]tus}); the imperial eagle of Europe ({Aquila
      mogilnik} or {Aquila imperialis}); the American bald eagle
      ({Hali[ae]etus leucocephalus}); the European sea eagle
      ({Hali[ae]etus albicilla}); and the great harpy eagle
      ({Thrasaetus harpyia}). The figure of the eagle, as the
      king of birds, is commonly used as an heraldic emblem, and
      also for standards and emblematic devices. See {Bald
      eagle}, {Harpy}, and {Golden eagle}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A gold coin of the United States, of the value of ten
      dollars.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Astron.) A northern constellation, containing Altair, a
      star of the first magnitude. See {Aquila}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The figure of an eagle borne as an emblem on the standard
      of the ancient Romans, or so used upon the seal or
      standard of any people.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though the Roman eagle shadow thee.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Some modern nations, as the United States, and France
         under the Bonapartes, have adopted the eagle as their
         national emblem. Russia, Austria, and Prussia have for
         an emblem a double-headed eagle.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Bald eagle}. See {Bald eagle}.

   {Bold eagle}. See under {Bold}.

   {Double eagle}, a gold coin of the United States worth twenty
      dollars.

   {Eagle hawk} (Zo["o]l.), a large, crested, South American
      hawk of the genus {Morphnus}.

   {Eagle owl} (Zo["o]l.), any large owl of the genus {Bubo},
      and allied genera; as the American great horned owl ({Bubo
      Virginianus}), and the allied European species ({B.
      maximus}). See {Horned owl}.

   {Eagle ray} (Zo["o]l.), any large species of ray of the genus
      {Myliobatis} (esp. {M. aquila}).

   {Eagle vulture} (Zo["o]l.), a large West African bid
      ({Gypohierax Angolensis}), intermediate, in several
      respects, between the eagles and vultures.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eagle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>eagle
     n 1: any of various large keen-sighted diurnal birds of prey
          noted for their broad wings and strong soaring flight
          [syn: {bird of Jove}]
     2: (golf) a score of two strokes under par on a hole
     3: a former gold coin in the United States worth 10 dollars
     4: an emblem representing power; "the Roman eagle"
     v : shoot in two strokes under par
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
