<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>earthquake</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earthquake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earthquake
   mentioned among the extraordinary phenomena of Palestine (Ps.
   18:7; comp. Hab. 3:6; Nah. 1:5; Isa. 5:25).
   
     The first earthquake in Palestine of which we have any record
   happened in the reign of Ahab (1 Kings 19:11, 12). Another took
   place in the days of Uzziah, King of Judah (Zech. 14:5). The
   most memorable earthquake taking place in New Testament times
   happened at the crucifixion of our Lord (Matt. 27:54). An
   earthquake at Philippi shook the prison in which Paul and Silas
   were imprisoned (Act 16:26).
   
     It is used figuratively as a token of the presence of the Lord
   (Judg. 5:4; 2 Sam. 22:8; Ps. 77:18; 97:4; 104:32).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earthquake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>earthquake
     
        (IBM) The ultimate real-world shock test for computer
        hardware.  Hackish sources at {IBM} deny the rumor that the
        San Francisco Bay Area quake of 1989 was initiated by the
        company to test quality-assurance procedures at its California
        plants.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-04-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earthquake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earthquake \Earth"quake`\, n.
   A shaking, trembling, or concussion of the earth, due to
   subterranean causes, often accompanied by a rumbling noise.
   The wave of shock sometimes traverses half a hemisphere,
   destroying cities and many thousand lives; -- called also
   {earthdin}, {earthquave}, and {earthshock}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Earthquake alarm}, a bell signal constructed to operate on
      the theory that a few seconds before the occurrence of an
      earthquake the magnet temporarily loses its power.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earthquake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earthquake \Earth"quake`\, a.
   Like, or characteristic of, an earthquake; loud; startling.
   [1913 Webster]

         The earthquake voice of victory.         --Byron.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earthquake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>earthquake n. [IBM] The ultimate real-world shock test for computer
   hardware. Hackish sources at IBM deny the rumor that the Bay Area quake
   of 1989 was initiated by the company to test quality-assurance
   procedures at its California plants.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earthquake</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>earthquake
     n 1: shaking and vibration at the surface of the earth resulting
          from underground movement along a fault plane of from
          volcanic activity [syn: {quake}, {temblor}, {seism}]
     2: a disturbance that is extremely disruptive; "selling the
        company caused an earthquake among the employees"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
