<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>earth</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earth
   (1.) In the sense of soil or ground, the translation of the word
   _adamah'_. In Gen. 9:20 "husbandman" is literally "man of the
   ground or earth." Altars were to be built of earth (Ex. 20:24).
   Naaman asked for two mules' burden of earth (2 Kings 5:17),
   under the superstitious notion that Jehovah, like the gods of
   the heathen, could be acceptably worshipped only on his own
   soil.
   
     (2). As the rendering of _'erets_, it means the whole world
   (Gen. 1:2); the land as opposed to the sea (1:10). _Erets_ also
   denotes a country (21:32); a plot of ground (23:15); the ground
   on which a man stands (33:3); the inhabitants of the earth (6:1;
   11:1); all the world except Israel (2 Chr. 13:9). In the New
   Testament "the earth" denotes the land of Judea (Matt. 23:35);
   also things carnal in contrast with things heavenly (John 3:31;
   Col. 3:1, 2).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earth, TX (city, FIPS 21928)
  Location: 34.23349 N, 102.40843 W
  Population (1990): 1228 (469 housing units)
  Area: 3.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 79031
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earth \Earth\ ([~e]rth), n. [AS. eor[eth]e; akin to OS. ertha,
   OFries. irthe, D. aarde, OHG. erda, G. erde, Icel.
   j["o]r[eth], Sw. &amp; Dan. jord, Goth. a[=i]r[thorn]a, OHG. ero,
   Gr. ?, adv., to earth, and perh. to E. ear to plow.]
   1. The globe or planet which we inhabit; the world, in
      distinction from the sun, moon, or stars. Also, this world
      as the dwelling place of mortals, in distinction from the
      dwelling place of spirits.
      [1913 Webster]

            That law preserves the earth a sphere
            And guides the planets in their course. --S. Rogers.
      [1913 Webster]

            In heaven, or earth, or under earth, in hell.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The solid materials which make up the globe, in
      distinction from the air or water; the dry land.
      [1913 Webster]

            God called the dry land earth.        --Gen. i. 10.
      [1913 Webster]

            He is pure air and fire, and the dull elements of
            earth and water never appear in him.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The softer inorganic matter composing part of the surface
      of the globe, in distinction from the firm rock; soil of
      all kinds, including gravel, clay, loam, and the like;
      sometimes, soil favorable to the growth of plants; the
      visible surface of the globe; the ground; as, loose earth;
      rich earth.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give him a little earth for charity.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A part of this globe; a region; a country; land.
      [1913 Webster]

            Would I had never trod this English earth. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Worldly things, as opposed to spiritual things; the
      pursuits, interests, and allurements of this life.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our weary souls by earth beguiled.    --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The people on the globe.
      [1913 Webster]

            The whole earth was of one language.  --Gen. xi. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Chem.)
      (a) Any earthy-looking metallic oxide, as alumina,
          glucina, zirconia, yttria, and thoria.
      (b) A similar oxide, having a slight alkaline reaction, as
          lime, magnesia, strontia, baryta.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. A hole in the ground, where an animal hides himself; as,
      the earth of a fox. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            They [ferrets] course the poor conies out of their
            earths.                               --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Elec.) The connection of any part an electric conductor
      with the ground; specif., the connection of a telegraph
      line with the ground through a fault or otherwise.

   Note: When the resistance of the earth connection is low it
         is termed a good earth.
         [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: Earth is used either adjectively or in combination to
         form compound words; as, earth apple or earth-apple;
         earth metal or earth-metal; earth closet or
         earth-closet.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Adamic earth}, {Bitter earth}, {Bog earth}, {Chian earth},
      etc. See under {Adamic}, {Bitter}, etc.

   {Alkaline earths}. See under {Alkaline}.

   {Earth apple}. (Bot.)
      (a) A potato.
      (b) A cucumber.

   {Earth auger}, a form of auger for boring into the ground; --
      called also {earth borer}.

   {Earth bath}, a bath taken by immersing the naked body in
      earth for healing purposes.

   {Earth battery} (Physics), a voltaic battery the elements of
      which are buried in the earth to be acted on by its
      moisture.

   {Earth chestnut}, the pignut.

   {Earth closet}, a privy or commode provided with dry earth or
      a similar substance for covering and deodorizing the
      f[ae]cal discharges.

   {Earth dog} (Zo["o]l.), a dog that will dig in the earth, or
      enter holes of foxes, etc.

   {Earth hog}, {Earth pig} (Zo["o]l.), the aard-vark.

   {Earth hunger}, an intense desire to own land, or, in the
      case of nations, to extend their domain.

   {Earth light} (Astron.), the light reflected by the earth, as
      upon the moon, and corresponding to moonlight; -- called
      also {earth shine}. --Sir J. Herschel.

   {Earth metal}. See 1st {Earth}, 7. (Chem.)

   {Earth oil}, petroleum.

   {Earth pillars} or {Earth pyramids} (Geol.), high pillars or
      pyramids of earth, sometimes capped with a single stone,
      found in Switzerland. --Lyell.

   {Earth pitch} (Min.), mineral tar, a kind of asphaltum.

   {Earth quadrant}, a fourth of the earth's circumference.

   {Earth table} (Arch.), the lowest course of stones visible in
      a building; the ground table.

   {On earth}, an intensive expression, oftenest used in
      questions and exclamations; as, What on earth shall I do?
      Nothing on earth will satisfy him. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earth \Earth\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Earthed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Earthing}.]
   1. To hide, or cause to hide, in the earth; to chase into a
      burrow or den. ``The fox is earthed.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover with earth or mold; to inter; to bury; --
      sometimes with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            The miser earths his treasure, and the thief,
            Watching the mole, half beggars him ere noon.
                                                  --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

            Why this in earthing up a carcass?    --R. Blair.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earth \Earth\, v. i.
   To burrow. --Tickell.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earth \Earth\, n. [From {Ear} to plow.]
   A plowing. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Such land as ye break up for barley to sow,
         Two earths at the least, ere ye sow it, bestow.
                                                  --Tusser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>earth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Earth
     n 1: the 3rd planet from the sun; the planet on which we live;
          "the Earth moves around the sun"; "he sailed around the
          world" [syn: {world}, {globe}]
     2: the loose soft material that makes up a large part of the
        land surface; "they dug into the earth outside the church"
        [syn: {ground}]
     3: the solid part of the earth's surface; "the plane turned
        away from the sea and moved back over land"; "the earth
        shook for several minutes"; "he dropped the logs on the
        ground" [syn: {land}, {dry land}, {ground}, {solid ground},
         {terra firma}]
     4: the abode of mortals (as contrasted with heaven or hell);
        "it was hell on earth"
     5: once thought to be one of four elements composing the
        universe (Empedocles)
     6: the concerns of the world as distinguished from heaven and
        the afterlife; "they consider the church to be independent
        of the world" [syn: {worldly concern}, {earthly concern},
        {world}]
     7: a connection between an electrical device and the earth
        (which is a zero voltage) [syn: {ground}]
     v 1: hide in the earth like a hunted animal
     2: connect to the earth; "earth the circuit"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
