<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>east</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>east</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>East
   (1.) The orient (mizrah); the rising of the sun. Thus "the east
   country" is the country lying to the east of Syria, the Elymais
   (Zech. 8:7).
   
     (2). Properly what is in front of one, or a country that is
   before or in front of another; the rendering of the word
   _kedem_. In pointing out the quarters, a Hebrew always looked
   with his face toward the east. The word _kedem_ is used when the
   four quarters of the world are described (Gen. 13:14; 28:14);
   and _mizrah_ when the east only is distinguished from the west
   (Josh. 11:3; Ps. 50:1; 103:12, etc.). In Gen. 25:6 "eastward" is
   literally "unto the land of kedem;" i.e., the lands lying east
   of Palestine, namely, Arabia, Mesopotamia, etc.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>east</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>EAST
     
        A {Eureka} project developing a {software engineering}
        {platform}.
     
        (1994-12-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>east</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>East \East\, a.
   1. Toward the rising sun; or toward the point where the sun
      rises when in the equinoctial; as, the east gate; the east
      border; the east side; the east wind is a wind that blows
      from the east.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Eccl.) Designating, or situated in, that part of a church
      which contains the choir or chancel; as, the east front of
      a cathedral.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>east</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>East \East\ ([=e]st), n. [OE. est, east, AS. e['a]st; akin to D.
   oost, oosten, OHG. [=o]stan, G. ost, osten, Icel. austr, Sw.
   ost, Dan. ["o]st, ["o]sten, Lith. auszra dawn, L. aurora (for
   ausosa), Gr. 'hw`s, "e`os, 'a`yws, Skr. ushas; cf. Skr. ush
   to burn, L. urere. [root]149, 288. Cf. {Aurora}, {Easter},
   {Sterling}.]
   1. The point in the heavens where the sun is seen to rise at
      the equinox, or the corresponding point on the earth; that
      one of the four cardinal points of the compass which is in
      a direction at right angles to that of north and south,
      and which is toward the right hand of one who faces the
      north; the point directly opposite to the west.
      [1913 Webster]

            The east began kindle.                --E. Everett.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The eastern parts of the earth; the regions or countries
      which lie east of Europe; the orient. In this indefinite
      sense, the word is applied to Asia Minor, Syria, Chaldea,
      Persia, India, China, etc.; as, the riches of the East;
      the diamonds and pearls of the East; the kings of the
      East.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gorgeous East, with richest hand,
            Showers on her kings barbaric pearl and gold.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (U. S. Hist. and Geog.) Formerly, the part of the United
      States east of the Alleghany Mountains, esp. the Eastern,
      or New England, States; now, commonly, the whole region
      east of the Mississippi River, esp. that which is north of
      Maryland and the Ohio River; -- usually with the definite
      article; as, the commerce of the East is not independent
      of the agriculture of the West.
      [1913 Webster]

   {East by north}, {East by south}, according to the notation
      of the mariner's compass, that point which lies 111/4[deg]
      to the north or south, respectively, of the point due
      east.

   {East-northeast}, {East-southeast}, that which lies
      221/2[deg] to the north or south of east, or half way
      between east and northeast or southeast, respectively. See
      Illust. of {Compass}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>east</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>East \East\, adv.
   Eastward.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>east</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>East \East\, v. i.
   To move toward the east; to veer from the north or south
   toward the east; to orientate.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>east</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>east
     adj : situated in or facing or moving toward the east [ant: {west}]
     n 1: the cardinal compass point that is at 90 degrees [syn: {due
          east}, {E}]
     2: the countries of Asia [syn: {Orient}]
     3: the region of the United States lying north of the Ohio
        River and east of the Mississippi River [syn: {eastern
        United States}]
     adv : to, toward, or in the east; "we travelled east for several
           miles"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
