<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>echoes</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>echoes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Echo \Ech"o\ ([e^]k"[-o]), n.; pl. {Echoes} ([e^]k"[=o]z). [L.
   echo, Gr. 'hchw` echo, sound, akin to 'hchh`, 'h^chos, sound,
   noise; cf. Skr. v[=a][,c] to sound, bellow; perh. akin to E.
   voice: cf. F. ['e]cho.]
   1. A sound reflected from an opposing surface and repeated to
      the ear of a listener; repercussion of sound; repetition
      of a sound.
      [1913 Webster]

            The babbling echo mocks the hounds.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The woods shall answer, and the echo ring. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: Sympathetic recognition; response; answer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fame is the echo of actions, resounding them.
                                                  --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many kind, and sincere speeches found an echo in his
            heart.                                --R. L.
                                                  Stevenson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3.
      (a) (Myth. &amp; Poetic) A wood or mountain nymph, regarded as
          repeating, and causing the reverberation of them.
          [1913 Webster]

                Sweet Echo, sweetest nymph, that liv'st unseen
                Within thy airy shell.            --Milton.
      (b) (Gr. Myth.) A nymph, the daughter of Air and Earth,
          who, for love of Narcissus, pined away until nothing
          was left of her but her voice.
          [1913 Webster]

                Compelled me to awake the courteous Echo
                To give me answer from her mossy couch.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Whist, Contract Bridge)
      (a) A signal, played in the same manner as a trump signal,
          made by a player who holds four or more trumps (or as
          played by some exactly three trumps) and whose partner
          has led trumps or signaled for trumps.
      (b) A signal showing the number held of a plain suit when
          a high card in that suit is led by one's partner.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Echo organ} (Mus.), a set organ pipes inclosed in a box so
      as to produce a soft, distant effect; -- generally
      superseded by the swell.

   {Echo stop} (Mus.), a stop upon a harpsichord contrived for
      producing the soft effect of distant sound.

   {To applaud to the echo}, to give loud and continuous
      applause. --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would applaud thee to the very echo,
            That should applaud again.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>echoes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Echo \Ech"o\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Echoed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Echoing}. -- 3d pers. sing. pres. {Echoes}.]
   1. To send back (a sound); to repeat in sound; to
      reverberate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those peals are echoed by the Trojan throng.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wondrous sound
            Is echoed on forever.                 --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To repeat with assent; to respond; to adopt.
      [1913 Webster]

            They would have echoed the praises of the men whom
            they envied, and then have sent to the newspaper
            anonymous libels upon them.           --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>echoes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>echoes
     See {echo}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>echoes</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>echo
     n 1: the persistence of a sound after its source has stopped
          [syn: {reverberation}, {sound reflection}, {replication}]
     2: (Greek mythology) a nymph who was spurned by Narcissus and
        pined away until only her voice remained
     3: a reply that repeats what has just been said
     v 1: to say again or imitate; "followers echoing the cries of
          their leaders" [syn: {repeat}]
     2: ring or echo with sound; "the hall resounded with laughter"
        [syn: {resound}, {ring}, {reverberate}]
     3: call to mind; "His words echoed John F. Kennedy" [syn: {recall}]
     [also: {echoes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
