<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ed
   witness, a word not found in the original Hebrew, nor in the
   LXX. and Vulgate, but added by the translators in the Authorized
   Version, also in the Revised Version, of Josh. 22:34. The words
   are literally rendered: "And the children of Reuben and the
   children of Gad named the altar. It is a witness between us that
   Jehovah is God." This great altar stood probably on the east
   side of the Jordan, in the land of Gilead, "over against the
   land of Canaan." After the division of the Promised Land, the
   tribes of Reuben and Gad and the half-tribe of Manasseh, on
   returning to their own settlements on the east of Jordan (Josh.
   22:1-6), erected a great altar, which they affirmed, in answer
   to the challenge of the other tribes, was not for sacrifice, but
   only as a witness ('Ed) or testimony to future generations that
   they still retained the same interest in the nation as the other
   tribes.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ed
     
        &lt;tool, text&gt; (editor) {Unix}'s {line editor}.  Ed is rarely
        used by humans since even {vi} is better.
     
        {Unix manual page}: ed(1).
     
        (1999-03-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-ed \-ed\
   The termination of the past participle of regular, or weak,
   verbs; also, of analogous participial adjectives from nouns;
   as, pigmented; talented.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ed, witness

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ed n. "ed is the standard text editor." Line taken from original the
   {Unix} manual page on ed, an ancient line-oriented editor that is by now
   used only by a few {Real Programmer}s, and even then only for batch
   operations. The original line is sometimes uttered near the beginning of
   an emacs vs. vi holy war on {Usenet}, with the (vain) hope to quench the
   discussion before it really takes off. Often followed by a standard text
   describing the many virtues of ed (such as the small memory {footprint}
   on a Timex Sinclair, and the consistent (because nearly non-existent)
   user interface).


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ED
     End Delimiter (FDDI, Token Ring)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ED
     Enhanced Density
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ED
     n : impotence resulting from a man's inability to have or
         maintain an erection of his penis [syn: {erectile
         dysfunction}, {male erecticle dysfunction}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
