<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>edge</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>edge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Edge \Edge\ ([e^]j), n. [OE. eg, egge, AS. ecg; akin to OHG.
   ekka, G. ecke, Icel. &amp; Sw. egg, Dan. eg, and to L. acies, Gr.
   'akh` point, Skr. a[,c]ri edge. [root]1. Cf. {Egg}, v. t.,
   {Eager}, {Ear} spike of corn, {Acute}.]
   1. The thin cutting side of the blade of an instrument; as,
      the edge of an ax, knife, sword, or scythe. Hence,
      (figuratively), that which cuts as an edge does, or wounds
      deeply, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            He which hath the sharp sword with two edges. --Rev.
                                                  ii. 12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Slander,
            Whose edge is sharper than the sword. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any sharp terminating border; a margin; a brink; extreme
      verge; as, the edge of a table, a precipice.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon the edge of yonder coppice.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In worst extremes, and on the perilous edge
            Of battle.                            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pursue even to the very edge of destruction. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Sharpness; readiness or fitness to cut; keenness;
      intenseness of desire.
      [1913 Webster]

            The full edge of our indignation.     --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Death and persecution lose all the ill that they can
            have, if we do not set an edge upon them by our
            fears and by our vices.               --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The border or part adjacent to the line of division; the
      beginning or early part; as, in the edge of evening. ``On
      the edge of winter.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Edge joint} (Carp.), a joint formed by two edges making a
      corner.

   {Edge mill}, a crushing or grinding mill in which stones roll
      around on their edges, on a level circular bed; -- used
      for ore, and as an oil mill. Called also {Chilian mill}.
      

   {Edge molding} (Arch.), a molding whose section is made up of
      two curves meeting in an angle.

   {Edge plane}.
      (a) (Carp.) A plane for edging boards.
      (b) (Shoemaking) A plane for edging soles.

   {Edge play}, a kind of swordplay in which backswords or
      cutlasses are used, and the edge, rather than the point,
      is employed.

   {Edge rail}. (Railroad)
      (a) A rail set on edge; -- applied to a rail of more depth
          than width.
      (b) A guard rail by the side of the main rail at a switch.
          --Knight.

   {Edge railway}, a railway having the rails set on edge.

   {Edge stone}, a curbstone.

   {Edge tool}.
      (a) Any tool or instrument having a sharp edge intended
          for cutting.
      (b) A tool for forming or dressing an edge; an edging
          tool.

   {To be on edge},
      (a) to be eager, impatient, or anxious.
      (b) to be irritable or nervous.

   {on edge},
      (a) See {to be on edge}.
      (b) See {to set the teeth on edge}.

   {To set the teeth on edge},
      (a) to cause a disagreeable tingling sensation in the
          teeth, as by bringing acids into contact with them.
          [archaic] --Bacon.
      (b) to produce a disagreeable or unpleasant sensation; to
          annoy or repel; -- often used of sounds; as, the
          screeching of of the subway train wheels sets my teeth
          on edge.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>edge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Edge \Edge\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Edged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Edging}.]
   1. To furnish with an edge as a tool or weapon; to sharpen.
      [1913 Webster]

            To edge her champion's sword.         --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To shape or dress the edge of, as with a tool.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To furnish with a fringe or border; as, to edge a dress;
      to edge a garden with box.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hills whose tops were edged with groves. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make sharp or keen, figuratively; to incite; to
      exasperate; to goad; to urge or egg on. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            By such reasonings, the simple were blinded, and the
            malicious edged.                      --Hayward.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To move by little and little or cautiously, as by pressing
      forward edgewise; as, edging their chairs forwards.
      --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>edge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Edge \Edge\, v. i.
   1. To move sideways; to move gradually; as, edge along this
      way.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To sail close to the wind.
      [1913 Webster]

            I must edge up on a point of wind.    --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To edge away} or {To edge off} (Naut.), to increase the
      distance gradually from the shore, vessel, or other
      object.

   {To edge down} (Naut.), to approach by slow degrees, as when
      a sailing vessel approaches an object in an oblique
      direction from the windward.

   {To edge in}, to get in edgewise; to get in by degrees.

   {To edge in with}, as with a coast or vessel (Naut.), to
      advance gradually, but not directly, toward it.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>edge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>EDGE
     Enhanced Data rate for GSM Evolution (GSM, mobile-systems)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>edge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>edge
     n 1: the boundary of a surface [syn: {border}]
     2: a sharp side formed by the intersection of two surfaces of
        an object; "he rounded the edges of the box"
     3: a line determining the limits of an area [syn: {boundary}, {bound}]
     4: the attribute of urgency; "his voice had an edge to it"
        [syn: {sharpness}]
     5: a slight competitive advantage; "he had an edge on the
        competition"
     6: a strip near the boundary of an object; "he jotted a note on
        the margin of the page" [syn: {margin}]
     v 1: advance slowly, as if by inches; "He edged towards the car"
          [syn: {inch}]
     2: provide with a border or edge; "edge the tablecloth with
        embroidery" [syn: {border}]
     3: lie adjacent to another or share a boundary; "Canada adjoins
        the U.S."; "England marches with Scotland" [syn: {border},
         {adjoin}, {abut}, {march}, {butt}, {butt against}, {butt
        on}]
     4: provide with an edge; "edge a blade"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
