<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>effect</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>effect</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>EFFECT, n.  The second of two phenomena which always occur together in
the same order.  The first, called a Cause, is said to generate the
other -- which is no more sensible than it would be for one who has
never seen a dog except in the pursuit of a rabbit to declare the
rabbit the cause of a dog.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>effect</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Effect \Ef*fect"\, n. [L. effectus, fr. efficere, effectum, to
   effect; ex + facere to make: cf. F. effet, formerly also
   spelled effect. See {Fact}.]
   1. Execution; performance; realization; operation; as, the
      law goes into effect in May.
      [1913 Webster]

            That no compunctious visitings of nature
            Shake my fell purpose, nor keep peace between
            The effect and it.                    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Manifestation; expression; sign.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the large effects
            That troop with majesty.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. In general: That which is produced by an agent or cause;
      the event which follows immediately from an antecedent,
      called the cause; result; consequence; outcome; fruit; as,
      the effect of luxury.
      [1913 Webster]

            The effect is the unfailing index of the amount of
            the cause.                            --Whewell.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Impression left on the mind; sensation produced.
      [1913 Webster]

            Patchwork . . . introduced for oratorical effect.
                                                  --J. C.
                                                  Shairp.
      [1913 Webster]

            The effect was heightened by the wild and lonely
            nature of the place.                  --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Power to produce results; efficiency; force; importance;
      account; as, to speak with effect.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Consequence intended; purpose; meaning; general intent; --
      with to.
      [1913 Webster]

            They spake to her to that effect.     --2 Chron.
                                                  xxxiv. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The purport; the sum and substance. ``The effect of his
      intent.'' --Chaucer.

   8. Reality; actual meaning; fact, as distinguished from mere
      appearance.
      [1913 Webster]

            No other in effect than what it seems. --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. pl. Goods; movables; personal estate; -- sometimes used to
      embrace real as well as personal property; as, the people
      escaped from the town with their effects.
      [1913 Webster]

   {For effect}, for an exaggerated impression or excitement.

   {In effect}, in fact; in substance. See 8, above.

   {Of no effect}, {Of none effect}, {To no effect}, or {Without
   effect}, destitute of results, validity, force, and the like;
      vain; fruitless. ``Making the word of God of none effect
      through your tradition.'' --Mark vii. 13. ``All my study
      be to no effect.'' --Shak.

   {To give effect to}, to make valid; to carry out in practice;
      to push to its results.

   {To take effect}, to become operative, to accomplish aims.
      --Shak.

   Syn: {Effect}, {Consequence}, {Result}.

   Usage: These words indicate things which arise out of some
          antecedent, or follow as a consequent. Effect, which
          may be regarded as the generic term, denotes that
          which springs directly from something which can
          properly be termed a cause. A consequence is more
          remote, not being strictly caused, nor yet a mere
          sequence, but following out of and following
          indirectly, or in the train of events, something on
          which it truly depends. A result is still more remote
          and variable, like the rebound of an elastic body
          which falls in very different directions. We may
          foresee the effects of a measure, may conjecture its
          consequences, but can rarely discover its final
          results.
          [1913 Webster]

                Resolving all events, with their effects
                And manifold results, into the will
                And arbitration wise of the Supreme. --Cowper.
          [1913 Webster]

                Shun the bitter consequence, for know,
                The day thou eatest thereof, . . . thou shalt
                die.                              --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>effect</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Effect \Ef*fect"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Effected}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Effecting}.]
   1. To produce, as a cause or agent; to cause to be.
      [1913 Webster]

            So great a body such exploits to effect. --Daniel.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring to pass; to execute; to enforce; to achieve; to
      accomplish.
      [1913 Webster]

            To effect that which the divine counsels had
            decreed.                              --Bp. Hurd.
      [1913 Webster]

            They sailed away without effecting their purpose.
                                                  --Jowett (Th.
                                                  ).

   Syn: To accomplish; fulfill; achieve; complete; execute;
        perform; attain. See {Accomplish}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>effect</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>effect
     n 1: a phenomenon that follows and is caused by some previous
          phenomenon; "the magnetic effect was greater when the
          rod was lengthwise"; "his decision had depressing
          consequences for business"; "he acted very wise after
          the event" [syn: {consequence}, {outcome}, {result}, {event},
           {issue}, {upshot}]
     2: an outward appearance; "he made a good impression"; "I
        wanted to create an impression of success"; "she retained
        that bold effect in her reproductions of the original
        painting" [syn: {impression}]
     3: (of a law) having legal validity; "the law is still in
        effect" [syn: {force}]
     4: a symptom caused by an illness or a drug; "the effects of
        sleep loss"; "the effect of the anesthetic"
     5: an impression (especially one that is artificial or
        contrived); "he just did it for effect"
     6: the central meaning or theme of a speech or literary work
        [syn: {essence}, {burden}, {core}, {gist}]
     v 1: produce; "The scientists set up a shockwave" [syn: {effectuate},
           {bring about}, {set up}]
     2: act so as to bring into existence; "effect a change"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
