<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>elizabeth</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>elizabeth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Elizabeth, AR
  Zip code(s): 72531
Elizabeth, CO (town, FIPS 23740)
  Location: 39.36013 N, 104.59953 W
  Population (1990): 818 (312 housing units)
  Area: 1.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 80107
Elizabeth, IL (village, FIPS 23165)
  Location: 42.31615 N, 90.22465 W
  Population (1990): 641 (323 housing units)
  Area: 1.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 61028
Elizabeth, IN (town, FIPS 20674)
  Location: 38.12533 N, 85.97477 W
  Population (1990): 153 (66 housing units)
  Area: 0.4 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 47117
Elizabeth, LA (town, FIPS 23235)
  Location: 30.86837 N, 92.79768 W
  Population (1990): 414 (173 housing units)
  Area: 4.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Elizabeth, MN (city, FIPS 18566)
  Location: 46.37931 N, 96.13040 W
  Population (1990): 152 (79 housing units)
  Area: 0.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 56533
Elizabeth, MS
  Zip code(s): 38756
Elizabeth, NJ (city, FIPS 21000)
  Location: 40.66637 N, 74.19416 W
  Population (1990): 110002 (41315 housing units)
  Area: 31.9 sq km (land), 3.7 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 07201, 07202, 07206, 07208
Elizabeth, PA (borough, FIPS 22992)
  Location: 40.27152 N, 79.88646 W
  Population (1990): 1610 (773 housing units)
  Area: 0.9 sq km (land), 0.2 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 15037
Elizabeth, WV (town, FIPS 24364)
  Location: 39.06242 N, 81.39737 W
  Population (1990): 900 (452 housing units)
  Area: 1.2 sq km (land), 0.2 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 26143
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>elizabeth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Elizabeth \Elizabeth\ prop. n. [a proper name from the Hebrew,
   probably meaning `` God of the oath'' or `` oath of God''.]
   1. Queen Elizabeth II. of the United Kingdom, born 1926.

   Syn: Elizabeth II.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. Elizabeth I., the Queen of England from 1558 to 1603. She
      was the daughter of Henry VIII. and Anne Boleyn
      (1533-1603).

   Syn: Elizabeth I.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   Note: Elizabeth was born at Greenwich, near London, Sept. 7,
         1533: died at Richmond, near London, March 24, 1603.
         She reigned as Queen of England from 1558 to 1603. She
         was the daughter of Henry VIII. and Anne Boleyn; was
         brought up in the Protestant faith; studied the
         classical languages under Roger Ascham; and is said to
         have been proficient in French and Italian. On her
         accession she appointed as secretary of state Sir
         William Cecil (later Baron Burleigh), who remained her
         chief adviser for forty years, until his death in 1598.
         She repealed the Roman Catholic legislation of the
         previous reign, reenacted the laws of Henry VIII.
         relating to the church, published the Thirty-nine
         Articles (1563), and completed the establishment of the
         Anglican Church. In 1564 she concluded the treaty of
         Troyes with France, by which she renounced her claims
         to Calais in consideration of 220,000 crowns. In 1587
         she signed the death-warrant of Mary Queen of Scots,
         who, expelled by a rebellion of her subjects, had taken
         refuge in England in 1568, and who, by means, it is
         said, of forged documents, had been involved by the
         government in a conspiracy of Savage, Ballard,
         Babington, and others against Queen Elizabeth. In 1588
         her admiral Howard, assisted by Drake, Hawkins,
         Frobisher, Winter, and Raleigh defeated the Spanish
         Armada in the English Channel, and prevented an
         invasion of England. Her reign, which was one of
         commercial enterprise and of intellectual activity, was
         made illustrious by Shakespeare, Sidney, Spenser,
         Bacon, and Ben Jonson.
         [Century Dict.]

   3. Saint Elizabeth of Hungary; Born at Presburg, Hungary
      1207, died died at Marburg, Germany, Nov. 19, 1231. She
      was a Hungarian princess, daughter of Andrew II. of
      Hungary, and wife of Louis, landgrave of Thuringia,
      celebrated for her sanctity.
      [PJC]

   4. a city in Union County in northeastern New Jersy, pop. ca.
      106,000. It lies between Newark to the north and Linden to
      the south, and has a large port, regulated by the Port of
      New York Authority. It also contains most of the runway
      area of the Newark International Airport.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>elizabeth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Elizabeth
     n 1: daughter of George VI who became the Queen of England and
          Northern Ireland in 1952 on the death of her father
          (1926-) [syn: {Elizabeth II}]
     2: Queen of England from 1558 to 1603; daughter of Henry VIII
        and Anne Boleyn; she succeeded Mary I (who was a Catholic)
        and restored Protestantism to England; during her reign
        Mary Queen of Scots was executed and the Spanish Armada
        was defeated; her reign was marked by prosperity and
        literary genius (1533-1603) [syn: {Elizabeth I}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
