<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>embarrassed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>embarrassed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Embarrass \Em*bar"rass\ ([e^]m*b[a^]r"ras), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Embarrassed} ([e^]m*b[a^]r"rast); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Embarrassing}.] [F. embarrasser (cf. Sp. embarazar, Pg.
   embara[,c]ar, Pr. barras bar); pref. em- (L. in) + LL. barra
   bar. See {Bar}.]
   1. To hinder from freedom of thought, speech, or action by
      something which impedes or confuses mental action; to make
      (a person) unpleasantly self-conscious; to perplex; to
      discompose; to disconcert; as, laughter may embarrass an
      orator. [WordNet sense 1]

   Syn: abash, discompose, disconcert, discomfit, chagrin. [1913
        Webster +PJC]

   2. To hinder from liberty of movement; to impede; to
      obstruct; as, business is embarrassed; public affairs are
      embarrassed. [WordNet sense 2]

   Syn: obstruct, blockade, block, hinder, stymie. [1913
        Webster]

   3. (Com.) To involve in difficulties concerning money
      matters; to incumber with debt; to beset with urgent
      claims or demands; -- said of a person or his affairs; as,
      a man or his business is embarrassed when he can not meet
      his pecuniary engagements.

   Syn: To hinder; perplex; entangle; confuse; puzzle;
        disconcert; abash; distress. -- To {Embarrass},
        {Puzzle}, {Perplex}. We are puzzled when our faculties
        are confused by something we do not understand. We are
        perplexed when our feelings, as well as judgment, are so
        affected that we know not how to decide or act. We are
        embarrassed when there is some bar or hindrance upon us
        which impedes our powers of thought, speech, or motion.
        A schoolboy is puzzled by a difficult sum; a reasoner is
        perplexed by the subtleties of his opponent; a youth is
        sometimes so embarrassed before strangers as to lose his
        presence of mind.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>embarrassed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>embarrassed \embarrassed\ adj.
   1. feeling uneasily or unpleasantly self-conscious due to
      some event or circumstance; as, she was embarrassed by her
      child's tantrums.

   Syn: abashed, self-conscious.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. feeling inferior or unworthy and hence unpleasantly
      self-conscious; as, too embarrassed to say hello to his
      drunken father on the street.

   Syn: chagrined, mortified.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>embarrassed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>embarrassed
     adj 1: feeling or caused to feel uneasy and self-conscious; "felt
            abashed at the extravagant praise"; "chagrined at the
            poor sales of his book"; "was embarrassed by her
            child's tantrums" [syn: {abashed}, {chagrined}]
     2: caused to feel self-conscious and uncomfortable; "was
        discomfited by the personal questions"; "the child felt
        embarrassed by the attention of the adults" [syn: {discomfited}]
     3: made to feel uncomfortable because of shame or wounded
        pride; "too embarrassed to say hello to his drunken father
        on the street"; "humiliated that his wife had to go out to
        work"; "felt mortified by the comparison with her sister"
        [syn: {humiliated}, {mortified}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
