<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>engineering</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>engineering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Engineer \En`gi*neer"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Engineered}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Engineering}.]
   1. To lay out or construct, as an engineer; to perform the
      work of an engineer on; as, to engineer a road. --J.
      Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To use contrivance and effort for; to guide the course of;
      to manage; as, to engineer a bill through Congress.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>engineering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Engineering \En`gi*neer"ing\, n.
   Originally, the art of managing engines; in its modern and
   extended sense, the art and science by which the properties
   of matter are made useful to man, whether in structures,
   machines, chemical substances, or living organisms; the
   occupation and work of an engineer. In the modern sense, the
   application of mathematics or systematic knowledge beyond the
   routine skills of practise, for the design of any complex
   system which performs useful functions, may be considered as
   engineering, including such abstract tasks as designing
   software ({software engineering}).
   [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: In a comprehensive sense, engineering includes
         architecture as a mechanical art, in distinction from
         architecture as a fine art. It was formerly divided
         into military engineering, which is the art of
         designing and constructing offensive and defensive
         works, and civil engineering, in a broad sense, as
         relating to other kinds of public works, machinery,
         etc.

   {Civil engineering}, in modern usage, is strictly the art of
      planning, laying out, and constructing fixed public works,
      such as railroads, highways, canals, aqueducts, water
      works, bridges, lighthouses, docks, embankments,
      breakwaters, dams, tunnels, etc.

   {Mechanical engineering} relates to machinery, such as steam
      engines, machine tools, mill work, etc.

   {Mining engineering} deals with the excavation and working of
      mines, and the extraction of metals from their ores, etc.
      Engineering is further divided into steam engineering, gas
      engineering, agricultural engineering, topographical
      engineering, electrical engineering, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>engineering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>engineering
     n 1: the practical application of science to commerce or industry
          [syn: {technology}]
     2: the discipline dealing with the art or science of applying
        scientific knowledge to practical problems; "he had
        trouble deciding which branch of engineering to study"
        [syn: {engineering science}, {applied science}, {technology}]
     3: a room (as on a ship) in which the engine is located [syn: {engine
        room}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
