<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>english</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>english</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>English
     
        1. (Obsolete) The source code for a program, which may be in
        any language, as opposed to the linkable or executable binary
        produced from it by a compiler.  The idea behind the term is
        that to a real hacker, a program written in his favourite
        programming language is at least as readable as English.
        Usage: mostly by old-time hackers, though recognisable in
        context.
     
        2. The official name of the {database} language used by the
        {Pick} {operating system}, actually a sort of crufty,
        brain-damaged {SQL} with delusions of grandeur.  The name
        permits {marketroid}s to say "Yes, and you can program our
        computers in English!" to ignorant {suit}s without quite
        running afoul of the truth-in-advertising laws.
     
        ["Exploring the Pick Operating System", J.E. Sisk et al,
        Hayden 1986].
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>english</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>English, IN (town, FIPS 21214)
  Location: 38.33302 N, 86.46328 W
  Population (1990): 614 (260 housing units)
  Area: 3.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 47118
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>english</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>English \Eng"lish\, n.
   1. Collectively, the people of England; English people or
      persons.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The language of England or of the English nation, and of
      their descendants in America, India, and other countries.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The English language has been variously divided into
         periods by different writers. In the division most
         commonly recognized, the first period dates from about
         450 to 1150. This is the period of full inflection, and
         is called Anglo-Saxon, or, by many recent writers, Old
         English. The second period dates from about 1150 to
         1550 (or, if four periods be recognized, from about
         1150 to 1350), and is called Early English, Middle
         English, or more commonly (as in the usage of this
         book), Old English. During this period most of the
         inflections were dropped, and there was a great
         addition of French words to the language. The third
         period extends from about 1350 to 1550, and is Middle
         English. During this period orthography became
         comparatively fixed. The last period, from about 1550,
         is called Modern English.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. A kind of printing type, in size between Pica and Great
      Primer. See {Type}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The type called English.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. (Billiards) A twist or spinning motion given to a ball in
      striking it that influences the direction it will take
      after touching a cushion or another ball.
      [1913 Webster]

   {The King's English} or {The Queen's English}. See under
      {King}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>english</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>English \Eng"lish\, a. [AS. Englisc, fr. Engle, Angle, Engles,
   Angles, a tribe of Germans from the southeast of Sleswick, in
   Denmark, who settled in Britain and gave it the name of
   England. Cf. {Anglican}.]
   Of or pertaining to England, or to its inhabitants, or to the
   present so-called Anglo-Saxon race.
   [1913 Webster]

   {English bond} (Arch.) See 1st {Bond}, n., 8.

   {English breakfast tea}. See {Congou}.

   {English horn}. (Mus.) See {Corno Inglese}.

   {English walnut}. (Bot.) See under {Walnut}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>english</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>English \Eng"lish\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Englished}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Englishing}.]
   1. To translate into the English language; to Anglicize;
      hence, to interpret; to explain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those gracious acts . . . may be Englished more
            properly, acts of fear and dissimulation. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Caxton does not care to alter the French forms and
            words in the book which he was Englishing. --T. L.
                                                  K. Oliphant.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Billiards) To strike (the cue ball) in such a manner as
      to give it in addition to its forward motion a spinning
      motion, that influences its direction after impact on
      another ball or the cushion. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>english</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>English 1. n. obs. The source code for a program, which may be in any
   language, as opposed to the linkable or executable binary produced from
   it by a compiler. The idea behind the term is that to a real hacker, a
   program written in his favorite programming language is at least as
   readable as English. Usage: mostly by old-time hackers, though
   recognizable in context. Today the preferred shorthand is simply
   {source}. 2. The official name of the database language used by the old
   Pick Operating System, actually a sort of crufty, brain-damaged SQL with
   delusions of grandeur. The name permitted {marketroid}s to say "Yes, and
   you can program our computers in English!" to ignorant {suit}s without
   quite running afoul of the truth-in-advertising laws.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>english</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>English
     adj : of or relating to or characteristic of England or its
           culture; "English history"; "the English landed
           aristocracy"; "English literature"
     n 1: an Indo-European language belonging to the West Germanic
          branch; the official language of Britain and the United
          States and most of the Commonwealth countries [syn: {English
          language}]
     2: the people of England [syn: {English people}, {the English}]
     3: the discipline that studies the English language and
        literature
     4: (sports) the spin given to a ball by striking it on one side
        or releasing it with a sharp twist [syn: {side}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
