<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ensign</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ensign</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ensign
   (1.) Heb. 'oth, a military standard, especially of a single
   tribe (Num. 2:2). Each separate tribe had its own "sign" or
   "ensign."
   
     (2.) Heb. nes, a lofty signal, as a column or high pole (Num.
   21:8, 9); a standard or signal or flag placed on high mountains
   to point out to the people a place of rendezvous on the
   irruption of an enemy (Isa. 5:26; 11:12; 18:3; 62:10; Jer. 4:6,
   21; Ps. 60:4). This was an occasional signal, and not a military
   standard. Elevation and conspicuity are implied in the word.
   
     (3.) The Hebrew word _degel_ denotes the standard given to
   each of the four divisions of the host of the Israelites at the
   Exodus (Num. 1:52; 2:2; 10:14). In Cant. 2:4 it is rendered
   "banner." We have no definite information as to the nature of
   these military standards. (See {BANNER}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ensign</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ensign, KS (city, FIPS 21400)
  Location: 37.65358 N, 100.23224 W
  Population (1990): 192 (80 housing units)
  Area: 0.7 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 67841
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ensign</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ensign \En"sign\, v. t.
   1. To designate as by an ensign. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Henry but joined the roses that ensigned
            Particular families.                  --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To distinguish by a mark or ornament; esp. (Her.), by a
      crown; thus, any charge which has a crown immediately
      above or upon it, is said to be ensigned.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ensign</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ensign \en"sign\ ([e^]n"s[i^]n also [e^]n"s[imac]n, except for
   4a), n. [L. enseigne, L. insignia, pl. of insigne a
   distinctive mark, badge, flag; in + signum mark, sign. See
   {Sign}, and cf. {Insignia}, 3d {Ancient}.]
   1. A flag; a banner; a standard; esp., the national flag, or
      a banner indicating nationality, carried by a ship or a
      body of soldiers; -- as distinguished from flags
      indicating divisions of the army, rank of naval officers,
      or private signals, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hang up your ensigns, let your drums be still.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A signal displayed like a standard, to give notice.
      [1913 Webster]

            He will lift an ensign to the nations from far.
                                                  --Is. v. 26.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Sign; badge of office, rank, or power; symbol.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ensigns of our power about we bear. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   4.
      (a) Formerly, a commissioned officer of the army who
          carried the ensign or flag of a company or regiment.
      (b) A commissioned officer of the lowest grade in the
          navy, corresponding to the grade of second lieutenant
          in the army. --Ham. Nav. Encyc.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the British army the rank of ensign was abolished in
         1871. In the United States army the rank is not
         recognized; the regimental flags being carried by a
         sergeant called the color sergeant.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Ensign bearer}, one who carries a flag; an ensign.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ensign</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ensign
     n 1: a person who holds a commissioned rank in the United States
          Navy or the United States Coast Guard; below lieutenant
          junior grade
     2: an emblem flown as a symbol of nationality [syn: {national
        flag}]
     3: colors flown by a ship to show its nationality
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
