<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>entered</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>entered</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Enter \En"ter\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Entered}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Entering}.] [OE. entren, enteren, F. entrer, fr. L. intrare,
   fr. intro inward, contr. fr. intero (sc. loco), fr. inter in
   between, between. See {Inter-}, {In}, and cf. {Interior}.]
   1. To come or go into; to pass into the interior of; to pass
      within the outer cover or shell of; to penetrate; to
      pierce; as, to enter a house, a closet, a country, a door,
      etc.; the river enters the sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            That darksome cave they enter.        --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            I, . . . with the multitude of my redeemed,
            Shall enter heaven, long absent.      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To unite in; to join; to be admitted to; to become a
      member of; as, to enter an association, a college, an
      army.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To engage in; to become occupied with; as, to enter the
      legal profession, the book trade, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To pass within the limits of; to attain; to begin; to
      commence upon; as, to enter one's teens, a new era, a new
      dispensation.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To cause to go (into), or to be received (into); to put
      in; to insert; to cause to be admitted; as, to enter a
      knife into a piece of wood, a wedge into a log; to enter a
      boy at college, a horse for a race, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To inscribe; to enroll; to record; as, to enter a name, or
      a date, in a book, or a book in a catalogue; to enter the
      particulars of a sale in an account, a manifest of a ship
      or of merchandise at the customhouse.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law)
      (a) To go into or upon, as lands, and take actual
          possession of them.
      (b) To place in regular form before the court, usually in
          writing; to put upon record in proper from and order;
          as, to enter a writ, appearance, rule, or judgment.
          --Burrill.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. To make report of (a vessel or her cargo) at the
      customhouse; to submit a statement of (imported goods),
      with the original invoices, to the proper officer of the
      customs for estimating the duties. See {Entry}, 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To file or inscribe upon the records of the land office
      the required particulars concerning (a quantity of public
      land) in order to entitle a person to a right pf
      pre["e]mption. [U.S.] --Abbott.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To deposit for copyright the title or description of (a
       book, picture, map, etc.); as, ``entered according to act
       of Congress.''
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To initiate; to introduce favorably. [Obs.] --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
