<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>entry</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>entry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Entry \En"try\, n.; pl. {Entries}. [OE. entree, entre, F.
   entr['e]e, fr. entrer to enter. See {Enter}, and cf.
   {Entr['e]e}.]
   1. The act of entering or passing into or upon; entrance;
      ingress; hence, beginnings or first attempts; as, the
      entry of a person into a house or city; the entry of a
      river into the sea; the entry of air into the blood; an
      entry upon an undertaking.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of making or entering a record; a setting down in
      writing the particulars, as of a transaction; as, an entry
      of a sale; also, that which is entered; an item.
      [1913 Webster]

            A notary made an entry of this act.   --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That by which entrance is made; a passage leading into a
      house or other building, or to a room; a vestibule; an
      adit, as of a mine.
      [1913 Webster]

            A straight, long entry to the temple led. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Com.) The exhibition or depositing of a ship's papers at
      the customhouse, to procure license to land goods; or the
      giving an account of a ship's cargo to the officer of the
      customs, and obtaining his permission to land the goods.
      See {Enter}, v. t., 8, and {Entrance}, n., 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law)
      (a) The actual taking possession of lands or tenements, by
          entering or setting foot on them.
      (b) A putting upon record in proper form and order.
      (c) The act in addition to breaking essential to
          constitute the offense or burglary. --Burrill.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Bill of entry}. See under {Bill}.

   {Double entry}, {Single entry}. See {Bookkeeping}.

   {Entry clerk} (Com.), a clerk who makes the original entries
      of transactions in a business.

   {Writ of entry} (Law), a writ issued for the purpose of
      obtaining possession of land from one who has unlawfully
      entered and continues in possession. --Bouvier.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>entry</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>entry
     n 1: an item inserted in a written record
     2: the act of beginning something new; "they looked forward to
        the debut of their new product line" [syn: {introduction},
         {debut}, {first appearance}, {launching}, {unveiling}]
     3: a written record of a commercial transaction [syn: {accounting
        entry}, {ledger entry}]
     4: something (manuscripts or architectural plans and models or
        estimates or works of art of all genres etc.) submitted
        for the judgment of others (as in a competition); "several
        of his submissions were rejected by publishers"; "what was
        the date of submission of your proposal?" [syn: {submission}]
     5: something that provides access (entry or exit); "they waited
        at the entrance to the garden"; "beggars waited just
        outside the entryway to the cathedral" [syn: {entrance}, {entranceway},
         {entryway}, {entree}]
     6: the act of entering; "she made a grand entrance" [syn: {entrance},
         {entering}, {ingress}, {incoming}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
