<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>envy</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>envy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ENVY, n.  Emulation adapted to the meanest capacity.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>envy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Envy \En"vy\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Envied}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Envying}.] [F. envier.]
   1. To feel envy at or towards; to be envious of; to have a
      feeling of uneasiness or mortification in regard to (any
      one), arising from the sight of another's excellence or
      good fortune and a longing to possess it.
      [1913 Webster]

            A woman does not envy a man for his fighting
            courage, nor a man a woman for her beauty.
                                                  --Collier.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whoever envies another confesses his superiority.
                                                  --Rambler.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To feel envy on account of; to have a feeling of grief or
      repining, with a longing to possess (some excellence or
      good fortune of another, or an equal good fortune, etc.);
      to look with grudging upon; to begrudge.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have seen thee fight,
            When I have envied thy behavior.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jeffrey . . . had actually envied his friends their
            cool mountain breezes.                --Froude.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To long after; to desire strongly; to covet.
      [1913 Webster]

            Or climb his knee the envied kiss to share. --T.
                                                  Gray.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To do harm to; to injure; to disparage. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            If I make a lie
            To gain your love and envy my best mistress,
            Put me against a wall.                --J. Fletcher.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To hate. [Obs.] --Marlowe.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To emulate. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>envy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Envy \En"vy\, n.; pl. {Envies}. [F. envie, L. invidia envious;
   akin to invidere to look askance at, to look with enmity; in
   against + videre to see. See {Vision}.]
   1. Malice; ill will; spite. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            If he evade us there,
            Enforce him with his envy to the people. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Chagrin, mortification, discontent, or uneasiness at the
      sight of another's excellence or good fortune, accompanied
      with some degree of hatred and a desire to possess equal
      advantages; malicious grudging; -- usually followed by of;
      as, they did this in envy of C[ae]sar.
      [1913 Webster]

            Envy is a repining at the prosperity or good of
            another, or anger and displeasure at any good of
            another which we want, or any advantage another hath
            above us.                             --Ray.
      [1913 Webster]

            No bliss
            Enjoyed by us excites his envy more.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Envy, to which the ignoble mind's a slave,
            Is emulation in the learned or brave. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Emulation; rivalry. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Such as cleanliness and decency
            Prompt to a virtuous envy.            --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Public odium; ill repute. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To lay the envy of the war upon Cicero. --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An object of envious notice or feeling.
      [1913 Webster]

            This constitution in former days used to be the envy
            of the world.                         --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>envy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Envy \En"vy\, v. i.
   1. To be filled with envious feelings; to regard anything
      with grudging and longing eyes; -- used especially with
      at.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who would envy at the prosperity of the wicked?
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To show malice or ill will; to rail. [Obs.] ``He has . . .
      envied against the people.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>envy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>envy
     n 1: a feeling of grudging admiration and desire to have
          something possessed by another [syn: {enviousness}, {the
          green-eyed monster}]
     2: spite and resentment at seeing the success of another
        (personified as one of the deadly sins) [syn: {invidia}]
     v 1: feel envious towards; admire enviously
     2: be envious of; set one's heart on [syn: {begrudge}]
     [also: {envied}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
