<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>error</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>error</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>error
     
        1. A discrepancy between a computed, observed, or measured
        value or condition and the true, specified, or theoretically
        correct value or condition.
     
        2. &lt;programming&gt; A mental mistake made by a programmer that
        may result in a program {fault}.
     
        3. (verb) What a program does when it stops as result of a
        programming error.
     
        (2000-03-28)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>error</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Error \Er"ror\, n. [OF. error, errur, F. erreur, L. error, fr.
   errare to err. See {Err}.]
   1. A wandering; a roving or irregular course. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The rest of his journey, his error by sea. --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A wandering or deviation from the right course or
      standard; irregularity; mistake; inaccuracy; something
      made wrong or left wrong; as, an error in writing or in
      printing; a clerical error.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A departing or deviation from the truth; falsity; false
      notion; wrong opinion; mistake; misapprehension.
      [1913 Webster]

            His judgment was often in error, though his candor
            remained unimpaired.                  --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A moral offense; violation of duty; a sin or
      transgression; iniquity; fault. --Ps. xix. 12.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) The difference between the approximate result and
      the true result; -- used particularly in the rule of
      double position.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mensuration)
      (a) The difference between an observed value and the true
          value of a quantity.
      (b) The difference between the observed value of a
          quantity and that which is taken or computed to be the
          true value; -- sometimes called {residual error}.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law.) A mistake in the proceedings of a court of record
      in matters of law or of fact.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Baseball) A fault of a player of the side in the field
      which results in failure to put out a player on the other
      side, or gives him an unearned base.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Law of error}, or {Law of frequency of error} (Mensuration),
      the law which expresses the relation between the magnitude
      of an error and the frequency with which that error will
      be committed in making a large number of careful
      measurements of a quantity.

   {Probable error}. (Mensuration) See under {Probable}.

   {Writ of error} (Law), an original writ, which lies after
      judgment in an action at law, in a court of record, to
      correct some alleged error in the proceedings, or in the
      judgment of the court. --Bouvier. Burrill.

   Syn: Mistake; fault; blunder; failure; fallacy; delusion;
        hallucination; sin. See {Blunder}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>error</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>error
     n 1: a wrong action attributable to bad judgment or ignorance or
          inattention; "he made a bad mistake"; "she was quick to
          point out my errors"; "I could understand his English in
          spite of his grammatical faults" [syn: {mistake}, {fault}]
     2: inadvertent incorrectness [syn: {erroneousness}]
     3: a misconception resulting from incorrect information [syn: {erroneous
        belief}]
     4: (baseball) a failure of a defensive player to make an out
        when normal play would have sufficed [syn: {misplay}]
     5: departure from what is ethically acceptable [syn: {wrongdoing}]
     6: (computer science) the occurrence of an incorrect result
        produced by a computer [syn: {computer error}]
     7: part of a statement that is not correct; "the book was full
        of errors" [syn: {mistake}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
