<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>escort</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>escort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Escort \Es*cort"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Escorted}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Escorting}.] [Cf. F. escorter, It. scortare. See
   {Escort}, n.]
   To attend with a view to guard and protect; to accompany as
   safeguard; to give honorable or ceremonious attendance to; --
   used esp. with reference to journeys or excursions on land;
   as, to escort a public functionary, or a lady; to escort a
   baggage wagon.

   Syn: To accompany; attend. See {Accompany}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>escort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Escort \Es"cort\, n. [F. escorte, It. scorta a guard or guide,
   fr. scorgere to perceive, discern, lead, fr. L. ex out, quite
   + corrigere to correct, set right. See {Correct}.]
   1. A body of armed men to attend a person of distinction for
      the sake of affording safety when on a journey; one who
      conducts some one as an attendant; a guard, as of
      prisoners on a march; also, a body of persons, attending
      as a mark of respect or honor; -- applied to movements on
      land, as convoy is to movements at sea.
      [1913 Webster]

            The troops of my escort marched at the ordinary
            rate.                                 --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Protection, care, or safeguard on a journey or excursion;
      as, to travel under the escort of a friend.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>escort</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>escort
     n 1: someone who escorts and protects a prominent person [syn: {bodyguard}]
     2: the act of accompanying someone or something in order to
        protect them [syn: {accompaniment}]
     3: an attendant who is employed to accompany someone
     4: a participant in a date; "his date never stopped talking"
        [syn: {date}]
     v 1: accompany as an escort; "She asked her older brother to
          escort her to the ball"
     2: accompany or escort; "I'll see you to the door" [syn: {see}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
