<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>essence</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>essence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Essence \Es"sence\, n. [F. essence, L. essentia, formed as if
   fr. a p. pr. of esse to be. See {Is}, and cf. {Entity}.]
   1. The constituent elementary notions which constitute a
      complex notion, and must be enumerated to define it;
      sometimes called the nominal essence.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The constituent quality or qualities which belong to any
      object, or class of objects, or on which they depend for
      being what they are (distinguished as real essence); the
      real being, divested of all logical accidents; that
      quality which constitutes or marks the true nature of
      anything; distinctive character; hence, virtue or quality
      of a thing, separated from its grosser parts.
      [1913 Webster]

            The laws are at present, both in form and essence,
            the greatest curse that society labors under.
                                                  --Landor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Gifts and alms are the expressions, not the essence
            of this virtue [charity].             --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            The essence of Addison's humor is irony.
                                                  --Courthope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Constituent substance.
      [1913 Webster]

            And uncompounded is their essence pure. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A being; esp., a purely spiritual being.
      [1913 Webster]

            As far as gods and heavenly essences
            Can perish.                           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            He had been indulging in fanciful speculations on
            spiritual essences, until . . . he had and ideal
            world of his own around him.          --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The predominant qualities or virtues of a plant or drug,
      extracted and refined from grosser matter; or, more
      strictly, the solution in spirits of wine of a volatile or
      essential oil; as, the essence of mint, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            The . . . word essence . . . scarcely underwent a
            more complete transformation when from being the
            abstract of the verb ``to be,'' it came to denote
            something sufficiently concrete to be inclosed in a
            glass bottle.                         --J. S. Mill.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Perfume; odor; scent; or the volatile matter constituting
      perfume.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor let the essences exhale.          --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>essence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Essence \Es"sence\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Essenced}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Essencing}.]
   To perfume; to scent. ``Essenced fops.'' --Addison.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>essence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>essence
     n 1: the choicest or most essential or most vital part of some
          idea or experience; "the gist of the prosecutor's
          argument"; "the heart and soul of the Republican Party";
          "the nub of the story" [syn: {kernel}, {substance}, {core},
           {center}, {gist}, {heart}, {heart and soul}, {inwardness},
           {marrow}, {meat}, {nub}, {pith}, {sum}, {nitty-gritty}]
     2: any substance possessing to a high degree the predominant
        properties of a plant or drug or other natural product
        from which it is extracted
     3: the central meaning or theme of a speech or literary work
        [syn: {effect}, {burden}, {core}, {gist}]
     4: a toiletry that emits and diffuses a fragrant odor [syn: {perfume}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
