<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>estate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>estate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Estate \Es*tate"\ ([e^]s*t[=a]t"), n. [OF. estat, F. ['e]tat, L.
   status, fr. stare to stand. See {Stand}, and cf. {State}.]
   1. Settled condition or form of existence; state; condition
      or circumstances of life or of any person; situation.
      ``When I came to man's estate.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mind not high things, but condescend to men of low
            estate.                               --Romans xii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Social standing or rank; quality; dignity.
      [1913 Webster]

            God hath imprinted his authority in several parts,
            upon several estates of men.          --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A person of high rank. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            She's a duchess, a great estate.      --Latimer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Herod on his birthday made a supper to his lords,
            high captains, and chief estates of Galilee. --Mark
                                                  vi. 21.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A property which a person possesses; a fortune;
      possessions, esp. property in land; also, property of all
      kinds which a person leaves to be divided at his death.
      [1913 Webster]

            See what a vast estate he left his son. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The state; the general body politic; the common-wealth;
      the general interest; state affairs. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I call matters of estate not only the parts of
            sovereignty, but whatsoever . . . concerneth
            manifestly any great portion of people. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. pl. The great classes or orders of a community or state
      (as the clergy, the nobility, and the commonalty of
      England) or their representatives who administer the
      government; as, the estates of the realm (England), which
      are (1) the lords spiritual, (2) the lords temporal, (3)
      the commons.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) The degree, quality, nature, and extent of one's
      interest in, or ownership of, lands, tenements, etc.; as,
      an estate for life, for years, at will, etc. --Abbott.
      [1913 Webster]

   {The fourth estate}, a name often given to the public press.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>estate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Estate \Es*tate"\, v. t.
   1. To establish. [Obs.] --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Tom settle as a fortune. [Archaic] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To endow with an estate. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Then would I . . .
            Estate them with large land and territory.
                                                  --Tennyson.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>estate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>estate
     n 1: everything you own; all of your assets (whether real
          property or personal property) and liabilities
     2: extensive landed property (especially in the country)
        retained by the owner for his own use; "the family owned a
        large estate on Long Island" [syn: {land}, {landed estate},
         {acres}, {demesne}]
     3: a major social class or order of persons regarded
        collectively as part of the body politic of the country
        and formerly possessing distinct political rights [syn: {estate
        of the realm}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
