<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>eve</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eve
   life; living, the name given by Adam to his wife (Gen. 3:20;
   4:1). The account of her creation is given in Gen. 2:21, 22. The
   Creator, by declaring that it was not good for man to be alone,
   and by creating for him a suitable companion, gave sanction to
   monogamy. The commentator Matthew Henry says: "This companion
   was taken from his side to signify that she was to be dear unto
   him as his own flesh. Not from his head, lest she should rule
   over him; nor from his feet, lest he should tyrannize over her;
   but from his side, to denote that species of equality which is
   to subsist in the marriage state." And again, "That wife that is
   of God's making by special grace, and of God's bringing by
   special providence, is likely to prove a helpmeet to her
   husband." Through the subtle temptation of the serpent she
   violated the commandment of God by taking of the forbidden
   fruit, which she gave also unto her husband (1 Tim. 2:13-15; 2
   Cor. 11:3). When she gave birth to her first son, she said, "I
   have gotten a man from the Lord" (R.V., "I have gotten a man
   with the help of the Lord," Gen. 4:1). Thus she welcomed Cain,
   as some think, as if he had been the Promised One the "Seed of
   the woman."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>EVE
     
        {Extensible VAX Editor}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eve \Eve\ ([=e]v), n. [See {Even}, n.]
   1. Evening. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            Winter oft, at eve resumes the breeze. --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The evening before a holiday, -- from the Jewish mode of
      reckoning the day as beginning at sunset, not at midnight;
      as, Christmas eve is the evening before Christmas; also,
      the period immediately preceding some important event.
      ``On the eve of death.'' --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Eve churr} (Zo["o]l), the European goatsucker or nightjar;
      -- called also {night churr}, and {churr owl}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eve, living; enlivening

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>EVE
     Extended Virtual Environment
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>eve</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Eve
     n 1: (Old Testament) Adam's wife in Judeo-Christian mythology:
          the first woman and mother of the human race; God
          created Eve from Adam's rib and placed Adam and Eve in
          the Garden of Eden
     2: the day before; "he always arrives on the eve of her
        departure"
     3: the period immediately before something; "on the eve of the
        French Revolution"
     4: the latter part of the day (the period of decreasing
        daylight from late afternoon until nightfall); "he enjoyed
        the evening light across the lake" [syn: {evening}, {eventide}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
