<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>evolution</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>evolution</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Evolution \Ev`o*lu"tion\ ([e^]v`[-o]*l[=u]"sh[u^]n), n. [L.
   evolutio an unrolling: cf. F. ['e]volution evolution. See
   {Evolve}.]
   1. The act of unfolding or unrolling; hence, any process of
      growth or development; as, the evolution of a flower from
      a bud, or an animal from the egg.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A series of things unrolled or unfolded. ``The whole
      evolution of ages.'' --Dr. H. More.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Geom.) The formation of an involute by unwrapping a
      thread from a curve as an evolute. --Hutton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Arith. &amp; Alg.) The extraction of roots; -- the reverse of
      involution.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mil. &amp; Naval) A prescribed movement of a body of troops,
      or a vessel or fleet; any movement designed to effect a
      new arrangement or disposition; a maneuver.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those evolutions are best which can be executed with
            the greatest celerity, compatible with regularity.
                                                  --Campbell.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Biol.) A general name for the history of the steps by
      which any living organism has acquired the morphological
      and physiological characters which distinguish it; a
      gradual unfolding of successive phases of growth or
      development.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Biol.) That theory of generation which supposes the germ
      to pre["e]xist in the parent, and its parts to be
      developed, but not actually formed, by the procreative
      act; -- opposed to {epigenesis}.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Metaph.) That series of changes under natural law which
      involves continuous progress from the homogeneous to the
      heterogeneous in structure, and from the single and simple
      to the diverse and manifold in quality or function. The
      process is by some limited to organic beings; by others it
      is applied to the inorganic and the psychical. It is also
      applied to explain the existence and growth of
      institutions, manners, language, civilization, and every
      product of human activity. The agencies and laws of the
      process are variously explained by different philosophrs.
      [1913 Webster]

            Evolution is to me series with development.
                                                  --Gladstone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>evolution</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>evolution
     n 1: a process in which something passes by degrees to a
          different stage (especially a more advanced or mature
          stage); "the development of his ideas took many years";
          "the evolution of Greek civilization"; "the slow
          development of her skill as a writer" [syn: {development}]
          [ant: {degeneration}]
     2: (biology) the sequence of events involved in the
        evolutionary development of a species or taxonomic group
        of organisms [syn: {phylogeny}, {phylogenesis}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
