<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>exception</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exception</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>EXCEPTION, n.  A thing which takes the liberty to differ from other
things of its class, as an honest man, a truthful woman, etc.  "The
exception proves the rule" is an expression constantly upon the lips
of the ignorant, who parrot it from one another with never a thought
of its absurdity.  In the Latin, "_Exceptio probat regulam_" means
that the exception _tests_ the rule, puts it to the proof, not
_confirms_ it.  The malefactor who drew the meaning from this
excellent dictum and substituted a contrary one of his own exerted an
evil power which appears to be immortal.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exception</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exception
     
        An error condition that changes the normal {flow of control}
        in a program.  An exception may be generated ("raised") by
        {hardware} or {software}.  Hardware exceptions include
        {reset}, {interrupt} or a signal from a {memory management
        unit}.  Exceptions may be generated by the {arithmetic logic
        unit} or {floating-point unit} for numerical errors such as
        divide by zero, {overflow} or {underflow} or {instruction
        decoding} errors such as privileged, reserved, {trap} or
        undefined instructions.  Software exceptions are even more
        varied and the term could be applied to any kind of error
        checking which alters the normal behaviour of the program.
     
        (1994-10-31)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exception</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exception \Ex*cep"tion\ ([e^]k*s[e^]p"sh[u^]n), n. [L. exceptio:
   cf. F. exception.]
   1. The act of excepting or excluding; exclusion; restriction
      by taking out something which would otherwise be included,
      as in a class, statement, rule.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is excepted or taken out from others; a person,
      thing, or case, specified as distinct, or not included;
      as, almost every general rule has its exceptions.
      [1913 Webster]

            Such rare exceptions, shining in the dark,
            Prove, rather than impeach, the just remark.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Often with to.
         [1913 Webster]

               That proud exception to all nature's laws.
                                                  --Pope.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Law) An objection, oral or written, taken, in the course
      of an action, as to bail or security; or as to the
      decision of a judge, in the course of a trail, or in his
      charge to a jury; or as to lapse of time, or scandal,
      impertinence, or insufficiency in a pleading; also, as in
      conveyancing, a clause by which the grantor excepts
      something before granted. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An objection; cavil; dissent; disapprobation; offense;
      cause of offense; -- usually followed by to or against.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will never answer what exceptions they can have
            against our account [relation].       --Bentley.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . took exception to the place of their
            burial.                               --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            She takes exceptions at your person.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bill of exceptions} (Law), a statement of exceptions to the
      decision, or instructions of a judge in the trial of a
      cause, made for the purpose of putting the points decided
      on record so as to bring them before a superior court or
      the full bench for review.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exception</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exception
     n 1: a deliberate act of omission; "with the exception of the
          children, everyone was told the news" [syn: {exclusion},
           {elision}]
     2: an instance that does not conform to a rule or
        generalization; "all her children were brilliant; the only
        exception was her last child"; "an exception tests the
        rule"
     3: grounds for adverse criticism; "his authority is beyond
        exception"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
