<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>exercise</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exercise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exercise \Ex"er*cise\, n. [F. exercice, L. exercitium, from
   exercere, exercitum, to drive on, keep, busy, prob. orig., to
   thrust or drive out of the inclosure; ex out + arcere to shut
   up, inclose. See {Ark}.]
   1. The act of exercising; a setting in action or practicing;
      employment in the proper mode of activity; exertion;
      application; use; habitual activity; occupation, in
      general; practice.
      [1913 Webster]

            exercise of the important function confided by the
            constitution to the legislature.      --Jefferson.
      [1913 Webster]

            O we will walk this world,
            Yoked in all exercise of noble end.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Exertion for the sake of training or improvement whether
      physical, intellectual, or moral; practice to acquire
      skill, knowledge, virtue, perfectness, grace, etc.
      ``Desire of knightly exercise.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            An exercise of the eyes and memory.   --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Bodily exertion for the sake of keeping the organs and
      functions in a healthy state; hygienic activity; as, to
      take exercise on horseback; to exercise on a treadmill or
      in a gym.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            The wise for cure on exercise depend. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The performance of an office, a ceremony, or a religious
      duty.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lewis refused even those of the church of England .
            . . the public exercise of their religion.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            To draw him from his holy exercise.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is done for the sake of exercising, practicing,
      training, or promoting skill, health, mental, improvement,
      moral discipline, etc.; that which is assigned or
      prescribed for such ends; hence, a disquisition; a lesson;
      a task; as, military or naval exercises; musical
      exercises; an exercise in composition; arithmetic
      exercises.
      [1913 Webster]

            The clumsy exercises of the European tourney.
                                                  --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

            He seems to have taken a degree, and performed
            public exercises in Cambridge, in 1565. --Brydges.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That which gives practice; a trial; a test.
      [1913 Webster]

            Patience is more oft the exercise
            Of saints, the trial of their fortitude. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Exercise bone} (Med.), a deposit of bony matter in the soft
      tissues, produced by pressure or exertion.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exercise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exercise \Ex"er*cise\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Exercised}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Exercising}.]
   1. To set in action; to cause to act, move, or make exertion;
      to give employment to; to put in action habitually or
      constantly; to school or train; to exert repeatedly; to
      busy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Herein do I Exercise myself, to have always a
            conscience void of offence.           --Acts xxiv.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To exert for the sake of training or improvement; to
      practice in order to develop; hence, also, to improve by
      practice; to discipline, and to use or to for the purpose
      of training; as, to exercise arms; to exercise one's self
      in music; to exercise troops.
      [1913 Webster]

            About him exercised heroic games
            The unarmed youth.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To occupy the attention and effort of; to task; to tax,
      especially in a painful or vexatious manner; harass; to
      vex; to worry or make anxious; to affect; to discipline;
      as, exercised with pain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where pain of unextinguishable fire
            Must exercise us without hope of end. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To put in practice; to carry out in action; to perform the
      duties of; to use; to employ; to practice; as, to exercise
      authority; to exercise an office.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am the Lord which exercise loving-kindness,
            judgment, and righteousness in the earth. --Jer. ix.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

            The people of the land have used oppression and
            exercised robbery.                    --Ezek. xxii.
                                                  29.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exercise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exercise \Ex"er*cise\, v. i.
   To exercise one's self, as under military training; to drill;
   to take exercise; to use action or exertion; to practice
   gymnastics; as, to exercise for health or amusement.
   [1913 Webster]

         I wear my trusty sword,
         When I do exercise.                      --Cowper.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exercise</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exercise
     n 1: the activity of exerting your muscles in various ways to
          keep fit; "the doctor recommended regular exercise"; "he
          did some exercising"; "the physical exertion required by
          his work kept him fit" [syn: {exercising}, {physical
          exercise}, {physical exertion}, {workout}]
     2: the act of using; "he warned against the use of narcotic
        drugs"; "skilled in the utilization of computers" [syn: {use},
         {usage}, {utilization}, {utilisation}, {employment}]
     3: systematic training by multiple repetitions; "practice makes
        perfect" [syn: {practice}, {drill}, {practice session}, {recitation}]
     4: a task performed or problem solved in order to develop skill
        or understanding; "you must work the examples at the end
        of each chapter in the textbook" [syn: {example}]
     5: (usually plural) a ceremony that involves processions and
        speeches; "academic exercises"
     v 1: put to use; "exert one's power or influence" [syn: {exert}]
     2: carry out or practice; as of jobs and professions; "practice
        law" [syn: {practice}, {practise}, {do}]
     3: give a work-out to; "Some parents exercise their infants";
        "My personal trainer works me hard"; "work one's muscles"
        [syn: {work}, {work out}]
     4: do physical exercise; "She works out in the gym every day"
        [syn: {work out}]
     5: learn by repetition; "We drilled French verbs every day";
        "Pianists practice scales" [syn: {drill}, {practice}, {practise}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
