<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>exhaust</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exhaust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exhaust \Ex*haust"\, a. [L. exhaustus, p. p.]
   1. Drained; exhausted; having expended or lost its energy.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Pertaining to steam, air, gas, etc., that is released from
      the cylinder of an engine after having preformed its work.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Exhaust draught}, a forced draught produced by drawing air
      through a place, as through a furnace, instead of blowing
      it through.

   {Exhaust fan}, a fan blower so arranged as to produce an
      exhaust draught, or to draw air or gas out of a place, as
      out of a room in ventilating it.

   {Exhaust nozzle}, {Exhaust orifice} (Steam Engine), the blast
      orifice or nozzle.

   {Exhaust pipe} (Steam Engine), the pipe that conveys exhaust
      steam from the cylinder to the atmosphere or to the
      condenser.

   {Exhaust port} (Steam Engine), the opening, in the cylinder
      or valve, by which the exhaust steam escapes.

   {Exhaust purifier} (Milling), a machine for sorting grains,
      or purifying middlings by an exhaust draught. --Knight.

   {Exhaust steam} (Steam Engine), steam which is allowed to
      escape from the cylinder after having been employed to
      produce motion of the piston.

   {Exhaust valve} (Steam Engine), a valve that lets exhaust
      steam escape out of a cylinder.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exhaust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exhaust \Ex*haust"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Exhausted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Exhausting}.] [L. exhaustus, p. p. of exhaurire; ex
   out + haurire, haustum, to draw, esp. water; perhaps akin to
   Icel. asua to sprinkle, pump.]
   1. To draw or let out wholly; to drain off completely; as, to
      exhaust the water of a well; the moisture of the earth is
      exhausted by evaporation.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To empty by drawing or letting out the contents; as, to
      exhaust a well, or a treasury.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To drain, metaphorically; to use or expend wholly, or till
      the supply comes to an end; to deprive wholly of strength;
      to use up; to weary or tire out; to wear out; as, to
      exhaust one's strength, patience, or resources.
      [1913 Webster]

            A decrepit, exhausted old man at fifty-five.
                                                  --Motley.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To bring out or develop completely; to discuss thoroughly;
      as, to exhaust a subject.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Chem.) To subject to the action of various solvents in
      order to remove all soluble substances or extractives; as,
      to exhaust a drug successively with water, alcohol, and
      ether.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Exhausted receiver}. (Physics) See under {Receiver}.

   Syn: To spend; consume; tire out; weary.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exhaust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exhaust \Ex*haust"\, n. (Steam Engine)
   1. The steam let out of a cylinder after it has done its work
      there.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The foul air let out of a room through a register or pipe
      provided for the purpose.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exhaust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exhaust
     n 1: gases ejected from an engine as waste products [syn: {exhaust
          fumes}, {fumes}]
     2: system consisting of the parts of an engine through which
        burned gases or steam are discharged [syn: {exhaust system}]
     v 1: wear out completely; "This kind of work exhausts me"; "I'm
          beat"; "He was all washed up after the exam" [syn: {wash
          up}, {beat}, {tucker}, {tucker out}]
     2: use up (resources or materials); "this car consumes a lot of
        gas"; "We exhausted our savings"; "They run through 20
        bottles of wine a week" [syn: {consume}, {eat up}, {use up},
         {eat}, {deplete}, {run through}, {wipe out}]
     3: deplete; "exhaust one's savings"; "We quickly played out our
        strength" [syn: {run down}, {play out}, {sap}, {tire}]
     4: use up the whole supply of; "We have exhausted the food
        supplies"
     5: create a vacuum in (a bulb, flask, reaction vessel, etc.)
        [syn: {evacuate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
