<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>experience</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>experience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>EXPERIENCE, n.  The wisdom that enables us to recognize as an
undesirable old acquaintance the folly that we have already embraced.

    To one who, journeying through night and fog,
    Is mired neck-deep in an unwholesome bog,
    Experience, like the rising of the dawn,
    Reveals the path that he should not have gone.
                                                        Joel Frad Bink


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>experience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Experience \Ex*pe"ri*ence\ ([e^]ks*p[=e]"r[i^]*ens), n. [F.
   exp['e]rience, L. experientia, tr. experiens, experientis, p.
   pr. of experiri, expertus, to try; ex out + the root of
   peritus experienced. See {Peril}, and cf. {Expert}.]
   1. Trial, as a test or experiment. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            She caused him to make experience
            Upon wild beasts.                     --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The effect upon the judgment or feelings produced by any
      event, whether witnessed or participated in; personal and
      direct impressions as contrasted with description or
      fancies; personal acquaintance; actual enjoyment or
      suffering. ``Guided by other's experiences.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have but one lamp by which my feet are guided, and
            that is the lamp of experience.       --P. Henry
      [1913 Webster]

            To most men experience is like the stern lights of a
            ship, which illumine only the track it has passed.
                                                  --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the consuls . . . came in . . . they knew soon
            by experience how slenderly guarded against danger
            the majesty of rulers is where force is wanting.
                                                  --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those that undertook the religion of our Savior upon
            his preaching, had no experience of it. --Sharp.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An act of knowledge, one or more, by which single facts or
      general truths are ascertained; experimental or inductive
      knowledge; hence, implying skill, facility, or practical
      wisdom gained by personal knowledge, feeling or action;
      as, a king without experience of war.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whence hath the mind all the materials of reason and
            knowledge? To this I answer in one word, from
            experience.                           --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Experience may be acquired in two ways; either,
            first by noticing facts without any attempt to
            influence the frequency of their occurrence or to
            vary the circumstances under which they occur; this
            is observation; or, secondly, by putting in action
            causes or agents over which we have control, and
            purposely varying their combinations, and noticing
            what effects take place; this is experiment. --Sir
                                                  J. Herschel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>experience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Experience \Ex*pe"ri*ence\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Experienced}
   ([e^]ks*p[=e]"r[i^]*enst); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Experiencing}
   ([e^]ks*p[=e]"r[i^]*en*s[i^]ng).]
   1. To make practical acquaintance with; to try personally; to
      prove by use or trial; to have trial of; to have the lot
      or fortune of; to have befall one; to be affected by; to
      feel; as, to experience pain or pleasure; to experience
      poverty; to experience a change of views.
      [1913 Webster]

            The partial failure and disappointment which he had
            experienced in India.                 --Thirwall.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To exercise; to train by practice.
      [1913 Webster]

            The youthful sailors thus with early care
            Their arms experience, and for sea prepare. --Harte.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To experience religion} (Theol.), to become a convert to the
      doctrines of Christianity; to yield to the power of
      religious truth.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>experience</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>experience
     n 1: the accumulation of knowledge or skill that results from
          direct participation in events or activities; "a man of
          experience"; "experience is the best teacher" [ant: {inexperience}]
     2: the content of direct observation or participation in an
        event; "he had a religious experience"; "he recalled the
        experience vividly"
     3: an event as apprehended; "a surprising experience"; "that
        painful experience certainly got our attention"
     v 1: go or live through; "We had many trials to go through"; "he
          saw action in Viet Nam" [syn: {undergo}, {see}, {go
          through}]
     2: have firsthand knowledge of states, situations, emotions, or
        sensations; "I know the feeling!"; "have you ever known
        hunger?"; "I have lived a kind of hell when I was a drug
        addict"; "The holocaust survivors have lived a nightmare";
        "I lived through two divorces" [syn: {know}, {live}]
     3: of mental or physical states or experiences; "get an idea";
        "experience vertigo"; "get nauseous"; "undergo a strange
        sensation"; "The chemical undergoes a sudden change"; "The
        fluid undergoes shear"; "receive injuries"; "have a
        feeling" [syn: {receive}, {have}, {get}, {undergo}]
     4: undergo an emotional sensation; "She felt resentful"; "He
        felt regret" [syn: {feel}]
     5: undergo; "The stocks had a fast run-up" [syn: {have}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
