<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>explode</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>explode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Explode \Ex*plode"\, v. t.
   1. To drive from the stage by noisy expressions of
      disapprobation; to hoot off; to drive away or reject
      noisily; as, to explode a play. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Him old and young
            Exploded, and seized with violent hands. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring into disrepute, and reject; to drive from notice
      and acceptance; as, to explode a scheme, fashion, or
      doctrine.
      [1913 Webster]

            Old exploded contrivances of mercantile fraud.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

            To explode and exterminate dark atheism. --Bently.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to explode or burst noisily; to detonate; as, to
      explode powder by touching it with fire.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To drive out with violence and noise, as by powder.
      [1913 Webster]

            But late the kindled powder did explode
            The massy ball and the brass tube unload.
                                                  --Blackmore.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>explode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Explode \Ex*plode"\ ([e^]ks*pl[=o]d"), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Exploded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Exploding}.] [L. explodere,
   explosum, to drive out, drive out a player by clapping; ex
   out + plaudere, plodere, to clap, strike, applaud: cf. OF.
   exploder. See {Plausible}.]
   1. To become suddenly expanded into a great volume of gas or
      vapor; to burst violently into flame; as, gunpowder
      explodes.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To burst with force and a loud report; to detonate, as a
      shell filled with powder or the like material, or as a
      boiler from too great pressure of steam.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To burst forth with sudden violence and noise; as, at
      this, his wrath exploded.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>explode</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>explode
     v 1: cause to explode; "We exploded the nuclear bomb" [syn: {detonate},
           {blow up}, {set off}]
     2: burst outward, usually with noise; "The champagne bottle
        exploded" [syn: {burst}] [ant: {implode}]
     3: show a violent emotional reaction; "The boss exploded when
        he heard of the resignation of the secretary"
     4: be unleashed; burst forth with violence or noise; "His anger
        exploded" [syn: {burst forth}, {break loose}]
     5: destroy by exploding; "The enemy exploded the bridge"
     6: cause to burst as a result of air pressure; of stop
        consonants like /p/, /t/, and /k/
     7: drive from the stage by noisy disapproval
     8: show (a theory or claim) to be baseless, or refute and make
        obsolete
     9: increase rapidly and in an uncontrolled manner; "The
        population of India is exploding"; "The island's rodent
        population irrupted" [syn: {irrupt}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
