<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>exposure</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exposure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Exposure \Ex*po"sure\ (?;135), n. [From {Expose}.]
   1. The act of exposing or laying open, setting forth, laying
      bare of protection, depriving of care or concealment, or
      setting out to reprobation or contempt.
      [1913 Webster]

            The exposure of Fuller . . . put an end to the
            practices of that vile tribe.         --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being exposed or laid open or bare; openness
      to danger; accessibility to anything that may affect,
      especially detrimentally; as, exposure to observation, to
      cold, to inconvenience.
      [1913 Webster]

            When we have our naked frailties hid,
            That suffer in exposure.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Position as to points of compass, or to influences of
      climate, etc. ``Under a southern exposure.'' --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

            The best exposure of the two for woodcocks. --Sir.
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Photog.) The exposing of a sensitized plate to the action
      of light.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exposure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exposure
     n 1: vulnerability to the elements; to the action of heat or cold
          or wind or rain; "exposure to the weather" or "they died
          from exposure";
     2: the act of subjecting someone to an influencing experience;
        "she denounced the exposure of children to pornography"
     3: the disclosure of something secret; "they feared exposure of
        their campaign plans"
     4: aspect re light or wind; "the studio had a northern
        exposure"
     5: the state of being vulnerable or exposed; "his vulnerability
        to litigation"; "his exposure to ridicule" [syn: {vulnerability}]
     6: the intensity of light falling on a photographic film or
        plate; "he used the wrong exposure"
     7: a picture of a person or scene in the form of a print or
        transparent slide; recorded by a camera on light-sensitive
        material [syn: {photograph}, {photo}, {pic}]
     8: the act of exposing film to light
     9: presentation to view in an open or public manner; "the
        exposure of his anger was shocking"
     10: abandoning without shelter or protection (as by leaving as
         infant out in the open)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
