<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>expose</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>expose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Expos'e \Ex`po`s['e]"\, n. [F., prop. p. p. of exposer. See
   {Expose}, v. t.]
   A formal recital or exposition of facts; exposure, or
   revelation, of something which some one wished to keep
   concealed.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>expose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Expose \Ex*pose"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Exposed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Exposing}.] [F. exposer; pref. ex- (L. ex out)+poser to
   place. See {Pose}, v. t.]
   1. To set forth; to set out to public view; to exhibit; to
      show; to display; as, to expose goods for sale; to expose
      pictures to public inspection.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those who seek truth only, freely expose their
            principles to the test, and are pleased to have them
            examined.                             --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay bare; to lay open to attack, danger, or anything
      objectionable; to render accessible to anything which may
      affect, especially detrimentally; to make liable; as, to
      expose one's self to the heat of the sun, or to cold,
      insult, danger, or ridicule; to expose an army to
      destruction or defeat.
      [1913 Webster]

            Expose thyself to feel what wretches feel. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To deprive of concealment; to discover; to lay open to
      public inspection, or bring to public notice, as a thing
      that shuns publicity, something criminal, shameful, or the
      like; as, to expose the faults of a neighbor.
      [1913 Webster]

            You only expose the follies of men, without
            arraigning their vices.               --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To disclose the faults or reprehensible practices of; to
      lay open to general condemnation or contempt by making
      public the character or arts of; as, to expose a cheat,
      liar, or hypocrite.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>expose</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>expose
     n : the exposure of an impostor or a fraud; "he published an
         expose of the graft and corruption in city government"
         [syn: {unmasking}]
     v 1: expose or make accessible to some action or influence;
          "Expose your students to art"; "expose the blanket to
          sunshine"
     2: make known to the public information that was previously
        known only to a few people or that was meant to be kept a
        secret; "The auction house would not disclose the price at
        which the van Gogh had sold"; "The actress won't reveal
        how old she is"; "bring out the truth"; "he broke the news
        to her" [syn: {disclose}, {let on}, {bring out}, {reveal},
         {discover}, {divulge}, {impart}, {break}, {give away}, {let
        out}]
     3: to show, make visible or apparent; "The Metropolitan Museum
        is exhibiting Goya's works this month"; "Why don't you
        show your nice legs and wear shorter skirts?"; "National
        leaders will have to display the highest skills of
        statesmanship" [syn: {exhibit}, {display}]
     4: remove all or part of one's clothes to show one's body;
        "uncover your belly"; "The man exposed himself in the
        subway" [syn: {uncover}] [ant: {cover}]
     5: disclose to view as by removing a cover; "The curtain rose
        to disclose a stunning set" [syn: {disclose}]
     6: put in a dangerous, disadvantageous, or difficult position
        [syn: {queer}, {scupper}, {endanger}, {peril}]
     7: expose to light, of photographic film
     8: expose while ridiculing; especially of pretentious or false
        claims and ideas; "The physicist debunked the psychic's
        claims" [syn: {debunk}]
     9: abandon by leaving out in the open air; "The infant was
        exposed by the teenage mother"; "After Christmas, many
        pets get abandoned"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
