<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>exposed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exposed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Expose \Ex*pose"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Exposed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Exposing}.] [F. exposer; pref. ex- (L. ex out)+poser to
   place. See {Pose}, v. t.]
   1. To set forth; to set out to public view; to exhibit; to
      show; to display; as, to expose goods for sale; to expose
      pictures to public inspection.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those who seek truth only, freely expose their
            principles to the test, and are pleased to have them
            examined.                             --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay bare; to lay open to attack, danger, or anything
      objectionable; to render accessible to anything which may
      affect, especially detrimentally; to make liable; as, to
      expose one's self to the heat of the sun, or to cold,
      insult, danger, or ridicule; to expose an army to
      destruction or defeat.
      [1913 Webster]

            Expose thyself to feel what wretches feel. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To deprive of concealment; to discover; to lay open to
      public inspection, or bring to public notice, as a thing
      that shuns publicity, something criminal, shameful, or the
      like; as, to expose the faults of a neighbor.
      [1913 Webster]

            You only expose the follies of men, without
            arraigning their vices.               --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To disclose the faults or reprehensible practices of; to
      lay open to general condemnation or contempt by making
      public the character or arts of; as, to expose a cheat,
      liar, or hypocrite.
      [1913 Webster] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exposed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exposed \exposed\ adj.
   1. with no protection or shield; as, the exposed northeast
      frontier.

   Syn: open.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. visible due to absence of clothing at that point; -- of
      body parts.

   Syn: uncovered, bare.
        [WordNet 1.5 +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>exposed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>exposed
     adj 1: with no protection or shield; "the exposed northeast
            frontier"; "open to the weather"; "an open wound"
            [syn: {open}]
     2: not covered with clothing; "her exposed breast" [syn: {uncovered}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
