<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>express</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>express</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Express
     
        1. A language supporting {concurrency} through {message
        passing} to named message queues from {ParaSoft} Corporation
     
        {(ftp://ftp.parasoft.com/express/docs)}.
     
        2. Data definition language, meant to become an ISO standard
        for product data representation and exchange.  TC 184/SC4 N83,
        ISO, 1991-05-31.  E-mail: &lt;smith@cme.nist.gov&gt;.
     
        3. A data modelling language adopted by the {ISO} working
        group on {STEP}.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>express</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Express \Ex*press"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Expressed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Expressing}.] [Cf. OF. espresser, expresser, L.
   exprimere, expressum. See {Express}, a.; cf. {Sprain}.]
   1. To press or squeeze out; as, to express the juice of
      grapes, or of apples; hence, to extort; to elicit.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the fruits out of which drink is expressed.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            And th'idle breath all utterly expressed. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Halters and racks can not express from thee
            More than by deeds.                   --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make or offer a representation of; to show by a copy or
      likeness; to represent; to resemble.
      [1913 Webster]

            Each skillful artist shall express thy form. --E.
                                                  Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

            So kids and whelps their sires and dams express.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give a true impression of; to represent and make known;
      to manifest plainly; to show in general; to exhibit, as an
      opinion or feeling, by a look, gesture, and esp. by
      language; to declare; to utter; to tell.
      [1913 Webster]

            My words express my purpose.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            They expressed in their lives those excellent
            doctrines of morality.                --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To make known the opinions or feelings of; to declare what
      is in the mind of; to show (one's self); to cause to
      appear; -- used reflexively.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mr. Phillips did express with much indignation
            against me, one evening.              --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To denote; to designate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Moses and Aaron took these men, which are expressed
            by their names.                       --Num. i. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To send by express messenger; to forward by special
      opportunity, or through the medium of an express; as, to
      express a package.

   7. (Genetics) to produce products that cause the appearance
      of the corresponding phenotype; -- of a gene or of an
      organism with a specific gene; as, to express the
      beta-galactosidase gene,
      [PJC]

   Syn: To declare; utter; signify; testify; intimate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>express</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Express \Ex*press"\, n. [Cf. F. expr[`e]s a messenger.]
   1. A clear image or representation; an expression; a plain
      declaration. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The only remanent express of Christ's sacrifice on
            earth.                                --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A messenger sent on a special errand; a courier; hence, a
      regular and fast conveyance; commonly, a company or system
      for the prompt and safe transportation of merchandise or
      parcels.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An express office.
      [1913 Webster]

            She charged him . . . to ask at the express if
            anything came up from town.           --E. E. Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is sent by an express messenger or message.
      [Obs.] --Eikon Basilike.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. a railway train or bus for transporting passengers or
      goods with speed and punctuality; a train or bus that does
      not stop at certain stations. Contrasted to {local}; as,
      take the express to get there faster.

   Syn: express train. [PJC]

   {Express office}, an office where packages for an express are
      received or delivered.

   {Express train}, a railway train (such as a subway train)
      that does not stop at certain stations, but only at
      stations designated express stops.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>express</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Express \Ex*press"\ ([e^]ks*pr[e^]s"), a. [F. expr[`e]s, L.
   expressus, p. p. of exprimere to express; ex. out + premere
   To press. See {Press}.]
   1. Exactly representing; exact.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their human countenance
            The express resemblance of the gods.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Directly and distinctly stated; declared in terms; not
      implied or left to inference; made unambiguous by
      intention and care; clear; not dubious; as, express
      consent; an express statement.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have express commandment.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Intended for a particular purpose; relating to an express;
      sent on a particular errand; dispatched with special
      speed; as, an express messenger or train. Also used
      adverbially.
      [1913 Webster]

            A messenger sent express from the other world.
                                                  --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. of or pertaining to an {express train} or other conveyance
      designated an express[5]; makiung few or no intermediate
      stops; as, an express stop; an express fare; an express
      elevator.
      [PJC]

   {Express color}. (Law) See the Note under {Color}, n., 8.

   Syn: Explicit; clear; unambiguous. See {Explicit}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>express</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>express
     adj 1: not tacit or implied; "her express wish"
     2: without unnecessary stops; "an express train"; "an express
        shipment"
     n 1: rapid transport of goods [syn: {expressage}]
     2: mail that is distributed by a rapid and efficient system
        [syn: {express mail}]
     3: public transport consisting of a fast train or bus that
        makes a limited number of scheduled stops; "he caught the
        express to New York" [ant: {local}]
     adv : by express; "please send the letter express"
     v 1: give expression to; "She showed her disappointment" [syn: {show},
           {evince}]
     2: articulate; either verbally or with a cry, shout, or noise;
        "She expressed her anger"; "He uttered a curse" [syn: {verbalize},
         {verbalise}, {utter}, {give tongue to}]
     3: indicate through a symbol, formula, etc.; "Can you express
        this distance in kilometers?" [syn: {state}]
     4: serve as a means for expressing something; "The painting of
        Mary carries motherly love"; "His voice carried a lot af
        anger" [syn: {carry}, {convey}]
     5: manifest the effects of (a gene or genetic trait); "Many of
        the laboratory animals express the trait"
     6: obtain from a substance, as by mechanical action; "Italians
        express coffee rather than filter it" [syn: {press out}, {extract}]
     7: send my rapid transport or special messenger service; "She
        expressed the letter to Florida"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
