<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>extract</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>extract</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Extract \Ex"tract`\, n.
   1. That which is extracted or drawn out.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A portion of a book or document, separately transcribed; a
      citation; a quotation.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A decoction, solution, or infusion made by dissolving out
      from any substance that which gives it its essential and
      characteristic virtue; essence; as, extract of beef;
      extract of dandelion; also, any substance so extracted,
      and characteristic of that from which it is obtained; as,
      quinine is the most important extract of Peruvian bark.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Med.) A solid preparation obtained by evaporating a
      solution of a drug, etc., or the fresh juice of a plant;
      -- distinguished from an abstract. See {Abstract}, n., 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Old Chem.) A peculiar principle once erroneously supposed
      to form the basis of all vegetable extracts; -- called
      also the {extractive principle}. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Extraction; descent. [Obs.] --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Scots Law) A draught or copy of writing; certified copy
      of the proceedings in an action and the judgement therein,
      with an order for execution. --Tomlins.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fluid extract} (Med.), a concentrated liquid preparation,
      containing a definite proportion of the active principles
      of a medicinal substance. At present a fluid gram of
      extract should represent a gram of the crude drug.
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>extract</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Extract \Ex*tract"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Extracted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Extracting}.] [L. extractus, p. p. of extrahere to
   extract; ex out + trahere to draw. See {Trace}, and cf.
   {Estreat}.]
   1. To draw out or forth; to pull out; to remove forcibly from
      a fixed position, as by traction or suction, etc.; as, to
      extract a tooth from its socket, a stump from the earth, a
      splinter from the finger.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bee
            Sits on the bloom extracting liquid sweet. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To withdraw by expression, distillation, or other
      mechanical or chemical process; as, to extract an essence.
      Cf. {Abstract}, v. t., 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sunbeams may be extracted from cucumbers, but the
            process is tedious.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To take by selection; to choose out; to cite or quote, as
      a passage from a book.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have extracted out of that pamphlet a few
            notorious falsehoods.                 --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To extract the root} (Math.), to ascertain the root of a
      number or quantity.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>extract</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>extract
     n 1: a solution obtained by steeping or soaking a substance
          (usually in water) [syn: {infusion}]
     2: a passage selected from a larger work; "he presented
        excerpts from William James' philosophical writings" [syn:
         {excerpt}, {selection}]
     v 1: draw or pull out, usually with some force or effort; also
          used in an abstract sense; "pull weeds"; "extract a bad
          tooth"; "take out a splinter"; "extract information from
          the telegram" [syn: {pull out}, {pull}, {pull up}, {take
          out}, {draw out}]
     2: get despite difficulties or obstacles; "I extracted a
        promise from the Dean for two ne positions"
     3: deduce (a principle) or construe (a meaning); "We drew out
        some interesting linguistic data from the native
        informant" [syn: {educe}, {evoke}, {elicit}, {draw out}]
     4: extract by the process of distillation; "distill the essence
        of this compound" [syn: {distill}, {distil}]
     5: separate (a metal) from an ore
     6: obtain from a substance, as by mechanical action; "Italians
        express coffee rather than filter it" [syn: {press out}, {express}]
     7: take out of a literary work in order to cite or copy [syn: {excerpt},
         {take out}]
     8: calculate the root of a number
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
