<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>p</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>p</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>P+
     
        ["Experience with Remote Procedure Calls in a Real-Time
        Control System", B. Carpenter et al, Soft Prac &amp; Exp
        14(9):901-907 (Sep 1984)].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>p</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>P \P\ (p[=e]),
   the sixteenth letter of the English alphabet, is a nonvocal
   consonant whose form and value come from the Latin, into
   which language the letter was brought, through the ancient
   Greek, from the Ph[oe]nician, its probable origin being
   Egyptian. Etymologically P is most closely related to b, f,
   and v; as hobble, hopple; father, paternal; recipient,
   receive. See {B}, {F}, and {M}.
   [1913 Webster] See Guide to Pronunciation, [sect][sect] 247,
   248, and 184-195.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>p</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Labial \La"bi*al\, n.
   1. (Phonetics) A letter or character representing an
      articulation or sound formed or uttered chiefly with the
      lips, as {b}, {p}, {w}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mus.) An organ pipe that is furnished with lips; a flue
      pipe.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) One of the scales which border the mouth of a
      fish or reptile.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>p</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mute \Mute\, n.
   1. One who does not speak, whether from physical inability,
      unwillingness, or other cause. Specifically:
      (a) One who, from deafness, either congenital or from
          early life, is unable to use articulate language; a
          deaf-mute.
      (b) A person employed by undertakers at a funeral.
      (c) A person whose part in a play does not require him to
          speak.
      (d) Among the Turks, an officer or attendant who is
          selected for his place because he can not speak.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. (Phon.) A letter which represents no sound; a silent
      letter; also, a close articulation; an element of speech
      formed by a position of the mouth organs which stops the
      passage of the breath; as, {p}, {b}, {d}, {k}, {t}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.) A little utensil made of brass, ivory, or other
      material, so formed that it can be fixed in an erect
      position on the bridge of a violin, or similar instrument,
      in order to deaden or soften the tone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>p</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>P
     n 1: a multivalent nonmetallic element of the nitrogen family
          that occurs commonly in inorganic phosphate rocks and as
          organic phosphates in all living cells; is highly
          reactive and occurs in several allotropic forms [syn: {phosphorus},
           {atomic number 15}]
     2: the 16th letter of the Roman alphabet
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
