<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>packed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>packed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pack \Pack\ (p[a^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Packed} (p[a^]kt); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Packing}.] [Akin to D. pakken, G. packen, Dan.
   pakke, Sw. packa, Icel. pakka. See {Pack}, n.]
   1. To make a pack of; to arrange closely and securely in a
      pack; hence, to place and arrange compactly as in a pack;
      to press into close order or narrow compass; as, to pack
      goods in a box; to pack fish.
      [1913 Webster]

            Strange materials packed up with wonderful art.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where . . . the bones
            Of all my buried ancestors are packed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fill in the manner of a pack, that is, compactly and
      securely, as for transportation; hence, to fill closely or
      to repletion; to stow away within; to cause to be full; to
      crowd into; as, to pack a trunk; the play, or the
      audience, packs the theater.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To shuffle, sort and arrange (the cards) in a pack so as
      to secure the game unfairly; to stack[3] (the deck).
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            And mighty dukes pack cards for half a crown.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence: To bring together or make up unfairly and
      fraudulently, in order to secure a certain result; to
      stack[3]; as, to pack a jury or a caucus.
      [1913 Webster]

            The expected council was dwindling into . . . a
            packed assembly of Italian bishops.   --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To contrive unfairly or fraudulently; to plot. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He lost life . . . upon a nice point subtilely
            devised and packed by his enemies.    --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To load with a pack; hence, to load; to encumber; as, to
      pack a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our thighs packed with wax, our mouths with honey.
                                                  --Shack.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cause to go; to send away with baggage or belongings;
      esp., to send away peremptorily or suddenly; to {send
      packing}; -- sometimes with off; as, to pack a boy off to
      school.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . must not die
            Till George be packed with post horse up to heaven.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To transport in a pack, or in the manner of a pack (i. e.,
      on the backs of men or beasts). [Western U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Hydropathy) To envelop in a wet or dry sheet, within
      numerous coverings. See {Pack}, n., 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mech.) To render impervious, as by filling or
       surrounding with suitable material, or to fit or adjust
       so as to move without giving passage to air, water, or
       steam; as, to pack a joint; to pack the piston of a steam
       engine.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To cover, envelop, or protect tightly with something;
       specif. (Hydropathy), to envelop in a wet or dry sheet,
       within numerous coverings.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>packed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>packed \packed\ adj.
   1. Same as {jammed}.

   Syn: full, jammed, jam-packed.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. Crowded; as, the theater was packed.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>packed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>packed
     adj 1: filled to capacity; "a suitcase jammed with dirty clothes";
            "stands jam-packed with fans"; "a packed theater"
            [syn: {jammed}, {jam-pawncked}]
     2: pressed together or compressed; "packed snow"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
