<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>paddle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paddle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paddle
     
        A language for transformations leading from specification to
        program.  Used in the {POPART} programming environment
        generator.
     
        (1994-11-30)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paddle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paddle \Pad"dle\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Paddled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Paddling}]
   1. To pat or stroke amorously, or gently. [Obsolescent]
      [1913 Webster]

            To be paddling palms and pinching fingers. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To propel with, or as with, a paddle or paddles.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To pad; to tread upon; to trample. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To spank with a paddle or as if with a paddle; -- usually
      as a disciplinary punishment of children.
      [PJC]

   5. To mix (a viscous liquid) by stirring or beating with a
      paddle.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paddle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paddle \Pad"dle\, v. i. [Prob. for pattle, and a dim. of pat,
   v.; cf. also E. pad to tread, Prov. G. paddeln, padden, to
   walk with short steps, to paddle, G. patschen to splash,
   dash, dabble, F. patouiller to dabble, splash, fr. patte a
   paw. [root]21.]
   1. To use the hands or fingers in toying; to make caressing
      strokes. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To dabble in water with hands or feet; to use a paddle, or
      something which serves as a paddle, in swimming, in
      paddling a boat, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            As the men were paddling for their lives.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            While paddling ducks the standing lake desire.
                                                  --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paddle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paddle \Pad"dle\, n. [See {Paddle}, v. i.]
   1. An implement with a broad blade, which is used without a
      fixed fulcrum in propelling and steering canoes and boats.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The broad part of a paddle, with which the stroke is made;
      hence, any short, broad blade, resembling that of a
      paddle, such as that used in table tennis.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt have a paddle upon thy weapon. --Deut.
                                                  xxiii. 13.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One of the broad boards, or floats, at the circumference
      of a water wheel, or paddle wheel.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A small gate in sluices or lock gates to admit or let off
      water; -- also called {clough}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Zo["o]l.) A paddle-shaped foot, as of the sea turtle.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A paddle-shaped implement for stirring or mixing.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. [In this sense prob. for older spaddle, a dim. of spade.]
      See {Paddle staff} (b), below. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Paddle beam} (Shipbuilding), one of two large timbers
      supporting the spring beam and paddle box of a steam
      vessel.

   {Paddle board}. See {Paddle}, n., 3.

   {Paddle shaft}, the revolving shaft which carries the paddle
      wheel of a steam vessel.

   {Paddle staff}.
      (a) A staff tipped with a broad blade, used by mole
          catchers. [Prov. Eng.]
      (b) A long-handled spade used to clean a plowshare; --
          called also {plow staff}. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Paddle steamer}, a steam vessel propelled by paddle wheels,
      in distinction from a screw propeller.

   {Paddle wheel}, the propelling wheel of a steam vessel,
      having paddles (or floats) on its circumference, and
      revolving in a vertical plane parallel to the vessel's
      length.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paddle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paddle
     n 1: small wooden bat with a flat surface; used for hitting balls
          in various games
     2: a blade of a paddle wheel or water wheel
     3: an instrument of punishment consisting of a flat board
     4: a short light oar used without an oarlock to propel a canoe
        or small boat [syn: {boat paddle}]
     v 1: propel with a paddle; "paddle your own canoe"
     2: play in or as if in water, as of small children [syn: {dabble},
         {splash around}]
     3: swim like a dog in shallow water
     4: walk unsteadily; "small children toddle" [syn: {toddle}, {coggle},
         {totter}, {dodder}, {waddle}]
     5: give a spanking to; subject to a spanking [syn: {spank}, {larrup}]
     6: stir with a paddle
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
