<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>paging</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paging
     
        &lt;operating system&gt; A technique for increasing the memory space
        available by moving infrequently-used parts of a program's
        working memory from {RAM} to a secondary storage medium,
        usually disk.  The unit of transfer is called a page.
     
        A {memory management unit} (MMU) monitors accesses to memory
        and splits each address into a page number (the most
        significant bits) and an offset within that page (the lower
        bits).  It then looks up the page number in its page table.
        The page may be marked as paged in or paged out.  If it is
        paged in then the memory access can proceed after translating
        the {virtual address} to a {physical address}.  If the
        requested page is paged out then space must be made for it by
        paging out some other page, i.e. copying it to disk.  The
        requested page is then located on the area of the disk
        allocated for "{swap space}" and is read back into {RAM}.  The
        page table is updated to indicate that the page is paged in
        and its physical address recorded.
     
        The MMU also records whether a page has been modified since it
        was last paged in.  If it has not been modified then there is
        no need to copy it back to disk and the space can be reused
        immediately.
     
        Paging allows the total memory requirements of all running
        tasks (possibly just one) to exceed the amount of {physical
        memory}, whereas {swapping} simply allows multiple processes
        to run concurrently, so long as each process on its own fits
        within {physical memory}.
     
        (1996-11-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Page \Page\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Paged} (p[=a]jd); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Paging} (p[=a]"j[i^]ng).]
   To mark or number the pages of, as a book or manuscript; to
   furnish with folios.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paging \Pa"ging\, n.
   The marking or numbering of the pages of a book.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paging</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paging
     n 1: calling out the name of a person (especially by a
          loudspeaker system); "the public address system in the
          hospital was used for paging"
     2: the system of numbering pages [syn: {pagination}, {folio}, {page
        number}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
