<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>painting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>painting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PAINTING, n.  The art of protecting flat surfaces from the weather and
exposing them to the critic.
    Formerly, painting and sculpture were combined in the same work: 
the ancients painted their statues.  The only present alliance between
the two arts is that the modern painter chisels his patrons.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>painting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paint \Paint\ (p[=a]nt), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Painted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Painting}.] [OE. peinten, fr. F. peint, p. p. of
   peindre to paint, fr. L. pingere, pictum; cf. Gr. poiki`los
   many-colored, Skr. pi[,c] to adorn. Cf. {Depict}, {Picture},
   {Pigment}, {Pint}.]
   1. To cover with coloring matter; to apply paint to; as, to
      paint a house, a signboard, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jezebel painted her face and tired her head. --2
                                                  Kings ix. 30.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: To color, stain, or tinge; to adorn or beautify with
      colors; to diversify with colors.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not painted with the crimson spots of blood. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cuckoo buds of yellow hue
            Do paint the meadows with delight.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To form in colors a figure or likeness of on a flat
      surface, as upon canvas; to represent by means of colors
      or hues; to exhibit in a tinted image; to portray with
      paints; as, to paint a portrait or a landscape.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Fig.: To represent or exhibit to the mind; to describe
      vividly; to delineate; to image; to depict; as, to paint a
      political opponent as a traitor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Disloyal?
            The word is too good to paint out her wickedness.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If folly grow romantic, I must paint it. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To color; picture; depict; portray; delineate; sketch;
        draw; describe.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>painting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Painting \Paint"ing\, n.
   1. The act or employment of laying on, or adorning with,
      paints or colors.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Fine Arts) The work of the painter; also, any work of art
      in which objects are represented in color on a flat
      surface; a colored representation of any object or scene;
      a picture.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Color laid on; paint. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A depicting by words; vivid representation in words.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See {Picture}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>painting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>painting
     n 1: graphic art consisting of an artistic composition made by
          applying paints to a surface; "a small painting by
          Picasso"; "he bought the painting as an investment";
          "his pictures hang in the Louvre" [syn: {picture}]
     2: creating a picture with paints; "he studied painting and
        sculpture for many years"
     3: the act of applying paint to a surface; "you can finish the
        job of painting faster with a roller than with a brush"
     4: the occupation of a house painter; "house painting was the
        only craft he knew" [syn: {house painting}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
