<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>palace</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PALACE, n.  A fine and costly residence, particularly that of a great
official.  The residence of a high dignitary of the Christian Church
is called a palace; that of the Founder of his religion was known as a
field, or wayside.  There is progress.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Palace
   Used now only of royal dwellings, although originally meaning
   simply (as the Latin word palatium, from which it is derived,
   shows) a building surrounded by a fence or a paling. In the
   Authorized Version there are many different words so rendered,
   presenting different ideas, such as that of citadel or lofty
   fortress or royal residence (Neh. 1:1; Dan. 8:2). It is the name
   given to the temple fortress (Neh. 2:8) and to the temple itself
   (1 Chr. 29:1). It denotes also a spacious building or a great
   house (Dan. 1:4; 4:4, 29: Esther 1:5; 7:7), and a fortified
   place or an enclosure (Ezek. 25:4). Solomon's palace is
   described in 1 Kings 7:1-12 as a series of buildings rather than
   a single great structure. Thirteen years were spent in their
   erection. This palace stood on the eastern hill, adjoining the
   temple on the south.
   
     In the New Testament it designates the official residence of
   Pilate or that of the high priest (Matt. 26:3, 58, 69; Mark
   14:54, 66; John 18:15). In Phil. 1:13 this word is the rendering
   of the Greek praitorion, meaning the praetorian cohorts at Rome
   (the life-guard of the Caesars). Paul was continually chained to
   a soldier of that corps (Acts 28:16), and hence his name and
   sufferings became known in all the praetorium. The "soldiers
   that kept" him would, on relieving one another on guard,
   naturally spread the tidings regarding him among their comrades.
   Some, however, regard the praetroium (q.v.) as the barrack
   within the palace (the palatium) of the Caesars in Rome where a
   detachment of these praetorian guards was stationed, or as the
   camp of the guards placed outside the eastern walls of Rome.
   
     "In the chambers which were occupied as guard-rooms," says Dr.
   Manning, "by the praetorian troops on duty in the palace, a
   number of rude caricatures are found roughly scratched upon the
   walls, just such as may be seen upon barrack walls in every part
   of the world. Amongst these is one of a human figure nailed upon
   a cross. To add to the 'offence of the cross,' the crucified one
   is represented with the head of an animal, probably that of an
   ass. Before it stands the figure of a Roman legionary with one
   hand upraised in the attitude of worship. Underneath is the
   rude, misspelt, ungrammatical inscription, Alexamenos worships
   his god. It can scarcely be doubted that we have here a
   contemporary caricature, executed by one of the praetorian
   guard, ridiculing the faith of a Christian comrade."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Palace
     
        &lt;virtual reality, chat&gt; A proprietary multi-user {virtual
        reality}-like {talk} system.
     
        The Palace is distinguished from most other VR-like systems in
        that it is only two-dimensional rather than three; rooms,
        {avatars}, and "props" are made up of relatively small 2D
        {bitmap} images.
     
        Palace is a crude {hack}, or lightweight, depending on
        your point of view.
     
        {Home (http://www.thepalace.com/)}.
     
        (1997-09-14)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Palace \Pal"ace\ (p[a^]l"[asl]s; 48), n. [OE. palais, F. palais,
   fr. L. palatium, fr. Palatium, one of the seven hills of
   Rome, on which Augustus had his residence. Cf. {Paladin}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The residence of a sovereign, including the lodgings of
      high officers of state, and rooms for business, as well as
      halls for ceremony and reception. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The official residence of a bishop or other distinguished
      personage.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Loosely, any unusually magnificent or stately house.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Palace car}. See under {Car}.

   {Palace court}, a court having jurisdiction of personal
      actions arising within twelve miles of the palace at
      Whitehall. The court was abolished in 1849. [Eng.]
      --Mozley &amp; W.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palace</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>palace
     n 1: a large and stately mansion [syn: {castle}]
     2: the governing group of a kingdom; "the palace issued an
        order binding on all subjects"
     3: a large ornate exhibition hall
     4: official residence of an exalted person (as a sovereign)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
