<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pale</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ordinary \Or"di*na*ry\, n.; pl. {Ordinaries} (-r[i^]z).
   1. (Law)
      (a) (Roman Law) An officer who has original jurisdiction
          in his own right, and not by deputation.
      (b) (Eng. Law) One who has immediate jurisdiction in
          matters ecclesiastical; an ecclesiastical judge; also,
          a deputy of the bishop, or a clergyman appointed to
          perform divine service for condemned criminals and
          assist in preparing them for death.
      (c) (Am. Law) A judicial officer, having generally the
          powers of a judge of probate or a surrogate.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. The mass; the common run. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I see no more in you than in the ordinary
            Of nature's salework.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is so common, or continued, as to be considered
      a settled establishment or institution. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Spain had no other wars save those which were grown
            into an ordinary.                     --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything which is in ordinary or common use.
      [1913 Webster]

            Water buckets, wagons, cart wheels, plow socks, and
            other ordinaries.                     --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A dining room or eating house where a meal is prepared for
      all comers, at a fixed price for the meal, in distinction
      from one where each dish is separately charged; a table
      d'h[^o]te; hence, also, the meal furnished at such a
      dining room. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the odd words they have picked up in a
            coffeehouse, or a gaming ordinary, are produced as
            flowers of style.                     --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

            He exacted a tribute for licenses to hawkers and
            peddlers and to ordinaries.           --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Her.) A charge or bearing of simple form, one of nine or
      ten which are in constant use. The {bend}, {chevron},
      {chief}, {cross}, {fesse}, {pale}, and {saltire} are
      uniformly admitted as ordinaries. Some authorities include
      bar, bend sinister, pile, and others. See {Subordinary}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {In ordinary}.
      (a) In actual and constant service; statedly attending and
          serving; as, a physician or chaplain in ordinary. An
          ambassador in ordinary is one constantly resident at a
          foreign court.
      (b) (Naut.) Out of commission and laid up; -- said of a
          naval vessel.

   {Ordinary of the Mass} (R. C. Ch.), the part of the Mass
      which is the same every day; -- called also the {canon of
      the Mass}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pale \Pale\ (p[=a]l), a. [Compar. {Paler} (p[=a]l"[~e]r);
   superl. {Palest}.] [F. p[^a]le, fr. p[^a]lir to turn pale, L.
   pallere to be or look pale. Cf. {Appall}, {Fallow}, {pall},
   v. i., {Pallid}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Wanting in color; not ruddy; dusky white; pallid; wan; as,
      a pale face; a pale red; a pale blue. ``Pale as a forpined
      ghost.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Speechless he stood and pale.         --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            They are not of complexion red or pale. --T.
                                                  Randolph.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Not bright or brilliant; of a faint luster or hue; dim;
      as, the pale light of the moon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The night, methinks, is but the daylight sick;
            It looks a little paler.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Pale is often used in the formation of self-explaining
         compounds; as, pale-colored, pale-eyed, pale-faced,
         pale-looking, etc.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pale \Pale\, v. t.
   To inclose with pales, or as with pales; to encircle; to
   encompass; to fence off.
   [1913 Webster]

         [Your isle, which stands] ribbed and paled in
         With rocks unscalable and roaring waters. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pale \Pale\, n.
   Paleness; pallor. [R.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pale \Pale\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Paled} (p[=a]ld); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Paling}.]
   To turn pale; to lose color or luster. --Whittier.
   [1913 Webster]

         Apt to pale at a trodden worm.           --Mrs.
                                                  Browning.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pale \Pale\, v. t.
   To make pale; to diminish the brightness of.
   [1913 Webster]

         The glowworm shows the matin to be near,
         And 'gins to pale his uneffectual fire.  --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pale \Pale\, n. [F. pal, fr. L. palus: cf. D. paal. See {Pole} a
   stake, and 1st {Pallet}.]
   1. A pointed stake or slat, either driven into the ground, or
      fastened to a rail at the top and bottom, for fencing or
      inclosing; a picket.
      [1913 Webster]

            Deer creep through when a pale tumbles down.
                                                  --Mortimer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which incloses or fences in; a boundary; a limit; a
      fence; a palisade. ``Within one pale or hedge.''
      --Robynson (More's Utopia).
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A space or field having bounds or limits; a limited region
      or place; an inclosure; -- often used figuratively. ``To
      walk the studious cloister's pale.'' --Milton. ``Out of
      the pale of civilization.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence: A region within specified bounds, whether or not
      enclosed or demarcated.
      [PJC]

   5. A stripe or band, as on a garment. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Her.) One of the greater ordinaries, being a broad
      perpendicular stripe in an escutcheon, equally distant
      from the two edges, and occupying one third of it.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A cheese scoop. --Simmonds.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Shipbuilding) A shore for bracing a timber before it is
      fastened.
      [1913 Webster]

   {English pale}, {Irish pale} (Hist.), the limits or territory
      in Eastern Ireland within which alone the English
      conquerors of Ireland held dominion for a long period
      after their invasion of the country by Henry II in 1172.
      See note, below.

   {beyond the pale} outside the limits of what is allowed or
      proper; also, outside the limits within which one is
      protected. --Spencer.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: The English Pale. That part of Ireland in which English
         law was acknowledged, and within which the dominion of
         the English was restricted, for some centuries after
         the conquests of Henry II. John distributed the part of
         Ireland then subject to England into 12 counties
         palatine, and this region became subsequently known as
         the Pale, but the limits varied at different times.
         [Century Dict., 1906]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pale</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pale
     adj 1: very light colored; highly diluted with white; "pale
            seagreen"; "pale blue eyes"
     2: (of light) lacking in intensity or brightness; dim or
        feeble; "the pale light of a half moon"; "a pale sun";
        "the late afternoon light coming through the el tracks
        fell in pale oblongs on the street"; "a pallid sky"; "the
        pale (or wan) stars"; "the wan light of dawn" [syn: {pallid},
         {wan}]
     3: lacking in vitality or interest or effectiveness; "a pale
        rendition of the aria"; "pale prose with the faint
        sweetness of lavender"; "a pallid performance" [syn: {pallid}]
     4: abnormally deficient in color as suggesting physical or
        emotional distress; "the pallid face of the invalid"; "her
        wan face suddenly flushed" [syn: {pallid}, {wan}]
     5: not full or rich; "high, pale, pure and lovely song"
     n : a wooden strip forming part of a fence [syn: {picket}]
     v : turn pale, as if in fear [syn: {blanch}, {blench}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
