<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>palm</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PALM, n.  A species of tree having several varieties, of which the
familiar "itching palm" (_Palma hominis_) is most widely distributed
and sedulously cultivated.  This noble vegetable exudes a kind of
invisible gum, which may be detected by applying to the bark a piece
of gold or silver.  The metal will adhere with remarkable tenacity. 
The fruit of the itching palm is so bitter and unsatisfying that a
considerable percentage of it is sometimes given away in what are known
as "benefactions."


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Palm, PA
  Zip code(s): 18070
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>palm \palm\ (p[aum]m), n. [OE. paume, F. paume, L. palma, Gr.
   pala`mh, akin to Skr. p[=a][.n]i hand, and E. fumble. See
   {Fumble}, {Feel}, and cf. 2d {Palm}.]
   1. (Anat.) The inner and somewhat concave part of the hand
      between the bases of the fingers and the wrist.
      [1913 Webster]

            Clench'd her fingers till they bit the palm.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lineal measure equal either to the breadth of the hand
      or to its length from the wrist to the ends of the
      fingers; a hand; -- used in measuring a horse's height.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In Greece, the palm was reckoned at three inches. The
         Romans adopted two measures of this name, the lesser
         palm of 2.91 inches, and the greater palm of 8.73
         inches. At the present day, this measure varies in the
         most arbitrary manner, being different in each country,
         and occasionally varying in the same. --Internat. Cyc.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Sailmaking) A metallic disk, attached to a strap, and
      worn on the palm of the hand, -- used to push the needle
      through the canvas, in sewing sails, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Zo["o]l.) The broad flattened part of an antler, as of a
      full-grown fallow deer; -- so called as resembling the
      palm of the hand with its protruding fingers.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.) The flat inner face of an anchor fluke.
      [1913 Webster]

   {to grease the palm of}, v. t. To bribe or tip. [Slang]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Palm \Palm\ (p[aum]m), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Palmed} (p[aum]md);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Palming}.]
   1. To handle. [Obs.] --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To manipulate with, or conceal in, the palm of the hand;
      to juggle.
      [1913 Webster]

            They palmed the trick that lost the game. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: To take (something small) stealthily, especially by
      concealing it in the palm of the hand; as, he palmed one
      of the coins and walked out with it.
      [PJC]

   4. To impose by fraud, as by sleight of hand; to put by
      unfair means; -- usually with on or upon; as, to palm a
      stolen coin on an unsuspecting dealer. See also {palm
      off}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            For you may palm upon us new for old. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Palm \Palm\, n. [AS. palm, L. palma; -- so named fr. the leaf
   resembling a hand. See 1st {Palm}, and cf. {Pam}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Bot.) Any endogenous tree of the order {Palm[ae]} or
      {Palmace[ae]}; a palm tree.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Palms are perennial woody plants, often of majestic
         size. The trunk is usually erect and rarely branched,
         and has a roughened exterior composed of the persistent
         bases of the leaf stalks. The leaves are borne in a
         terminal crown, and are supported on stout, sheathing,
         often prickly, petioles. They are usually of great
         size, and are either pinnately or palmately many-cleft.
         There are about one thousand species known, nearly all
         of them growing in tropical or semitropical regions.
         The wood, petioles, leaves, sap, and fruit of many
         species are invaluable in the arts and in domestic
         economy. Among the best known are the date palm, the
         cocoa palm, the fan palm, the oil palm, the wax palm,
         the palmyra, and the various kinds called cabbage palm
         and palmetto.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A branch or leaf of the palm, anciently borne or worn as a
      symbol of victory or rejoicing.
      [1913 Webster]

            A great multitude . . . stood before the throne, and
            before the Lamb, clothed with white robes, and palme
            in their hands.                       --Rev. vii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: Any symbol or token of superiority, success, or
      triumph; also, victory; triumph; supremacy. ``The palm of
      martyrdom.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            So get the start of the majestic world
            And bear the palm alone.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Molucca palm} (Bot.), a labiate herb from Asia ({Molucella
      l[ae]vis}), having a curious cup-shaped calyx.

   {Palm cabbage}, the terminal bud of a cabbage palm, used as
      food.

   {Palm cat} (Zo["o]l.), the common paradoxure.

   {Palm crab} (Zo["o]l.), the purse crab.

   {Palm oil}, a vegetable oil, obtained from the fruit of
      several species of palms, as the African oil palm
      ({El[ae]is Guineensis}), and used in the manufacture of
      soap and candles. See {El[ae]is}.

   {Palm swift} (Zo["o]l.), a small swift ({Cypselus
      Batassiensis}) which frequents the palmyra and cocoanut
      palms in India. Its peculiar nest is attached to the leaf
      of the palmyra palm.

   {Palm toddy}. Same as {Palm wine}.

   {Palm weevil} (Zo["o]l.), any one of mumerous species of very
      large weevils of the genus {Rhynchophorus}. The larv[ae]
      bore into palm trees, and are called {palm borers}, and
      {grugru worms}. They are considered excellent food.

   {Palm wine}, the sap of several species of palms, especially,
      in India, of the wild date palm ({Ph[oe]nix sylvestrix}),
      the palmyra, and the {Caryota urens}. When fermented it
      yields by distillation arrack, and by evaporation jaggery.
      Called also {palm toddy}.

   {Palm worm}, or {Palmworm}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) The larva of a palm weevil.
      (b) A centipede.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>palm</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>palm
     n 1: the inner surface of the hand from the wrist to the base of
          the fingers [syn: {thenar}]
     2: a linear unit based on the length or width of the human hand
     3: any plant of the family Palmae having an unbranched trunk
        crowned by large pinnate or palmate leaves [syn: {palm
        tree}]
     4: an award for winning a championship or commemorating some
        other event [syn: {decoration}, {laurel wreath}, {medal},
        {medallion}, {ribbon}]
     v : touch, lift, or hold with the hands; "Don't handle the
         merchandise" [syn: {handle}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
