<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>panel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>panel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Panel \Pan"el\, n. [Orig., a little piece; OF. panel, pannel, F.
   panneau, dim. of pan skirt, lappet, part or piece of a wall,
   side. See 2d {Pane}.]
   1. (Arch.) A sunken compartment with raised margins, molded
      or otherwise, as in ceilings, wainscotings, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law)
      (a) A piece of parchment or a schedule, containing the
          names of persons summoned as jurors by the sheriff;
          hence, more generally, the whole group of persons
          summoned on a particular day, from whom a jury is to
          be selected; also, the jury selected from that group.
          --Blackstone.
      (b) (Scots Law) A prisoner arraigned for trial at the bar
          of a criminal court. --Burrill.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: Any group of persons selected to judge a contest,
      conduct a discussion, serve as advisers, or participate in
      any group activity in which they will provide information
      or make judgments.
      [PJC]

   4. Formerly, a piece of cloth serving as a saddle; hence, a
      soft pad beneath a saddletree to prevent chafing.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Joinery) A board having its edges inserted in the groove
      of a surrounding frame; as, the panel of a door.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Masonry) One of the faces of a hewn stone. --Gwilt.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Painting) A slab or plank of wood upon which, instead of
      canvas, a picture is painted.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mining)
      (a) A heap of dressed ore.
      (b) One of the districts divided by pillars of extra size,
          into which a mine is laid off in one system of
          extracting coal.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Dressmaking) A plain strip or band, as of velvet or
      plush, placed at intervals lengthwise on the skirt of a
      dress, for ornament.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A portion of a framed structure between adjacent posts or
       struts, as in a bridge truss.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (A["e]ronautics) A segment of an a["e]roplane wing. In a
       biplane the outer panel extends from the wing tip to the
       next row of posts, and is trussed by oblique stay wires.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Panel game}, a method of stealing money in a panel house.

   {Panel house}, a house of prostitution in which the rooms
      have secret entrances to facilitate theft from customers
      by accomplices of the inmates.

   {Panel saw}, handsaw with fine teeth, -- used for cutting out
      panels, etc.

   {Panel thief}, one who robs in a panel house.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>panel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Panel \Pan"el\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Paneled}or {Panelled}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Paneling} or {Panelling}.]
   To form in or with panels; as, to panel a wainscot.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Paneled back} (Arch.), the paneled work covering the window
      back. See {Window back}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>panel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>panel
     n 1: sheet that forms a distinct (usually flat) section or
          component of something
     2: a committee appointed to judge a competition [syn: {jury}]
     3: (law) a group of people summoned for jury service (from whom
        a jury will be chosen) [syn: {venire}]
     4: a group of people gathered for a special purpose as to plan
        or discuss an issue or judge a contest etc
     5: a pad placed under a saddle
     6: (computer science) a small temporary window in a graphical
        user interface that appears in order to request
        information from the user; after the information has been
        provided the user dismisses the box with `okay' or
        `cancel' [syn: {dialog box}]
     7: electrical device consisting of an insulated panel
        containing switches and dials and meters for controlling
        other electrical devices; "he checked the instrument
        panel"; "suddenly the board lit up like a Christmas tree"
        [syn: {control panel}, {instrument panel}, {control board},
         {board}]
     v 1: decorate with panels; "panel the walls with wood"
     2: select from a list; "empanel prospective jurors" [syn: {empanel},
         {impanel}]
     [also: {panelling}, {panelled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
