<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>paper</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paper
   The expression in the Authorized Version (Isa. 19:7), "the paper
   reeds by the brooks," is in the Revised Version more correctly
   "the meadows by the Nile." The words undoubtedly refer to a
   grassy place on the banks of the Nile fit for pasturage.
   
     In 2 John 1:12 the word is used in its proper sense. The
   material so referred to was manufactured from the papyrus, and
   hence its name. The papyrus (Heb. gome) was a kind of bulrush
   (q.v.). It is mentioned by Job (8:11) and Isaiah (35:7). It was
   used for many purposes. This plant (Papyrus Nilotica) is now
   unknown in Egypt; no trace of it can be found. The unaccountable
   disappearance of this plant from Egypt was foretold by Isaiah
   (19:6, 7) as a part of the divine judgment on that land. The
   most extensive papyrus growths now known are in the marshes at
   the northern end of the lake of Merom.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paper \Pa"per\ (p[=a]"p[~e]r), n. [F. papier, fr. L. papyrus
   papyrus, from which the Egyptians made a kind of paper, Gr.
   pa`pyros. Cf. {Papyrus}.]
   1. A substance in the form of thin sheets or leaves intended
      to be written or printed on, or to be used in wrapping. It
      is made of rags, straw, bark, wood, or other fibrous
      material, which is first reduced to pulp, then molded,
      pressed, and dried.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A sheet, leaf, or piece of such substance.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A printed or written instrument; a document, essay, or the
      like; a writing; as, a paper read before a scientific
      society.
      [1913 Webster]

            They brought a paper to me to be signed. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A printed sheet appearing periodically; a newspaper; a
      journal; as, a daily paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Negotiable evidences of indebtedness; notes; bills of
      exchange, and the like; as, the bank holds a large amount
      of his paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Decorated hangings or coverings for walls, made of paper.
      See {Paper hangings}, below.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A paper containing (usually) a definite quantity; as, a
      paper of pins, tacks, opium, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A medicinal preparation spread upon paper, intended for
      external application; as, cantharides paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. pl. Documents establishing a person's identity, or status,
      or attesting to some right, such as the right to drive a
      vehicle; as, the border guard asked for his papers.
      [PJC]

   Note: Paper is manufactured in sheets, the trade names of
         which, together with the regular sizes in inches, are
         shown in the following table. But paper makers vary the
         size somewhat.
         [1913 Webster]
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the manufacture of books, etc., a sheet, of whatever
         size originally, is termed, when folded once, a folio;
         folded twice, a quarto, or 4to; three times, an octavo,
         or 8vo; four times, a sextodecimo, or 16mo; five times,
         a 32mo; three times, with an offcut folded twice and
         set in, a duodecimo, or 12mo; four times, with an
         offcut folded three times and set in, a 24mo.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: Paper is often used adjectively or in combination,
         having commonly an obvious signification; as, paper
         cutter or paper-cutter; paper knife, paper-knife, or
         paperknife; paper maker, paper-maker, or papermaker;
         paper mill or paper-mill; paper weight, paper-weight,
         or paperweight, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Business paper}, checks, notes, drafts, etc., given in
      payment of actual indebtedness; -- opposed to
      accommodation paper.

   {Fly paper}, paper covered with a sticky preparation, -- used
      for catching flies.

   {Laid paper}. See under {Laid}.

   {Paper birch} (Bot.), the canoe birch tree ({Betula
      papyracea}).

   {Paper blockade}, an ineffective blockade, as by a weak naval
      force.

   {Paper boat} (Naut.), a boat made of water-proof paper.

   {Paper car wheel} (Railroad), a car wheel having a steel
      tire, and a center formed of compressed paper held between
      two plate-iron disks. --Forney.

   {Paper credit}, credit founded upon evidences of debt, such
      as promissory notes, duebills, etc.

   {Paper hanger}, one who covers walls with paper hangings.

   {Paper hangings}, paper printed with colored figures, or
      otherwise made ornamental, prepared to be pasted against
      the walls of apartments, etc.; wall paper.

   {Paper house}, an audience composed of people who have come
      in on free passes. [Cant]

   {Paper money}, notes or bills, usually issued by government
      or by a banking corporation, promising payment of money,
      and circulated as the representative of coin.

   {Paper mulberry}. (Bot.) See under Mulberry.

   {Paper muslin}, glazed muslin, used for linings, etc.

   {Paper nautilus}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Argonauta}.

   {Paper reed} (Bot.), the papyrus.

   {Paper sailor}. (Zo["o]l.) See Argonauta.

   {Paper stainer}, one who colors or stamps wall paper. --De
      Colange.

   {Paper wasp} (Zo["o]l.), any wasp which makes a nest of
      paperlike material, as the yellow jacket.

   {Paper weight}, any object used as a weight to prevent loose
      papers from being displaced by wind, or otherwise.

   {on paper}.
      (a) in writing; as, I would like to see that on paper.
      (b) in theory, though not necessarily in paractice.
      (c) in the design state; planned, but not yet put into
          practice.

   {Parchment paper}. See {Papyrine}.

   {Tissue paper}, thin, gauzelike paper, such as is used to
      protect engravings in books.

   {Wall paper}. Same as {Paper hangings}, above.

   {Waste paper}, paper thrown aside as worthless or useless,
      except for uses of little account.

   {Wove paper}, a writing paper with a uniform surface, not
      ribbed or watermarked.

   {paper tiger}, a person or group that appears to be powerful
      and dangerous but is in fact weak and ineffectual.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paper \pa"per\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {papered} (p[=a]"p[~e]rd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {papering}.]
   1. To cover or line with paper, especially with wallpaper; to
      furnish with paper hangings; to wallpaper; as, to paper a
      room or a house.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. To fold or inclose in paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To put on paper; to make a memorandum of. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paper \pa"per\ (p[=a]"p[~e]r), a.
   1. Of or pertaining to paper; made of paper; resembling
      paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Existing only on paper; unsubstantial; as, a paper box; a
      paper army; a paper tiger.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Poonah painting \Poo"nah paint`ing\ [From Poona, in Bombay
   Province, India.]
   A style of painting, popular in England in the 19th century,
   in which a thick opaque color is applied without background
   and with scarcely any shading, to thin paper, producing
   flowers, birds, etc., in imitation of Oriental work.

   Note: Hence:

   {Poonah brush},

   {paper},

   {painter}, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paper</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paper
     adj : made of paper; "they wore paper hats at the party"
     n 1: a material made of cellulose pulp derived mainly from wood
          or rags or certain grasses
     2: an essay (especially one written as an assignment); "he got
        an A on his composition" [syn: {composition}, {report}, {theme}]
     3: a daily or weekly publication on folded sheets; contains
        news and articles and advertisements; "he read his
        newspaper at breakfast" [syn: {newspaper}]
     4: a scholarly article describing the results of observations
        or stating hypotheses; "he has written many scientific
        papers"
     5: medium for written communication; "the notion of an office
        running without paper is absurd"
     6: a business firm that publishes newspapers; "Murdoch owns
        many newspapers" [syn: {newspaper}, {newspaper publisher}]
     7: a newspaper as a physical object; "when it began to rain he
        covered his head with a newspaper" [syn: {newspaper}]
     v 1: cover with paper; "paper the box"
     2: cover with wallpaper [syn: {wallpaper}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
