<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>paragraph</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paragraph</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paragraph \Par"a*graph\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Paragraphed}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Paragraphing}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To divide into paragraphs; to mark with the character
      [para].
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To express in the compass of a paragraph; as, to paragraph
      an article.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To mention in a paragraph or paragraphs
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paragraph</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paragraph \Par"a*graph\, n. [F. paragraphe, LL. paragraphus, fr.
   Gr. para`grafos (sc. grammh`) a line or stroke drawn in the
   margin, fr. paragra`fein to write beside; para` beside +
   gra`fein to write. See {Para-}, and {Graphic}, and cf.
   {Paraph}.]
   1. Originally, a marginal mark or note, set in the margin to
      call attention to something in the text, e. g., a change
      of subject; now, the character [para], commonly used in
      the text as a reference mark to a footnote, or to indicate
      the place of a division into sections.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: This character is merely a modification of a capital P
         (the initial of the word paragraph), the letter being
         reversed, and the black part made white and the white
         part black for the sake of distinctiveness.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A distinct part of a discourse or writing; any section or
      subdivision of a writing or chapter which relates to a
      particular point, whether consisting of one or many
      sentences. The division is sometimes noted by the mark
      [para], but usually, by beginning the first sentence of
      the paragraph on a new line and at more than the usual
      distance from the margin, also called indenting the line.
      See {indentation}[4].

   3. A brief composition complete in one typographical section
      or paragraph; an item, remark, or quotation comprised in a
      few lines forming one paragraph; as, a column of news
      paragraphs; an editorial paragraph.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paragraph</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paragraph
     n : one of several distinct subdivisions of a text intended to
         separate ideas; the beginning is usually marked by a new
         indented line
     v 1: divide into paragraphs, as of text; "This story is well
          paragraphed"
     2: write about in a paragraph; "All her friends were
        paragraphed in last Monday's paper"
     3: write paragraphs; work as a paragrapher
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
