<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>paraffin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paraffin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Paraffin \Par"af*fin\ (p[a^]r"[a^]f*f[i^]n), Paraffine
\Par"af*fine\ (p[a^]r"[a^]f*f[i^]n or p[a^]r"[a^]f*f[=e]n), n.
   [F. paraffine, fr. L. parum too little + affinis akin. So
   named in allusion to its chemical inactivity.] (Chem.)
   A white waxy substance, resembling spermaceti, tasteless and
   odorless, and obtained from coal tar, wood tar, petroleum,
   etc., by distillation. It is used in candles, as a sealing
   agent (such as in canning of preserves), as a waterproofing
   agent, as an illuminant and as a lubricant. It is very inert,
   not being acted upon by most of the strong chemical reagents.
   It was formerly regarded as a definite compound, but is now
   known to be a complex mixture of several higher hydrocarbons
   of the methane or marsh-gas series; hence, by extension, any
   substance, whether solid, liquid, or gaseous, of the same
   chemical series; thus gasoline, coal gas and kerosene consist
   largely of paraffins.
   [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: In the present chemical usage this word is spelled
         paraffin, but in commerce it is commonly spelled
         paraffine.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Native paraffin}. See {Ozocerite}.

   {Paraffin series}. See {Methane series}, under {Methane}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paraffin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paraffin
     n 1: from crude petroleum; used for candles and for preservative
          or waterproof coatings [syn: {paraffin wax}]
     2: a non-aromatic saturated hydrocarbon with the general
        formula CnH(2n+2) [syn: {methane series}, {alkane series},
         {alkane}]
     3: British usage [syn: {paraffin oil}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
