<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>parachute</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parachute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Parachute, CO (town, FIPS 57400)
  Location: 39.44582 N, 108.05510 W
  Population (1990): 658 (405 housing units)
  Area: 3.0 sq km (land), 0.1 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parachute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Parachute \Par"a*chute\ (p[a^]r"[.a]*sh[=oo]t or
   p[a^]r"[.a]*sh[udd]t), n. [F., fr. parer to ward off, guard +
   chute a fall. See {Parry}, and {Chute}, {Chance}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A device made of a piece of cloth, usually silk, attached
      to multiple chords fastened to a harness; when attached to
      a person or object falling through the air, it opens from
      a folded configuration into an umbrella-shaped form, thus
      slowing the rate of descent so that a safe descent and
      landing may be made through the air from an airplane,
      balloon, or other high point. It is commonly used for
      descending to the ground from a flying airplane, as for
      military operations (as of airborne troops) or in an
      emergency, or for sport. In the case of use as a sport,
      the descent from an airplane by parachute is called {sky
      diving}. Some older versions of parachute were more rigid,
      and were shaped somewhat in the form of an umbrella.

   2. (Zo["o]l.) A web or fold of skin which extends between the
      legs of certain mammals, as the flying squirrels, colugo,
      and phalangister.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parachute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>parachute \par"a*chute\, v. i.
   TO descend to th ground from an airplane or other high place
   using a parachute; as, when the plane stalled, he parachuted
   safely to the ground.
   [PJC]

   {golden parachute} a generous set of financial benefits,
      including severance pay, provided by contract to a
      high-level corporate employee in the event s/he is
      dismissed or his/her job is lost in a corporate takeover
      or merger; also, the contract providing for such benefits.
      

   {drogue parachute} a small parachute that is first released
      and opened in order to more reliably deploy a larger
      parachute. Also called {drogue}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parachute</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>parachute
     n : rescue equipment consisting of a device that fills with air
         and retards your fall [syn: {chute}]
     v : jump from an airplane and descend with a parachute [syn: {jump}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
