<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pardon</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pardon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PARDON, v.  To remit a penalty and restore to the life of crime.  To
add to the lure of crime the temptation of ingratitude.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pardon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pardon
   the forgiveness of sins granted freely (Isa. 43:25), readily
   (Neh. 9:17; Ps. 86:5), abundantly (Isa. 55:7; Rom. 5:20). Pardon
   is an act of a sovereign, in pure sovereignty, granting simply a
   remission of the penalty due to sin, but securing neither honour
   nor reward to the pardoned. Justification (q.v.), on the other
   hand, is the act of a judge, and not of a sovereign, and
   includes pardon and, at the same time, a title to all the
   rewards and blessings promised in the covenant of life.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pardon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pardon \Par"don\ (p[aum]r"d'n), n. [F., fr. pardonner to pardon.
   See {Pardon}, v. t.]
   1. The act of pardoning; forgiveness, as of an offender, or
      of an offense; release from penalty; remission of
      punishment; absolution.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pardon, my lord, for me and for my tidings. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            But infinite in pardon was my judge.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Usage: Used in expressing courteous denial or contradiction;
          as, I beg your pardon; or in indicating that one has
          not understood another; as, I beg pardon; or pardon
          me?.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. An official warrant of remission of penalty.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sign me a present pardon for my brother. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The state of being forgiven. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) A release, by a sovereign, or officer having
      jurisdiction, from the penalties of an offense, being
      distinguished from {amnesty}, which is a general
      obliteration and canceling of a particular line of past
      offenses.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Forgiveness; remission. See {Forgiveness}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pardon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pardon \Par"don\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pardoned} (p[aum]r"d'nd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Pardoning}.] [Either fr. pardon, n., or from
   F. pardonner, LL. perdonare; L. per through, thoroughly,
   perfectly + donare to give, to present. See {Par-}, and
   {Donation}.]
   1. To absolve from the consequences of a fault or the
      punishment of crime; to free from penalty; -- applied to
      the offender.
      [1913 Webster]

            In this thing the Lord pardon thy servant. --2 Kings
                                                  v. 18.
      [1913 Webster]

            I pray you, pardon me; pray heartily, pardon me.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To remit the penalty of; to suffer to pass without
      punishment; to forgive; -- applied to offenses.
      [1913 Webster]

            I pray thee, pardon my sin.           --1 Sam. xv.
                                                  25.
      [1913 Webster]

            Apollo, pardon
            My great profaneness 'gainst thine oracle! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To refrain from exacting as a penalty.
      [1913 Webster]

            I pardon thee thy life before thou ask it. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To give leave (of departure) to. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Even now about it! I will pardon you. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Pardon me}, forgive me; excuse me; -- a phrase used also to
      express courteous denial or contradiction, or to request
      forgiveness for a mild transgression, such as bumping a
      person while passing.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Syn: To forgive; absolve; excuse; overlook; remit; acquit.
        See {Excuse}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pardon</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pardon
     n 1: the act of excusing a mistake or offense [syn: {forgiveness}]
     2: a warrant granting release from punishment for an offense
        [syn: {amnesty}]
     3: the formal act of liberating someone [syn: {amnesty}, {free
        pardon}]
     v 1: accept an excuse for; "Please excuse my dirty hands" [syn: {excuse}]
     2: grant a pardon to; "Ford pardoned Nixon"; "The Thanksgiving
        turkey was pardoned by the President"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
