<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>park</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>park</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Park, KS (city, FIPS 54400)
  Location: 39.11229 N, 100.36166 W
  Population (1990): 150 (91 housing units)
  Area: 0.8 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 67751
Park, PA
  Zip code(s): 15690
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>park</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Park \Park\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Parked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Parking}.]
   1. To inclose in a park, or as in a park.
      [1913 Webster]

            How are we parked, and bounded in a pale. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) To bring together in a park, or compact body; as,
      to park artillery, wagons, automobiles, etc.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. In oyster culture, to inclose in a park.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. To bring (a vehicle) to a stop and leave it standing; --
      typically a parked vehicle is off of the public road, the
      motor is not running, and the driver has left the vehicle.

   Note: a vehicle stopped but still running with the driver in
         it is said to be {standing}. {parallel-park} [PJC]

   5. To place (an object) in a temporary location; as, to park
      oneself on the couch; to park one's money in a mutual
      fund. [informal]
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>park</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Park \Park\ (p[aum]rk), n. [AS. pearroc, or perh. rather fr. F.
   parc; both being of the same origin; cf. LL. parcus,
   parricus, Ir. &amp; Gael. pairc, W. park, parwg. Cf. {Paddock} an
   inclosure, {Parrock}.]
   1. (Eng. Law) A piece of ground inclosed, and stored with
      beasts of the chase, which a man may have by prescription,
      or the king's grant. --Mozley &amp; W.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A tract of ground kept in its natural state, about or
      adjacent to a residence, as for the preservation of game,
      for walking, riding, or the like. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            While in the park I sing, the listening deer
            Attend my passion, and forget to fear. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A piece of ground, in or near a city or town, inclosed and
      kept for ornament and recreation; as, Hyde Park in London;
      Central Park in New York.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) A space occupied by the animals, wagons, pontoons,
      and materials of all kinds, as ammunition, ordnance
      stores, hospital stores, provisions, etc., when brought
      together; also, the objects themselves; as, a park of
      wagons; a park of artillery.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A partially inclosed basin in which oysters are grown.
      [Written also {parc}.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Any place where vehicles are assembled according to a
      definite arrangement; also, the vehicles.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. A position of the gear lever in a vehicle with automatic
      transmission, used when the vehicle is stopped, in which
      the transmission is in neutral and a brake is engaged.
      [PJC]

   {Park of artillery}. See under {Artillery}.

   {Park phaeton}, a small, low carriage, for use in parks.

   {industrial park} a region located typically in a suburban or
      rural area, zoned by law for specific types of business
      use (as, retail business, light industry, and sometimes
      heavy industry), often having some parklike
      characteristics, and having businesses, parking lots, and
      sometimes recreation areas and restaurants. The sponsoring
      agency may also provide supporting facilities, such as
      water towers, office buildings, or for large industrial
      parks, an airport.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>park</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Park \Park\, v. i.
   1. To promenade or drive in a park; also, of horses, to
      display style or gait on a park drive.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. To come to a stop [in a vehicle] off of the public road
      and leave the vehicle standing; -- typically the motor of
      a parked vehicle is not left running; as, he parked in a
      no-parking zone.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>park</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>park
     n 1: a large area of land preserved in its natural state as
          public property; "there are laws that protect the
          wildlife in this park" [syn: {parkland}]
     2: a piece of open land for recreational use in an urban area;
        "they went for a walk in the park" [syn: {commons}, {common},
         {green}]
     3: a facility in which ball games are played (especially
        baseball games); "take me out to the ballpark" [syn: {ballpark}]
     4: Scottish explorer in Africa (1771-1806) [syn: {Mungo Park}]
     5: a lot where cars are parked [syn: {parking lot}, {car park},
         {parking area}]
     6: a gear position that acts as a parking brake; "the put the
        car in park and got out"
     v 1: place temporarily; "park the car in the yard"; "park the
          children with the in-laws"; "park your bag in this
          locker"
     2: maneuver a vehicle into a parking space; "Park the car in
        front of the library"; "Can you park right here?"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
