<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>parlour</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parlour</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Parlour
   (from the Fr. parler, "to speak") denotes an "audience chamber,"
   but that is not the import of the Hebrew word so rendered. It
   corresponds to what the Turks call a kiosk, as in Judg. 3:20
   (the "summer parlour"), or as in the margin of the Revised
   Version ("the upper chamber of cooling"), a small room built on
   the roof of the house, with open windows to catch the breeze,
   and having a door communicating with the outside by which
   persons seeking an audience may be admitted. While Eglon was
   resting in such a parlour, Ehud, under pretence of having a
   message from God to him, was admitted into his presence, and
   murderously plunged his dagger into his body (21, 22).
   
     The "inner parlours" in 1 Chr. 28:11 were the small rooms or
   chambers which Solomon built all round two sides and one end of
   the temple (1 Kings 6:5), "side chambers;" or they may have
   been, as some think, the porch and the holy place.
   
     In 1 Sam. 9:22 the Revised Version reads "guest chamber," a
   chamber at the high place specially used for sacrificial feasts.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parlour</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>parlour \parlour\ n.
   1. Same as {parlor}.

   Syn: living room, sitting room, front room, parlor.
        [WordNet 1.5]

   2. A room in an inn or club where visitors can be received.

   Syn: parlor.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parlour</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Parlor \Par"lor\, n. [OE. parlour, parlur, F. parloir, LL.
   parlatorium. See {Parley}.] [Written also {parlour}.]
   1. A room for business or social conversation, for the
      reception of guests, etc. Specifically:
      (a) The apartment in a monastery or nunnery where the
          inmates are permitted to meet and converse with each
          other, or with visitors and friends from without.
          --Piers Plowman.
      (b) In large private houses, a sitting room for the family
          and for familiar guests, -- a room for less formal
          uses than the drawing-room. Esp., in modern times, the
          dining room of a house having few apartments, as a
          London house, where the dining parlor is usually on
          the ground floor.
      (c) Commonly, in the United States, a drawing-room, or the
          room where visitors are received and entertained; a
          room in a private house where people can sit and talk
          and relax, not usually the same as the dining room.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: ``In England people who have a drawing-room no longer
         call it a parlor, as they called it of old and till
         recently.'' --Fitzed. Hall.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A room in an inn or club where visitors can be received.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   {Parlor car}. See {Palace car}, under {Car}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>parlour</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>parlour
     n 1: reception room in an inn or club where visitors can be
          received [syn: {parlor}]
     2: a room in a private house or establishment where people can
        sit and talk and relax [syn: {living room}, {living-room},
         {sitting room}, {front room}, {parlor}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
