<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>party</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>party</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>@-party
     
        &lt;event&gt; /at'par-tee/ (Or "@-sign party" /at'si:n par'tee/,
        from the {@} sign in an {electronic mail address}) A
        semi-closed party thrown for hackers at a science-fiction
        convention (especially the annual Worldcon); one must have an
        {electronic mail address} to get in, or at least be in company
        with someone who does.  One of the most reliable opportunities
        for hackers to meet {face-to-face} with people who might
        otherwise be represented by mere phosphor dots on their
        screens.
     
        Compare {boink}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1996-05-08)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>party</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Party \Par"ty\ (p[aum]r"t[y^]), n.; pl. {Parties}
   (p[aum]r"t[i^]z). [F. parti and partie, fr. F. partir to
   part, divide, L. partire, partiri. See {Part}, v.]
   1. A part or portion. [Obs.] ``The most party of the time.''
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A number of persons united in opinion or action, as
      distinguished from, or opposed to, the rest of a community
      or association; esp., one of the parts into which a people
      is divided on questions of public policy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Win the noble Brutus to our party.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The peace both parties want is like to last.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A part of a larger body of company; a detachment;
      especially (Mil.), a small body of troops dispatched on
      special service.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A number of persons invited to a social entertainment; a
      select company; as, a dinner party; also, the
      entertainment itself; as, to give a party.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. One concerned or interested in an affair; one who takes
      part with others; a participator; as, he was a party to
      the plot; a party to the contract.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The plaintiff or the defendant in a lawsuit, whether an
      individual, a firm, or corporation; a litigant.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cause of both parties shall come before the
            judges.                               --Ex. xxii. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence, any certain person who is regarded as being opposed
      or antagonistic to another.
      [1913 Webster]

            If the jury found that the party slain was of
            English race, it had been adjudged felony. --Sir J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Cause; side; interest.
      [1913 Webster]

            Have you nothing said
            Upon this Party 'gainst the Duke of Albany? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A person; as, he is a queer party. [Now accounted a
      vulgarism.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: ``For several generations, our ancestors largely
         employed party for person; but this use of the word,
         when it appeared to be reviving, happened to strike,
         more particularly, the fancy of the vulgar; and the
         consequence has been, that the polite have chosen to
         leave it in their undisputed possession.'' --Fitzed.
         Hall.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Party jury} (Law), a jury composed of different parties, as
      one which is half natives and half foreigners.

   {Party man}, a partisan. --Swift.

   {Party spirit}, a factious and unreasonable temper, not
      uncommonly shown by party men. --Whately.

   {Party verdict}, a joint verdict. --Shak.

   {Party wall}.
      (a) (Arch.) A wall built upon the dividing line between
          two adjoining properties, usually having half its
          thickness on each property.
      (b) (Law) A wall that separates adjoining houses, as in a
          block or row.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>party</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Party \Par"ty\, adv.
   Partly. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>party</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Party \Par"ty\, a. [F. parti divided, fr. partir to divide. See
   {Part}, v., and cf. {Partite}.]
   1. (Her.) Parted or divided, as in the direction or form of
      one of the ordinaries; as, an escutcheon party per pale.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Partial; favoring one party; partisan.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will be true judge, and not party.  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Charter party}. See under {Charter}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>party</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>@-party /at'par`tee/ n. [from the @-sign in an Internet address] (alt.
   `@-sign party' /at'si:n par`tee/) A semi-closed party thrown for hackers
   at a science-fiction convention (esp. the annual World Science Fiction
   Convention or "Worldcon"); one must have a {network address} to get in,
   or at least be in company with someone who does. One of the most
   reliable opportunities for hackers to meet face to face with people who
   might otherwise be represented by mere phosphor dots on their screens.
   Compare {boink}.

   The first recorded @-party was held at the Westercon (a U.S. western
   regional SF convention) over the July 4th weekend in 1980. It is not
   clear exactly when the canonical @-party venue shifted to the Worldcon
   but it had certainly become established by Constellation in 1983. Sadly,
   the @-party tradition has been in decline since about 1996, mainly
   because having an @-address no longer functions as an effective lodge
   pin.

   We are informed, however, that rec.skydiving members have maintained a
   tradition of formation jumps in the shape of an @; picture at
   `http://www.birdwalk.com/DevilsWorkshop/favorites/source/6.html'.

= A =


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>party</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>party
     n 1: an organization to gain political power; "in 1992 Perot
          tried to organize a third party at the national level"
          [syn: {political party}]
     2: an occasion on which people can assemble for social
        interaction and entertainment; "he planned a party to
        celebrate Bastille Day"
     3: a band of people associated temporarily in some activity;
        "they organized a party to search for food"; "the company
        of cooks walked into the kitchen" [syn: {company}]
     4: a group of people gathered together for pleasure; "she
        joined the party after dinner"
     5: a person involved in legal proceedings; "the party of the
        first part"
     v : have or participate in a party; "The students were partying
         all night before the exam"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
