<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>partition</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>partition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>partition
     
        1. &lt;storage&gt; A {logical} section of a {disk}.  Each partition
        normally has its own {file system}.  {Unix} tends to treat
        partitions as though they were separate physical entities.
     
        2. &lt;mathematics&gt; A division of a set into subsets so that each
        of its elements is in exactly one subset.
     
        (1996-12-09)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>partition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Partition \Par*ti"tion\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Partitioned}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Partitioning}.]
   1. To divide into parts or shares; to divide and distribute;
      as, to partition an estate among various heirs.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To divide into distinct parts by lines, walls, etc.; as,
      to partition a house.
      [1913 Webster]

            Uniform without, though severally partitioned
            within.                               --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>partition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Partition \Par*ti"tion\, n. [F. partition, L. partitio. See
   {Part}, v.]
   1. The act of parting or dividing; the state of being parted;
      separation; division; distribution; as, the partition of a
      kingdom.
      [1913 Webster]

            And good from bad find no partition.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which divides or separates; that by which different
      things, or distinct parts of the same thing, are
      separated; separating boundary; dividing line or space;
      specifically, an interior wall dividing one part or
      apartment of a house, a compartment of a room, an
      inclosure, or the like, from another; as, a brick
      partition; lath and plaster partitions; cubicles with
      four-foot high partitions.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            No sight could pass
            Betwixt the nice partitions of the grass. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A part divided off by walls; an apartment; a compartment.
      [R.] ``Lodged in a small partition.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law.) The severance of common or undivided interests,
      particularly in real estate. It may be effected by consent
      of parties, or by compulsion of law.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.) A score.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Partition of numbers} (Math.), the resolution of integers
      into parts subject to given conditions. --Brande &amp; C.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>partition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>partition
     n 1: a vertical structure that divides or separates (as a wall
          divides one room from another) [syn: {divider}]
     2: the act of dividing or partitioning; separation by the
        creation of a boundary that divides or keeps apart [syn: {division},
         {partitioning}, {segmentation}, {sectionalization}, {sectionalisation}]
     3: (computer science) the part of a hard disk that is dedicated
        to a particular operating system or application and
        accessed as a single unit
     v 1: divide into parts, pieces, or sections; "The Arab peninsula
          was partitioned by the British" [syn: {partition off}]
     2: separate or apportion into sections; "partition a room off"
        [syn: {zone}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
