<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>part</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>part</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Part \Part\ (p[aum]rt), n. [F. part, L. pars, gen. partis; cf.
   parere to bring forth, produce. Cf. {Parent}, {Depart},
   {Parcel}, {Partner}, {Party}, {Portion}.]
   1. One of the portions, equal or unequal, into which anything
      is divided, or regarded as divided; something less than a
      {whole}; a number, quantity, mass, or the like, regarded
      as going to make up, with others, a larger number,
      quantity, mass, etc., whether actually separate or not; a
      piece; a fragment; a fraction; a division; a member; a
      constituent.
      [1913 Webster]

            And kept back part of the price, . . . and brought a
            certain part and laid it at the apostles'feet.
                                                  --Acts v. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our ideas of extension and number -- do they not
            contain a secret relation of the parts ? --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am a part of all that I have met.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, specifically:
      (a) An equal constituent portion; one of several or many
          like quantities, numbers, etc., into which anything is
          divided, or of which it is composed; proportional
          division or ingredient.
          [1913 Webster]

                An homer is the tenth part of an ephah. --Ex.
                                                  xvi. 36.
          [1913 Webster]

                A thought which, quartered, hath but one part
                wisdom,
                And ever three parts coward.      --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A constituent portion of a living or spiritual whole;
          a member; an organ; an essential element.
          [1913 Webster]

                All the parts were formed . . . into one
                harmonious body.                  --Locke.
          [1913 Webster]

                The pulse, the glow of every part. --Keble.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) A constituent of character or capacity; quality;
          faculty; talent; -- usually in the plural with a
          collective sense. ``Men of considerable parts.''
          --Burke. ``Great quickness of parts.'' --Macaulay.
          [1913 Webster]

                Which maintained so politic a state of evil,
                that they will not admit any good part to
                intermingle with them.            --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) Quarter; region; district; -- usually in the plural.
          ``The uttermost part of the heaven.'' --Neh. i. 9.
          [1913 Webster]

                All parts resound with tumults, plaints, and
                fears.                            --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) (Math.) Such portion of any quantity, as when taken a
          certain number of times, will exactly make that
          quantity; as, 3 is a part of 12; -- the opposite of
          {multiple}. Also, a line or other element of a
          geometrical figure.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. That which belongs to one, or which is assumed by one, or
      which falls to one, in a division or apportionment; share;
      portion; lot; interest; concern; duty; office.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have no part in David.             --2 Sam. xx.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

            Accuse not Nature! she hath done her part;
            Do thou but thine.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let me bear
            My part of danger with an equal share. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, specifically:
      (a) One of the opposing parties or sides in a conflict or
          a controversy; a faction.
          [1913 Webster]

                For he that is not against us is on our part.
                                                  --Mark ix. 40.
          [1913 Webster]

                Make whole kingdoms take her brother's part.
                                                  --Waller.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A particular character in a drama or a play; an
          assumed personification; also, the language, actions,
          and influence of a character or an actor in a play;
          or, figuratively, in real life; as, to play the part
          of Macbeth. See {To act a part}, under {Act}.
          [1913 Webster]

                That part
                Was aptly fitted and naturally performed.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                It was a brute part of him to kill so capital a
                calf.                             --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                Honor and shame from no condition rise;
                Act well your part, there all the honor lies.
                                                  --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) (Mus.) One of the different melodies of a concerted
          composition, which heard in union compose its harmony;
          also, the music for each voice or instrument; as, the
          treble, tenor, or bass part; the violin part, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   {For my part}, so far as concerns me; for my share.

   {For the most part}. See under {Most}, a.

   {In good part}, as well done; favorably; acceptably; in a
      friendly manner; as, to take an act in good part.
      --Hooker.

   {In ill part}, unfavorably; with displeasure.

   {In part}, in some degree; partly.

   {Part and parcel}, an essential or constituent portion; -- a
      reduplicative phrase. Cf. {might and main}, {kith and
      kin}, etc. ``She was . . . part and parcel of the race and
      place.'' --Howitt.

   {Part of speech} (Gram.), a sort or class of words of a
      particular character; thus, the noun is a part of speech
      denoting the name of a thing; the verb is a part of speech
      which asserts something of the subject of a sentence.

   {Part owner} (Law), one of several owners or tenants in
      common. See {Joint tenant}, under {Joint}.

   {Part singing}, singing in which two or more of the harmonic
      parts are taken.

   {Part song}, a song in two or more (commonly four) distinct
      vocal parts. ``A part song differs from a madrigal in its
      exclusion of contrapuntual devices; from a glee, in its
      being sung by many voices, instead of by one only, to each
      part.'' --Stainer &amp; Barrett.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Portion; section; division; fraction; fragment; piece;
        share; constituent. See {Portion}, and {Section}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>part</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Part \Part\, v. i.
   1. To be broken or divided into parts or pieces; to break; to
      become separated; to go asunder; as, rope parts; his hair
      parts in the middle.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To go away; to depart; to take leave; to quit each other;
      hence, to die; -- often with from.
      [1913 Webster]

            He wrung Bassanio's hand, and so they parted.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He owned that he had parted from the duke only a few
            hours before.                         --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            His precious bag, which he would by no means part
            from.                                 --G. Eliot.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To perform an act of parting; to relinquish a connection
      of any kind; -- followed by with or from; as, to part with
      one's money.
      [1913 Webster]

            Celia, for thy sake, I part
            With all that grew so near my heart.  --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

            Powerful hands . . . will not part
            Easily from possession won with arms. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was strange to him that a father should feel no
            tenderness at parting with an only son. --A.
                                                  Trollope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To have a part or share; to partake. [Obs.] ``They shall
      part alike.'' --1 Sam. xxx. 24.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>part</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Part \Part\ (p[aum]rt), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Parted}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Parting}.] [F. partir, L. partire, partiri, p. p.
   partitus, fr. pars, gen. partis, a part. See {Part}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To divide; to separate into distinct parts; to break into
      two or more parts or pieces; to sever. ``Thou shalt part
      it in pieces.'' --Lev. ii. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            There, [celestial love] parted into rainbow hues.
                                                  --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To divide into shares; to divide and distribute; to allot;
      to apportion; to share.
      [1913 Webster]

            To part his throne, and share his heaven with thee.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            They parted my raiment among them.    --John xix.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To separate or disunite; to cause to go apart; to remove
      from contact or contiguity; to sunder.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord do so to me, and more also, if aught but
            death part thee and me.               --Ruth i. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

            While he blessed them, he was parted from them, and
            carried up into heaven.               --Luke xxiv.
                                                  51.
      [1913 Webster]

            The narrow seas that part
            The French and English.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence: To hold apart; to stand between; to intervene
      betwixt, as combatants.
      [1913 Webster]

            The stumbling night did part our weary powers.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To separate by a process of extraction, elimination, or
      secretion; as, to part gold from silver.
      [1913 Webster]

            The liver minds his own affair, . . .
            And parts and strains the vital juices. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To leave; to quit. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Since presently your souls must part your bodies.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To separate (a collection of objects) into smaller
      collections; as, to part one's hair in the middle.
      [PJC]

   {To part a cable} (Naut.), to break it.

   {To part company}, to separate, as travelers or companions.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>part</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Part \Part\, adv.
   Partly; in a measure. [R.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>part</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>part
     n 1: something determined in relation to something that includes
          it; "he wanted to feel a part of something bigger than
          himself"; "I read a portion of the manuscript"; "the
          smaller component is hard to reach" [syn: {portion}, {component
          part}, {component}]
     2: the extended spatial location of something; "the farming
        regions of France"; "religions in all parts of the world";
        "regions of outer space" [syn: {region}]
     3: so far as concerns the actor specified; "it requires
        vigilance on our part" or "they resisted every effort on
        his part";
     4: something less than the whole of a human artifact; "the rear
        part of the house"; "glue the two parts together" [syn: {portion}]
     5: one of the portions into which something is regarded as
        divided and which together constitute a whole; "the
        written part of the exam"; "the finance section of the
        company"; "the BBC's engineering division" [syn: {section},
         {division}]
     6: the actions and activities assigned to or required or
        expected of a person or group; "the function of a
        teacher"; "the government must do its part"; "play its
        role" [syn: {function}, {office}, {role}]
     7: a portion of a natural object; "they analyzed the river into
        three parts"; "he needed a piece of granite" [syn: {piece}]
     8: an actor's portrayal of someone in a play; "she played the
        part of Desdemona" [syn: {character}, {role}, {theatrical
        role}, {persona}]
     9: assets belonging to or due to or contributed by an
        individual person or group; "he wanted his share in cash"
        [syn: {share}, {portion}, {percentage}]
     10: any one of a number of individual efforts in a common
         endeavor; "I am proud of my contribution to the team's
         success"; "they all did their share of the work" [syn: {contribution},
          {share}]
     11: the melody carried by a particular voice or instrument in
         polyphonic music; "he tried to sing the tenor part" [syn:
          {voice}]
     12: a line where the hair is parted; "his part was right in the
         middle"
     adv : in part; in some degree; not wholly; "I felt partly to
           blame"; "He was partially paralyzed" [syn: {partially},
            {partly}] [ant: {wholly}]
     v 1: go one's own away; move apart; "The friends separated after
          the party" [syn: {separate}, {split}]
     2: discontinue an association or relation; go different ways;
        "The business partners broke over a tax question"; "The
        couple separated after 25 years of marriage"; "My friend
        and I split up" [syn: {separate}, {split up}, {split}, {break},
         {break up}]
     3: leave; "The family took off for Florida" [syn: {depart}, {start},
         {start out}, {set forth}, {set off}, {set out}, {take off}]
     4: come apart; "The two pieces that we had glued separated"
        [syn: {separate}, {divide}]
     5: force, take, or pull apart; "He separated the fighting
        children"; "Moses parted the Red Sea" [syn: {separate}, {disunite},
         {divide}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
