<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>passion</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Passion
   Only once found, in Acts 1:3, meaning suffering, referring to
   the sufferings of our Lord.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Passion \Pas"sion\, n. [F., fr. L. passio, fr. pati, passus, to
   suffer. See {Patient}.]
   1. A suffering or enduring of imposed or inflicted pain; any
      suffering or distress (as, a cardiac passion);
      specifically, the suffering of Christ between the time of
      the last supper and his death, esp. in the garden upon the
      cross. ``The passions of this time.'' --Wyclif (Rom. viii.
      18).
      [1913 Webster]

            To whom also he showed himself alive after his
            passion, by many infallible proofs.   --Acts i. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being acted upon; subjection to an external
      agent or influence; a passive condition; -- opposed to
      action.
      [1913 Webster]

            A body at rest affords us no idea of any active
            power to move, and, when set is motion, it is rather
            a passion than an action in it.       --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Capacity of being affected by external agents;
      susceptibility of impressions from external agents. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Moldable and not moldable, scissible and not
            scissible, and many other passions of matter.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The state of the mind when it is powerfully acted upon and
      influenced by something external to itself; the state of
      any particular faculty which, under such conditions,
      becomes extremely sensitive or uncontrollably excited; any
      emotion or sentiment (specifically, love or anger) in a
      state of abnormal or controlling activity; an extreme or
      inordinate desire; also, the capacity or susceptibility of
      being so affected; as, to be in a passion; the passions of
      love, hate, jealously, wrath, ambition, avarice, fear,
      etc.; a passion for war, or for drink; an orator should
      have passion as well as rhetorical skill. ``A passion fond
      even to idolatry.'' --Macaulay. ``Her passion is to seek
      roses.'' --Lady M. W. Montagu.
      [1913 Webster]

            We also are men of like passions with you. --Acts
                                                  xiv. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

            The nature of the human mind can not be sufficiently
            understood, without considering the affections and
            passions, or those modifications or actions of the
            mind consequent upon the apprehension of certain
            objects or events in which the mind generally
            conceives good or evil.               --Hutcheson.
      [1913 Webster]

            The term passion, and its adverb passionately, often
            express a very strong predilection for any pursuit,
            or object of taste -- a kind of enthusiastic
            fondness for anything.                --Cogan.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bravery of his grief did put me
            Into a towering passion.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The ruling passion, be it what it will,
            The ruling passion conquers reason still. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who walked in every path of human life,
            Felt every passion.                   --Akenside.
      [1913 Webster]

            When statesmen are ruled by faction and interest,
            they can have no passion for the glory of their
            country.                              --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Disorder of the mind; madness. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Passion week. See {Passion week}, below. --R. of Gl.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Passion flower} (Bot.), any flower or plant of the genus
      {Passiflora}; -- so named from a fancied resemblance of
      parts of the flower to the instruments of our Savior's
      crucifixion.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The flowers are showy, and the fruit is sometimes
         highly esteemed (see {Granadilla}, and {Maypop}). The
         roots and leaves are generally more or less noxious,
         and are used in medicine. The plants are mostly tendril
         climbers, and are commonest in the warmer parts of
         America, though a few species are Asiatic or
         Australian.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Passion music} (Mus.), originally, music set to the gospel
      narrative of the passion of our Lord; after the
      Reformation, a kind of oratorio, with narrative, chorals,
      airs, and choruses, having for its theme the passion and
      crucifixion of Christ.

   {Passion play}, a mystery play, in which the scenes connected
      with the passion of our Savior are represented
      dramatically.

   {Passion Sunday} (Eccl.), the fifth Sunday in Lent, or the
      second before Easter.

   {Passion Week}, the last week but one in Lent, or the second
      week preceding Easter. ``The name of Passion week is
      frequently, but improperly, applied to Holy Week.''
      --Shipley.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: {Passion}, {Feeling}, {Emotion}.

   Usage: When any feeling or emotion completely masters the
          mind, we call it a passion; as, a passion for music,
          dress, etc.; especially is anger (when thus extreme)
          called passion. The mind, in such cases, is considered
          as having lost its self-control, and become the
          passive instrument of the feeling in question.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Passion \Pas"sion\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Passioned}; p. pr &amp; vb.
   n. {Passioning}.]
   To give a passionate character to. [R.] --Keats.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Passion \Pas"sion\, v. i.
   To suffer pain or sorrow; to experience a passion; to be
   extremely agitated. [Obs.] ``Dumbly she passions, frantically
   she doteth.'' --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passion</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>passion
     n 1: strong feeling or emotion [syn: {passionateness}]
     2: intense passion or emotion [syn: {heat}, {warmth}]
     3: something that is desired intensely; "his rage for fame
        destroyed him" [syn: {rage}]
     4: an irrational but irresistible motive for a belief or action
        [syn: {mania}, {cacoethes}]
     5: a feeling of strong sexual desire
     6: any object of warm affection or devotion; "the theater was
        her first love" or "he has a passion for cock fighting";
        [syn: {love}]
     7: the suffering of Jesus at the crucifixion [syn: {Passion of
        Christ}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
