<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>passive</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Passive \Pas"sive\, a. [L. passivus: cf. F. passif. See
   {Passion}.]
   1. Not active, but acted upon; suffering or receiving
      impressions or influences; as, they were passive
      spectators, not actors in the scene.
      [1913 Webster]

            The passive air
            Upbore their nimble tread.            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The mind is wholly passive in the reception of all
            its simple ideas.                     --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Receiving or enduring without either active sympathy or
      active resistance; without emotion or excitement; patient;
      not opposing; unresisting; as, passive obedience; passive
      submission.
      [1913 Webster]

            The best virtue, passive fortitude.   --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Chem.) Inactive; inert; not showing strong affinity; as,
      red phosphorus is comparatively passive.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Med.) Designating certain morbid conditions, as
      hemorrhage or dropsy, characterized by relaxation of the
      vessels and tissues, with deficient vitality and lack of
      reaction in the affected tissues.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Passive congestion} (Med.), congestion due to obstruction to
      the return of the blood from the affected part.

   {Passive iron} (Chem.), iron which has been subjected to the
      action of heat, of strong nitric acid, chlorine, etc. It
      is then not easily acted upon by acids.

   {Passive movement} (Med.), a movement of a part, in order to
      exercise it, made without the assistance of the muscles
      which ordinarily move the part.

   {Passive obedience} (as used by writers on government),
      obedience or submission of the subject or citizen as a
      duty in all cases to the existing government.

   {Passive prayer}, among mystic divines, a suspension of the
      activity of the soul or intellectual faculties, the soul
      remaining quiet, and yielding only to the impulses of
      grace.

   {Passive verb}, or {Passive voice} (Gram.), a verb, or form
      of a verb, which expresses the effect of the action of
      some agent; as, in Latin, doceor, I am taught; in English,
      she is loved; the picture is admired by all; he is
      assailed by slander.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Inactive; inert; quiescent; unresisting; unopposing;
        suffering; enduring; submissive; patient.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>passive
     adj 1: lacking in energy or will; "Much benevolence of the passive
            order may be traced to a disinclination to inflict
            pain upon oneself"- George Meredith [syn: {inactive}]
            [ant: {active}]
     2: peacefully resistant in response to injustice; "passive
        resistance" [syn: {peaceful}]
     3: expressing thatthe subject of the sentence is the patient of
        the action denoted by the verb; "academics seem to favor
        passive sentences" [ant: {active}]
     n : the voice used to indicate that the grammatical subject of
         the verb is the recipient (not the source) of the action
         denoted by the verb; "`The ball was thrown by the boy'
         uses the passive voice"; "`The ball was thrown' is an
         abbreviated passive" [syn: {passive voice}] [ant: {active
         voice}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
