<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>passed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>passed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pass \Pass\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Passed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Passing}.] [F. passer, LL. passare, fr. L. passus step, or
   from pandere, passum, to spread out, lay open. See {Pace}.]
   1. To go; to move; to proceed; to be moved or transferred
      from one point to another; to make a transit; -- usually
      with a following adverb or adverbal phrase defining the
      kind or manner of motion; as, to pass on, by, out, in,
      etc.; to pass swiftly, directly, smoothly, etc.; to pass
      to the rear, under the yoke, over the bridge, across the
      field, beyond the border, etc. ``But now pass over [i. e.,
      pass on].'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            On high behests his angels to and fro
            Passed frequent.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sweet sounds rose slowly through their mouths,
            And from their bodies passed.         --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move or be transferred from one state or condition to
      another; to change possession, condition, or
      circumstances; to undergo transition; as, the business has
      passed into other hands.
      [1913 Webster]

            Others, dissatisfied with what they have, . . . pass
            from just to unjust.                  --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To move beyond the range of the senses or of knowledge; to
      pass away; hence, to disappear; to vanish; to depart;
      specifically, to depart from life; to die.
      [1913 Webster]

            Disturb him not, let him pass paceably. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Beauty is a charm, but soon the charm will pass.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            The passing of the sweetest soul
            That ever looked with human eyes.     --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To move or to come into being or under notice; to come and
      go in consciousness; hence, to take place; to occur; to
      happen; to come; to occur progressively or in succession;
      to be present transitorily.
      [1913 Webster]

            So death passed upon all men.         --Rom. v. 12.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our own consciousness of what passes within our own
            mind.                                 --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To go by or glide by, as time; to elapse; to be spent; as,
      their vacation passed pleasantly.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now the time is far passed.           --Mark vi. 35
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To go from one person to another; hence, to be given and
      taken freely; as, clipped coin will not pass; to obtain
      general acceptance; to be held or regarded; to circulate;
      to be current; -- followed by for before a word denoting
      value or estimation. ``Let him pass for a man.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            False eloquence passeth only where true is not
            understood.                           --Felton.
      [1913 Webster]

            This will not pass for a fault in him. --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To advance through all the steps or stages necessary to
      validity or effectiveness; to be carried through a body
      that has power to sanction or reject; to receive
      legislative sanction; to be enacted; as, the resolution
      passed; the bill passed both houses of Congress.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To go through any inspection or test successfully; to be
      approved or accepted; as, he attempted the examination,
      but did not expect to pass.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To be suffered to go on; to be tolerated; hence, to
      continue; to live along. ``The play may pass.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To go unheeded or neglected; to proceed without hindrance
       or opposition; as, we let this act pass.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To go beyond bounds; to surpass; to be in excess. [Obs.]
       ``This passes, Master Ford.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To take heed; to care. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

             As for these silken-coated slaves, I pass not.
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To go through the intestines. --Arbuthnot.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Law) To be conveyed or transferred by will, deed, or
       other instrument of conveyance; as, an estate passes by a
       certain clause in a deed. --Mozley &amp; W.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Fencing) To make a lunge or pass; to thrust.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. (Card Playing) To decline to play in one's turn; in
       euchre, to decline to make the trump.
       [1913 Webster]

             She would not play, yet must not pass. --Prior.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To bring to pass}, {To come to pass}. See under {Bring}, and
      {Come}.

   {To pass away}, to disappear; to die; to vanish. ``The
      heavens shall pass away.'' --2 Pet. iii. 10. ``I thought
      to pass away before, but yet alive I am.'' --Tennyson.

   {To pass by}, to go near and beyond a certain person or
      place; as, he passed by as we stood there.

   {To pass into}, to change by a gradual transmission; to blend
      or unite with.

   {To pass on}, to proceed.

   {To pass on} or {To pass upon}.
       (a) To happen to; to come upon; to affect. ``So death
           passed upon all men.'' --Rom. v. 12. ``Provided no
           indirect act pass upon our prayers to define them.''
           --Jer. Taylor.
       (b) To determine concerning; to give judgment or sentence
           upon. ``We may not pass upon his life.'' --Shak.

   {To pass off}, to go away; to cease; to disappear; as, an
      agitation passes off.

   {To pass over}, to go from one side or end to the other; to
      cross, as a river, road, or bridge.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
