<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>patternmatching</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>patternmatching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pattern matching
     
        1. A function is defined to take arguments of a particular
        type, form or value.  When applying the function to its actual
        arguments it is necessary to match the type, form or value of
        the actual arguments against the formal arguments in some
        definition.  For example, the function
     
        	length []     = 0
        	length (x:xs) = 1 + length xs
     
        uses pattern matching in its argument to distinguish a null
        list from a non-null one.
     
        There are well known {algorithm} for translating pattern
        matching into conditional expressions such as "if" or "case".
        E.g. the above function could be transformed to
     
        	length l = case l of
        		   []   -&gt; 0
        		   x:xs -&gt; 1 : length xs
     
        Pattern matching is usually performed in textual order though
        there are languages which match more specific patterns before
        less specific ones.
     
        2. Descriptive of a type of language or utility such as {awk}
        or {Perl} which is suited to searching for strings or patterns
        in input data, usually using some kind of {regular
        expression}.
     
        (1994-11-28)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>patternmatching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pattern matching \Pat"tern match"ing\, n. [See {pattern}.]
   a technique in automated data analysis, usually performed on
   a computer, by which a group of characteristic properties of
   an unknown object is compared with the comparable groups of
   characteristics of a set of known objects, to discover the
   idenity or proper classification of the unknown object.

   Note: There are two major types of pattern matching,
         statistical pattern matching and syntactic pattern
         matching. In statistical pattern matching, the criteria
         used to recognize identity or class membership vary,
         but in general some combination of the differences in
         the groups of characteristics of known and unknown
         objects are considered to be a measure of the
         difference ("distance") between them, and the closest
         known object or objects are viewed as presenting the
         most likely identity or class for the unknown object.
         In syntactic pattern matching, a set of known patterns,
         e.g. as in the possible order of parts of speech in a
         language, is defined, and the unknown pattern is
         compared to find that known pattern or patterns which
         matches the unknown exactly. In general, statistical
         pattern matching is used where properties of objects
         with continuous values are being compared, and
         syntactic pattern matching where a complex arrangement
         of at least two different objects may be built by
         application of a set of rules (a "grammar") for
         combining the objects in a specified order. Examples of
         the latter are natural and formal languages.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
