<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pay</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pay</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pay \Pay\, v. t. [OF. peier, fr. L. picare to pitch, i? pitch:
   cf. OF. peiz pitch, F. poix. See {Pitch} a black substance.]
   (Naut.)
   To cover, as bottom of a vessel, a seam, a spar, etc., with
   tar or pitch, or waterproof composition of tallow, resin,
   etc.; to smear.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pay</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pay \Pay\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Paid}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Paying}.] [OE. paien, F. payer, fr. L. pacare to pacify,
   appease, fr. pax, pacis, peace. See {Peace}.]
   1. To satisfy, or content; specifically, to satisfy (another
      person) for service rendered, property delivered, etc.; to
      discharge one's obligation to; to make due return to; to
      compensate; to remunerate; to recompense; to requite; as,
      to pay workmen or servants.
      [1913 Webster]

            May no penny ale them pay [i. e., satisfy]. --P.
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            [She] pays me with disdain.           --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, figuratively: To compensate justly; to requite
      according to merit; to reward; to punish; to retort or
      retaliate upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            For which, or pay me quickly, or I'll pay you. --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To discharge, as a debt, demand, or obligation, by giving
      or doing what is due or required; to deliver the amount or
      value of to the person to whom it is owing; to discharge a
      debt by delivering (money owed). ``Pay me that thou
      owest.'' --Matt. xviii. 28.
      [1913 Webster]

            Have patience with me, and I will pay thee all.
                                                  --Matt. xviii.
                                                  26.
      [1913 Webster]

            If they pay this tax, they starve.    --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To discharge or fulfill, as a duy; to perform or render
      duty, as that which has been promised.
      [1913 Webster]

            This day have I paid my vows.         --Prov. vii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To give or offer, without an implied obligation; as, to
      pay attention; to pay a visit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not paying me a welcome.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pay off}.
      (a) To make compensation to and discharge; as, to pay off
          the crew of a ship.
      (b) To allow (a thread, cord, etc.) to run off; to unwind.
          

   {To pay one's duty}, to render homage, as to a sovereign or
      other superior.

   {To pay out} (Naut.), to pass out; hence, to slacken; to
      allow to run out; as, to pay out more cable. See under
      {Cable}.

   {To pay the piper}, to bear the cost, expense, or trouble.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pay</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pay \Pay\ (p[=a]), v. i.
   To give a recompense; to make payment, requital, or
   satisfaction; to discharge a debt.
   [1913 Webster]

         The wicked borroweth, and payeth not again. --Ps.
                                                  xxxvii. 21.
   [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to make or secure suitable return for expense or
      trouble; to be remunerative or profitable; to be worth the
      effort or pains required; as, it will pay to ride; it will
      pay to wait; politeness always pays.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pay for}.
      (a) To make amends for; to atone for; as, men often pay
          for their mistakes with loss of property or
          reputation, sometimes with life.
      (b) To give an equivalent for; to bear the expense of; to
          be mulcted on account of.
          [1913 Webster]

                'T was I paid for your sleeps; I watched your
                wakings.                          --Beau. &amp; Fl.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To pay off}. [Etymol. uncertain.] (Naut.) To fall to
      leeward, as the head of a vessel under sail.

   {To pay on}. [Etymol. uncertain.] To beat with vigor; to
      redouble blows. [Colloq.]

   {To pay round} [Etymol. uncertain.] (Naut.) To turn the
      ship's head.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pay</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pay \Pay\, n.
   1. Satisfaction; content. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An equivalent or return for money due, goods purchased, or
      services performed; salary or wages for work or service;
      compensation; recompense; payment; hire; as, the pay of a
      clerk; the pay of a soldier.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where only merit constant pay receives. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is neither pay nor plunder to be got.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Full pay}, the whole amount of wages or salary; maximum pay;
      especially, the highest pay or allowance to civil or
      military officers of a certain rank, without deductions.
      

   {Half pay}. See under {Half}.

   {Pay day}, the day of settlement of accounts.

   {Pay dirt} (Mining), earth which yields a profit to the
      miner. [Western U.S.]

   {Pay office}, a place where payment is made.

   {Pay roll}, a roll or list of persons entitled to payment,
      with the amounts due.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pay</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pay
     n : something that remunerates; "wages were paid by check"; "he
         wasted his pay on drink"; "they saved a quarter of all
         their earnings" [syn: {wage}, {earnings}, {remuneration},
          {salary}]
     v 1: give money, usually in exchange for goods or services; "I
          paid four dollars for this sandwich"; "Pay the waitress,
          please"
     2: convey, as of a compliment, regards, attention, etc.;
        bestow; "Don't pay him any mind"; "give the orders"; "Give
        him my best regards"; "pay attention" [syn: {give}]
     3: do or give something to somebody in return; "Does she pay
        you for the work you are doing?" [syn: {pay off}, {make up},
         {compensate}]
     4: bear (a cost or penalty), in recompense for some action;
        "You'll pay for this!"; "She had to pay the penalty for
        speaking out rashly"; "You'll pay for this opinion later"
     5: cancel or discharge a debt; "pay up, please!" [syn: {pay up},
         {ante up}] [ant: {default}]
     6: bring in; "interest-bearing accounts"; "How much does this
        savings certificate pay annually?" [syn: {yield}, {bear}]
     7: render; "pay a visit"; "pay a call"
     8: be worth it; "It pays to go through the trouble"
     9: dedicate; "give thought to"; "give priority to"; "pay
        attention to" [syn: {give}, {devote}]
     10: discharge or settle; "pay a debt"; "pay an obligation"
     11: make a compensation for; "a favor that cannot be paid back"
     [also: {paid}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
