<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>paying</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pay \Pay\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Paid}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Paying}.] [OE. paien, F. payer, fr. L. pacare to pacify,
   appease, fr. pax, pacis, peace. See {Peace}.]
   1. To satisfy, or content; specifically, to satisfy (another
      person) for service rendered, property delivered, etc.; to
      discharge one's obligation to; to make due return to; to
      compensate; to remunerate; to recompense; to requite; as,
      to pay workmen or servants.
      [1913 Webster]

            May no penny ale them pay [i. e., satisfy]. --P.
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            [She] pays me with disdain.           --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, figuratively: To compensate justly; to requite
      according to merit; to reward; to punish; to retort or
      retaliate upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            For which, or pay me quickly, or I'll pay you. --B.
                                                  Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To discharge, as a debt, demand, or obligation, by giving
      or doing what is due or required; to deliver the amount or
      value of to the person to whom it is owing; to discharge a
      debt by delivering (money owed). ``Pay me that thou
      owest.'' --Matt. xviii. 28.
      [1913 Webster]

            Have patience with me, and I will pay thee all.
                                                  --Matt. xviii.
                                                  26.
      [1913 Webster]

            If they pay this tax, they starve.    --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To discharge or fulfill, as a duy; to perform or render
      duty, as that which has been promised.
      [1913 Webster]

            This day have I paid my vows.         --Prov. vii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To give or offer, without an implied obligation; as, to
      pay attention; to pay a visit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not paying me a welcome.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pay off}.
      (a) To make compensation to and discharge; as, to pay off
          the crew of a ship.
      (b) To allow (a thread, cord, etc.) to run off; to unwind.
          

   {To pay one's duty}, to render homage, as to a sovereign or
      other superior.

   {To pay out} (Naut.), to pass out; hence, to slacken; to
      allow to run out; as, to pay out more cable. See under
      {Cable}.

   {To pay the piper}, to bear the cost, expense, or trouble.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>paying</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>paying
     adj 1: yielding a fair profit [syn: {gainful}, {paid}]
     2: for which money is paid; "a paying job"; "remunerative
        work"; "salaried employment"; "stipendiary services" [syn:
         {compensable}, {paying(a)}, {remunerative}, {salaried}, {stipendiary}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
