<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>penicillin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>penicillin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>penicillin \pen`i*cil"lin\, n. [From Penicillium, the fungus
   genus from which it was first isolated.] (Chem.)
   Any of a variety of substances having a structure containing
   a beta-lactam ring fused to a thiirane ring, to which a
   carboxyl group is attached, most commonly referring to
   {benzyl penicillin}. They are notable as powerful
   antibacterial agents of relatively low toxicity which have
   found extensive use in medicine for treating bacterial
   infections. They are categorized as one of the classes of
   beta-lactam antibiotic. They are produced naturally by some
   fungi and bacteria, and industrial production processes
   almost invariably start from some form of the penicillin
   nucleus produced by fermentation of microorganisms. The
   fermentation products are then chemically modified to produce
   derivatives of enhanced potency, safety, or antibacterial
   spectrum. The first penicillin to see extensive use
   clinically (during World War II) was {penicillin G}, also
   called {benzypenicillin}, and commonly simply ``penicillin''.
   [PJC]

   Note: [hand]The characteristic portion of the structure
         characterizing a penicillin is the bicyclic structure
         3,3-Dimethyl-7-oxo-4-thia-1-azabicylo[3.2.0]heptane-2-carboxylic
         acid. The different penicillins have varying acyl
         groups forming an amide bond with a nitrogen attached
         to the 6-carbon of this nucleus. This distinguishes it
         from the other classes of beta-lactam antibiotic, the
         {cephalosporins}, {thienamycins} and {sulfazecin}.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>penicillin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lactam \Lac"tam\, n. [Lactone + amido.] (Chem.)
   One of a series of anhydrides of an amido type, analogous to
   the lactones, as oxindol; a cyclic amide.
   [1913 Webster]

   {beta-lactam} or {[beta]-lactam},
   (a) a lactam in which the amide bond is contained within a
       four-membered ring, which includes the amide nitrogen and
       the carbonyl carbon.
   (b) an antibiotic containing a beta-lactam, such as a
       {penicillin}, {cephalosporin}, or {carbapenem}; also
       called a {beta-lactam antibiotic}. [informal, laboratory
       slang]
       [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>penicillin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>penicillin
     n : any of various antibiotics obtained from penicillium molds
         (or produced synthetically) and used in the treatment of
         various infections and diseases
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
