<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>perceived</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>perceived</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Perceive \Per*ceive"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Perceived}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Perceiving}.] [OF. percevoir, perceveir, L.
   percipere, perceptum; per (see {Per-}) + capere to take,
   receive. See {Capacious}, and cf. {Perception}.]
   1. To obtain knowledge of through the senses; to receive
      impressions from by means of the bodily organs; to take
      cognizance of the existence, character, or identity of, by
      means of the senses; to see, hear, or feel; as, to
      perceive a distant ship; to perceive a discord. --Reid.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take intellectual cognizance of; to apprehend by the
      mind; to be convinced of by direct intuition; to note; to
      remark; to discern; to see; to understand.
      [1913 Webster]

            Jesus perceived their wickedness.     --Matt. xxii.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

            You may, fair lady,
            Perceive I speak sincerely.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Till we ourselves see it with our own eyes, and
            perceive it by our own understandings, we are still
            in the dark.                          --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To be affected of influented by. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The upper regions of the air perceive the collection
            of the matter of tempests before the air here below.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To discern; distinguish; observe; see; feel; know;
        understand.

   Usage: To {Perceive}, {Discern}. To perceive a thing is to
          apprehend it as presented to the senses or the
          intellect; to discern is to mark differences, or to
          see a thing as distinguished from others around it. We
          may perceive two persons afar off without being able
          to discern whether they are men or women. Hence,
          discern is often used of an act of the senses or the
          mind involving close, discriminating, analytical
          attention. We perceive that which is clear or obvious;
          we discern that which requires much attention to get
          an idea of it. ``We perceive light, darkness, colors,
          or the truth or falsehood of anything. We discern
          characters, motives, the tendency and consequences of
          actions, etc.'' --Crabb.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>perceived</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>perceived
     adj 1: detected by instinct or inference rather than by recognized
            perceptual cues; "the felt presence of an intruder";
            "a sensed presence in the room raised goosebumps on
            her arms"; "a perceived threat" [syn: {sensed}]
     2: detected by means of the senses; "a perceived difference in
        temperature"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
