<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>person</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>person</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Person \Per"son\, n. [OE. persone, persoun, person, parson, OF.
   persone, F. personne, L. persona a mask (used by actors), a
   personage, part, a person, fr. personare to sound through;
   per + sonare to sound. See {Per-}, and cf. {Parson}.]
   1. A character or part, as in a play; a specific kind or
      manifestation of individual character, whether in real
      life, or in literary or dramatic representation; an
      assumed character. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            His first appearance upon the stage in his new
            person of a sycophant or juggler.     --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            No man can long put on a person and act a part.
                                                  --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            To bear rule, which was thy part
            And person, hadst thou known thyself aright.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            How different is the same man from himself, as he
            sustains the person of a magistrate and that of a
            friend!                               --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The bodily form of a human being; body; outward
      appearance; as, of comely person.
      [1913 Webster]

            A fair persone, and strong, and young of age.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            If it assume my noble father's person. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Love, sweetness, goodness, in her person shined.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A living, self-conscious being, as distinct from an animal
      or a thing; a moral agent; a human being; a man, woman, or
      child.
      [1913 Webster]

            Consider what person stands for; which, I think, is
            a thinking, intelligent being, that has reason and
            reflection.                           --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A human being spoken of indefinitely; one; a man; as, any
      person present.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A parson; the parish priest. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Theol.) Among Trinitarians, one of the three subdivisions
      of the Godhead (the Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost);
      an hypostasis. ``Three persons and one God.'' --Bk. of
      Com. Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Gram.) One of three relations or conditions (that of
      speaking, that of being spoken to, and that of being
      spoken of) pertaining to a noun or a pronoun, and thence
      also to the verb of which it may be the subject.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A noun or pronoun, when representing the speaker, is
         said to be in the first person; when representing what
         is spoken to, in the second person; when representing
         what is spoken of, in the third person.
         [1913 Webster]

   8. (Biol.) A shoot or bud of a plant; a polyp or zooid of the
      compound Hydrozoa Anthozoa, etc.; also, an individual, in
      the narrowest sense, among the higher animals. --Haeckel.
      [1913 Webster]

            True corms, composed of united person[ae] . . .
            usually arise by gemmation, . . . yet in sponges and
            corals occasionally by fusion of several originally
            distinct persons.                     --Encyc. Brit.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Artificial person}, or {Fictitious person} (Law), a
      corporation or body politic; -- this term is used in
      contrast with {natural person}, a real human being. See
      also {legal person}. --Blackstone.

   {Legal person} (Law), an individual or group that is allowed
      by law to take legal action, as plaintiff or defendent. It
      may include natural persons as well as fictitious persons
      (such as corporations).

   {Natural person} (Law), a man, woman, or child, in
      distinction from a corporation.

   {In person}, by one's self; with bodily presence; not by
      representative. ``The king himself in person is set
      forth.'' --Shak.

   {In the person of}, in the place of; acting for. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>person</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Person \Per"son\, v. t.
   To represent as a person; to personify; to impersonate.
   [Obs.] --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>person</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>person
     n 1: a human being; "there was too much for one person to do"
          [syn: {individual}, {someone}, {somebody}, {mortal}, {human},
           {soul}]
     2: a person's body (usually including their clothing); "a
        weapon was hidden on his person"
     3: a grammatical category of pronouns and verb forms; "stop
        talking about yourself in the third person"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
