<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>perspective</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>perspective</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>perspective
     
        &lt;games&gt; In computer games, the {virtual} position from which
        the human player views the playing area.  There are three
        different perspectives: first person, second person, and third
        person.
     
        First person perspective: Viewing the world through the eyes
        of the primary character in three dimensions.  e.g. Doom,
        Quake.
     
        Second person perspective: Viewing the game through a
        spectator's eyes, in two or three dimensions.  Depending on
        the game, the main character is always in view. e.g. Super
        Mario Bros., Tomb Raider.
     
        Third person perspective: a point of view which is independent
        of where characters or playing units are.  The gaming world is
        viewed much as a satellite would view a battlefield.
        E.g. Warcraft, Command &amp; Conquer.
     
        (1997-06-19)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>perspective</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Perspective \Per*spec"tive\, a. [L. perspicere, perspectum, to
   look through; per + spicere, specere, to look: cf. F.
   perspectif; or from E. perspective, n. See {Spy}, n.]
   1. Of or pertaining to the science of vision; optical. [Obs.]
      --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Pertaining to the art, or in accordance with the laws, of
      perspective.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Perspective plane}, the plane or surface on which the
      objects are delineated, or the picture drawn; the plane of
      projection; -- distinguished from the ground plane, which
      is that on which the objects are represented as standing.
      When this plane is oblique to the principal face of the
      object, the perspective is called oblique perspective;
      when parallel to that face, parallel perspective.

   {Perspective shell} (Zo["o]l.), any shell of the genus
      {Solarium} and allied genera. See {Solarium}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>perspective</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Perspective \Per*spec"tive\, n. [F. perspective, fr. perspectif:
   cf. It. perspettiva. See {Perspective}, a.]
   1. A glass through which objects are viewed. [Obs.] ``Not a
      perspective, but a mirror.'' --Sir T. Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is seen through an opening; a view; a vista.
      ``The perspective of life.'' --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The effect of distance upon the appearance of objects, by
      means of which the eye recognized them as being at a more
      or less measurable distance. Hence, a["e]rial perspective,
      the assumed greater vagueness or uncertainty of outline in
      distant objects.
      [1913 Webster]

            A["e]rial perspective is the expression of space by
            any means whatsoever, sharpness of edge, vividness
            of color, etc.                        --Ruskin.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The art and the science of so delineating objects that
      they shall seem to grow smaller as they recede from the
      eye; -- called also {linear perspective}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A drawing in linear perspective.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Isometrical perspective}, an inaccurate term for a
      mechanical way of representing objects in the direction of
      the diagonal of a cube.

   {Perspective glass}, a telescope which shows objects in the
      right position.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>perspective</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>perspective
     n 1: a way of regarding situations or topics etc.; "consider what
          follows from the positivist view" [syn: {position}, {view}]
     2: the appearance of things relative to one another as
        determined by their distance from the viewer [syn: {linear
        perspective}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
