<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>phase</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>phase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>phase
     
        1. The offset of one's waking-sleeping schedule with respect
        to the standard 24-hour cycle; a useful concept among people
        who often work at night and/or according to no fixed schedule.
        It is not uncommon to change one's phase by as much as 6 hours
        per day on a regular basis.  "What's your phase?"  "I've been
        getting in about 8 P.M. lately, but I'm going to {wrap around}
        to the day schedule by Friday."  A person who is roughly 12
        hours out of phase is sometimes said to be in "night mode".
        (The term "day mode" is also (but less frequently) used,
        meaning you're working 9 to 5 (or, more likely, 10 to 6).)
        The act of altering one's cycle is called "changing phase";
        "phase shifting" has also been recently reported from Caltech.
     
        2. "change phase the hard way": To stay awake for a very long
        time in order to get into a different phase.
     
        3. "change phase the easy way": To stay asleep, etc.  However,
        some claim that either staying awake longer or sleeping longer
        is easy, and that it is *shortening* your day or night that is
        really hard (see {wrap around}).  The "jet lag" that afflicts
        travelers who cross many time-zone boundaries may be
        attributed to two distinct causes: the strain of travel per
        se, and the strain of changing phase.  Hackers who suddenly
        find that they must change phase drastically in a short period
        of time, particularly the hard way, experience something very
        like jet lag without travelling.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>phase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Phase \Phase\ (f[=a]z), n.; pl. {Phases} (f[=a]z"[e^]z). [NL.
   phasis, Gr. ?, fr. ? to make to appear: cf. F. phase. See
   {Phenomenon}, {Phantom}, and {Emphasis}.]
   1. That which is exhibited to the eye; the appearance which
      anything manifests, especially any one among different and
      varying appearances of the same object.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any appearance or aspect of an object of mental
      apprehension or view; as, the problem has many phases.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Astron.) A particular appearance or state in a regularly
      recurring cycle of changes with respect to quantity of
      illumination or form of enlightened disk; as, the phases
      of the moon or planets. See Illust. under {Moon}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Physics) Any one point or portion in a recurring series
      of changes, as in the changes of motion of one of the
      particles constituting a wave or vibration; one portion of
      a series of such changes, in distinction from a contrasted
      portion, as the portion on one side of a position of
      equilibrium, in contrast with that on the opposite side.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Phys. Chem.) A homogenous, physically distinct portion of
      matter in a system not homogeneous; as, the three phases,
      ice, water, and aqueous vapor. A phase may be either a
      single chemical substance or a mixture, as of gases.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. (Zo["o]l.) In certain birds and mammals, one of two or
      more color variations characteristic of the species, but
      independent of the ordinary seasonal and sexual
      differences, and often also of age. Some of the herons
      which appear in white and colored phases, and certain
      squirrels which are sometimes uniformly blackish instead
      of the usual coloration, furnish examples. Color phases
      occur also in other animals, notably in butterflies.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. (Elec.) The relation at any instant of a periodically
      varying electric magnitude, as electro-motive force, a
      current, etc., to its initial value as expressed in
      factorial parts of the complete cycle. It is usually
      expressed in angular measure, the cycle beb four right
      angles, or 360[deg]. Such periodic variations are
      generally well represented by sine curves; and phase
      relations are shown by the relative positions of the
      crests and hollows of such curves. Magnitudes which have
      the same phase are said to be in phase.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. (Physics) the relation at any instant of any cyclically
      varying physical quantity, such as voltage in an A.C.
      circuit, an electromagnetic wave, a sound wave, or a
      rotating object, to its initial value as expressed as a
      fractional part of the complete cycle. It is usually
      expressed in angular measure, the complete cycle being
      360[deg].

   Note: The concept of phase is also applied generally to any
         periodically varying phenomenon, as the cycle of
         daylight. One person who speeps during the day and
         another who sleeps at noght may be said to be out of
         phase with each other.
         [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>phase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Phase \Phase\ (f[=a]z), v. t. [Cf. {Feeze}.]
   To disturb the composure of; to disconcert; to nonplus; -- an
   older spelling, now replaced by {faze}. [Colloq., Archaic]

   Syn: faze. [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>phase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>phase 1. n. The offset of one's waking-sleeping schedule with respect
   to the standard 24-hour cycle; a useful concept among people who often
   work at night and/or according to no fixed schedule. It is not uncommon
   to change one's phase by as much as 6 hours per day on a regular basis.
   "What's your phase?" "I've been getting in about 8 P.M. lately, but I'm
   going to {wrap around} to the day schedule by Friday." A person who is
   roughly 12 hours out of phase is sometimes said to be in `night mode'.
   (The term `day mode' is also (but less frequently) used, meaning you're
   working 9 to 5 (or, more likely, 10 to 6).) The act of altering one's
   cycle is called `changing phase'; `phase shifting' has also been
   recently reported from Caltech. 2. `change phase the hard way': To stay
   awake for a very long time in order to get into a different phase. 3.
   `change phase the easy way': To stay asleep, etc. However, some claim
   that either staying awake longer or sleeping longer is easy, and that it
   is _shortening_ your day or night that is really hard (see {wrap
   around}). The `jet lag' that afflicts travelers who cross many time-zone
   boundaries may be attributed to two distinct causes: the strain of
   travel per se, and the strain of changing phase. Hackers who suddenly
   find that they must change phase drastically in a short period of time,
   particularly the hard way, experience something very like jet lag
   without traveling.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>phase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>phase
     n 1: (physical chemistry) a distinct state of matter in a system;
          matter that is identical in chemical composition and
          physical state and separated from other material by the
          phase boundary; "the reaction occurs in the liquid phase
          of the system" [syn: {form}]
     2: any distinct time period in a sequence of events; "we are in
        a transitional stage in which many former ideas must be
        revised or rejected" [syn: {stage}]
     3: a particular point in the time of a cycle; measured from
        some arbitrary zero and expressed as an angle [syn: {phase
        angle}]
     4: (astronomy) the particular appearance of a body's state of
        illumination (especially one of the recurring shapes of
        the part of Earth's moon that is illuminated by the sun);
        "the full phase of the moon"
     v 1: arrange in phases or stages; "phase a withdrawal"
     2: adjust so as to be in a synchronized condition; "he phased
        the intake with the output of the machine"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
