<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>physical</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>physical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>physical
     
        &lt;jargon&gt; The opposite of {logical} in its jargon sense.
        Compare {real}, {virtual}, and {transparent}.
     
        It is said that what you can touch and see is real; what you
        can see but not touch is virtual; what you can touch but not
        see is transparent; and what you can neither touch nor see is
        probably imaginary.
     
        (2001-10-26)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>physical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Physical \Phys"ic*al\, a.
   1. Of or pertaining to nature (as including all created
      existences); in accordance with the laws of nature; also,
      of or relating to natural or material things, or to the
      bodily structure, as opposed to things mental, moral,
      spiritual, or imaginary; material; natural; as, armies and
      navies are the physical force of a nation; the body is the
      physical part of man.
      [1913 Webster]

            Labor, in the physical world, is . . . employed in
            putting objects in motion.            --J. S. Mill.
      [1913 Webster]

            A society sunk in ignorance, and ruled by mere
            physical force.                       --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of or pertaining to physics, or natural philosophy;
      treating of, or relating to, the causes and connections of
      natural phenomena; as, physical science; physical laws.
      ``Physical philosophy.'' --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Perceptible through a bodily or material organization;
      cognizable by the senses; external; as, the physical,
      opposed to chemical, characters of a mineral.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Of or pertaining to physic, or the art of medicine;
      medicinal; curative; healing; also, cathartic; purgative.
      [Obs.] ``Physical herbs.'' --Sir T. North.
      [1913 Webster]

            Is Brutus sick? and is it physical
            To walk unbraced, and suck up the humors
            Of the dank morning?                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Physical astronomy}, that part of astronomy which treats of
      the causes of the celestial motions; specifically, that
      which treats of the motions resulting from universal
      gravitation.

   {Physical education}, training of the bodily organs and
      powers with a view to the promotion of health and vigor.
      

   {Physical examination} (Med.), an examination of the bodily
      condition of a person.

   {Physical geography}. See under {Geography}.

   {Physical point}, an indefinitely small portion of matter; a
      point conceived as being without extension, yet having
      physical properties, as weight, inertia, momentum, etc.; a
      material point.

   {Physical signs} (Med.), the objective signs of the bodily
      state afforded by a physical examination.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>physical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>physical
     adj 1: involving the body as distinguished from the mind or spirit;
            "physical exercise"; "physical suffering"; "was sloppy
            about everything but her physical appearance" [ant: {mental}]
     2: relating to the sciences dealing with matter and energy;
        especially physics; "physical sciences"; "physical laws"
     3: having substance or material existence; perceptible to the
        senses; "a physical manifestation"; "surrounded by
        tangible objects" [syn: {tangible}, {touchable}]
     4: according with material things or natural laws (other than
        those peculiar to living matter); "a reflex response to
        physical stimuli"
     5: characterized by energetic bodily activity; "tennis is an
        active sport"; "a very physical dance performance" [syn: {active}]
     6: concerned with material things; "physical properties"; "the
        physical characteristics of the earth"; "the physical size
        of a computer"
     7: impelled by physical force especially against resistance;
        "forcible entry"; "a real cop would get physical";
        "strong-arm tactics" [syn: {forcible}, {strong-arm}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
