<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>picking</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>picking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pick \Pick\ (p[i^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Picked} (p[i^]kt); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Picking}.] [OE. picken, pikken, to prick, peck;
   akin to Icel. pikka, Sw. picka, Dan. pikke, D. pikken, G.
   picken, F. piquer, W. pigo. Cf. {Peck}, v., {Pike}, {Pitch}
   to throw.]
   1. To throw; to pitch. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            As high as I could pick my lance.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To peck at, as a bird with its beak; to strike at with
      anything pointed; to act upon with a pointed instrument;
      to pierce; to prick, as with a pin.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To separate or open by means of a sharp point or points;
      as, to pick matted wool, cotton, oakum, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To open (a lock) as by a wire.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To pull apart or away, especially with the fingers; to
      pluck; to gather, as fruit from a tree, flowers from the
      stalk, feathers from a fowl, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To remove something from with a pointed instrument, with
      the fingers, or with the teeth; as, to pick the teeth; to
      pick a bone; to pick a goose; to pick a pocket.
      [1913 Webster]

            Did you pick Master Slender's purse?  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He picks clean teeth, and, busy as he seems
            With an old tavern quill, is hungry yet. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To choose; to select; to separate as choice or desirable;
      to cull; as, to pick one's company; to pick one's way; --
      often with out. ``One man picked out of ten thousand.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To take up; esp., to gather from here and there; to
      collect; to bring together; as, to pick rags; -- often
      with up; as, to pick up a ball or stones; to pick up
      information.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To trim. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pick at}, to tease or vex by pertinacious annoyance.

   {To pick a bone with}. See under {Bone}.

   {To pick a thank}, to curry favor. [Obs.] --Robynson (More's
      Utopia).

   {To pick off}.
      (a) To pluck; to remove by picking.
      (b) To shoot or bring down, one by one; as, sharpshooters
          pick off the enemy.

   {To pick out}.
      (a) To mark out; to variegate; as, to pick out any dark
          stuff with lines or spots of bright colors.
      (b) To select from a number or quantity.

   {To pick to pieces}, to pull apart piece by piece; hence
      [Colloq.], to analyze; esp., to criticize in detail.

   {To pick a quarrel}, to give occasion of quarrel
      intentionally.

   {To pick up}.
      (a) To take up, as with the fingers.
      (b) To get by repeated efforts; to gather here and there;
          as, to pick up a livelihood; to pick up news.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>picking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Picking \Pick"ing\, n.
   1. The act of digging or breaking up, as with a pick.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of choosing, plucking, or gathering.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is, or may be, picked or gleaned.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Pilfering; also, that which is pilfered.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. The pulverized shells of oysters used in making walks.
      [Eng.] --Simmonds.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mining) Rough sorting of ore.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Overburned bricks. --Simmonds.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>picking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Picking \Pick"ing\, a.
   1. Done or made as with a pointed tool; as, a picking sound.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Nice; careful. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            was too warm on picking work to dwell. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Picking peg}. (Weaving) See {Picker}, n., 3.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>picking</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>picking
     n 1: the quantity of a crop that is harvested; "he sent the first
          picking of berries to the market"; "it was the biggest
          peach pick in years" [syn: {pick}]
     2: the act of picking (crops or fruit or hops etc.)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
