<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pick</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pick \Pick\ (p[i^]k), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Picked} (p[i^]kt); p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Picking}.] [OE. picken, pikken, to prick, peck;
   akin to Icel. pikka, Sw. picka, Dan. pikke, D. pikken, G.
   picken, F. piquer, W. pigo. Cf. {Peck}, v., {Pike}, {Pitch}
   to throw.]
   1. To throw; to pitch. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            As high as I could pick my lance.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To peck at, as a bird with its beak; to strike at with
      anything pointed; to act upon with a pointed instrument;
      to pierce; to prick, as with a pin.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To separate or open by means of a sharp point or points;
      as, to pick matted wool, cotton, oakum, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To open (a lock) as by a wire.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To pull apart or away, especially with the fingers; to
      pluck; to gather, as fruit from a tree, flowers from the
      stalk, feathers from a fowl, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To remove something from with a pointed instrument, with
      the fingers, or with the teeth; as, to pick the teeth; to
      pick a bone; to pick a goose; to pick a pocket.
      [1913 Webster]

            Did you pick Master Slender's purse?  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He picks clean teeth, and, busy as he seems
            With an old tavern quill, is hungry yet. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To choose; to select; to separate as choice or desirable;
      to cull; as, to pick one's company; to pick one's way; --
      often with out. ``One man picked out of ten thousand.''
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To take up; esp., to gather from here and there; to
      collect; to bring together; as, to pick rags; -- often
      with up; as, to pick up a ball or stones; to pick up
      information.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To trim. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pick at}, to tease or vex by pertinacious annoyance.

   {To pick a bone with}. See under {Bone}.

   {To pick a thank}, to curry favor. [Obs.] --Robynson (More's
      Utopia).

   {To pick off}.
      (a) To pluck; to remove by picking.
      (b) To shoot or bring down, one by one; as, sharpshooters
          pick off the enemy.

   {To pick out}.
      (a) To mark out; to variegate; as, to pick out any dark
          stuff with lines or spots of bright colors.
      (b) To select from a number or quantity.

   {To pick to pieces}, to pull apart piece by piece; hence
      [Colloq.], to analyze; esp., to criticize in detail.

   {To pick a quarrel}, to give occasion of quarrel
      intentionally.

   {To pick up}.
      (a) To take up, as with the fingers.
      (b) To get by repeated efforts; to gather here and there;
          as, to pick up a livelihood; to pick up news.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pick \Pick\, v. i.
   1. To eat slowly, sparingly, or by morsels; to nibble.
      [1913 Webster]

            Why stand'st thou picking? Is thy palate sore?
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To do anything nicely or carefully, or by attending to
      small things; to select something with care.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To steal; to pilfer. ``To keep my hands from picking and
      stealing.'' --Book of Com. Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pick up}, to improve by degrees; as, he is picking up in
      health or business. [Colloq. U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pick \Pick\, n. [F. pic a pickax, a pick. See {Pick}, and cf.
   {Pike}.]
   1. A sharp-pointed tool for picking; -- often used in
      composition; as, a toothpick; a picklock.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mining &amp; Mech.) A heavy iron tool, curved and sometimes
      pointed at both ends, wielded by means of a wooden handle
      inserted in the middle, -- used for digging ino the ground
      by quarrymen, roadmakers, etc.; also, a pointed hammer
      used for dressing millstones.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A pike or spike; the sharp point fixed in the center of a
      buckler. [Obs.] ``Take down my buckler . . . and grind the
      pick on 't.'' --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Choice; right of selection; as, to have one's pick; in cat
      breeding, the owner of a stud gets the pick of the litter.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            France and Russia have the pick of our stables.
                                                  --Ld. Lytton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence: That which would be picked or chosen first; the
      best; as, the pick of the flock.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Print.) A particle of ink or paper imbedded in the hollow
      of a letter, filling up its face, and occasioning a spot
      on a printed sheet. --MacKellar.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Painting) That which is picked in, as with a pointed
      pencil, to correct an unevenness in a picture.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Weaving) The blow which drives the shuttle, -- the rate
      of speed of a loom being reckoned as so many picks per
      minute; hence, in describing the fineness of a fabric, a
      weft thread; as, so many picks to an inch.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Pick dressing} (Arch.), in cut stonework, a facing made by a
      pointed tool, leaving the surface in little pits or
      depressions.

   {Pick hammer}, a pick with one end sharp and the other blunt,
      used by miners.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pick</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pick
     n 1: the person or thing chosen or selected; "he was my pick for
          mayor" [syn: {choice}, {selection}]
     2: the quantity of a crop that is harvested; "he sent the first
        picking of berries to the market"; "it was the biggest
        peach pick in years" [syn: {picking}]
     3: the best people or things in a group; "the cream of
        England's young men were killed in the Great War" [syn: {cream}]
     4: the yarn woven across the warp yarn in weaving [syn: {woof},
         {weft}, {filling}]
     5: a small thin device (of metal or plastic or ivory) used to
        pluck a stringed instrument [syn: {plectrum}, {plectron}]
     6: a thin sharp implement used for picking; "he used a pick to
        clean dirt out of the cracks"
     7: a heavy iron tool with a wooden handle and a curved head
        that is pointed on both ends; "they used picks and sledges
        to break the rocks" [syn: {pickax}, {pickaxe}]
     8: a basketball maneuver; obstructing an opponent with one's
        body; "he was called for setting an illegal pick"
     9: the act of choosing or selecting; "your choice of colors was
        unfortunate"; "you can take your pick" [syn: {choice}, {selection},
         {option}]
     v 1: select carefully from a group; "She finally picked her
          successor"; "He picked his way carefully"
     2: look for and gather; "pick mushrooms"; "pick flowers" [syn:
        {pluck}, {cull}]
     3: harass with constant criticism; "Don't always pick on your
        little brother" [syn: {blame}, {find fault}]
     4: provoke; "pick a fight or a quarrel"
     5: remove in small bits; "pick meat from a bone"
     6: remove unwanted substances from, such as feathers or pits;
        "Clean the turkey" [syn: {clean}]
     7: pilfer or rob; "pick pockets"
     8: pay for something; "pick up the tab"; "pick up the burden of
        high-interest mortgages"; "foot the bill" [syn: {foot}]
     9: pull lightly but sharply with a plucking motion; "he plucked
        the strings of his mandolin" [syn: {pluck}, {plunk}]
     10: attack with or as if with a pickaxe of ice or rocky ground,
         for example; "Pick open the ice" [syn: {break up}]
     11: hit lightly with a picking motion [syn: {peck}, {beak}]
     12: eat intermittently; take small bites of; "He pieced at the
         sandwich all morning"; "She never eats a full meal--she
         just nibbles" [syn: {nibble}, {piece}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
