<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PIN
     
        {Personal Identification Number}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pin \Pin\, v. t. (Metal Working)
   To peen.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pin \Pin\, v. t. [Cf. {Pen} to confine, or {Pinfold}.]
   To inclose; to confine; to pen; to pound.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pin \Pin\, n. [OE. pinne, AS. pinn a pin, peg; cf. D. pin, G.
   pinne, Icel. pinni, W. pin, Gael. &amp; Ir. pinne; all fr. L.
   pinna a pinnacle, pin, feather, perhaps orig. a different
   word from pinna feather. Cf. {Fin} of a fish, {Pen} a
   feather.]
   1. A piece of wood, metal, etc., generally cylindrical, used
      for fastening separate articles together, or as a support
      by which one article may be suspended from another; a peg;
      a bolt.
      [1913 Webster]

            With pins of adamant
            And chains they made all fast.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, a small, pointed and headed piece of brass or
      other wire (commonly tinned), largely used for fastening
      clothes, attaching papers, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, a thing of small value; a trifle.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . did not care a pin for her.  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which resembles a pin in its form or use; as:
      (a) A peg in musical instruments, for increasing or
          relaxing the tension of the strings.
      (b) A linchpin.
      (c) A rolling-pin.
      (d) A clothespin.
      (e) (Mach.) A short shaft, sometimes forming a bolt, a
          part of which serves as a journal. See Illust. of
          {Knuckle joint}, under {Knuckle}.
      (f) (Joinery) The tenon of a dovetail joint.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. One of a row of pegs in the side of an ancient drinking
      cup to mark how much each man should drink.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The bull's eye, or center, of a target; hence, the center.
      [Obs.] ``The very pin of his heart cleft.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Mood; humor. [Obs.] ``In merry pin.'' --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Med.) Caligo. See {Caligo}. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. An ornament, as a brooch or badge, fastened to the
      clothing by a pin; as, a Masonic pin.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The leg; as, to knock one off his pins. [Slang]
       [1913 Webster]

   {Banking pin} (Horol.), a pin against which a lever strikes,
      to limit its motion.

   {Pin drill} (Mech.), a drill with a central pin or projection
      to enter a hole, for enlarging the hole, or for sinking a
      recess for the head of a bolt, etc.; a counterbore.

   {Pin grass}. (Bot.) See {Alfilaria}.

   {Pin hole}, a small hole made by a pin; hence, any very small
      aperture or perforation.

   {Pin lock}, a lock having a cylindrical bolt; a lock in which
      pins, arranged by the key, are used instead of tumblers.
      

   {Pin money}, an allowance of money, as that made by a husband
      to his wife, for private and personal expenditure.

   {Pin rail} (Naut.), a rail, usually within the bulwarks, to
      hold belaying pins. Sometimes applied to the {fife rail}.
      Called also {pin rack}.

   {Pin wheel}.
       (a) A contrate wheel in which the cogs are cylindrical
           pins.
       (b) (Fireworks) A small coil which revolves on a common
           pin and makes a wheel of yellow or colored fire.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pin \Pin\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pinned}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Pinning}.] [See {Pin}, n.]
   To fasten with, or as with, a pin; to join; as, to pin a
   garment; to pin boards together. ``As if she would pin her to
   her heart.'' --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To pin one's faith upon}, to depend upon; to trust to.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PIN
     Personal Identification Number (banking, ICC)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PIN
     Personal Internet Name (RFC 3042)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PIN
     Processor Independent Netware (Novell, HP, DEC, Apple, Sun)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pin
     n 1: a piece of jewelry that is pinned onto the wearer's garment
     2: when a wrestler's shoulders are forced to the mat [syn: {fall}]
     3: small markers inserted into a surface to mark scores or
        define locations etc. [syn: {peg}]
     4: a number you choose and use to gain access to various
        accounts [syn: {personal identification number}, {PIN
        number}]
     5: informal terms of the leg; "fever left him weak on his
        sticks" [syn: {peg}, {stick}]
     6: axis consisting of a short shaft that supports something
        that turns [syn: {pivot}]
     7: cylindrical tumblers consisting of two parts that are held
        in place by springs; when they are aligned with a key the
        bolt can be thrown
     8: flagpole used to mark the position of the hole on a golf
        green [syn: {flag}]
     9: a small slender (often pointed) piece of wood or metal used
        to support or fasten or attach things
     10: a holder attached to the gunwale of a boat that holds the
         oar in place and acts as a fulcrum for rowing [syn: {peg},
          {thole}, {tholepin}, {rowlock}, {oarlock}]
     11: a club-shaped wooden object used in bowling; set up in
         groups as a target [syn: {bowling pin}]
     v 1: to hold fast or prevent from moving; "The child was pinned
          under the fallen tree" [syn: {trap}, {immobilize}, {immobilise}]
     2: attach or fasten with pins [ant: {unpin}]
     3: pierce with a pin; "pin down the butterfly"
     4: immobilize a piece
     [also: {pinning}, {pinned}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
