<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pipe</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pipe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pipe
   (1 Sam. 10:5; 1 Kings 1:40; Isa. 5:12; 30:29). The Hebrew word
   halil, so rendered, means "bored through," and is the name given
   to various kinds of wind instruments, as the fife, flute,
   Pan-pipes, etc. In Amos 6:5 this word is rendered "instrument of
   music." This instrument is mentioned also in the New Testament
   (Matt. 11:17; 1 Cor. 14:7). It is still used in Palestine, and
   is, as in ancient times, made of different materials, as reed,
   copper, bronze, etc.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pipe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pipe
     
        1. &lt;operating system&gt; One of {Unix}'s buffers which can be
        written to by one {asynchronous} process and read by another,
        with the {kernel} suspending and waking up the sender and
        receiver according to how full the pipe is.  In later versions
        of Unix, rather than using an anonymous kernel-managed
        temporary file to implement a pipe, it can be named and is
        implemented as a local {socket} pair.
     
        2. &lt;character&gt; "|" {ASCII} character 124.  Used to represent a
        pipe between two processes in a {shell} command line.  E.g.
     
        	grep foo log | more
     
        which feeds the output of grep into the input of more without
        requiring a named temporary file and without waiting for the
        first process to finish.
     
        3. &lt;jargon, networking&gt; A connection to a {network}.
     
        See also {light pipe}.
     
        (1996-09-24)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pipe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pipe \Pipe\, n. [AS. p[=i]pe, probably fr. L. pipare, pipire, to
   chirp; of imitative origin. Cf. {Peep}, {Pibroch}, {Fife}.]
   1. A wind instrument of music, consisting of a tube or tubes
      of straw, reed, wood, or metal; any tube which produces
      musical sounds; as, a shepherd's pipe; the pipe of an
      organ. ``Tunable as sylvan pipe.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now had he rather hear the tabor and the pipe.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any long tube or hollow body of wood, metal, earthenware,
      or the like: especially, one used as a conductor of water,
      steam, gas, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A small bowl with a hollow stem, -- used in smoking
      tobacco, and, sometimes, other substances.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A passageway for the air in speaking and breathing; the
      windpipe, or one of its divisions.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The key or sound of the voice. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The peeping whistle, call, or note of a bird.
      [1913 Webster]

            The earliest pipe of half-awakened birds.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. The bagpipe; as, the pipes of Lucknow.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mining) An elongated body or vein of ore.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A roll formerly used in the English exchequer, otherwise
      called the Great Roll, on which were taken down the
      accounts of debts to the king; -- so called because put
      together like a pipe. --Mozley &amp; W.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Naut.) A boatswain's whistle, used to call the crew to
       their duties; also, the sound of it.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. [Cf. F. pipe, fr. pipe a wind instrument, a tube, fr. L.
       pipare to chirp. See Etymol. above.] A cask usually
       containing two hogsheads, or 126 wine gallons; also, the
       quantity which it contains.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Pipe fitter}, one who fits pipes together, or applies pipes,
      as to an engine or a building.

   {Pipe fitting}, a piece, as a coupling, an elbow, a valve,
      etc., used for connecting lengths of pipe or as accessory
      to a pipe.

   {Pipe office}, an ancient office in the Court of Exchequer,
      in which the clerk of the pipe made out leases of crown
      lands, accounts of cheriffs, etc. [Eng.]

   {Pipe tree} (Bot.), the lilac and the mock orange; -- so
      called because their were formerly used to make pipe
      stems; -- called also {pipe privet}.

   {Pipe wrench}, or {Pipe tongs}, a jawed tool for gripping a
      pipe, in turning or holding it.

   {To smoke the pipe of peace}, to smoke from the same pipe in
      token of amity or preparatory to making a treaty of peace,
      -- a custom of the American Indians.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pipe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pipe \Pipe\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Piped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Piping}.]
   1. To perform, as a tune, by playing on a pipe, flute, fife,
      etc.; to utter in the shrill tone of a pipe.
      [1913 Webster]

            A robin . . . was piping a few querulous notes. --W.
                                                  Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) To call or direct, as a crew, by the boatswain's
      whistle.
      [1913 Webster]

            As fine a ship's company as was ever piped aloft.
                                                  --Marryat.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To furnish or equip with pipes; as, to pipe an engine, or
      a building.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pipe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pipe \Pipe\, v. i.
   1. To play on a pipe, fife, flute, or other tubular wind
      instrument of music.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have piped unto you, and ye have not danced.
                                                  --Matt. xi.
                                                  17.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) To call, convey orders, etc., by means of signals
      on a pipe or whistle carried by a boatswain.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To emit or have a shrill sound like that of a pipe; to
      whistle. ``Oft in the piping shrouds.'' --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Metal.) To become hollow in the process of solodifying;
      -- said of an ingot, as of steel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pipe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pipe n. [common] Idiomatically, one's connection to the Internet; in
   context, the expansion "bit pipe" is understood. A "fat pipe" is a line
   with T1 or higher capacity. A person with a 28.8 modem might be heard to
   complain "I need a bigger pipe".


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pipe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pipe
     n 1: a tube with a small bowl at one end; used for smoking
          tobacco [syn: {tobacco pipe}]
     2: a long tube made of metal or plastic that is used to carry
        water or oil or gas etc. [syn: {pipage}, {piping}]
     3: a hollow cylindrical shape [syn: {tube}]
     4: a tubular wind instrument [syn: {tabor pipe}]
     5: the flues and stops on a pipe organ [syn: {organ pipe}, {pipework}]
     v 1: utter a shrill cry [syn: {shriek}, {shrill}, {pipe up}]
     2: transport by pipeline; "pipe oil, water, and gas into the
        desert"
     3: play on a pipe; "pipe a tune"
     4: trim with piping; "pipe the skirt"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
