<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pit
   a hole in the ground (Ex. 21:33, 34), a cistern for water (Gen.
   37:24; Jer. 14:3), a vault (41:9), a grave (Ps. 30:3). It is
   used as a figure for mischief (Ps. 9:15), and is the name given
   to the unseen place of woe (Rev. 20:1, 3). The slime-pits in the
   vale of Siddim were wells which yielded asphalt (Gen. 14:10).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PIT
     
        Language for IBM 650.  (See {IT}).
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pit \Pit\, n. [OE. pit, put, AS. pytt a pit, hole, L. puteus a
   well, pit.]
   1. A large cavity or hole in the ground, either natural or
      artificial; a cavity in the surface of a body; an
      indentation; specifically:
      (a) The shaft of a coal mine; a coal pit.
      (b) A large hole in the ground from which material is dug
          or quarried; as, a stone pit; a gravel pit; or in
          which material is made by burning; as, a lime pit; a
          charcoal pit.
      (c) A vat sunk in the ground; as, a tan pit.
          [1913 Webster]

                Tumble me into some loathsome pit. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Any abyss; especially, the grave, or hades.
      [1913 Webster]

            Back to the infernal pit I drag thee chained.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            He keepth back his soul from the pit. --Job xxxiii.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A covered deep hole for entrapping wild beasts; a pitfall;
      hence, a trap; a snare. Also used figuratively.
      [1913 Webster]

            The anointed of the Lord was taken in their pits.
                                                  --Lam. iv. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A depression or hollow in the surface of the human body;
      as:
      (a) The hollow place under the shoulder or arm; the
          axilla, or armpit.
      (b) See {Pit of the stomach} (below).
      (c) The indentation or mark left by a pustule, as in
          smallpox.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. Formerly, that part of a theater, on the floor of the
      house, below the level of the stage and behind the
      orchestra; now, in England, commonly the part behind the
      stalls; in the United States, the parquet; also, the
      occupants of such a part of a theater.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An inclosed area into which gamecocks, dogs, and other
      animals are brought to fight, or where dogs are trained to
      kill rats. ``As fiercely as two gamecocks in the pit.''
      --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. [Cf. D. pit, akin to E. pith.] (Bot.)
      (a) The endocarp of a drupe, and its contained seed or
          seeds; a stone; as, a peach pit; a cherry pit, etc.
      (b) A depression or thin spot in the wall of a duct.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Cold pit} (Hort.), an excavation in the earth, lined with
      masonry or boards, and covered with glass, but not
      artificially heated, -- used in winter for the storing and
      protection of half-hardly plants, and sometimes in the
      spring as a forcing bed.

   {Pit coal}, coal dug from the earth; mineral coal.

   {Pit frame}, the framework over the shaft of a coal mine.

   {Pit head}, the surface of the ground at the mouth of a pit
      or mine.

   {Pit kiln}, an oven for coking coal.

   {Pit martin} (Zo["o]l.), the bank swallow. [Prov. Eng.]

   {Pit of the stomach} (Anat.), the depression on the middle
      line of the epigastric region of the abdomen at the lower
      end of the sternum; the infrasternal depression.

   {Pit saw} (Mech.), a saw worked by two men, one of whom
      stands on the log and the other beneath it. The place of
      the latter is often in a pit, whence the name.

   {pit stop}, See {pit stop} in the vocabulary.

   {Pit viper} (Zo["o]l.), any viperine snake having a deep pit
      on each side of the snout. The rattlesnake and copperhead
      are examples.

   {Working pit} (Min.), a shaft in which the ore is hoisted and
      the workmen carried; -- in distinction from a shaft used
      for the pumps.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pit \Pit\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pitted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Pitting}.]
   1. To place or put into a pit or hole.
      [1913 Webster]

            They lived like beasts, and were pitted like beasts,
            tumbled into the grave.               --T. Grander.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mark with little hollows, as by various pustules; as, a
      face pitted by smallpox.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To introduce as an antagonist; to set forward for or in a
      contest; as, to pit one dog against another.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PIT
     Programmable Interval Timer
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pit
     n 1: a sizeable hole (usually in the ground); "they dug a pit to
          bury the body" [syn: {cavity}]
     2: a concavity in a surface (especially an anatomical
        depression) [syn: {fossa}]
     3: the hard inner (usually woody) layer of the pericarp of some
        fruits (as peaches or plums or cherries or olives) that
        contains the seed; "you should remove the stones from
        prunes before cooking" [syn: {stone}, {endocarp}]
     4: a trap in the form of a concealed hole [syn: {pitfall}]
     5: a surface excavation for extracting stone or slate; "a
        British term for `quarry' is `stone pit'" [syn: {quarry},
        {stone pit}]
     6: lowered area in front of a stage where an orchestra
        accompanies the performers [syn: {orchestra pit}]
     7: a workplace consisting of a coal mine plus all the buildings
        and equipment connected with it [syn: {colliery}]
     v 1: set into opposition or rivalry; "let them match their best
          athletes against ours"; "pit a chess player against the
          Russian champion"; "He plays his two children off
          against each other" [syn: {oppose}, {match}, {play off}]
     2: mark with a scar; "The skin disease scarred his face
        permanently" [syn: {scar}, {mark}, {pock}]
     3: remove the pits from; "pit plums and cherries" [syn: {stone}]
     [also: {pitting}, {pitted}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
