<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>place</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>place</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PLACE
     
        Programming Language for Automatic Checkout Equipment.
     
        ["The Compiler for the Programming Language for Automatic
        Checkout Equipment (PLACE)", AFAPL TR-68-27, Battelle Inst,
        Columbus, May 1968].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>place</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Place \Place\ (pl[=a]s), n. [F., fr. L. platea a street, an
   area, a courtyard, from Gr. platei^a a street, properly fem.
   of platy`s, flat, broad; akin to Skr. p[.r]thu, Lith. platus.
   Cf. {Flawn}, {Piazza}, {Plate}, {Plaza}.]
   1. Any portion of space regarded as measured off or distinct
      from all other space, or appropriated to some definite
      object or use; position; ground; site; spot; rarely,
      unbounded space.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here is the place appointed.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            What place can be for us
            Within heaven's bound?                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The word place has sometimes a more confused sense,
            and stands for that space which any body takes up;
            and so the universe is a place.       --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A broad way in a city; an open space; an area; a court or
      short part of a street open only at one end. ``Hangman
      boys in the market place.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A position which is occupied and held; a dwelling; a
      mansion; a village, town, or city; a fortified town or
      post; a stronghold; a region or country.
      [1913 Webster]

            Are you native of this place?         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Rank; degree; grade; order of priority, advancement,
      dignity, or importance; especially, social rank or
      position; condition; also, official station; occupation;
      calling. ``The enervating magic of place.'' --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men in great place are thrice servants. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            I know my place as I would they should do theirs.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Vacated or relinquished space; room; stead (the departure
      or removal of another being or thing being implied). ``In
      place of Lord Bassanio.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A definite position or passage of a document.
      [1913 Webster]

            The place of the scripture which he read was this.
                                                  --Acts viii.
                                                  32.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Ordinal relation; position in the order of proceeding; as,
      he said in the first place.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Reception; effect; -- implying the making room for.
      [1913 Webster]

            My word hath no place in you.         --John viii.
                                                  37.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Astron.) Position in the heavens, as of a heavenly body;
      -- usually defined by its right ascension and declination,
      or by its latitude and longitude.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Racing) The position of first, second, or third at the
       finish, esp. the second position. In betting, to win a
       bet on a horse for place it must, in the United States,
       finish first or second, in England, usually, first,
       second, or third.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Place of arms} (Mil.), a place calculated for the rendezvous
      of men in arms, etc., as a fort which affords a safe
      retreat for hospitals, magazines, etc. --Wilhelm.

   {High place} (Script.), a mount on which sacrifices were
      offered. ``Him that offereth in the high place.'' --Jer.
      xlviii. 35.

   {In place}, in proper position; timely.

   {Out of place}, inappropriate; ill-timed; as, his remarks
      were out of place.

   {Place kick} (Football), the act of kicking the ball after it
      has been placed on the ground.

   {Place name}, the name of a place or locality. --London
      Academy.

   {To give place}, to make room; to yield; to give way; to give
      advantage. ``Neither give place to the devil.'' --Eph. iv.
      27. ``Let all the rest give place.'' --Shak.

   {To have place}, to have a station, room, or seat; as, such
      desires can have no place in a good heart.

   {To take place}.
       (a) To come to pass; to occur; as, the ceremony will not
           take place.
       (b) To take precedence or priority. --Addison.
       (c) To take effect; to prevail. ``If your doctrine takes
           place.'' --Berkeley. ``But none of these excuses
           would take place.'' --Spenser.

   {To take the place of}, to be substituted for.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Situation; seat; abode; position; locality; location;
        site; spot; office; employment; charge; function; trust;
        ground; room; stead.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>place</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Place \Place\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Placed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Placing}.] [Cf. F. placer. See {Place}, n.]
   1. To assign a place to; to put in a particular spot or
      place, or in a certain relative position; to direct to a
      particular place; to fix; to settle; to locate; as, to
      place a book on a shelf; to place balls in tennis.

   Syn: Put.
        [1913 Webster]

              Upon my head they placed a fruitless crown.
                                                  --Shak.
        [1913 Webster]

   2. To put or set in a particular rank, office, or position;
      to surround with particular circumstances or relations in
      life; to appoint to certain station or condition of life;
      as, in whatever sphere one is placed.
      [1913 Webster]

            Place such over them to be rulers.    --Ex. xviii.
                                                  21.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To put out at interest; to invest; to loan; as, to place
      money in a bank.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To set; to fix; to repose; as, to place confidence in a
      friend. ``My resolution 's placed.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To attribute; to ascribe; to set down.
      [1913 Webster]

            Place it for her chief virtue.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Racing) To determine or announce the place of at the
      finish. Usually, in horse racing only the first three
      horses are placed officially.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. (Rugby Football) To place-kick ( a goal).
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. to recognize or identify (a person). [Colloq. U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>place</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>place
     n 1: a point located with respect to surface features of some
          region; "this is a nice place for a picnic" [syn: {topographic
          point}, {spot}]
     2: any area set aside for a particular purpose; "who owns this
        place?"; "the president was concerned about the property
        across from the White House" [syn: {property}]
     3: an abstract mental location; "he has a special place in my
        thoughts"; "a place in my heart"; "a political system with
        no place for the less prominent groups"
     4: a general vicinity; "He comes from a place near Chicago"
     5: the function or position properly or customarily occupied or
        served by another; "can you go in my stead?"; "took his
        place"; "in lieu of" [syn: {stead}, {position}, {lieu}]
     6: a particular situation; "If you were in my place what would
        you do?" [syn: {shoes}]
     7: where you live at a particular time; "deliver the package to
        my home"; "he doesn't have a home to go to"; "your place
        or mine?" [syn: {home}]
     8: a job in an organization; "he occupied a post in the
        treasury" [syn: {position}, {post}, {berth}, {office}, {spot},
         {billet}, {situation}]
     9: the particular portion of space occupied by a physical
        object; "he put the lamp back in its place" [syn: {position}]
     10: proper or designated social situation; "he overstepped his
         place"; "the responsibilities of a man in his station";
         "married above her station" [syn: {station}]
     11: a space reserved for sitting (as in a theater or on a train
         or airplane); "he booked their seats in advance"; "he sat
         in someone else's place" [syn: {seat}]
     12: the passage that is being read; "he lost his place on the
         page"
     13: proper or appropriate position or location; "a woman's place
         is no longer in the kitchen"
     14: a public square with room for pedestrians; "they met at Elm
         Plaza"; "Grosvenor Place" [syn: {plaza}, {piazza}]
     15: an item on a list or in a sequence; "in the second place";
         "moved from third to fifth position" [syn: {position}]
     16: a blank area; "write your name in the space provided" [syn:
         {space}, {blank space}]
     v 1: put into a certain place or abstract location; "Put your
          things here"; "Set the tray down"; "Set the dogs on the
          scent of the missing children"; "Place emphasis on a
          certain point" [syn: {put}, {set}, {pose}, {position}, {lay}]
     2: place somebody in a particular situation or location; "he
        was placed on probation"
     3: assign a rank or rating to; "how would you rank these
        students?"; "The restaurant is rated highly in the food
        guide" [syn: {rate}, {rank}, {range}, {order}, {grade}]
     4: assign a location to; "The company located some of their
        agents in Los Angeles" [syn: {locate}, {site}]
     5: to arrange for; "place a phone call", "place a bet"
     6: take a place in a competition; often followed by an ordinal;
        "Jerry came in third in the Marathon" [syn: {come in}, {come
        out}]
     7: intend (something) to move towards a certain goal; "He aimed
        his fists towards his opponent's face"; "criticism
        directed at her superior"; "direct your anger towards
        others, not towards yourself" [syn: {target}, {aim}, {direct},
         {point}]
     8: recognize as being; establish the identity of someone or
        something; "She identified the man on the 'wanted' poster"
        [syn: {identify}]
     9: assign to (a job or a home)
     10: locate; "The film is set in Africa" [syn: {set}, {localize},
          {localise}]
     11: estimate; "We put the time of arrival at 8 P.M." [syn: {put},
          {set}]
     12: identify the location or place of; "We localized the source
         of the infection" [syn: {localize}, {localise}]
     13: make an investment; "Put money into bonds" [syn: {invest}, {put},
          {commit}] [ant: {divest}]
     14: assign to a station [syn: {station}, {post}, {base}, {send}]
     15: finish second or better in a horse or dog race; "he bet $2
         on number six to place"
     16: sing a note with the correct pitch
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
