<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>planet</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>planet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Planet
     
        ["An Experiment in Language Design for Distributed Systems",
        D. Crookes et al, Soft Prac &amp; Exp 14(10):957-971 (Oct 1984)].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>planet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Planet \Plan"et\, n. [OE. planete, F. plan[`e]te, L. planeta,
   fr. Gr. ?, and ? a planet; prop. wandering, fr. ? to wander,
   fr. ? a wandering.]
   1. (Astron.) A celestial body which revolves about the sun in
      an orbit of a moderate degree of eccentricity. It is
      distinguished from a comet by the absence of a coma, and
      by having a less eccentric orbit. See {Solar system}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The term planet was first used to distinguish those
         stars which have an apparent motion through the
         constellations from the fixed stars, which retain their
         relative places unchanged. The inferior planets are
         Mercury and Venus, which are nearer to the sun than is
         the earth; the superior planets are Mars, the
         asteroids, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune, which
         are farther from the sun than is the earth. Primary
         planets are those which revolve about the sun;
         secondary planets, or moons, are those which revolve
         around the primary planets as satellites, and at the
         same time revolve with them about the sun.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A star, as influencing the fate of a men.
      [1913 Webster]

            There's some ill planet reigns.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Planet gear}. (Mach.) See {Epicyclic train}, under
      {Epicyclic}.

   {Planet wheel}, a gear wheel which revolves around the wheel
      with which it meshes, in an epicyclic train.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>planet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>planet
     n 1: any of the celestial bodies (other than comets or
          satellites) that revolve around the sun in the solar
          system
     2: a person who follows or serves another [syn: {satellite}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
