<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>plastic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plastic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-plastic \-plas"tic\ (-pl[a^]s"t[i^]k). [Gr. ? fit for molding,
   plastic, fr. ? to mold, to form.]
   A combining form signifying developing, forming, growing; as,
   heteroplastic, monoplastic, polyplastic.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plastic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Plastic \Plas"tic\ (pl[a^]s"t[i^]k), a. [L. plasticus, Gr. ?,
   fr. ? to form, mold: cf. F. plastique.]
   1. Having the power to give form or fashion to a mass of
      matter; as, the plastic hand of the Creator. --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

            See plastic Nature working to his end. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Capable of being molded, formed, or modeled, as clay or
      plaster; -- used also figuratively; as, the plastic mind
      of a child.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Pertaining or appropriate to, or characteristic of,
      molding or modeling; produced by, or appearing as if
      produced by, molding or modeling; -- said of sculpture and
      the kindred arts, in distinction from painting and the
      graphic arts.
      [1913 Webster]

            Medallions . . . fraught with the plastic beauty and
            grace of the palmy days of Italian art. --J. S.
                                                  Harford.
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Plastic clay} (Geol.), one of the beds of the Eocene period;
      -- so called because used in making pottery. --Lyell.

   {Plastic element} (Physiol.), one that bears within the germs
      of a higher form.

   {Plastic exudation} (Med.), an exudation thrown out upon a
      wounded surface and constituting the material of repair by
      which the process of healing is effected.

   {Plastic foods}. (Physiol.) See the second Note under {Food}.
      

   {Plastic force}. (Physiol.) See under {Force}.

   {Plastic operation}, an operation in plastic surgery.

   {Plastic surgery}, that branch of surgery which is concerned
      with the repair or restoration of lost, injured, or
      deformed parts of the body.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plastic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>plastic \plastic\ (pl[a^]s"t[i^]k), n.
   A substance composed predominantly of a synthetic organic
   high polymer capable of being cast or molded; many varieties
   of plastic are used to produce articles of commerce (after
   1900). [MW10 gives origin of word as 1905]
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plastic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Money \Mon"ey\, n.; pl. {Moneys}. [OE. moneie, OF. moneie, F.
   monnaie, fr. L. moneta. See {Mint} place where coin is made,
   {Mind}, and cf. {Moidore}, {Monetary}.]
   1. A piece of metal, as gold, silver, copper, etc., coined,
      or stamped, and issued by the sovereign authority as a
      medium of exchange in financial transactions between
      citizens and with government; also, any number of such
      pieces; coin.
      [1913 Webster]

            To prevent such abuses, . . . it has been found
            necessary . . . to affix a public stamp upon certain
            quantities of such particular metals, as were in
            those countries commonly made use of to purchase
            goods. Hence the origin of coined money, and of
            those public offices called mints.    --A. Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any written or stamped promise, certificate, or order, as
      a government note, a bank note, a certificate of deposit,
      etc., which is payable in standard coined money and is
      lawfully current in lieu of it; in a comprehensive sense,
      any currency usually and lawfully employed in buying and
      selling.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any article used as a medium of payment in financial
      transactions, such as checks drawn on checking accounts.
      [PJC]

   4. (Economics) Any form of wealth which affects a person's
      propensity to spend, such as checking accounts or time
      deposits in banks, credit accounts, letters of credit,
      etc. Various aggregates of money in different forms are
      given different names, such as {M-1}, the total sum of all
      currency in circulation plus all money in demand deposit
      accounts (checking accounts).
      [PJC]

   Note: Whatever, among barbarous nations, is used as a medium
         of effecting exchanges of property, and in the terms of
         which values are reckoned, as sheep, wampum, copper
         rings, quills of salt or of gold dust, shovel blades,
         etc., is, in common language, called their money.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. In general, wealth; property; as, he has much money in
      land, or in stocks; to make, or lose, money.
      [1913 Webster]

            The love of money is a root of all kinds of evil.
                                                  --1 Tim vi. 10
                                                  (Rev. Ver. ).
      [1913 Webster]

   {Money bill} (Legislation), a bill for raising revenue.

   {Money broker}, a broker who deals in different kinds of
      money; one who buys and sells bills of exchange; -- called
      also {money changer}.

   {Money cowrie} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      {Cypr[ae]a} (esp. {Cypr[ae]a moneta}) formerly much used
      as money by savage tribes. See {Cowrie}.

   {Money of account}, a denomination of value used in keeping
      accounts, for which there may, or may not, be an
      equivalent coin; e. g., the mill is a money of account in
      the United States, but not a coin.

   {Money order},
      (a) an order for the payment of money; specifically, a
          government order for the payment of money, issued at
          one post office as payable at another; -- called also
          {postal money order}.
      (b) a similar order issued by a bank or other financial
          institution.

   {Money scrivener}, a person who procures the loan of money to
      others. [Eng.]

   {Money spider}, {Money spinner} (Zo["o]l.), a small spider;
      -- so called as being popularly supposed to indicate that
      the person upon whom it crawls will be fortunate in money
      matters.

   {Money's worth}, a fair or full equivalent for the money
      which is paid.

   {A piece of money}, a single coin.

   {Ready money}, money held ready for payment, or actually
      paid, at the time of a transaction; cash.

   {plastic money}, credit cards, usually made out of plastic;
      also called {plastic}; as, put it on the plastic.

   {To make money}, to gain or acquire money or property; to
      make a profit in dealings.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plastic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>integrative \integrative\ adj.
   1. tending to combine and coordinate diverse elements into a
      whole. [Narrower terms: {consolidative, unifying};
      {plastic )}] Also See: {collective}, {combinative},
      {integrated}. Antonym: {disintegrative}.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   2. centralizing(prenominal). Opposite of {decentralizing}.

   Syn: consolidative.
        [WordNet 1.5]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plastic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>plastic
     adj 1: used of the imagination; "material...transformed by the
            plastic power of the imagination"--Coleridge
     2: capable of being molded or modeled (especially of earth or
        clay or other soft material); "plastic substances such as
        wax or clay" [syn: {fictile}, {moldable}]
     3: capable of being influenced or formed; "the plastic minds of
        children"; "a pliant nature" [syn: {pliant}]
     n : generic name for certain synthetic or semisynthetic
         materials that can be molded or extruded into objects or
         films or filaments or used for making e.g. coatings and
         adhesives
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
