<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>plate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Plate \Plate\, n. [OF. plate a plate of metal, a cuirsas, F.
   plat a plate, a shallow vessel of silver, other metal, or
   earth, fr. plat flat, Gr. ?. See {Place}, n.]
   1. A flat, or nearly flat, piece of metal, the thickness of
      which is small in comparison with the other dimensions; a
      thick sheet of metal; as, a steel plate.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Metallic armor composed of broad pieces.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mangled . . . through plate and mail. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Domestic vessels and utensils, as flagons, dishes, cups,
      etc., wrought in gold or silver.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Metallic ware which is plated, in distinction from that
      which is silver or gold throughout.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A small, shallow, and usually circular, vessel of metal or
      wood, or of earth glazed and baked, from which food is
      eaten at table.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. [Cf. Sp. plata silver.] A piece of money, usually silver
      money. [Obs.] ``Realms and islands were as plates dropp'd
      from his pocket.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A piece of metal on which anything is engraved for the
      purpose of being printed; hence, an impression from the
      engraved metal; as, a book illustrated with plates; a
      fashion plate.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A page of stereotype, electrotype, or the like, for
      printing from; as, publisher's plates.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. That part of an artificial set of teeth which fits to the
      mouth, and holds the teeth in place. It may be of gold,
      platinum, silver, rubber, celluloid, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Arch.) A horizontal timber laid upon a wall, or upon
       corbels projecting from a wall, and supporting the ends
       of other timbers; also used specifically of the roof
       plate which supports the ends of the roof trusses or, in
       simple work, the feet of the rafters.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Her.) A roundel of silver or tinctured argent.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Photog.) A sheet of glass, porcelain, metal, etc., with
       a coating that is sensitive to light.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. A prize giving to the winner in a contest.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Baseball) A small five-sided area (enveloping a
       diamond-shaped area one foot square) beside which the
       batter stands and which must be touched by some part of a
       player on completing a run; -- called also {home base},
       or {home plate}.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   15. One of the thin parts of the bricket of an animal.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   16. A very light steel racing horsehoe.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   17. Loosely, a sporting contest for a prize; specif., in
       horse racing, a race for a prize, the contestants not
       making a stake.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   18. Skins for fur linings of garments, sewed together and
       roughly shaped, but not finally cut or fitted. [Furrier's
       Cant]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   19. (Hat Making) The fine nap (as of beaver, hare's wool,
       musquash, nutria, or English black wool) on a hat the
       body of which is of an inferior substance.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   20. a quantity sufficient to fill a plate; a {plateful}; a
       dish containing that quantity; a plate of spaghetti.
       [PJC]

   21. the food and service supplied to a customer at a
       restaurant; as, the turkey dinner is $9 a plate; I'll
       have a plate of spaghetti.
       [PJC]

   22. a flat dish of glass or plastic with a fitted cover, used
       for culturing microorganisms in a laboratory.
       [PJC]

   23. the identification tag required to be displayed on the
       outside of a vehicle; same as {license plate}; -- often
       used in the plural.
       [PJC]

   24. an agenda or schedule of tasks to be performed; I have a
       lot on my plate today. [colloq.]
       [PJC]

   Note: Plate is sometimes used in an adjectival sense or in
         combination, the phrase or compound being in most cases
         of obvious signification; as, plate basket or
         plate-basket, plate rack or plate-rack.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Home plate}. (Baseball) See {Home base}, under {Home}.

   {Plate armor}.
       (a) See {Plate}, n., 2.
       (b) Strong metal plates for protecting war vessels,
           fortifications, and the like.

   {Plate bone}, the shoulder blade, or scapula.

   {Plate girder}, a girder, the web of which is formed of a
      single vertical plate, or of a series of such plates
      riveted together.

   {Plate glass}. See under {Glass}.

   {Plate iron}, wrought iron plates.

   {Plate layer}, a workman who lays down the rails of a railway
      and fixes them to the sleepers or ties.

   {Plate mark}, a special mark or emblematic figure stamped
      upon gold or silver plate, to indicate the place of
      manufacture, the degree of purity, and the like; thus, the
      local mark for London is a lion.

   {Plate paper}, a heavy spongy paper, for printing from
      engraved plates. --Fairholt.

   {Plate press}, a press with a flat carriage and a roller, --
      used for printing from engraved steel or copper plates.

   {Plate printer}, one who prints from engraved plates.

   {Plate printing}, the act or process of printing from an
      engraved plate or plates.

   {Plate tracery}. (Arch.) See under {Tracery}.

   {Plate wheel} (Mech.), a wheel, the rim and hub of which are
      connected by a continuous plate of metal, instead of by
      arms or spokes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Plate \Plate\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Plated}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Plating}.]
   1. To cover or overlay with gold, silver, or other metals,
      either by a mechanical process, as hammering, or by a
      chemical process, as electrotyping.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cover or overlay with plates of metal; to arm with
      metal for defense.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus plated in habiliments of war.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To adorn with plated metal; as, a plated harness.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To beat into thin, flat pieces, or lamin[ae].
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To calender; as, to plate paper.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>plate
     n 1: a sheet of metal or wood or glass or plastic
     2: (baseball) base consisting of a rubber slab where the batter
        stands; it must be touched by a base runner in order to
        score; "he ruled that the runner failed to touch home"
        [syn: {home plate}, {home base}, {home}]
     3: a full-page illustration (usually on slick paper)
     4: dish on which food is served or from which food is eaten
     5: the quantity contained in a plate [syn: {plateful}]
     6: a rigid layer of the Earth's crust that is believed to drift
        slowly [syn: {crustal plate}]
     7: the thin under portion of the forequarter
     8: a main course served on a plate; "a vegetable plate"; "the
        blue plate special"
     9: any flat platelike body structure or part
     10: the positively charged electrode in a vacuum tube
     11: a flat sheet of metal or glass on which a photographic image
         can be recorded [syn: {photographic plate}]
     12: structural member consisting of a horizontal beam that
         provides bearing and anchorage
     13: a shallow receptacle for collection in church [syn: {collection
         plate}]
     14: a metal sheathing of uniform thickness (such as the shield
         attached to an artillery piece to protect the gunners)
         [syn: {scale}, {shell}]
     15: a dental appliance that artificially replaces missing teeth
         [syn: {denture}, {dental plate}]
     16: the position on a baseball team of the player who is
         stationed behind home plate and who catches the balls
         that the pitcher throws; "a catcher needs a lot of
         protective equipment"; "he plays behind the plate" [syn:
         {catcher}]
     v : coat with a layer of metal; "plate spoons with silver"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
