<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>playing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>playing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Play \Play\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Played}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Playing}.] [OE. pleien, AS. plegian, plegan, to play, akin
   to plega play, game, quick motion, and probably to OS. plegan
   to promise, pledge, D. plegen to care for, attend to, be
   wont, G. pflegen; of unknown origin. [root]28. Cf. {Plight},
   n.]
   1. To engage in sport or lively recreation; to exercise for
      the sake of amusement; to frolic; to spot.
      [1913 Webster]

            As Cannace was playing in her walk.   --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lamb thy riot dooms to bleed to-day,
            Had he thy reason, would he skip and play! --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            And some, the darlings of their Lord,
            Play smiling with the flame and sword. --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To act with levity or thoughtlessness; to trifle; to be
      careless.
      [1913 Webster]

            ``Nay,'' quod this monk, ``I have no lust to
            pleye.''                              --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men are apt to play with their healths. --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To contend, or take part, in a game; as, to play ball;
      hence, to gamble; as, he played for heavy stakes.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To perform on an instrument of music; as, to play on a
      flute.
      [1913 Webster]

            One that . . . can play well on an instrument.
                                                  --Ezek.
                                                  xxxiii. 32.
      [1913 Webster]

            Play, my friend, and charm the charmer. --Granville.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To act; to behave; to practice deception.
      [1913 Webster]

            His mother played false with a smith. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To move in any manner; especially, to move regularly with
      alternate or reciprocating motion; to operate; to act; as,
      the fountain plays.
      [1913 Webster]

            The heart beats, the blood circulates, the lungs
            play.                                 --Cheyne.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To move gayly; to wanton; to disport.
      [1913 Webster]

            Even as the waving sedges play with wind. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The setting sun
            Plays on their shining arms and burnished helmets.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            All fame is foreign but of true desert,
            Plays round the head, but comes not to the heart.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To act on the stage; to personate a character.
      [1913 Webster]

            A lord will hear your play to-night.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Courts are theaters where some men play. --Donne.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To play into a person's hands}, to act, or to manage
      matters, to his advantage or benefit.

   {To play off}, to affect; to feign; to practice artifice.

   {To play upon}.
      (a) To make sport of; to deceive.
          [1913 Webster]

                Art thou alive?
                Or is it fantasy that plays upon our eyesight.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To use in a droll manner; to give a droll expression
          or application to; as, to play upon words.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>playing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Playing \Play"ing\,
   a. &amp; vb. n. of {Play}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Playing cards}. See under {Card}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>playing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>playing
     n 1: the act of playing a musical instrument
     2: the action of taking part in a game or sport or other
        recreation
     3: the performance of a part or role in a drama [syn: {acting},
         {playacting}, {performing}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
