<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pledge</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pledge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pledge
   See {LOAN}.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pledge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pledge \Pledge\, n. [OF. plege, pleige, pledge, guaranty, LL.
   plegium, plivium; akin to OF. plevir to bail, guaranty,
   perhaps fr. L. praebere to proffer, offer (sc. fidem a trust,
   a promise of security), but cf. also E. play. [root]28. Cf.
   {Prebend}, {Replevin}.]
   1. (Law) The transfer of possession of personal property from
      a debtor to a creditor as security for a debt or
      engagement; also, the contract created between the debtor
      and creditor by a thing being so delivered or deposited,
      forming a species of bailment; also, that which is so
      delivered or deposited; something put in pawn.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Pledge is ordinarily confined to personal property; the
         title or ownership does not pass by it; possession is
         essential to it. In all these points it differs from a
         mortgage [see {Mortgage}]; and in the last, from the
         hypotheca of the Roman law. See {Hypotheca}. --Story.
         Kent.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. (Old Eng. Law) A person who undertook, or became
      responsible, for another; a bail; a surety; a hostage. ``I
      am Grumio's pledge.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A hypothecation without transfer of possession.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything given or considered as a security for the
      performance of an act; a guarantee; as, mutual interest is
      the best pledge for the performance of treaties. ``That
      voice, their liveliest pledge of hope.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A promise or agreement by which one binds one's self to
      do, or to refrain from doing, something; especially, a
      solemn promise in writing to refrain from using
      intoxicating liquors or the like; as, to sign the pledge;
      the mayor had made no pledges.
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A sentiment to which assent is given by drinking one's
      health; a toast; a health.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Dead pledge}. [A translation of {LL}. mortuum vadium.] (Law)
      A mortgage. See {Mortgage}.

   {Living pledge}. [A translation of LL. vivum vadium.] (Law)
      The conveyance of an estate to another for money borrowed,
      to be held by him until the debt is paid out of the rents
      and profits.

   {To hold in pledge}, to keep as security.

   {To put in pledge}, to pawn; to give as security.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See {Earnest}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pledge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pledge \Pledge\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pledged}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Pledging}.] [Cf. OF. pleiger to give security. See {Pledge},
   n.]
   1. To deposit, as a chattel, in pledge or pawn; to leave in
      possession of another as security; as, to pledge one's
      watch.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give or pass as a security; to guarantee; to engage; to
      plight; as, to pledge one's word and honor.
      [1913 Webster]

            We mutually pledge to each other our lives, our
            fortunes, and our sacred honor.       --The
                                                  Declaration of
                                                  Independence.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To secure performance of, as by a pledge. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To pledge my vow, I give my hand.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To bind or engage by promise or declaration; to engage
      solemnly; as, to pledge one's self.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To invite another to drink, by drinking of the cup first,
      and then handing it to him, as a pledge of good will;
      hence, to drink the health of; to toast.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pledge me, my friend, and drink till thou be'st
            wise.                                 --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pledge</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pledge
     n 1: a deposit of personal property as security for a debt; "his
          saxophone was in pledge"
     2: someone accepted for membership but not yet fully admitted
        to the group
     3: a drink in honor of or to the health of a person or event
        [syn: {toast}]
     4: a binding commitment to do or give or refrain from
        something; "an assurance of help when needed"; "signed a
        pledge never to reveal the secret" [syn: {assurance}]
     v 1: promise solemnly and formally; "I pledge that will honor my
          wife" [syn: {plight}]
     2: pay (an amount of money) as a contribution to a charity or
        service, especially at regular intervals; "I pledged $10 a
        month to my favorite radio station" [syn: {subscribe}]
     3: propose a toast to; "Let us toast the birthday girl!";
        "Let's drink to the New Year" [syn: {toast}, {drink}, {salute},
         {wassail}]
     4: give as a guarantee; "I pledge my honor"
     5: bind or secure by a pledge; "I was pledged to silence"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
