<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>plumbing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plumbing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>plumbing
     
        (Unix) Term used for {shell} code, so called because of the
        prevalence of "{pipeline}s" that feed the output of one
        program to the input of another.  Under {Unix}, user utilities
        can often be implemented or at least prototyped by a suitable
        collection of pipelines and temporary file {grind}ing
        encapsulated in a {shell script}.  This is much less effort
        than writing {C} every time, and the capability is considered
        one of Unix's major winning features.  A few other {operating
        system}s such as {IBM}'s {VM/CMS} support similar facilities.
     
        The {tee} utility is specifically designed for plumbing.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-02-23)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plumbing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Plumb \Plumb\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Plumbed} (pl[u^]md); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Plumbing} (pl[u^]m"[i^]ng).]
   1. To adjust by a plumb line; to cause to be perpendicular;
      as, to plumb a building or a wall.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To sound with a plumb or plummet, as the depth of water;
      hence, to examine by test; to ascertain the depth,
      quality, dimension, etc.; to sound; to fathom; to test.
      [1913 Webster]

            He did not attempt to plumb his intellect. --Ld.
                                                  Lytton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To seal with lead; as, to plumb a drainpipe.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To supply, as a building, with a system of plumbing.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plumbing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Plumbing \Plumb"ing\, n.
   1. The art of casting and working in lead, and applying it to
      building purposes; especially, the business of furnishing,
      fitting, and repairing pipes for conducting water, sewage,
      etc. --Gwilt.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The lead or iron pipes, and other apparatus, used in
      conveying water, sewage, etc., in a building.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plumbing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>plumbing n. [Unix] Term used for {shell} code, so called because of the
   prevalence of `pipelines' that feed the output of one program to the
   input of another. Under Unix, user utilities can often be implemented or
   at least prototyped by a suitable collection of pipelines and temp-file
   grinding encapsulated in a shell script; this is much less effort than
   writing C every time, and the capability is considered one of Unix's
   major winning features. A few other OSs such as IBM's VM/CMS support
   similar facilities. Esp. used in the construction `hairy plumbing' (see
   {hairy}). "You can kluge together a basic spell-checker out of
   `sort(1)', `comm(1)', and `tr(1)' with a little plumbing." See also
   {tee}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>plumbing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>plumbing
     n 1: utility consisting of the pipes and fixtures for the
          distribution of water or gas in a building and for the
          disposal of sewage [syn: {plumbing system}]
     2: the occupation of a plumber (installing and repairing pipes
        and fixtures for water or gas or sewage in a building)
        [syn: {plumbery}]
     3: measuring the depths of the oceans [syn: {bathymetry}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
