<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pocket</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>POCKET, n.  The cradle of motive and the grave of conscience.  In
woman this organ is lacking; so she acts without motive, and her
conscience, denied burial, remains ever alive, confessing the sins of
others.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pocket \Pock"et\, n.
   Any hollow place suggestive of a pocket in form or use;
   specif.:
   (a) A bin for strong coal, grain, etc.
   (b) A socket for receiving the foot of a post, stake, etc.
   (c) A bright on a lee shore.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pocket \Pock"et\ (p[o^]k"[e^]t), n. [OE. poket, Prov. F. &amp; OF.
   poquette, F. pochette, dim. fr. poque, pouque, F. poche;
   probably of Teutonic origin. See {Poke} a pocket, and cf.
   {Poach} to cook eggs, to plunder, and {Pouch}.]
   1. A bag or pouch; especially; a small bag inserted in a
      garment for carrying small articles, particularly money;
      hence, figuratively, money; wealth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One of several bags attached to a billiard table, into
      which the balls are driven.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A large bag or sack used in packing various articles, as
      ginger, hops, cowries, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the wool or hop trade, the pocket contains half a
         sack, or about 168 Ibs.; but it is a variable quantity,
         the articles being sold by actual weight.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. (Arch.) A hole or space covered by a movable piece of
      board, as in a floor, boxing, partitions, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mining.)
      (a) A cavity in a rock containing a nugget of gold, or
          other mineral; a small body of ore contained in such a
          cavity.
      (b) A hole containing water.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Nat.) A strip of canvas, sewn upon a sail so that a
      batten or a light spar can placed in the interspace.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Zo["o]l.) Same as {Pouch}.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Any hollow place suggestive of a pocket in form or use;
      specif.:
      (a) A bin for storing coal, grain, etc.
      (b) A socket for receiving the foot of a post, stake, etc.
      (c) A bight on a lee shore.
      (d) a small cavity in the body, especially one abnormally
          filled with a fluid; as, a pocket of pus.
      (e) (Dentistry) a small space between a tooth and the
          adjoining gum, formed by an abnormal separation of the
          gum from the tooth.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   9. An isolated group or area which has properties in contrast
      to the surrounding area; as, a pocket of poverty in an
      affluent region; pockets of resistance in a conquered
      territory; a pocket of unemployment in a booming ecomony.
      [PJC]

   10. (Football) The area from which a quarterback throws a
       pass, behind the line of scrimmage, delineated by the
       defensive players of his own team who protect him from
       attacking opponents; as, he had ample time in the pocket
       to choose an open receiver.
       [PJC]

   11. (Baseball) The part of a baseball glove covering the palm
       of the wearer's hand.
       [PJC]

   12. (Bowling) the space between the head pin and one of the
       pins in the second row, considered as the optimal point
       at which to aim the bowling ball in order to get a
       strike.
       [PJC]

   Note: Pocket is often used adjectively in the sense of small,
         or in the formation of compound words usually of
         obvious signification; as, pocket knife, pocket comb,
         pocket compass, pocket edition, pocket handkerchief,
         pocket money, pocket picking, or pocket-picking, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {deep pocket} or

   {deep pockets}, wealth or substantial financial assets.

   Note: Used esp. in legal actions, where plaintiffs desire to
         find a defendant with "deep pockets", so as to be able
         to actually obtain the sum of damages which may be
         judged due to him. This contrasts with a
         "judgment-proof" defendant, one who has neither assets
         nor insurance, and against whom a judgment for monetary
         damages would be uncollectable and worthless. 

   {Out of pocket}. See under {Out}, prep.

   {Pocket borough}, a borough ``owned'' by some person. See
      under {Borough}. [Eng.]

   {Pocket gopher} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      American rodents of the genera {Geomys}, and {Thomomys},
      family {Geomyd[ae]}. They have large external cheek
      pouches, and are fossorial in their habits. they inhabit
      North America, from the Mississippi Valley west to the
      Pacific. Called also {pouched gopher}.

   {Pocket mouse} (Zo["o]l.), any species of American mice of
      the family {Saccomyid[ae]}. They have external cheek
      pouches. Some of them are adapted for leaping (genus
      {Dipadomys}), and are called {kangaroo mice}. They are
      native of the Southwestern United States, Mexico, etc.

   {Pocket piece}, a piece of money kept in the pocket and not
      spent.

   {Pocket pistol}, a pistol to be carried in the pocket.

   {Pocket sheriff} (Eng. Law), a sheriff appointed by the sole
      authority of the crown, without a nomination by the judges
      in the exchequer. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pocket \Pock"et\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pocketed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Pocketing}.]
   1. To put, or conceal, in the pocket; as, to pocket the
      change.
      [1913 Webster]

            He would pocket the expense of the license.
                                                  --Sterne.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take clandestinely or fraudulently.
      [1913 Webster]

            He pocketed pay in the names of men who had long
            been dead.                            --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pocket a ball} (Billiards), to drive a ball into a pocket
      of the table.

   {To pocket an insult}, {affront}, etc., to receive an affront
      without open resentment, or without seeking redress. ``I
      must pocket up these wrongs.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pocket
     n 1: a small pouch inside a garment for carrying small articles
     2: an enclosed space; "the trapped miners found a pocket of
        air" [syn: {pouch}, {sac}, {sack}]
     3: a supply of money; "they dipped into the taxpayers' pockets"
     4: (bowling) the space between the headpin and the pins next
        bnehind it on the right or left; "the ball hit the pocket
        and gave him a perfect strike"
     5: a hollow concave shape made by removing something [syn: {scoop}]
     6: a local region of low pressure or descending air that causes
        a plane to lose height suddenly [syn: {air pocket}, {air
        hole}]
     7: a small isolated group of people; "they were concentrated in
        pockets inside the city"; "the battle was won except for
        cleaning up pockets of resistance"
     8: (anatomy) saclike structure in any of various animals (as a
        marsupial or gopher or pelican) [syn: {pouch}]
     9: an opening at the corner or on the side of a billiard table
        into which billiard balls are struck
     v 1: put in one's pocket; "He pocketed the change"
     2: take unlawfully [syn: {bag}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
