<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pointed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Point \Point\ (point), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pointed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Pointing}.] [Cf. F. pointer. See {Point}, n.]
   1. To give a point to; to sharpen; to cut, forge, grind, or
      file to an acute end; as, to point a dart, or a pencil.
      Used also figuratively; as, to point a moral.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To direct toward an abject; to aim; as, to point a gun at
      a wolf, or a cannon at a fort.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, to direct the attention or notice of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whosoever should be guided through his battles by
            Minerva, and pointed to every scene of them. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To supply with punctuation marks; to punctuate; as, to
      point a composition.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To mark (a text, as in Arabic or Hebrew) with {vowel
      points}; -- also called {vocalize}.

   Syn: vocalize. [1913 Webster + RP]

   6. To give particular prominence to; to designate in a
      special manner; to indicate, as if by pointing; as, the
      error was pointed out. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            He points it, however, by no deviation from his
            straightforward manner of speech.     --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To indicate or discover by a fixed look, as game.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Masonry) To fill up and finish the joints of (a wall), by
      introducing additional cement or mortar, and bringing it
      to a smooth surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Stone Cutting) To cut, as a surface, with a pointed tool.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To point a rope} (Naut.), to taper and neatly finish off the
      end by interweaving the nettles.

   {To point a sail} (Naut.), to affix points through the eyelet
      holes of the reefs.

   {To point off}, to divide into periods or groups, or to
      separate, by pointing, as figures.

   {To point the yards} (of a vessel) (Naut.), to brace them so
      that the wind shall strike the sails obliquely. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pointed \Point"ed\, a.
   1. Sharp; having a sharp point; as, a pointed rock.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Characterized by sharpness, directness, or pithiness of
      expression; terse; epigrammatic; especially, directed to a
      particular person or thing.
      [1913 Webster]

            His moral pleases, not his pointed wit. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Pointed arch} (Arch.), an arch with a pointed crown.

   {Pointed style} (Arch.), a name given to that style of
      architecture in which the pointed arch is the predominant
      feature; -- more commonly called {Gothic}.
      [1913 Webster] -- {Point"ed*ly}, adv. -- {Point"ed*ness},
      n.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pointed
     adj 1: having a point [ant: {pointless}]
     2: direct and obvious in meaning or reference; often
        unpleasant; "a pointed critique"; "a pointed allusion to
        what was going on"; "another pointed look in their
        direction"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
