<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pointer</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pointer
     
        1. &lt;programming&gt; An {address}, from the point of view of a
        programming language.  A pointer may be typed, with its {type}
        indicating the type of data to which it points.
     
        The terms "pointer" and "reference" are generally
        interchangable although particular programming languages often
        differentiate these two in subtle ways.  For example, {Perl}
        always calls them references, never pointers.  Conversely, in
        C, "pointer" is used, although "a reference" is often used to
        denote the concept that a pointer implements.
     
        {Anthony Hoare} once said:
     
        Pointers are like jumps, leading wildly from one part of the
        data structure to another.  Their introduction into high-level
        languages has been a step backward from which we may never
        recover.
     
        [C.A.R.Hoare "Hints on Programming Language Design", 1973,
        Prentice-Hall collection of essays and papers by Tony Hoare].
     
        2. &lt;operating system&gt; (Or "mouse pointer") An {icon}, usually
        a small arrow, that moves on the screen in response to
        movement of a {pointing device}, typically a {mouse}.  The
        pointer shows the user which object on the screen will be
        selected etc. when a mouse button is clicked.
     
        (1999-07-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pointer, KY
  Zip code(s): 42544
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Point \Point\, n. [F. point, and probably also pointe, L.
   punctum, puncta, fr. pungere, punctum, to prick. See
   {Pungent}, and cf. {Puncto}, {Puncture}.]
   1. That which pricks or pierces; the sharp end of anything,
      esp. the sharp end of a piercing instrument, as a needle
      or a pin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An instrument which pricks or pierces, as a sort of needle
      used by engravers, etchers, lace workers, and others;
      also, a pointed cutting tool, as a stone cutter's point;
      -- called also {pointer}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything which tapers to a sharp, well-defined
      termination. Specifically: A small promontory or cape; a
      tract of land extending into the water beyond the common
      shore line.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The mark made by the end of a sharp, piercing instrument,
      as a needle; a prick.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An indefinitely small space; a mere spot indicated or
      supposed. Specifically: (Geom.) That which has neither
      parts nor magnitude; that which has position, but has
      neither length, breadth, nor thickness, -- sometimes
      conceived of as the limit of a line; that by the motion of
      which a line is conceived to be produced.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. An indivisible portion of time; a moment; an instant;
      hence, the verge.
      [1913 Webster]

            When time's first point begun
            Made he all souls.                    --Sir J.
                                                  Davies.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A mark of punctuation; a character used to mark the
      divisions of a composition, or the pauses to be observed
      in reading, or to point off groups of figures, etc.; a
      stop, as a comma, a semicolon, and esp. a period; hence,
      figuratively, an end, or conclusion.
      [1913 Webster]

            And there a point, for ended is my tale. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Commas and points they set exactly right. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Whatever serves to mark progress, rank, or relative
      position, or to indicate a transition from one state or
      position to another, degree; step; stage; hence, position
      or condition attained; as, a point of elevation, or of
      depression; the stock fell off five points; he won by
      tenpoints. ``A point of precedence.'' --Selden. ``Creeping
      on from point to point.'' --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            A lord full fat and in good point.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. That which arrests attention, or indicates qualities or
      character; a salient feature; a characteristic; a
      peculiarity; hence, a particular; an item; a detail; as,
      the good or bad points of a man, a horse, a book, a story,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            He told him, point for point, in short and plain.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            In point of religion and in point of honor. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shalt thou dispute
            With Him the points of liberty ?      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Hence, the most prominent or important feature, as of an
       argument, discourse, etc.; the essential matter; esp.,
       the proposition to be established; as, the point of an
       anecdote. ``Here lies the point.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             They will hardly prove his point.    --Arbuthnot.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A small matter; a trifle; a least consideration; a
       punctilio.
       [1913 Webster]

             This fellow doth not stand upon points. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             [He] cared not for God or man a point. --Spenser.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Mus.) A dot or mark used to designate certain tones or
       time; as:
       (a) (Anc. Mus.) A dot or mark distinguishing or
           characterizing certain tones or styles; as, points of
           perfection, of augmentation, etc.; hence, a note; a
           tune. ``Sound the trumpet -- not a levant, or a
           flourish, but a point of war.'' --Sir W. Scott.
       (b) (Mod. Mus.) A dot placed at the right hand of a note,
           to raise its value, or prolong its time, by one half,
           as to make a whole note equal to three half notes, a
           half note equal to three quarter notes.
           [1913 Webster]

   13. (Astron.) A fixed conventional place for reference, or
       zero of reckoning, in the heavens, usually the
       intersection of two or more great circles of the sphere,
       and named specifically in each case according to the
       position intended; as, the equinoctial points; the
       solstitial points; the nodal points; vertical points,
       etc. See {Equinoctial Nodal}.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Her.) One of the several different parts of the
       escutcheon. See {Escutcheon}.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Naut.)
       (a) One of the points of the compass (see {Points of the
           compass}, below); also, the difference between two
           points of the compass; as, to fall off a point.
       (b) A short piece of cordage used in reefing sails. See
           {Reef point}, under {Reef}.
           [1913 Webster]

   16. (Anc. Costume) A a string or lace used to tie together
       certain parts of the dress. --Sir W. Scott.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. Lace wrought the needle; as, point de Venise; Brussels
       point. See Point lace, below.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. pl. (Railways) A switch. [Eng.]
       [1913 Webster]

   19. An item of private information; a hint; a tip; a pointer.
       [Cant, U. S.]
       [1913 Webster]

   20. (Cricket) A fielder who is stationed on the off side,
       about twelve or fifteen yards from, and a little in
       advance of, the batsman.
       [1913 Webster]

   21. The attitude assumed by a pointer dog when he finds game;
       as, the dog came to a point. See {Pointer}.
       [1913 Webster]

   22. (Type Making) A standard unit of measure for the size of
       type bodies, being one twelfth of the thickness of pica
       type. See {Point system of type}, under {Type}.
       [1913 Webster]

   23. A tyne or snag of an antler.
       [1913 Webster]

   24. One of the spaces on a backgammon board.
       [1913 Webster]

   25. (Fencing) A movement executed with the saber or foil; as,
       tierce point.
       [1913 Webster]

   26. (Med.) A pointed piece of quill or bone covered at one
       end with vaccine matter; -- called also {vaccine point}.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   27. One of the raised dots used in certain systems of
       printing and writing for the blind. The first practical
       system was that devised by Louis Braille in 1829, and
       still used in Europe (see {Braille}). Two modifications
       of this are current in the United States:

   {New York point} founded on three bases of equidistant points
      arranged in two lines (viz., : :: :::), and a later
      improvement,

   {American Braille}, embodying the Braille base (:::) and the
      New-York-point principle of using the characters of few
      points for the commonest letters.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   28. In technical senses:
       (a) In various games, a position of a certain player, or,
           by extension, the player himself; as: (1) (Lacrosse &amp;
           Ice Hockey) The position of the player of each side
           who stands a short distance in front of the goal
           keeper; also, the player himself. (2) (Baseball)
           (pl.) The position of the pitcher and catcher.
       (b) (Hunting) A spot to which a straight run is made;
           hence, a straight run from point to point; a
           cross-country run. [Colloq. Oxf. E. D.]
       (c) (Falconry) The perpendicular rising of a hawk over
           the place where its prey has gone into cover.
       (d) Act of pointing, as of the foot downward in certain
           dance positions.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: The word point is a general term, much used in the
         sciences, particularly in mathematics, mechanics,
         perspective, and physics, but generally either in the
         geometrical sense, or in that of degree, or condition
         of change, and with some accompanying descriptive or
         qualifying term, under which, in the vocabulary, the
         specific uses are explained; as, boiling point, carbon
         point, dry point, freezing point, melting point,
         vanishing point, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {At all points}, in every particular, completely; perfectly.
      --Shak.

   {At point}, {In point}, {At the point}, {In the point}, or
   {On the point}, as near as can be; on the verge; about (see
      {About}, prep., 6); as, at the point of death; he was on
      the point of speaking. ``In point to fall down.''
      --Chaucer. ``Caius Sidius Geta, at point to have been
      taken, recovered himself so valiantly as brought day on
      his side.'' --Milton.

   {Dead point}. (Mach.) Same as {Dead center}, under {Dead}.

   {Far point} (Med.), in ophthalmology, the farthest point at
      which objects are seen distinctly. In normal eyes the
      nearest point at which objects are seen distinctly; either
      with the two eyes together (binocular near point), or with
      each eye separately (monocular near point).

   {Nine points of the law}, all but the tenth point; the
      greater weight of authority.

   {On the point}. See {At point}, above.

   {Point lace}, lace wrought with the needle, as distinguished
      from that made on the pillow.

   {Point net}, a machine-made lace imitating a kind of Brussels
      lace (Brussels ground).

   {Point of concurrence} (Geom.), a point common to two lines,
      but not a point of tangency or of intersection, as, for
      instance, that in which a cycloid meets its base.

   {Point of contrary flexure}, a point at which a curve changes
      its direction of curvature, or at which its convexity and
      concavity change sides.

   {Point of order}, in parliamentary practice, a question of
      order or propriety under the rules.

   {Point of sight} (Persp.), in a perspective drawing, the
      point assumed as that occupied by the eye of the
      spectator.

   {Point of view}, the relative position from which anything is
      seen or any subject is considered.

   {Points of the compass} (Naut.), the thirty-two points of
      division of the compass card in the mariner's compass; the
      corresponding points by which the circle of the horizon is
      supposed to be divided, of which the four marking the
      directions of east, west, north, and south, are called
      cardinal points, and the rest are named from their
      respective directions, as N. by E., N. N. E., N. E. by N.,
      N. E., etc. See Illust. under {Compass}.

   {Point paper}, paper pricked through so as to form a stencil
      for transferring a design.

   {Point system of type}. See under {Type}.

   {Singular point} (Geom.), a point of a curve which possesses
      some property not possessed by points in general on the
      curve, as a cusp, a point of inflection, a node, etc.

   {To carry one's point}, to accomplish one's object, as in a
      controversy.

   {To make a point of}, to attach special importance to.

   {To make a point}, or {To gain a point}, accomplish that
      which was proposed; also, to make advance by a step,
      grade, or position.

   {To mark a point}, or {To score a point}, as in billiards,
      cricket, etc., to note down, or to make, a successful hit,
      run, etc.

   {To strain a point}, to go beyond the proper limit or rule;
      to stretch one's authority or conscience.

   {Vowel point}, in Arabic, Hebrew, and certain other Eastern
      and ancient languages, a mark placed above or below the
      consonant, or attached to it, representing the vowel, or
      vocal sound, which precedes or follows the consonant.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pointer \Point"er\, n.
   One who, or that which, points. Specifically:
   (a) The hand of a timepiece.
   (b) (Zo["o]l.) One of a breed of dogs trained to stop at
       scent of game, and with the nose point it out to
       sportsmen.
   (c) pl. (Astron.) The two stars (Merak and Dubhe) in the
       Great Bear, the line between which points nearly in the
       direction of the north star. See Illust. of {Ursa Major}.
   (b) pl. (Naut.) Diagonal braces sometimes fixed across the
       hold.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Dog \Dog\ (d[o^]g), n. [AS. docga; akin to D. dog mastiff, Dan.
   dogge, Sw. dogg.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) A quadruped of the genus {Canis}, esp. the
      domestic dog ({Canis familiaris}).

   Note: The dog is distinguished above all others of the
         inferior animals for intelligence, docility, and
         attachment to man. There are numerous carefully bred
         varieties, as the {akita}, {beagle}, {bloodhound},
         {bulldog}, {coachdog}, {collie}, {Danish dog},
         {foxhound}, {greyhound}, {mastiff}, {pointer},
         {poodle}, {St. Bernard}, {setter}, {spaniel}, {spitz
         dog}, {terrier}, {German shepherd}, {pit bull},
         {Chihuahua}, etc. There are also many mixed breeds, and
         partially domesticated varieties, as well as wild dogs,
         like the dingo and dhole. (See these names in the
         Vocabulary.)
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. A mean, worthless fellow; a wretch.
      [1913 Webster]

            What is thy servant, which is but a dog, that he
            should do this great thing?           -- 2 Kings
                                                  viii. 13 (Rev.
                                                  Ver. )
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A fellow; -- used humorously or contemptuously; as, a sly
      dog; a lazy dog. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Astron.) One of the two constellations, Canis Major and
      Canis Minor, or the Greater Dog and the Lesser Dog. Canis
      Major contains the Dog Star (Sirius).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An iron for holding wood in a fireplace; a firedog; an
      andiron.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mech.)
      (a) A grappling iron, with a claw or claws, for fastening
          into wood or other heavy articles, for the purpose of
          raising or moving them.
      (b) An iron with fangs fastening a log in a saw pit, or on
          the carriage of a sawmill.
      (c) A piece in machinery acting as a catch or clutch;
          especially, the carrier of a lathe, also, an
          adjustable stop to change motion, as in a machine
          tool.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. an ugly or crude person, especially an ugly woman. [slang]
      [PJC]

   8. a {hot dog}. [slang]
      [PJC]

   Note: Dog is used adjectively or in composition, commonly in
         the sense of relating to, or characteristic of, a dog.
         It is also used to denote a male; as, dog fox or g-fox,
         a male fox; dog otter or dog-otter, dog wolf, etc.; --
         also to denote a thing of cheap or mean quality; as,
         dog Latin.
         [1913 Webster]

   {A dead dog}, a thing of no use or value. --1 Sam. xxiv. 14.

   {A dog in the manger}, an ugly-natured person who prevents
      others from enjoying what would be an advantage to them
      but is none to him.

   {Dog ape} (Zo["o]l.), a male ape.

   {Dog cabbage}, or {Dog's cabbage} (Bot.), a succulent herb,
      native to the Mediterranean region ({Thelygonum
      Cynocrambe}).

   {Dog cheap}, very cheap. See under {Cheap}.

   {Dog ear} (Arch.), an acroterium. [Colloq.]

   {Dog flea} (Zo["o]l.), a species of flea ({Pulex canis})
      which infests dogs and cats, and is often troublesome to
      man. In America it is the common flea. See {Flea}, and
      {Aphaniptera}.

   {Dog grass} (Bot.), a grass ({Triticum caninum}) of the same
      genus as wheat.

   {Dog Latin}, barbarous Latin; as, the dog Latin of pharmacy.
      

   {Dog lichen} (Bot.), a kind of lichen ({Peltigera canina})
      growing on earth, rocks, and tree trunks, -- a lobed
      expansion, dingy green above and whitish with fuscous
      veins beneath.

   {Dog louse} (Zo["o]l.), a louse that infests the dog, esp.
      {H[ae]matopinus piliferus}; another species is
      {Trichodectes latus}.

   {Dog power}, a machine operated by the weight of a dog
      traveling in a drum, or on an endless track, as for
      churning.

   {Dog salmon} (Zo["o]l.), a salmon of northwest America and
      northern Asia; -- the {gorbuscha}; -- called also {holia},
      and {hone}.

   {Dog shark}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Dogfish}.

   {Dog's meat}, meat fit only for dogs; refuse; offal.

   {Dog Star}. See in the Vocabulary.

   {Dog wheat} (Bot.), Dog grass.

   {Dog whelk} (Zo["o]l.), any species of univalve shells of the
      family {Nassid[ae]}, esp. the {Nassa reticulata} of
      England.

   {To give to the dogs}, or {To throw to the dogs}, to throw
      away as useless. ``Throw physic to the dogs; I'll none of
      it.'' --Shak.

   {To go to the dogs}, to go to ruin; to be ruined.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pointer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pointer
     n 1: a mark to indicate a direction or relation [syn: {arrow}]
     2: an indicator as on a dial
     3: (computer science) indicator consisting of a movable spot of
        light (an icon) on a visual display; moving the cursor
        allows the user to point to commands or screen positions
        [syn: {cursor}]
     4: a strong slender smooth-haired dog of Spanish origin having
        a white coat with brown or black patches; scents out and
        points game [syn: {Spanish pointer}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
