<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>police</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>police</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>POLICE, n.  An armed force for protection and participation.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>police</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Police \Po*lice"\, n. [F., fr. L. politia the condition of a
   state, government, administration, Gr. ?, fr. ? to be a
   citizen, to govern or administer a state, fr. ? citizen, fr.
   ? city; akin to Skr. pur, puri. Cf. {Policy} polity,
   {Polity}.]
   1. A judicial and executive system, for the government of a
      city, town, or district, for the preservation of rights,
      order, cleanliness, health, etc., and for the enforcement
      of the laws and prevention of crime; the administration of
      the laws and regulations of a city, incorporated town, or
      borough.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which concerns the order of the community; the
      internal regulation of a state.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The organized body of civil officers in a city, town, or
      district, whose particular duties are the preservation of
      good order, the prevention and detection of crime, and the
      enforcement of the laws.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) Military police, the body of soldiers detailed to
      preserve civil order and attend to sanitary arrangements
      in a camp or garrison.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The cleaning of a camp or garrison, or the state ? a camp
      as to cleanliness.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Police commissioner}, a civil officer, usually one of a
      board, commissioned to regulate and control the
      appointment, duties, and discipline of the police.

   {Police constable}, or {Police officer}, a policeman.

   {Police court}, a minor court to try persons brought before
      it by the police.

   {Police inspector}, an officer of police ranking next below a
      superintendent.

   {Police jury}, a body of officers who collectively exercise
      jurisdiction in certain cases of police, as levying taxes,
      etc.; -- so called in Louisiana. --Bouvier.

   {Police justice}, or {Police magistrate}, a judge of a police
      court.

   {Police offenses} (Law), minor offenses against the order of
      the community, of which a police court may have final
      jurisdiction.

   {Police station}, the headquarters of the police, or of a
      section of them; the place where the police assemble for
      orders, and to which they take arrested persons.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>police</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Police \Po*lice"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Policed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Policing}.]
   1. To keep in order by police.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) To make clean; as, to police a camp.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>police</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>police
     n : the force of policemen and officers; "the law came looking
         for him" [syn: {police force}, {constabulary}, {law}]
     v : maintain the security of by carrying out a control [syn: {patrol}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
