<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pool</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pool
   a pond, or reservoir, for holding water (Heb. berekhah; modern
   Arabic, birket), an artificial cistern or tank. Mention is made
   of the pool of Gibeon (2 Sam. 2:13); the pool of Hebron (4:12);
   the upper pool at Jerusalem (2 Kings 18:17; 20:20); the pool of
   Samaria (1 Kings 22:38); the king's pool (Neh. 2:14); the pool
   of Siloah (Neh. 3:15; Eccles. 2:6); the fishpools of Heshbon
   (Cant. 7:4); the "lower pool," and the "old pool" (Isa.
   22:9,11).
   
     The "pool of Bethesda" (John 5:2,4, 7) and the "pool of
   Siloam" (John 9:7, 11) are also mentioned. Isaiah (35:7) says,
   "The parched ground shall become a pool." This is rendered in
   the Revised Version "glowing sand," etc. (marg., "the mirage,"
   etc.). The Arabs call the mirage "serab," plainly the same as
   the Hebrew word _sarab_, here rendered "parched ground." "The
   mirage shall become a pool", i.e., the mock-lake of the burning
   desert shall become a real lake, "the pledge of refreshment and
   joy." The "pools" spoken of in Isa. 14:23 are the marshes caused
   by the ruin of the canals of the Euphrates in the neighbourhood
   of Babylon.
   
     The cisterns or pools of the Holy City are for the most part
   excavations beneath the surface. Such are the vast cisterns in
   the temple hill that have recently been discovered by the
   engineers of the Palestine Exploration Fund. These underground
   caverns are about thirty-five in number, and are capable of
   storing about ten million gallons of water. They are connected
   with one another by passages and tunnels.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>POOL
     
        Parallel Object-Oriented Language.
     
        A series of languages from {Philips Research Labs}.
     
        See {POOL2}, {POOL-I}, {POOL-T}.
     
        (1995-02-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pool, WV
  Zip code(s): 26684
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pool \Pool\, n. [AS. p[=o]l; akin to LG. pool, pohl, D. poel, G.
   pfuhl; cf. Icel. pollr, also W. pwll, Gael. poll.]
   1. A small and rather deep collection of (usually) fresh
      water, as one supplied by a spring, or occurring in the
      course of a stream; a reservoir for water; as, the pools
      of Solomon. --Wyclif.
      [1913 Webster]

            Charity will hardly water the ground where it must
            first fill a pool.                    --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sleepy pool above the dam.        --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A small body of standing or stagnant water; a puddle.
      ``The filthy mantled pool beyond your cell.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pool \Pool\, n. [F. poule, properly, a hen. See {Pullet}.]
   [Written also {poule}.]
   1. The stake played for in certain games of cards, billiards,
      etc.; an aggregated stake to which each player has
      contributed a snare; also, the receptacle for the stakes.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A game at billiards, in which each of the players stakes a
      certain sum, the winner taking the whole; also, in public
      billiard rooms, a game in which the loser pays the
      entrance fee for all who engage in the game; a game of
      skill in pocketing the balls on a pool table.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: This game is played variously, but commonly with
         fifteen balls, besides one cue ball, the contest being
         to drive the most balls into the pockets.
         [1913 Webster]

               He plays pool at the billiard houses.
                                                  --Thackeray.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. In rifle shooting, a contest in which each competitor pays
      a certain sum for every shot he makes, the net proceeds
      being divided among the winners.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any gambling or commercial venture in which several
      persons join.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A combination of persons contributing money to be used for
      the purpose of increasing or depressing the market price
      of stocks, grain, or other commodities; also, the
      aggregate of the sums so contributed; as, the pool took
      all the wheat offered below the limit; he put $10,000 into
      the pool.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Railroads) A mutual arrangement between competing lines,
      by which the receipts of all are aggregated, and then
      distributed pro rata according to agreement.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) An aggregation of properties or rights, belonging to
      different people in a community, in a common fund, to be
      charged with common liabilities.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Pin pool}, a variety of the game of billiards in which small
      wooden pins are set up to be knocked down by the balls.

   {Pool ball}, one of the colored ivory balls used in playing
      the game at billiards called pool.

   {Pool snipe} (Zo["o]l.), the European redshank. [Prov. Eng.]
      

   {Pool table}, a billiard table with pockets.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pool \Pool\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pooled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Pooling}.]
   To put together; to contribute to a common fund, on the basis
   of a mutual division of profits or losses; to make a common
   interest of; as, the companies pooled their traffic.
   [1913 Webster]

         Finally, it favors the poolingof all issues. --U. S.
                                                  Grant.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pool \Pool\, v. i.
   To combine or contribute with others, as for a commercial,
   speculative, or gambling transaction.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>POOL
     Parallel Object Orientated Language (DOOM, OOP)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pool</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pool
     n 1: an excavation that is (usually) filled with water
     2: a small lake; "the pond was too small for sailing" [syn: {pond}]
     3: an organization of people or resources that can be shared;
        "a car pool"; "a secretarial pool"; "when he was first
        hired he was assigned to the pool"
     4: an association of companies for some definite purpose [syn:
        {consortium}, {syndicate}]
     5: any communal combination of funds; "everyone contributed to
        the pool"
     6: a small body of standing water (rainwater) or other liquid;
        "there were puddles of muddy water in the road after the
        rain"; "the body lay in a pool of blood" [syn: {puddle}]
     7: the combined stakes of the betters [syn: {kitty}]
     8: something resembling a pool of liquid; "he stood in a pool
        of light"; "his chair sat in a puddle of books and
        magazines" [syn: {puddle}]
     9: any of various games played on a pool table having 6 pockets
        [syn: {pocket billiards}]
     v 1: combine into a common fund; "We pooled resources"
     2: join or form a pool of people
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
