<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>portal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>portal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PORTAL
     
        Process-Oriented Real-Time Algorithmic Language.
     
        ["PORTAL - A Pascal-based Real-Time Programming Language",
        R. Schild in Algorithmic Languages, J.W. deBakker et al eds,
        N-H 1981].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>portal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>portal
     
        &lt;World-Wide Web&gt; A {web site} that aims to be an entry point
        to the {World-Wide Web}, typically offering a {search engine}
        and/or links to useful pages, and possibly news or other
        services.  These services are usually provided for free in the
        hope that users will make the site their default {home page}
        or at least visit it often.  Popular examples are {Yahoo} and
        {MSN}.  Most portals on the {Internet} exist to generate
        advertising income for their owners, others may be focused on
        a specific group of users and may be part of an {intranet} or
        {extranet}.  Some may just concentrate on one particular
        subject, say technology or medicine, and are known as a
        {vertical portals}.
     
        (2001-07-07)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>portal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Portal, AZ
  Zip code(s): 85632
Portal, GA (town, FIPS 62216)
  Location: 32.53627 N, 81.93058 W
  Population (1990): 522 (229 housing units)
  Area: 4.5 sq km (land), 0.1 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 30450
Portal, ND (city, FIPS 63740)
  Location: 48.99561 N, 102.54787 W
  Population (1990): 192 (104 housing units)
  Area: 1.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 58772
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>portal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Portal \Por"tal\, n. [OF. portal, F. portail, LL. portale, fr.
   L. porta a gate. See {Port} a gate.]
   1. A door or gate; hence, a way of entrance or exit,
      especially one that is grand and imposing.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thick with sparkling orient gems
            The portal shone.                     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            From out the fiery portal of the east. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.)
      (a) The lesser gate, where there are two of different
          dimensions.
      (b) Formerly, a small square corner in a room separated
          from the rest of the apartment by wainscoting, forming
          a short passage to another apartment.
      (c) By analogy with the French portail, used by recent
          writers for the whole architectural composition which
          surrounds and includes the doorways and porches of a
          church.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bridge Building) The space, at one end, between opposite
      trusses when these are terminated by inclined braces.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A prayer book or breviary; a portass. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Portal bracing} (Bridge Building), a combination of struts
      and ties which lie in the plane of the inclined braces at
      a portal, serving to transfer wind pressure from the upper
      parts of the trusses to an abutment or pier of the bridge.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>portal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Portal \Por"tal\, a. (Anat.)
   Of or pertaining to a porta, especially the porta of the
   liver; as, the portal vein, which enters the liver at the
   porta, and divides into capillaries after the manner of an
   artery.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: Portal is applied to other veins which break up into
         capillaries; as, the renal portal veins in the frog.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>portal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>portal
     n 1: a grand and imposing entrance (often extended
          metaphorically); "the portals of the cathedral"; "the
          portals of heaven"; "the portals of success"
     2: a site that the owner positions as an entrance to other
        sites on the internet; "a portal typically has search
        engines and free email and chat rooms etc." [syn: {portal
        site}]
     3: a short vein that carries blood into the liver [syn: {portal
        vein}, {hepatic portal vein}, {vena portae}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
