<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>position</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>position</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Position \Po*si"tion\, n. [F. position, L. positio, fr. ponere,
   positum, to put, place; prob. for posino, fr. an old
   preposition used only in comp. (akin to Gr. ?) + sinere to
   leave, let, permit, place. See {Site}, and cf. {Composite},
   {Compound}, v., {Depone}, {Deposit}, {Expound}, {Impostor},
   {Opposite}, {Propound}, {Pose}, v., {Posit}, {Post}, n.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The state of being posited, or placed; the manner in which
      anything is placed; attitude; condition; as, a firm, an
      inclined, or an upright position.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have different prospects of the same thing,
            according to our different positions to it. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The spot where a person or thing is placed or takes a
      place; site; place; station; situation; as, the position
      of man in creation; the fleet changed its position.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: The ground which any one takes in an argument or
      controversy; the point of view from which any one proceeds
      to a discussion; also, a principle laid down as the basis
      of reasoning; a proposition; a thesis; as, to define one's
      position; to appear in a false position.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let not the proof of any position depend on the
            positions that follow, but always on those which go
            before.                               --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Relative place or standing; social or official rank; as, a
      person of position; hence, office; post; as, to lose one's
      position.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Arith.) A method of solving a problem by one or two
      suppositions; -- called also the {rule of trial and
      error}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Angle of position} (Astron.), the angle which any line (as
      that joining two stars) makes with another fixed line,
      specifically with a circle of declination.

   {Double position} (Arith.), the method of solving problems by
      proceeding with each of two assumed numbers, according to
      the conditions of the problem, and by comparing the
      difference of the results with those of the numbers,
      deducing the correction to be applied to one of them to
      obtain the true result.

   {Guns of position} (Mil.), heavy fieldpieces, not designed
      for quick movements.

   {Position finder} (Mil.), a range finder. See under {Range}.
      

   {Position micrometer}, a micrometer applied to the tube of an
      astronomical telescope for measuring angles of position in
      the field of view.

   {Single position} (Arith.), the method of solving problems,
      in which the result obtained by operating with an assumed
      number is to the true result as the number assumed is to
      the number required.

   {Strategic position} (Mil.), a position taken up by an army
      or a large detachment of troops for the purpose of
      checking or observing an opposing force.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Situation; station; place; condition; attitude; posture;
        proposition; assertion; thesis.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>position</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Position \Po*si"tion\, v. t.
   To indicate the position of; to place. [R.] --Encyc. Brit.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>position</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Angle \An"gle\ ([a^][ng]"g'l), n. [F. angle, L. angulus angle,
   corner; akin to uncus hook, Gr. 'agky`los bent, crooked,
   angular, 'a`gkos a bend or hollow, AS. angel hook, fish-hook,
   G. angel, and F. anchor.]
   1. The inclosed space near the point where two lines meet; a
      corner; a nook.
      [1913 Webster]

            Into the utmost angle of the world.   --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            To search the tenderest angles of the heart.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geom.)
      (a) The figure made by. two lines which meet.
      (b) The difference of direction of two lines. In the lines
          meet, the point of meeting is the vertex of the angle.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. A projecting or sharp corner; an angular fragment.
      [1913 Webster]

            Though but an angle reached him of the stone.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Astrol.) A name given to four of the twelve astrological
      ``houses.'' [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. [AS. angel.] A fishhook; tackle for catching fish,
      consisting of a line, hook, and bait, with or without a
      rod.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give me mine angle: we 'll to the river there.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A fisher next his trembling angle bears. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Acute angle}, one less than a right angle, or less than
      90[deg].

   {Adjacent} or {Contiguous angles}, such as have one leg
      common to both angles.

   {Alternate angles}. See {Alternate}.

   {Angle bar}.
      (a) (Carp.) An upright bar at the angle where two faces of
          a polygonal or bay window meet. --Knight.
      (b) (Mach.) Same as {Angle iron}.

   {Angle bead} (Arch.), a bead worked on or fixed to the angle
      of any architectural work, esp. for protecting an angle of
      a wall.

   {Angle brace}, {Angle tie} (Carp.), a brace across an
      interior angle of a wooden frame, forming the hypothenuse
      and securing the two side pieces together. --Knight.

   {Angle iron} (Mach.), a rolled bar or plate of iron having
      one or more angles, used for forming the corners, or
      connecting or sustaining the sides of an iron structure to
      which it is riveted.

   {Angle leaf} (Arch.), a detail in the form of a leaf, more or
      less conventionalized, used to decorate and sometimes to
      strengthen an angle.

   {Angle meter}, an instrument for measuring angles, esp. for
      ascertaining the dip of strata.

   {Angle shaft} (Arch.), an enriched angle bead, often having a
      capital or base, or both.

   {Curvilineal angle}, one formed by two curved lines.

   {External angles}, angles formed by the sides of any
      right-lined figure, when the sides are produced or
      lengthened.

   {Facial angle}. See under {Facial}.

   {Internal angles}, those which are within any right-lined
      figure.

   {Mixtilineal angle}, one formed by a right line with a curved
      line.

   {Oblique angle}, one acute or obtuse, in opposition to a
      right angle.

   {Obtuse angle}, one greater than a right angle, or more than
      90[deg].

   {Optic angle}. See under {Optic}.

   {Rectilineal} or {Right-lined angle}, one formed by two right
      lines.

   {Right angle}, one formed by a right line falling on another
      perpendicularly, or an angle of 90[deg] (measured by a
      quarter circle).

   {Solid angle}, the figure formed by the meeting of three or
      more plane angles at one point.

   {Spherical angle}, one made by the meeting of two arcs of
      great circles, which mutually cut one another on the
      surface of a globe or sphere.

   {Visual angle}, the angle formed by two rays of light, or two
      straight lines drawn from the extreme points of an object
      to the center of the eye.

   {For Angles of commutation}, {draught}, {incidence},
   {reflection}, {refraction}, {position}, {repose}, {fraction},
      see {Commutation}, {Draught}, {Incidence}, {Reflection},
      {Refraction}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>position</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>position
     n 1: the particular portion of space occupied by a physical
          object; "he put the lamp back in its place" [syn: {place}]
     2: a point occupied by troops for tactical reasons [syn: {military
        position}]
     3: a way of regarding situations or topics etc.; "consider what
        follows from the positivist view" [syn: {view}, {perspective}]
     4: position or arrangement of the body and its limbs; "he
        assumed an attitude of surrender" [syn: {posture}, {attitude}]
     5: the relative position or standing of things or especially
        persons in a society; "he had the status of a minor"; "the
        novel attained the status of a classic"; "atheists do not
        enjoy a favorable position in American life" [syn: {status}]
     6: a job in an organization; "he occupied a post in the
        treasury" [syn: {post}, {berth}, {office}, {spot}, {billet},
         {place}, {situation}]
     7: the spatial property of a place where or way in which
        something is situated; "the position of the hands on the
        clock"; "he specified the spatial relations of every piece
        of furniture on the stage" [syn: {spatial relation}]
     8: the appropriate or customary location; "the cars were in
        position"
     9: (in team sports) the role assigned to an individual player;
        "what position does he play?"
     10: the act of putting something in a certain place or location
         [syn: {placement}, {location}, {locating}, {positioning},
          {emplacement}]
     11: a condition or position in which you find yourself; "the
         unpleasant situation (or position) of having to choose
         between two evils"; "found herself in a very fortunate
         situation" [syn: {situation}]
     12: an item on a list or in a sequence; "in the second place";
         "moved from third to fifth position" [syn: {place}]
     13: a rationalized mental attitude [syn: {stance}, {posture}]
     14: an opinion that is held in opposition to another in an
         argument or dispute; "there are two sides to every
         question" [syn: {side}]
     15: the function or position properly or customarily occupied or
         served by another; "can you go in my stead?"; "took his
         place"; "in lieu of" [syn: {stead}, {place}, {lieu}]
     16: the act of positing; an assumption taken as a postulate or
         axiom
     v 1: cause to be in an appropriate place, state, or relation
     2: put into a certain place or abstract location; "Put your
        things here"; "Set the tray down"; "Set the dogs on the
        scent of the missing children"; "Place emphasis on a
        certain point" [syn: {put}, {set}, {place}, {pose}, {lay}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
