<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>possession</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>possession</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Possession \Pos*ses"sion\, n. [F. possession, L. possessio.]
   1. The act or state of possessing, or holding as one's own.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) The having, holding, or detention of property in
      one's power or command; actual seizin or occupancy;
      ownership, whether rightful or wrongful.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Possession may be either actual or constructive;
         actual, when a party has the immediate occupancy;
         constructive, when he has only the right to such
         occupancy.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The thing possessed; that which any one occupies, owns, or
      controls; in the plural, property in the aggregate;
      wealth; dominion; as, foreign possessions.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the young man heard that saying, he went away
            sorrowful, for he had great possessions. --Matt.
                                                  xix. 22.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ananias, with Sapphira his wife, sold a possession.
                                                  --Acts v. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            The house of Jacob shall possess their possessions.
                                                  --Ob. 17.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The state of being possessed or controlled, as by an evil
      spirit, or violent passions; madness; frenzy; as,
      demoniacal possession.
      [1913 Webster]

            How long hath this possession held the man? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To give possession}, to put in another's power or occupancy.
      

   {To put in possession}.
      (a) To invest with ownership or occupancy; to provide or
          furnish with; as, to put one in possession of facts or
          information.
      (b) (Law) To place one in charge of property recovered in
          ejectment or writ of entry.

   {To take possession}, to enter upon, or to bring within one's
      power or occupancy.

   {Writ of possession} (Law), a precept directing a sheriff to
      put a person in peaceable possession of property recovered
      in ejectment or writ of entry.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>possession</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Possession \Pos*ses"sion\, v. t.
   To invest with property. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>possession</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>possession
     n 1: the act of having and controlling property [syn: {ownership}]
     2: anything owned or possessed
     3: being controlled by passion or the supernatural
     4: a mania restricted to one thing or idea [syn: {monomania}]
     5: a territory that is controllled by a ruling state
     6: the trait of resolutely controlling your own behavior [syn:
        {self-control}, {self-possession}, {willpower}, {self-command},
         {self-will}]
     7: (sport) the act of controlling the ball (or puck); "they
        took possession of the ball on their own goal line"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
