<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>possess</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>possess</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Possess \Pos*sess"\ (?; 277), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Possessed};
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Possessing}.] [L. possessus, p. p. of
   possidere to have, possess, from an inseparable prep. (cf.
   {Position}) + sedere to sit. See {Sit}.]
   1. To occupy in person; to hold or actually have in one's own
      keeping; to have and to hold.
      [1913 Webster]

            Houses and fields and vineyards shall be possessed
            again in this land.                   --Jer. xxxii.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet beauty, though injurious, hath strange power,
            After offense returning, to regain
            Love once possessed.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To have the legal title to; to have a just right to; to be
      master of; to own; to have; as, to possess property, an
      estate, a book.
      [1913 Webster]

            I am yours, and all that I possess.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To obtain occupation or possession of; to accomplish; to
      gain; to seize.
      [1913 Webster]

            How . . . to possess the purpose they desired.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To enter into and influence; to control the will of; to
      fill; to affect; -- said especially of evil spirits,
      passions, etc. ``Weakness possesseth me.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those which were possessed with devils. --Matt. iv.
                                                  24.
      [1913 Webster]

            For ten inspired, ten thousand are possessed.
                                                  --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To put in possession; to make the owner or holder of
      property, power, knowledge, etc.; to acquaint; to inform;
      -- followed by of or with before the thing possessed, and
      now commonly used reflexively.
      [1913 Webster]

            I have possessed your grace of what I purpose.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Record a gift . . . of all he dies possessed
            Unto his son.                         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            We possessed our selves of the kingdom of Naples.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            To possess our minds with an habitual good
            intention.                            --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To have; hold; occupy; control; own.

   Usage: {Possess}, {Have}. Have is the more general word. To
          possess denotes to have as a property. It usually
          implies more permanence or definiteness of control or
          ownership than is involved in having. A man does not
          possess his wife and children: they are (so to speak)
          part of himself. For the same reason, we have the
          faculties of reason, understanding, will, sound
          judgment, etc.: they are exercises of the mind, not
          possessions.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>possess</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>possess
     v 1: have as an attribute, knowledge, or skill; "he possesses
          great knowledge about the Middle East"
     2: have ownership or possession of; "He owns three houses in
        Florida"; "How many cars does she have?" [syn: {own}, {have}]
     3: enter into and control, as of emotions or ideas; "What
        possessed you to buy this house?"; "A terrible rage
        possessed her"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
