<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>posting</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>posting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>posting
     
        A message sent to a {newsgroup} or {mailing list} (may also be
        called "a post") or the act of sending it.  Distinguished from
        a "letter" or ordinary {electronic mail} message by the fact
        that it is broadcast rather than point-to-point.  It is not
        clear whether messages sent to a small mailing list are
        postings or e-mail; perhaps the best dividing line is that if
        you don't know the names of all the potential recipients, it
        is a posting.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>posting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Post \Post\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Posted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Posting}.]
   1. To attach to a post, a wall, or other usual place of
      affixing public notices; to placard; as, to post a notice;
      to post playbills.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Formerly, a large post was erected before the sheriff's
         office, or in some public place, upon which legal
         notices were displayed. This way of advertisement has
         not entirely gone of use.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. To hold up to public blame or reproach; to advertise
      opprobriously; to denounce by public proclamation; as, to
      post one for cowardice.
      [1913 Webster]

            On pain of being posted to your sorrow
            Fail not, at four, to meet me.        --Granville.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To enter (a name) on a list, as for service, promotion, or
      the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To assign to a station; to set; to place; as, to post a
      sentinel. ``It might be to obtain a ship for a lieutenant,
      . . . or to get him posted.'' --De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Bookkeeping) To carry, as an account, from the journal to
      the ledger; as, to post an account; to transfer, as
      accounts, to the ledger.
      [1913 Webster]

            You have not posted your books these ten years.
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To place in the care of the post; to mail; as, to post a
      letter.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To inform; to give the news to; to make (one) acquainted
      with the details of a subject; -- often with up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thoroughly posted up in the politics and literature
            of the day.                           --Lond. Sat.
                                                  Rev.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To post off}, to put off; to delay. [Obs.] ``Why did I,
      venturously, post off so great a business?'' --Baxter.

   {To post over}, to hurry over. [Obs.] --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>posting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Posting \Post"ing\, n.
   1. The act of traveling post.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bookkeeping) The act of transferring an account, as from
      the journal to the ledger.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Posting house}, a post house.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>posting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>posting n. Noun corresp. to v. {post} (but note that {post} can be
   nouned). Distinguished from a `letter' or ordinary {email} message by
   the fact that it is broadcast rather than point-to-point. It is not
   clear whether messages sent to a small mailing list are postings or
   email; perhaps the best dividing line is that if you don't know the
   names of all the potential recipients, it is a posting.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>posting</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>posting
     n 1: a sign posted in a public place as an advertisement; "a
          poster advertised the coming attractions" [syn: {poster},
           {placard}, {notice}, {bill}, {card}]
     2: (bookkeeping) a listing on the company's records; "the
        posting was made in the cash account"
     3: the transmission of a letter; "the postmark indicates the
        time of mailing" [syn: {mailing}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
