<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>presentation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>presentation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Presentation \Pres`en*ta"tion\, n. [L. praesentatio a showing,
   representation: cf. F. pr['e]sentation.]
   1. The act of presenting, or the state of being presented; a
      setting forth; an offering; bestowal.
      [1913 Webster]

            Prayers are sometimes a presentation of mere
            desires.                              --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, exhibition; representation; display; appearance;
      semblance; show.
      [1913 Webster]

            Under the presentation of the shoots his wit.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is presented or given; a present; a gift, as,
      the picture was a presentation. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Eccl.) The act of offering a clergyman to the bishop or
      ordinary for institution in a benefice; the right of
      presenting a clergyman.
      [1913 Webster]

            If the bishop admits the patron's presentation, the
            clerk so admitted is next to be instituted by him.
                                                  --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Med.) The particular position of the child during labor
      relatively to the passage though which it is to be brought
      forth; -- specifically designated by the part which first
      appears at the mouth of the uterus; as, a breech
      presentation.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Presentation copy}, a copy of a book, engraving, etc.,
      presented to some one by the author or artist, as a token
      of regard.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>presentation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>presentation
     n 1: the activity of formally presenting something (as a prize or
          reward); "she gave the trophy but he made the
          presentation"
     2: the act of making something publicly available; presenting
        news or other information by broadcasting or printing it;
        "he prepared his presentation carefully in advance"
     3: a show or display; the act of presenting something to sight
        or view; "the presentation of new data"; "he gave the
        customer a demonstration" [syn: {presentment}, {demonstration}]
     4: the act of presenting a proposal
     5: a visual representation of something [syn: {display}]
     6: formally making a person known to another or to the public
        [syn: {introduction}, {intro}]
     7: (obstetrics) position of the fetus in the uterus relative to
        the birth canal; "Cesarean sections are sometimes the
        result of abnormal presentations"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
