<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>press</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>press</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Press \Press\, n. (Zo["o]l.)
   An East Indian insectivore ({Tupaia ferruginea}). It is
   arboreal in its habits, and has a bushy tail. The fur is
   soft, and varies from rusty red to maroon and to brownish
   black.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>press</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Press \Press\, v. t. [Corrupt. fr. prest ready money advanced, a
   loan; hence, earnest money given soldiers on entering
   service. See {Prest}, n.]
   To force into service, particularly into naval service; to
   impress.
   [1913 Webster]

         To peaceful peasant to the wars is pressed. --Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>press</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Press \Press\, n. [For prest, confused with press.]
   A commission to force men into public service, particularly
   into the navy.
   [1913 Webster]

         I have misused the king's press.         --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Press gang}, or {Pressgang}, a detachment of seamen under
      the command of an officer empowered to force men into the
      naval service. See {Impress gang}, under {Impress}.

   {Press money}, money paid to a man enlisted into public
      service. See {Prest money}, under {Prest}, a.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>press</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Press \Press\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pressed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Pressing}.] [F. presser, fr. L. pressare to press, fr.
   premere, pressum, to press. Cf. {Print}, v.]
   1. To urge, or act upon, with force, as weight; to act upon
      by pushing or thrusting, in distinction from pulling; to
      crowd or compel by a gradual and continued exertion; to
      bear upon; to squeeze; to compress; as, we press the
      ground with the feet when we walk; we press the couch on
      which we repose; we press substances with the hands,
      fingers, or arms; we are pressed in a crowd.
      [1913 Webster]

            Good measure, pressed down, and shaken together.
                                                  --Luke vi. 38.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To squeeze, in order to extract the juice or contents of;
      to squeeze out, or express, from something.
      [1913 Webster]

            From sweet kernels pressed,
            She tempers dulcet creams.            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            And I took the grapes, and pressed them into
            Pharaoh's cup, and I gave the cup into Pharaoh's
            hand.                                 --Gen. xl. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To squeeze in or with suitable instruments or apparatus,
      in order to compact, make dense, or smooth; as, to press
      cotton bales, paper, etc.; to smooth by ironing; as, to
      press clothes.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To embrace closely; to hug.
      [1913 Webster]

            Leucothoe shook at these alarms,
            And pressed Palemon closer in her arms. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To oppress; to bear hard upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Press not a falling man too far.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To straiten; to distress; as, to be pressed with want or
      hunger.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To exercise very powerful or irresistible influence upon
      or over; to constrain; to force; to compel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Paul was pressed in the spirit, and testified to the
            Jews that Jesus was Christ.           --Acts xviii.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To try to force (something upon some one); to urge or
      inculcate with earnestness or importunity; to enforce; as,
      to press divine truth on an audience.
      [1913 Webster]

            He pressed a letter upon me within this hour.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Be sure to press upon him every motive. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To drive with violence; to hurry; to urge on; to ply hard;
      as, to press a horse in a race.
      [1913 Webster]

            The posts . . . went cut, being hastened and pressed
            on, by the king's commandment.        --Esther viii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Press differs from drive and strike in usually denoting
         a slow or continued application of force; whereas drive
         and strike denote a sudden impulse of force.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Pressed brick}. See under {Brick}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>press</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Press \Press\, v. i.
   1. To exert pressure; to bear heavily; to push, crowd, or
      urge with steady force.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move on with urging and crowding; to make one's way
      with violence or effort; to bear onward forcibly; to
      crowd; to throng; to encroach.
      [1913 Webster]

            They pressed upon him for to touch him. --Mark iii.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To urge with vehemence or importunity; to exert a strong
      or compelling influence; as, an argument presses upon the
      judgment.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>press</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Press \Press\, n. [F. presse. See 4th {Press}.]
   1. An apparatus or machine by which any substance or body is
      pressed, squeezed, stamped, or shaped, or by which an
      impression of a body is taken; sometimes, the place or
      building containing a press or presses.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Presses are differently constructed for various
         purposes in the arts, their specific uses being
         commonly designated; as, a cotton press, a wine press,
         a cider press, a copying press, etc. See {Drill press}.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Specifically, a printing press.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The art or business of printing and publishing; hence,
      printed publications, taken collectively, more especially
      newspapers or the persons employed in writing for them;
      as, a free press is a blessing, a licentious press is a
      curse.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An upright case or closet for the safe keeping of
      articles; as, a clothes press. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The act of pressing or thronging forward.
      [1913 Webster]

            In their throng and press to that last hold. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Urgent demands of business or affairs; urgency; as, a
      press of engagements.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A multitude of individuals crowded together; ? crowd of
      single things; a throng.
      [1913 Webster]

            They could not come nigh unto him for the press.
                                                  --Mark ii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cylinder press}, a printing press in which the impression is
      produced by a revolving cylinder under which the form
      passes; also, one in which the form of type or plates is
      curved around a cylinder, instead of resting on a flat
      bed.

   {Hydrostatic press}. See under {Hydrostatic}.

   {Liberty of the press}, the free right of publishing books,
      pamphlets, or papers, without previous restraint or
      censorship, subject only to punishment for libelous,
      seditious, or morally pernicious matters.

   {Press bed}, a bed that may be folded, and inclosed, in a
      press or closet. --Boswell.

   {Press of sail}, (Naut.), as much sail as the state of the
      wind will permit.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>press</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>press
     n 1: newspaper writers and photographers [syn: {fourth estate}]
     2: the state of urgently demanding notice or attention; "the
        press of business matters" [syn: {imperativeness}, {insistence},
         {insistency}, {pressure}]
     3: the gathering and publishing of news in the form of
        newspapers or magazines [syn: {public press}]
     4: a machine used for printing [syn: {printing press}]
     5: a dense crowd of people [syn: {crush}, {jam}]
     6: a tall piece of furniture that provides storage space for
        clothes; has a door and rails or hooks for hanging clothes
        [syn: {wardrobe}, {closet}]
     7: clamp to prevent wooden rackets from warping when not in use
     8: any machine that exerts pressure to form or shape or cut
        materials or extract liquids or compress solids [syn: {mechanical
        press}]
     9: a weightlift in which the barbell is lifted to shoulder
        height and then smoothly lifted overhead [syn: {military
        press}]
     10: the act of pressing; the exertion of pressure; "he gave the
         button a press"; "he used pressure to stop the bleeding";
         "at the pressing of a button" [syn: {pressure}, {pressing}]
     v 1: exert pressure or force to or upon; "He pressed down on the
          boards"; "press your thumb on this spot"
     2: force or impel in an indicated direction; "I urged him to
        finish his studies" [syn: {urge}, {urge on}, {exhort}]
     3: to be oppressive or burdensome; "weigh heavily on the mind",
        "Something pressed on his mind" [syn: {weigh}]
     4: place between two surfaces and apply weight or pressure;
        "pressed flowers"
     5: squeeze or press together; "she compressed her lips"; "the
        spasm contracted the muscle" [syn: {compress}, {constrict},
         {squeeze}, {compact}, {contract}]
     6: crowd closely; "The crowds pressed along the street"
     7: create by pressing; "Press little holes into the soft clay"
     8: be urgent; "This is a pressing problem"
     9: exert oneself continuously, vigorously, or obtrusively to
        gain an end or engage in a crusade for a certain cause or
        person; be an advocate for; "The liberal party pushed for
        reforms"; "She is crusading for women's rights"; "The Dean
        is pushing for his favorite candidate" [syn: {crusade}, {fight},
         {campaign}, {push}, {agitate}]
     10: press from a plastic; "press a record" [syn: {press out}]
     11: make strenuous pushing movements during birth to expel the
         baby; "`Now push hard,' said the doctor to the woman"
         [syn: {push}]
     12: lift weights; "This guy can press 300 pounds" [syn: {weight-lift},
          {weightlift}]
     13: ask for or request earnestly; "The prophet bid all people to
         become good persons" [syn: {bid}, {beseech}, {entreat}, {adjure},
          {conjure}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
