<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>presence</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>presence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Presence \Pres"ence\, n. [F. pr['e]sence, L. praesentia. See
   {Present}.]
   1. The state of being present, or of being within sight or
      call, or at hand; -- opposed to absence.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The place in which one is present; the part of space
      within one's ken, call, influence, etc.; neighborhood
      without the intervention of anything that forbids
      intercourse.
      [1913 Webster]

            Wrath shell be no more
            Thenceforth, but in thy presence joy entire.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically, neighborhood to the person of one of
      superior of exalted rank; also, presence chamber.
      [1913 Webster]

            In such a presence here to plead my thoughts.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            An't please your grace, the two great cardinals.
            Wait in the presence.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The whole of the personal qualities of an individual;
      person; personality; especially, the person of a superior,
      as a sovereign.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Sovran Presence thus replied.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An assembly, especially of person of rank or nobility;
      noble company.
      [1913 Webster]

            Odmar, of all this presence does contain,
            Give her your wreath whom you esteem most fair.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Port, mien; air; personal appearence. ``Rather dignity of
      presence than beauty of aspect.'' --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            A graceful presence bespeaks acceptance. -- Collier.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Presence chamber}, or {Presence room}, the room in which a
      great personage receives company. --Addison. `` Chambers
      of presence.'' --Bacon.

   {Presence of mind}, that state of the mind in which all its
      faculties are alert, prompt, and acting harmoniously in
      obedience to the will, enabling one to reach, as it were
      spontaneously or by intuition, just conclusions in sudden
      emergencies.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>presence</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>presence
     n 1: the state of being present; current existence; "he tested
          for the presence of radon" [ant: {absence}]
     2: the immediate proximity of someone or something; "she
        blushed in his presence"; "he sensed the presence of
        danger"; "he was well behaved in front of company" [syn: {front}]
     3: an invisible spiritual being felt to be nearby
     4: the impression that something is present; "he felt the
        presence of an evil force"
     5: dignified manner or conduct [syn: {bearing}, {comportment},
        {mien}]
     6: the act of being present [ant: {absence}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
