<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>presumption</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>presumption</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Presumption \Pre*sump"tion\ (?; 215), n. [L. praesumptio: cf. F.
   pr['e]somption, OF. also presumpcion. See {Presume}.]
   1. The act of presuming, or believing upon probable evidence;
      the act of assuming or taking for granted; belief upon
      incomplete proof.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Ground for presuming; evidence probable, but not
      conclusive; strong probability; reasonable supposition;
      as, the presumption is that an event has taken place.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is presumed or assumed; that which is supposed
      or believed to be real or true, on evidence that is
      probable but not conclusive. ``In contradiction to these
      very plausible presumptions.'' --De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The act of venturing beyond due beyond due bounds; an
      overstepping of the bounds of reverence, respect, or
      courtesy; forward, overconfident, or arrogant opinion or
      conduct; presumptuousness; arrogance; effrontery.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy son I killed for his presumption. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had the presumption to dedicate to you a very
            unfinished piece.                     --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Conclusive presumption}. See under {Conclusive}.

   {Presumption of fact} (Law), an argument of a fact from a
      fact; an inference as to the existence of one fact not
      certainly known, from the existence of some other fact
      known or proved, founded on a previous experience of their
      connection; supposition of the truth or real existence of
      something, without direct or positive proof of the fact,
      but grounded on circumstantial or probable evidence which
      entitles it to belief. --Burrill. --Best. --Wharton.

   {Presumption of law} (Law), a postulate applied in advance to
      all cases of a particular class; e. g., the presumption of
      innocence and of regularity of records. Such a presumption
      is rebuttable or irrebuttable.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>presumption</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>presumption
     n 1: an assumption that is taken for granted [syn: {given}, {precondition}]
     2: (law) an inference of the truth of a fact from other facts
        proved or admitted or judicially noticed
     3: audacious (even arrogant) behavior that you have no right
        to; "he despised them for their presumptuousness" [syn: {presumptuousness},
         {effrontery}, {assumption}]
     4: a kind of discourtesy in the form of an act of presuming;
        "his presumption was intolerable"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
