<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pressed</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pressed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Press \Press\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pressed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Pressing}.] [F. presser, fr. L. pressare to press, fr.
   premere, pressum, to press. Cf. {Print}, v.]
   1. To urge, or act upon, with force, as weight; to act upon
      by pushing or thrusting, in distinction from pulling; to
      crowd or compel by a gradual and continued exertion; to
      bear upon; to squeeze; to compress; as, we press the
      ground with the feet when we walk; we press the couch on
      which we repose; we press substances with the hands,
      fingers, or arms; we are pressed in a crowd.
      [1913 Webster]

            Good measure, pressed down, and shaken together.
                                                  --Luke vi. 38.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To squeeze, in order to extract the juice or contents of;
      to squeeze out, or express, from something.
      [1913 Webster]

            From sweet kernels pressed,
            She tempers dulcet creams.            --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            And I took the grapes, and pressed them into
            Pharaoh's cup, and I gave the cup into Pharaoh's
            hand.                                 --Gen. xl. 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To squeeze in or with suitable instruments or apparatus,
      in order to compact, make dense, or smooth; as, to press
      cotton bales, paper, etc.; to smooth by ironing; as, to
      press clothes.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To embrace closely; to hug.
      [1913 Webster]

            Leucothoe shook at these alarms,
            And pressed Palemon closer in her arms. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To oppress; to bear hard upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Press not a falling man too far.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To straiten; to distress; as, to be pressed with want or
      hunger.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To exercise very powerful or irresistible influence upon
      or over; to constrain; to force; to compel.
      [1913 Webster]

            Paul was pressed in the spirit, and testified to the
            Jews that Jesus was Christ.           --Acts xviii.
                                                  5.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To try to force (something upon some one); to urge or
      inculcate with earnestness or importunity; to enforce; as,
      to press divine truth on an audience.
      [1913 Webster]

            He pressed a letter upon me within this hour.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Be sure to press upon him every motive. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To drive with violence; to hurry; to urge on; to ply hard;
      as, to press a horse in a race.
      [1913 Webster]

            The posts . . . went cut, being hastened and pressed
            on, by the king's commandment.        --Esther viii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Press differs from drive and strike in usually denoting
         a slow or continued application of force; whereas drive
         and strike denote a sudden impulse of force.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Pressed brick}. See under {Brick}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pressed</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pressed
     adj : compacted by ironing
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
