<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>priest</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>priest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Priest
   The Heb. kohen, Gr. hierus, Lat. sacerdos, always denote one who
   offers sacrifices.
   
     At first every man was his own priest, and presented his own
   sacrifices before God. Afterwards that office devolved on the
   head of the family, as in the cases of Noah (Gen. 8:20), Abraham
   (12:7; 13:4), Isaac (26:25), Jacob (31:54), and Job (Job 1:5).
   
     The name first occurs as applied to Melchizedek (Gen. 14:18).
   Under the Levitical arrangements the office of the priesthood
   was limited to the tribe of Levi, and to only one family of that
   tribe, the family of Aaron. Certain laws respecting the
   qualifications of priests are given in Lev. 21:16-23. There are
   ordinances also regarding the priests' dress (Ex. 28:40-43) and
   the manner of their consecration to the office (29:1-37).
   
     Their duties were manifold (Ex. 27:20, 21; 29:38-44; Lev.
   6:12; 10:11; 24:8; Num. 10:1-10; Deut. 17:8-13; 33:10; Mal.
   2:7). They represented the people before God, and offered the
   various sacrifices prescribed in the law.
   
     In the time of David the priests were divided into twenty-four
   courses or classes (1 Chr. 24:7-18). This number was retained
   after the Captivity (Ezra 2:36-39; Neh. 7:39-42).
   
     "The priests were not distributed over the country, but lived
   together in certain cities [forty-eight in number, of which six
   were cities of refuge, q.v.], which had been assigned to their
   use. From thence they went up by turns to minister in the temple
   at Jerusalem. Thus the religious instruction of the people in
   the country generally was left to the heads of families, until
   the establishment of synagogues, an event which did not take
   place till the return from the Captivity, and which was the main
   source of the freedom from idolatry that became as marked a
   feature of the Jewish people thenceforward as its practice had
   been hitherto their great national sin."
   
     The whole priestly system of the Jews was typical. It was a
   shadow of which the body is Christ. The priests all prefigured
   the great Priest who offered "one sacrifice for sins" "once for
   all" (Heb. 10:10, 12). There is now no human priesthood. (See
   Epistle to the Hebrews throughout.) The term "priest" is indeed
   applied to believers (1 Pet. 2:9; Rev. 1:6), but in these cases
   it implies no sacerdotal functions. All true believers are now
   "kings and priests unto God." As priests they have free access
   into the holiest of all, and offer up the sacrifices of praise
   and thanksgiving, and the sacrifices of grateful service from
   day to day.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>priest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Presbyter \Pres"by*ter\, n. [L. an elder, fr. Gr. ?. See
   {Priest}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. An elder in the early Christian church. See 2d Citation
      under {Bishop}, n., 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Ch. of Eng. &amp; Prot. Epis. Ch.) One ordained to the second
      order in the ministry; -- called also {priest}.
      [1913 Webster]

            I rather term the one sort presbyter than priest.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            New presbyter is but old priest writ large.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Presbyterian Ch.) A member of a presbytery whether lay or
      clerical.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A Presbyterian. [Obs.] --Hudibras.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>priest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Priest \Priest\, n. [OE. prest, preost, AS. pre['o]st, fr. L.
   presbyter, Gr. ? elder, older, n., an elder, compar. of ? an
   old man, the first syllable of which is probably akin to L.
   pristinus. Cf. {Pristine}, {Presbyter}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Christian Church) A presbyter elder; a minister;
      specifically:
      (a) (R. C. Ch. &amp; Gr. Ch.) One who is authorized to
          consecrate the host and to say Mass; but especially,
          one of the lowest order possessing this power.
          --Murdock.
      (b) (Ch. of Eng. &amp; Prot. Epis. Ch.) A presbyter; one who
          belongs to the intermediate order between bishop and
          deacon. He is authorized to perform all ministerial
          services except those of ordination and confirmation.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. One who officiates at the altar, or performs the rites of
      sacrifice; one who acts as a mediator between men and the
      divinity or the gods in any form of religion; as, Buddhist
      priests. ``The priests of Dagon.'' --1 Sam. v. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then the priest of Jupiter . . . brought oxen and
            garlands . . . and would have done sacrifice with
            the people. --Acts xiv. 13.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every priest taken from among men is ordained for
            men in things pertaining to God, that he may offer
            both gifts and sacrifices for sins.   --Heb. v. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the New Testament presbyters are not called priests;
         but Christ is designated as a priest, and as a high
         priest, and all Christians are designated priests.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>priest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Priest \Priest\, v. t.
   To ordain as priest.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>priest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>priest
     n 1: a clergyman in Christian churches who has the authority to
          perform or administer various religious rites; one of
          the Holy Orders
     2: a spiritual leader in a non-Christian religion [syn: {non-Christian
        priest}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
