<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>primitive</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>primitive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>primitive
     
        &lt;programming&gt; A {function}, {operator}, or {type} which is
        built into a programming language (or {operating system}),
        either for speed of execution or because it would be
        impossible to write it in the language.  Primitives typically
        include the arithmetic and logical operations (plus, minus,
        and, or, etc.) and are implemented by a small number of
        {machine language} instructions.
     
        (1995-05-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>primitive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Primitive \Prim"i*tive\, a. [L. primitivus, fr. primus the
   first: cf. F. primitif. See {Prime}, a.]
   1. Of or pertaining to the beginning or origin, or to early
      times; original; primordial; primeval; first; as,
      primitive innocence; the primitive church. ``Our primitive
      great sire.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of or pertaining to a former time; old-fashioned;
      characterized by simplicity; as, a primitive style of
      dress.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Original; primary; radical; not derived; as, primitive
      verb in grammar.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Primitive axes of co["o]rdinate} (Geom.), that system of
      axes to which the points of a magnitude are first
      referred, with reference to a second set or system, to
      which they are afterward referred.

   {Primitive chord} (Mus.), that chord, the lowest note of
      which is of the same literal denomination as the
      fundamental base of the harmony; -- opposed to derivative.
      --Moore (Encyc. of Music).

   {Primitive circle} (Spherical Projection), the circle cut
      from the sphere to be projected, by the primitive plane.
      

   {Primitive colors} (Paint.), primary colors. See under
      {Color}.

   {Primitive Fathers} (Eccl.), the acknowledged Christian
      writers who flourished before the Council of Nice, A. D.
      325. --Shipley.

   {Primitive groove} (Anat.), a depression or groove in the
      epiblast of the primitive streak. It is not connected with
      the medullary groove, which appears later and in front of
      it.

   {Primitive plane} (Spherical Projection), the plane upon
      which the projections are made, generally coinciding with
      some principal circle of the sphere, as the equator or a
      meridian.

   {Primitive rocks} (Geol.), primary rocks. See under
      {Primary}.

   {Primitive sheath}. (Anat.) See {Neurilemma}.

   {Primitive streak} or {Primitive trace} (Anat.), an opaque
      and thickened band where the mesoblast first appears in
      the vertebrate blastoderm.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: First; original; radical; pristine; ancient; primeval;
        antiquated; old-fashioned.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>primitive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Primitive \Prim"i*tive\, n.
   An original or primary word; a word not derived from another;
   -- opposed to derivative.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>primitive</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>primitive
     adj 1: belonging to an early stage of technical development;
            characterized by simplicity and (often) crudeness;
            "the crude weapons and rude agricultural implements of
            early man"; "primitive movies of the 1890s";
            "primitive living conditions in the Appalachian
            mountains" [syn: {crude}, {rude}]
     2: little evolved from or characteristic of an earlier
        ancestral type; "archaic forms of life"; "primitive
        mammals"; "the okapi is a short-necked primitive cousin of
        the giraffe" [syn: {archaic}]
     3: used of preliterate or tribal or nonindustrial societies;
        "primitive societies"
     4: of or created by one without formal training; simple or
        naive in style; "primitive art such as that by Grandma
        Moses is often colorful and striking"
     n 1: a person who belongs to early stage of civilization [syn: {primitive
          person}]
     2: a mathematical expression from which another expression is
        derived
     3: a word serving as the basis for inflected or derived forms;
        "`pick' is the primitive from which `picket' is derived"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
