<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>prime</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>prime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Prime \Prime\, a. [F., fr. L. primus first, a superl.
   corresponding to the compar. prior former. See {Prior}, a.,
   {Foremost}, {Former}, and cf. {Prim}, a., {Primary},
   {Prince}.]
   1. First in order of time; original; primeval; primitive;
      primary. ``Prime forests.'' --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            She was not the prime cause, but I myself. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense the word is nearly superseded by
         primitive, except in the phrase prime cost.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. First in rank, degree, dignity, authority, or importance;
      as, prime minister. ``Prime virtues.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. First in excellence; of highest quality; as, prime wheat;
      a prime quality of cloth.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Early; blooming; being in the first stage. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            His starry helm, unbuckled, showed him prime
            In manhood where youth ended.         --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Lecherous; lustful; lewd. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Marked or distinguished by a mark (') called a prime mark.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Math.)
      (a) Divisible by no number except itself or unity; as, 7
          is a prime number.
      (b) Having no common factor; -- used with to; as, 12 is
          prime to 25.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Prime and ultimate ratio}. (Math.). See {Ultimate}.

   {Prime conductor}. (Elec.) See under {Conductor}.

   {Prime factor} (Arith.), a factor which is a prime number.

   {Prime figure} (Geom.), a figure which can not be divided
      into any other figure more simple than itself, as a
      triangle, a pyramid, etc.

   {Prime meridian} (Astron.), the meridian from which longitude
      is reckoned, as the meridian of Greenwich or Washington.
      

   {Prime minister}, the responsible head of a ministry or
      executive government; applied particularly to that of
      England.

   {Prime mover}. (Mech.)
      (a) A natural agency applied by man to the production of
          power. Especially: Muscular force; the weight and
          motion of fluids, as water and air; heat obtained by
          chemical combination, and applied to produce changes
          in the volume and pressure of steam, air, or other
          fluids; and electricity, obtained by chemical action,
          and applied to produce alternation of magnetic force.
      (b) An engine, or machine, the object of which is to
          receive and modify force and motion as supplied by
          some natural source, and apply them to drive other
          machines; as a water wheel, a water-pressure engine, a
          steam engine, a hot-air engine, etc.
      (c) Fig.: The original or the most effective force in any
          undertaking or work; as, Clarkson was the prime mover
          in English antislavery agitation.

   {Prime number} (Arith.), a number which is exactly divisible
      by no number except itself or unity, as 5, 7, 11.

   {Prime vertical} (Astron.), the vertical circle which passes
      through the east and west points of the horizon.

   {Prime-vertical dial}, a dial in which the shadow is
      projected on the plane of the prime vertical.

   {Prime-vertical transit instrument}, a transit instrument the
      telescope of which revolves in the plane of the prime
      vertical, -- used for observing the transit of stars over
      this circle.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>prime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Prime \Prime\, n.
   1. The first part; the earliest stage; the beginning or
      opening, as of the day, the year, etc.; hence, the dawn;
      the spring. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            In the very prime of the world.       --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hope waits upon the flowery prime.    --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The spring of life; youth; hence, full health, strength,
      or beauty; perfection. ``Cut off in their prime.''
      --Eustace. ``The prime of youth.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is first in quantity; the most excellent
      portion; the best part.
      [1913 Webster]

            Give him always of the prime.         --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. [F. prime, LL. prima (sc. hora). See {Prime}, a.] The
      morning; specifically (R. C. Ch.), the first canonical
      hour, succeeding to lauds.
      [1913 Webster]

            Early and late it rung, at evening and at prime.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Originally, prime denoted the first quarter of the
         artificial day, reckoned from 6 a. m. to 6 p. m.
         Afterwards, it denoted the end of the first quarter,
         that is, 9 a. m. Specifically, it denoted the first
         canonical hour, as now. Chaucer uses it in all these
         senses, and also in the sense of def. 1, above.
         [1913 Webster]

               They sleep till that it was pryme large.
                                                  --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. (Fencing) The first of the chief guards.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Chem.) Any number expressing the combining weight or
      equivalent of any particular element; -- so called because
      these numbers were respectively reduced to their lowest
      relative terms on the fixed standard of hydrogen as 1.
      [Obs. or Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Arith.) A prime number. See under {Prime}, a.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. An inch, as composed of twelve seconds in the duodecimal
      system; -- denoted by [']. See 2d {Inch}, n., 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Prime of the moon}, the new moon at its first appearance.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>prime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Prime \Prime\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Primed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Priming}.] [From {Prime}, a.]
   1. To apply priming to, as a musket or a cannon; to apply a
      primer to, as a metallic cartridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay the first color, coating, or preparation upon (a
      surface), as in painting; as, to prime a canvas, a wall.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To prepare; to make ready; to instruct beforehand; to
      post; to coach; as, to prime a witness; the boys are
      primed for mischief. [Colloq.] --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To trim or prune, as trees. [Obs. or Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) To mark with a prime mark.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To prime a pump}, to charge a pump with water, in order to
      put it in working condition.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>prime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Prime \Prime\, v. i.
   1. To be renewed, or as at first. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Night's bashful empress, though she often wane,
            As oft repeats her darkness, primes again.
                                                  --Quarles.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To serve as priming for the charge of a gun.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To work so that foaming occurs from too violent
      ebullition, which causes water to become mixed with, and
      be carried along with, the steam that is formed; -- said
      of a steam boiler.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>prime</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>prime
     adj 1: first in rank or degree; "an architect of premier rank";
            "the prime minister" [syn: {premier(a)}, {prime(a)}]
     2: used of the first or originating agent; "prime mover" [syn:
        {prime(a)}]
     3: of superior grade; "choice wines"; "prime beef"; "prize
        carnations"; "quality paper"; "select peaches" [syn: {choice},
         {prime(a)}, {prize}, {quality}, {select}]
     4: of or relating to or being an integer that cannot be
        factored into other integers; "prime number"
     5: at the best stage; "our manhood's prime vigor"- Robert
        Browning
     n 1: a number that has no factor but itself and 1 [syn: {prime
          quantity}]
     2: the period of greatest prosperity or productivity [syn: {flower},
         {peak}, {heyday}, {bloom}, {blossom}, {efflorescence}, {flush}]
     3: the second canonical hour; about 6 a.m.
     4: the time of maturity when power and vigor are greatest [syn:
         {prime of life}]
     v 1: insert a primer into (a gun, mine, charge, etc.) preparatory
          to detonation or firing; "prime a cannon"; "prime a
          mine"
     2: cover with a primer; apply a primer to [syn: {ground}, {undercoat}]
     3: fill with priming liquid; "prime a car engine"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
