<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>principle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>principle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Principle \Prin"ci*ple\, n. [F. principe, L. principium
   beginning, foundation, fr. princeps, -cipis. See {Prince}.]
   1. Beginning; commencement. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Doubting sad end of principle unsound. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A source, or origin; that from which anything proceeds;
      fundamental substance or energy; primordial substance;
      ultimate element, or cause.
      [1913 Webster]

            The soul of man is an active principle. --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An original faculty or endowment.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nature in your principles hath set [benignity].
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those active principles whose direct and ultimate
            object is the communication either of enjoyment or
            suffering.                            --Stewart.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A fundamental truth; a comprehensive law or doctrine, from
      which others are derived, or on which others are founded;
      a general truth; an elementary proposition; a maxim; an
      axiom; a postulate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore, leaving the principles of the doctrine of
            Christ, let us go on unto perfection. --Heb. vi. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

            A good principle, not rightly understood, may prove
            as hurtful as a bad.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A settled rule of action; a governing law of conduct; an
      opinion or belief which exercises a directing influence on
      the life and behavior; a rule (usually, a right rule) of
      conduct consistently directing one's actions; as, a person
      of no principle.
      [1913 Webster]

            All kinds of dishonesty destroy our pretenses to an
            honest principle of mind.             --Law.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Chem.) Any original inherent constituent which
      characterizes a substance, or gives it its essential
      properties, and which can usually be separated by
      analysis; -- applied especially to drugs, plant extracts,
      etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Cathartine is the bitter, purgative principle of
            senna.                                --Gregory.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bitter principle}, {Principle of contradiction}, etc. See
      under {Bitter}, {Contradiction}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>principle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Principle \Prin"ci*ple\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Principled}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Principling}.]
   To equip with principles; to establish, or fix, in certain
   principles; to impress with any tenet, or rule of conduct,
   good or ill.
   [1913 Webster]

         Governors should be well principled.     --L'Estrange.
   [1913 Webster]

         Let an enthusiast be principled that he or his teacher
         is inspired.                             --Locke.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>principle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>principle
     n 1: a basic generalization that is accepted as true and that can
          be used as a basis for reasoning or conduct; "their
          principles of composition characterized all their works"
          [syn: {rule}]
     2: a rule or standard especially of good behavior; "a man of
        principle"; "he will not violate his principles"
     3: a basic truth or law or assumption; "the principles of
        democracy"
     4: a rule or law concerning a natural phenomenon or the
        function of a complex system; "the principle of the
        conservation of mass"; "the principle of jet propulsion";
        "the right-hand rule for inductive fields" [syn: {rule}]
     5: rule of personal conduct [syn: {precept}]
     6: (law) an explanation of the fundamental reasons (especially
        an explanation of the working of some device in terms of
        laws of nature); "the rationale for capital punishment";
        "the principles of internal-combustion engines" [syn: {rationale}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
