<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>print</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>print</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PRINT
     
        &lt;language&gt; PRe-edited INTerpreter.
     
        An early mathematics language for the {IBM 705}.
     
        [Sammet 1969, p. 134].
     
        (1995-05-01)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>print</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Print \Print\, v. i.
   1. To use or practice the art of typography; to take
      impressions of letters, figures, or electrotypes, engraved
      plates, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To publish a book or an article.
      [1913 Webster]

            From the moment he prints, he must except to hear no
            more truth.                           --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>print</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Print \Print\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Printed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Printing}.] [Abbrev. fr. imprint. See {Imprint}, and {Press}
   to squeeze.]
   1. To fix or impress, as a stamp, mark, character, idea,
      etc., into or upon something.
      [1913 Webster]

            A look will print a thought that never may remove.
                                                  --Surrey.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon his breastplate he beholds a dint,
            Which in that field young Edward's sword did print.
                                                  --Sir John
                                                  Beaumont.
      [1913 Webster]

            Perhaps some footsteps printed in the clay.
                                                  --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To stamp something in or upon; to make an impression or
      mark upon by pressure, or as by pressure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Forth on his fiery steed betimes he rode,
            That scarcely prints the turf on which he trod.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Specifically: To strike off an impression or impressions
      of, from type, or from stereotype, electrotype, or
      engraved plates, or the like; in a wider sense, to do the
      typesetting, presswork, etc., of (a book or other
      publication); as, to print books, newspapers, pictures; to
      print an edition of a book.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To stamp or impress with colored figures or patterns; as,
      to print calico.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Photog.) To take (a copy, a positive picture, etc.), from
      a negative, a transparent drawing, or the like, by the
      action of light upon a sensitized surface.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Printed goods}, textile fabrics printed in patterns,
      especially cotton cloths, or calicoes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>print</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Print \Print\, n. [See {Print}, v., {Imprint}, n.]
   1. A mark made by impression; a line, character, figure, or
      indentation, made by the pressure of one thing on another;
      as, the print of teeth or nails in flesh; the print of the
      foot in sand or snow.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where print of human feet was never seen. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A stamp or die for molding or impressing an ornamental
      design upon an object; as, a butter print.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which receives an impression, as from a stamp or
      mold; as, a print of butter.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Printed letters; the impression taken from type, as to
      excellence, form, size, etc.; as, small print; large
      print; this line is in print.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is produced by printing. Specifically:
      (a) An impression taken from anything, as from an engraved
          plate. ``The prints which we see of antiquities.''
          --Dryden.
      (b) A printed publication, more especially a newspaper or
          other periodical. --Addison.
      (c) A printed cloth; a fabric figured by stamping,
          especially calico or cotton cloth.
      (d) A photographic copy, or positive picture, on prepared
          paper, as from a negative, or from a drawing on
          transparent paper.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Founding) A core print. See under {Core}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Blue print}, a copy in white lines on a blue ground, of a
      drawing, plan, tracing, etc., or a positive picture in
      blue and white, from a negative, produced by photographic
      printing on peculiarly prepared paper.

   {In print}.
      (a) In a printed form; issued from the press; published.
          --Shak.
      (b) To the letter; with accurateness. ``All this I speak
          in print.'' --Shak.

   {Out of print}. See under {Out}.

   {Print works}, a factory where cloth, as calico, is printed.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>print</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>print v. To output, even if to a screen. If a hacker says that a
   program "printed a message", he means this; if he refers to printing a
   file, he probably means it in the conventional sense of writing to a
   hardcopy device (compounds like `print job' and `printout', on the other
   hand, always refer to the latter). This very common term is likely a
   holdover from the days when printing terminals were the norm,
   perpetuated by programming language constructs like {C}'s printf(3). See
   senses 1 and 2 of {tty}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>print</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>print
     n 1: the result of the printing process; "I want to see it in
          black and white" [syn: {black and white}]
     2: a picture or design printed from an engraving
     3: a visible indication made on a surface; "some previous
        reader had covered the pages with dozens of marks"; "paw
        prints were everywhere" [syn: {mark}]
     4: a copy of a movie on film (especially a particular version
        of it)
     5: a fabric with a dyed pattern pressed onto it (usually by
        engraved rollers)
     6: a printed picture produced from a photographic negative
        [syn: {photographic print}]
     v 1: put into print; "The newspaper published the news of the
          royal couple's divorce"; "These news should not be
          printed" [syn: {publish}]
     2: write as if with print; not cursive
     3: make into a print;  "print the negative"
     4: reproduce by printing [syn: {impress}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
