<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>privilege</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>privilege</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Privilege \Priv"i*lege\, n. [F. privil[`e]ge, L. privilegium an
   ordinance or law against or in favor of an individual; privus
   private + lex, legis, law. See {Private}, and {Legal}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A peculiar benefit, advantage, or favor; a right or
      immunity not enjoyed by others or by all; special
      enjoyment of a good, or exemption from an evil or burden;
      a prerogative; advantage; franchise.
      [1913 Webster]

            He pleads the legal privilege of a Roman.
                                                  --Kettlewell.
      [1913 Webster]

            The privilege birthright was a double portion.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            A people inheriting privileges, franchises, and
            liberties.                            --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Stockbroker's Cant) See {Call}, {Put}, {Spread}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Breach of privilege}. See under {Breach}.

   {Question of privilege} (Parliamentary practice), a question
      which concerns the security of a member of a legislative
      body in his special privileges as such.

   {Water privilege}, the advantage of having machinery driven
      by a stream, or a place affording such advantage. [ U. S.]
      

   {Writ of privilege} (Law), a writ to deliver a privileged
      person from custody when arrested in a civil suit.
      --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Prerogative; immunity; franchise; right; claim; liberty.

   Usage: {Privilege}, {Prerogative}. Privilege, among the
          Romans, was something conferred upon an individual by
          a private law; and hence, it denotes some peculiar
          benefit or advantage, some right or immunity, not
          enjoyed by the world at large. Prerogative, among the
          Romans, was the right of voting first; and, hence, it
          denotes a right of precedence, or of doing certain
          acts, or enjoying certain privileges, to the exclusion
          of others. It is the privilege of a member of Congress
          not to be called in question elsewhere for words
          uttered in debate. It is the prerogative of the
          president to nominate judges and executive officers.
          It is the privilege of a Christian child to be
          instructed in the true religion. It is the prerogative
          of a parent to govern and direct his children.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>privilege</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Privilege \Priv"i*lege\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Privileged}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Privileging}.] [Cf. F. privil['e]gier.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To grant some particular right or exemption to; to invest
      with a peculiar right or immunity; to authorize; as, to
      privilege representatives from arrest.
      [1913 Webster]

            To privilege dishonor in thy name.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To bring or put into a condition of privilege or exemption
      from evil or danger; to exempt; to deliver.
      [1913 Webster]

            He took this place for sanctuary, And it shall
            privilege him from your hands.        --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>privilege</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>privilege
     n 1: a special advantage or immunity or benefit not enjoyed by
          all
     2: a right reserved exclusively by a particular person or group
        (especially a hereditary or official right); "suffrage was
        the prerogative of white adult males" [syn: {prerogative},
         {perquisite}, {exclusive right}]
     3: (law) the right to refuse to divulge information obtained in
        a confidential relationship
     v : bestow a privilege upon [syn: {favor}, {favour}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
