<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>prizefight</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>prizefight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Prize \Prize\ (pr[imac]z), n. [F. prise a seizing, hold, grasp,
   fr. pris, p. p. of prendre to take, L. prendere, prehendere;
   in some senses, as 2
   (b), either from, or influenced by, F. prix price. See
       {Prison}, {Prehensile}, and cf. {Pry}, and also {Price}.]
       [1913 Webster]

   1. That which is taken from another; something captured; a
      thing seized by force, stratagem, or superior power.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will depart my pris, or my prey, by deliberation.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            His own prize,
            Whom formerly he had in battle won.   --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, specifically;
      (a) (Law) Anything captured by a belligerent using the
          rights of war; esp., property captured at sea in
          virtue of the rights of war, as a vessel. --Kent.
          --Brande &amp; C.
      (b) An honor or reward striven for in a competitive
          contest; anything offered to be competed for, or as an
          inducement to, or reward of, effort.
          [1913 Webster]

                I'll never wrestle for prize more. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                I fought and conquered, yet have lost the prize.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) That which may be won by chance, as in a lottery.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything worth striving for; a valuable possession held or
      in prospect.
      [1913 Webster]

            I press toward the mark for the prize of the high
            calling of God in Christ Jesus.       --Phil. iii.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A contest for a reward; competition. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A lever; a pry; also, the hold of a lever. [Written also
      {prise}.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Prize court}, a court having jurisdiction of all captures
      made in war on the high seas. --Bouvier.

   {Prize fight}, an exhibition contest, esp. one of pugilists,
      for a stake or wager.

   {Prize fighter}, one who fights publicly for a reward; --
      applied esp. to a professional boxer or pugilist. --Pope.

   {Prize fighting}, fighting, especially boxing, in public for
      a reward or wager.

   {Prize master}, an officer put in charge or command of a
      captured vessel.

   {Prize medal}, a medal given as a prize.

   {Prize money}, a dividend from the proceeds of a captured
      vessel, etc., paid to the captors.

   {Prize ring}, the ring or inclosure for a prize fight; the
      system and practice of prize fighting.

   {To make prize of}, to capture. --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>prizefight</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>prizefight
     n : a boxing match between professional boxers for a cash prize
     v : box for a prize or money
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
