<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>probation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>probation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Probation \Pro*ba"tion\, n. [L. probatio, fr. probare to try,
   examine, prove: cf. F. probation. See {Prove}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of proving; also, that which proves anything;
      proof. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            When by miracle God dispensed great gifts to the
            laity, . . . he gave probation that he intended that
            all should prophesy and preach.       --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any proceeding designed to ascertain truth, to determine
      character, qualification, etc.; examination; trial; as, to
      engage a person on probation. Hence, specifically:
      (a) The novitiate which a person must pass in a convent,
          to probe his or her virtue and ability to bear the
          severities of the rule.
      (b) The trial of a ministerial candidate's qualifications
          prior to his ordination, or to his settlement as a
          pastor.
      (c) Moral trial; the state of man in the present life, in
          which he has the opportunity of proving his character,
          and becoming qualified for a happier state.
          [1913 Webster]

                No [view of human life] seems so reasonable as
                that which regards it as a state of probation.
                                                  --Paley.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>probation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>probation
     n 1: a trial period during which your character and abilities are
          tested to see whether you are suitable for work or for
          membership
     2: a trial period during which an offender has time to redeem
        himself or herself
     3: (law) a way of dealing with offenders without imprisoning
        them; a defendant found guilty of a crime is released by
        the court without imprisonment subject to conditions
        imposed by the court; "probation is part of the sentencing
        process"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
