<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>profile</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profile</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PROFILE
     
        Simple language for matching and scoring data.  "User's Manual
        for the PROFILE System", Cambridge Computer Assoc (May 1974).
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profile</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>profile
     
        1. A control file for a program, especially a text file
        automatically read from each user's home directory and
        intended to be easily modified by the user in order to
        customise the program's behaviour.  Used to avoid {hard-coded}
        choices (see also {dot file}, {rc file}).
     
        2. A report on the amounts of time spent in each routine of a
        program, used to find and {tune} away the {hot spot}s in it.
        This sense is often verbed.  Some profiling modes report units
        other than time (such as call counts) and/or report at
        granularities other than per-routine, but the idea is similar.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profile</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Profile \Pro"file\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Profiled}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Profiling}] [Cf. F. profiler, It. profilare. See
   {Profile}, n.]
   1. to draw the outline of; to draw in profile, as an
      architectural member.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mech.) To shape the outline of an object by passing a
      cutter around it.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Profiling machine}, a jigging machine.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profile</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Profile \Pro"file\, n. [It. profilo, fr. L. pro before + filum a
   thread, an outline, shape: cf. F. profil. See {File} arow,
   and cf. {Purfle}, {Purl}, a fringe.]
   1. An outline, or contour; as, the profile of an apple.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Paint &amp; Sculp.) A human head represented sidewise, or in
      a side view; the side face or half face.
      [1913 Webster]

   3.
      (a) (Arch.) A section of any member, made at right angles
          with its main lines, showing the exact shape of
          moldings and the like.
      (b) (Civil Engin.) A drawing exhibiting a vertical section
          of the ground along a surveyed line, or graded work,
          as of a railway, showing elevations, depressions,
          grades, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. a short biography.

   5. a set of data, often in graphical form, describing some
      significant features of something (e.g. a person,
      corporation); esp. a graph showing the results of tests of
      some attribute of a person.

   6. public notice, used esp. in the phrase "(keep/maintain) a
      low profile", i. e. avoid public notice, avoid publicity.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Profile paper} (Civil Engin.), paper ruled with vertical and
      horizontal lines forming small oblong rectangles, adapted
      for drawing profiles.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profile</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>profile n. 1. A control file for a program, esp. a text file
   automatically read from each user's home directory and intended to be
   easily modified by the user in order to customize the program's
   behavior. Used to avoid {hardcoded} choices (see also {dot file}, {rc
   file}). 2. [techspeak] A report on the amounts of time spent in each
   routine of a program, used to find and {tune} away the {hot spot}s in
   it. This sense is often verbed. Some profiling modes report units other
   than time (such as call counts) and/or report at granularities other
   than per-routine, but the idea is similar. 3.[techspeak] A subset of a
   standard used for a particular purpose. This sense confuses hackers who
   wander into the weird world of ISO standards no end!


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profile</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>profile
     n 1: an analysis (often in graphical form) representing the
          extent to which something exhibits various
          characteristics; "a biochemical profile of blood"; "a
          psychological profile of serial killers"
     2: a side view representation of an object (especially a human
        face)
     3: biographical sketch
     4: degree of exposure to public notice; "that candidate does
        not have sufficient visibility to win an election"; "he
        prefers a low profile" [syn: {visibility}]
     5: a vertical section of the Earth's crust showing the
        different horizons or layers
     v 1: write about; "The author of this article profiles a famous
          painter"
     2: represent in profile, by drawing or painting
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
