<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>profession</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profession</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Profession \Pro*fes"sion\, n. [F., fr. L. professio. See
   {Profess}, v.]
   1. The act of professing or claiming; open declaration;
      public avowal or acknowledgment; as, professions of
      friendship; a profession of faith.
      [1913 Webster]

            A solemn vow, promise, and profession. --Bk. of Com.
                                                  Prayer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which one professed; a declaration; an avowal; a
      claim; as, his professions are insincere.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Indians quickly perceive the coincidence or the
            contradiction between professions and conduct. --J.
                                                  Morse.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That of which one professed knowledge; the occupation, if
      not mechanical, agricultural, or the like, to which one
      devotes one's self; the business which one professes to
      understand, and to follow for subsistence; calling;
      vocation; employment; as, the profession of arms; the
      profession of a clergyman, lawyer, or physician; the
      profession of lecturer on chemistry.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hi tried five or six professions in turn.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The three professions, or learned professions, are,
         especially, theology, law, and medicine.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. The collective body of persons engaged in a calling; as,
      the profession distrust him.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Eccl. Law.) The act of entering, or becoming a member of,
      a religious order.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>profession</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>profession
     n 1: the body of people in a learned occupation; "the news spread
          rapidly through the medical community" [syn: {community}]
     2: an occupation requiring special education (especially in the
        liberal arts or sciences)
     3: an open avowal (true or false) of some belief or opinion; "a
        profession of disagreement" [syn: {professing}]
     4: affirmation of acceptance of some religion or faith; "a
        profession of Christianity"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
