<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>proof</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proof</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PROOF, n.  Evidence having a shade more of plausibility than of
unlikelihood.  The testimony of two credible witnesses as opposed to
that of only one.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proof</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PROOF-:READER:, n.  A malefactor who atones for making your writing
nonsense by permitting the compositor to make it unintelligible.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proof</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>proof
     
        1. &lt;logic&gt; A {finite} sequence of {well-formed formula}s, F1,
        F2, ... Fn, where each Fi either is an {axiom}, or follows by
        some rule of inference from some of the previous F's, and Fn
        is the statement being proved.
     
        See also {proof theory}.
     
        2. A left-associative {natural language} {parser} by Craig
        R. Latta &lt;latta@xcf.berkeley.edu&gt;.  Ported to {Decstation
        3100}, {Sun-4}.
     
        {(ftp://scam.berkeley.edu/pub/src/local/proof/)}.
     
        E-mail: &lt;proof@xcf.berkeley.edu&gt;.  Mailing list:
        proof-requestf@xcf.berkeley.edu (Subject: add me).
     
        (1994-11-29)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proof</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Proof \Proof\, a.
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Used in proving or testing; as, a proof load, or proof
      charge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Firm or successful in resisting; as, proof against harm;
      waterproof; bombproof.
      [1913 Webster]

            I . . . have found thee
            Proof against all temptation.         --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            This was a good, stout proof article of faith.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Being of a certain standard as to strength; -- said of
      alcoholic liquors.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Proof charge} (Firearms), a charge of powder and ball,
      greater than the service charge, fired in an arm, as a gun
      or cannon, to test its strength.

   {Proof impression}. See under {Impression}.

   {Proof load} (Engin.), the greatest load than can be applied
      to a piece, as a beam, column, etc., without straining the
      piece beyond the elastic limit.

   {Proof sheet}. See {Proof}, n., 5.

   {Proof spirit} (Chem.), a strong distilled liquor, or mixture
      of alcohol and water, containing not less than a standard
      amount of alcohol. In the United States ``proof spirit is
      defined by law to be that mixture of alcohol and water
      which contains one half of its volume of alcohol, the
      alcohol when at a temperature of 60[deg] Fahrenheit being
      of specific gravity 0.7939 referred to water at its
      maximum density as unity. Proof spirit has at 60[deg]
      Fahrenheit a specific gravity of 0.93353, 100 parts by
      volume of the same consisting of 50 parts of absolute
      alcohol and 53.71 parts of water,'' the apparent excess of
      water being due to contraction of the liquids on mixture.
      In England proof spirit is defined by Act 58, George III.,
      to be such as shall at a temperature of 51[deg] Fahrenheit
      weigh exactly the 12/13 part of an equal measure of
      distilled water. This contains 49.3 per cent by weight, or
      57.09 by volume, of alcohol. Stronger spirits, as those of
      about 60, 70, and 80 per cent of alcohol, are sometimes
      called second, third, and fourth proof spirits
      respectively.

   {Proof staff}, a straight-edge used by millers to test the
      flatness of a stone.

   {Proof stick} (Sugar Manuf.), a rod in the side of a vacuum
      pan, for testing the consistency of the sirup.

   {Proof text}, a passage of Scripture used to prove a
      doctrine.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proof</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Proof \Proof\, n. [OF. prove, proeve, F. preuve, fr. L. proba,
   fr. probare to prove. See {Prove}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. Any effort, process, or operation designed to establish or
      discover a fact or truth; an act of testing; a test; a
      trial.
      [1913 Webster]

            For whatsoever mother wit or art
            Could work, he put in proof.          --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            You shall have many proofs to show your skill.
                                                  --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

            Formerly, a very rude mode of ascertaining the
            strength of spirits was practiced, called the proof.
                                                  --Ure.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That degree of evidence which convinces the mind of any
      truth or fact, and produces belief; a test by facts or
      arguments that induce, or tend to induce, certainty of the
      judgment; conclusive evidence; demonstration.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll have some proof.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is no proof of a man's understanding to be able
            to confirm whatever he pleases.       --Emerson.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Properly speaking, proof is the effect or result of
         evidence, evidence is the medium of proof. Cf.
         {Demonstration}, 1.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The quality or state of having been proved or tried;
      firmness or hardness that resists impression, or does not
      yield to force; impenetrability of physical bodies.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Firmness of mind; stability not to be shaken.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Print.) A trial impression, as from type, taken for
      correction or examination; -- called also {proof sheet}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Math.) A process for testing the accuracy of an operation
      performed. Cf. {Prove}, v. t., 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Armor of excellent or tried quality, and deemed
      impenetrable; properly, armor of proof. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Artist's proof}, a very early proof impression of an
      engraving, or the like; -- often distinguished by the
      artist's signature.

   {Proof reader}, one who reads, and marks correction in,
      proofs. See def. 5, above.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Testimony; evidence; reason; argument; trial;
        demonstration. See {Testimony}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proof</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>proof
     adj : (used in combination or as a suffix) able to withstand;
           "temptation-proof"; "childproof locks" [syn: {proof(p)}]
     n 1: any factual evidence that helps to establish the truth of
          something; "if you have any proof for what you say, now
          is the time to produce it" [syn: {cogent evidence}]
     2: a formal series of statements showing that if one thing is
        true something else necessarily follows from it
     3: a measure of alcoholic strength expressed as an integer
        twice the percentage of alcohol present (by volume)
     4: (printing) an impression made to check for errors [syn: {test
        copy}, {trial impression}]
     5: a trial photographic print from a negative
     6: the act of validating; finding or testing the truth of
        something [syn: {validation}, {substantiation}]
     v 1: make or take a proof of, such as a photographic negative, an
          etching, or typeset
     2: knead to reach proper lightness; "proof dough"
     3: read for errors; "I should proofread my manuscripts" [syn: {proofread}]
     4: activate by mixing with water and sometimes sugar or milk;
        "proof yeast"
     5: make resistant to water, sound, errors, etc.; "proof the
        materials against shrinking in the dryer"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
