<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>proposition</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proposition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Proposition \Prop`o*si"tion\, n. [L. propositio: cf. F.
   proposition. See {Propound}.]
   1. The act of setting or placing before; the act of offering.
      ``Oblations for the altar of proposition.'' --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is proposed; that which is offered, as for
      consideration, acceptance, or adoption; a proposal; as,
      the enemy made propositions of peace; his proposition was
      not accepted.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A statement of religious doctrine; an article of faith;
      creed; as, the propositions of Wyclif and Huss.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some persons . . . change their propositions
            according as their temporal necessities or
            advantages do turn.                   --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Gram. &amp; Logic) A complete sentence, or part of a sentence
      consisting of a subject and predicate united by a copula;
      a thought expressed or propounded in language; a from of
      speech in which a predicate is affirmed or denied of a
      subject; as, snow is white.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) A statement in terms of a truth to be
      demonstrated, or of an operation to be performed.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: It is called a theorem when it is something to be
         proved, and a problem when it is something to be done.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. (Rhet.) That which is offered or affirmed as the subject
      of the discourse; anything stated or affirmed for
      discussion or illustration.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Poetry) The part of a poem in which the author states the
      subject or matter of it.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Leaves of proposition} (Jewish Antiq.), the showbread.
      --Wyclif (Luke vi. 4).
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Proposal; offer; statement; declaration.

   Usage: {Proposition}, {Proposal}. These words are both from
          the Latin verb proponere, to set forth, and as here
          compared they mark different forms or stages of a
          negotiation. A proposition is something presented for
          discussion or consideration; as, propositions of
          peace. A proposal is some definite thing offered by
          one party to be accepted or rejected by the other. If
          the proposition is favorably received, it is usually
          followed by proposals which complete the arrangement.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proposition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>proposition
     n 1: (logic) a statement that affirms or denies something and is
          either true or false
     2: a proposal offered for acceptance or rejection; "it was a
        suggestion we couldn't refuse" [syn: {suggestion}, {proffer}]
     3: an offer for a private bargain (especially a request for
        sexual favors)
     4: the act of making a proposal; "they listened to her
        proposal" [syn: {proposal}]
     5: a task to be dealt with; "securing adequate funding is a
        time-consuming proposition"
     v : suggest sex to; "She was propositioned by a stranger at the
         party"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
