<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>property</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>property</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>PROPERTY, n.  Any material thing, having no particular value, that may
be held by A against the cupidity of B.  Whatever gratifies the
passion for possession in one and disappoints it in all others.  The
object of man's brief rapacity and long indifference.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>property</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Property \Prop"er*ty\, n.; pl. {Properties}. [OE. proprete, OF.
   propret['e] property, F. propret['e] neatness, cleanliness,
   propri['e]t['e] property, fr. L. proprietas. See {Proper},
   a., and cf. {Propriety}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. That which is proper to anything; a peculiar quality of a
      thing; that which is inherent in a subject, or naturally
      essential to it; an attribute; as, sweetness is a property
      of sugar.
      [1913 Webster]

            Property is correctly a synonym for peculiar
            quality; but it is frequently used as coextensive
            with quality in general.              --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In physical science, the properties of matter are
         distinguished to the three following classes: 1.
         Physical properties, or those which result from the
         relations of bodies to the physical agents, light,
         heat, electricity, gravitation, cohesion, adhesion,
         etc., and which are exhibited without a change in the
         composition or kind of matter acted on. They are color,
         luster, opacity, transparency, hardness, sonorousness,
         density, crystalline form, solubility, capability of
         osmotic diffusion, vaporization, boiling, fusion, etc.
         2. Chemical properties, or those which are conditioned
         by affinity and composition; thus, combustion,
         explosion, and certain solutions are reactions
         occasioned by chemical properties. Chemical properties
         are identical when there is identity of composition and
         structure, and change according as the composition
         changes. 3. Organoleptic properties, or those forming a
         class which can not be included in either of the other
         two divisions. They manifest themselves in the contact
         of substances with the organs of taste, touch, and
         smell, or otherwise affect the living organism, as in
         the manner of medicines and poisons.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. An acquired or artificial quality; that which is given by
      art, or bestowed by man; as, the poem has the properties
      which constitute excellence.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The exclusive right of possessing, enjoying, and disposing
      of a thing; ownership; title.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here I disclaim all my paternal care,
            Propinquity and property of blood.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shall man assume a property in man?   --Wordsworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That to which a person has a legal title, whether in his
      possession or not; thing owned; an estate, whether in
      lands, goods, or money; as, a man of large property, or
      small property.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. pl. All the adjuncts of a play except the scenery and the
      dresses of the actors; stage requisites.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will draw a bill of properties.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Propriety; correctness. [Obs.] --Camden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Literary property}. (Law) See under {Literary}.

   {Property man}, one who has charge of the ``properties'' of a
      theater.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>property</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Property \Prop"er*ty\, v. t.
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To invest which properties, or qualities. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make a property of; to appropriate. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They have here propertied me.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>property</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>property
     n 1: any area set aside for a particular purpose; "who owns this
          place?"; "the president was concerned about the property
          across from the White House" [syn: {place}]
     2: something owned; any tangible or intangible possession that
        is owned by someone; "that hat is my property"; "he is a
        man of property"; [syn: {belongings}, {holding}, {material
        possession}]
     3: a basic or essential attribute shared by all members of a
        class; "a study of the physical properties of atomic
        particles"
     4: a construct whereby objects or individuals can be
        distinguished; "self-confidence is not an endearing
        property" [syn: {attribute}, {dimension}]
     5: any movable articles or objects used on the set of a play or
        movie; "before every scene he ran down his checklist of
        props" [syn: {prop}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
