<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>protocol</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protocol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>protocol
     
        A set of formal rules describing how to transmit data,
        especially across a {network}.  Low level protocols define the
        electrical and physical standards to be observed, bit- and
        byte-ordering and the transmission and {error detection and
        correction} of the bit stream.  High level protocols deal with
        the data formatting, including the {syntax} of messages, the
        terminal to computer dialogue, {character set}s, sequencing of
        messages etc.
     
        Many protocols are defined by {RFC}s or by {OSI}.
     
        See also {handshaking}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-01-12)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protocol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Protocol \Pro"to*col\, n. [F. protocole, LL. protocollum, fr.
   Gr. ? the first leaf glued to the rolls of papyrus and the
   notarial documents, on which the date was written; prw^tos
   the first (see {Proto-}) + ? glue.]
   1. The original copy of any writing, as of a deed, treaty,
      dispatch, or other instrument. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The minutes, or rough draught, of an instrument or
      transaction.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Diplomacy)
      (a) A preliminary document upon the basis of which
          negotiations are carried on.
      (b) A convention not formally ratified.
      (c) An agreement of diplomatists indicating the results
          reached by them at a particular stage of a
          negotiation.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. A strict code of etiquette for conduct of behavior among
      diplomatic or military personnel.

   5. A detailed plan for conduct of a scientific or medical
      experiment or procedure. A term used especially in conduct
      of medical research requiring approval of a regulatory
      agency.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protocol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Protocol \Pro"to*col\, v. t.
   To make a protocol of.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protocol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Protocol \Pro"to*col\, v. i.
   To make or write protocols, or first draughts; to issue
   protocols. --Carlyle.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protocol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>protocol n. As used by hackers, this never refers to niceties about the
   proper form for addressing letters to the Papal Nuncio or the order in
   which one should use the forks in a Russian-style place setting; hackers
   don't care about such things. It is used instead to describe any set of
   rules that allow different machines or pieces of software to coordinate
   with each other without ambiguity. So, for example, it does include
   niceties about the proper form for addressing packets on a network or
   the order in which one should use the forks in the Dining Philosophers
   Problem. It implies that there is some common message format and an
   accepted set of primitives or commands that all parties involved
   understand, and that transactions among them follow predictable logical
   sequences. See also {handshaking}, {do protocol}.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protocol</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>protocol
     n 1: (computer science) rules determining the format and
          transmission of data [syn: {communications protocol}]
     2: forms of ceremony and etiquette observed by diplomats and
        heads of state
     3: code of correct conduct; "safety protocols"; "academic
        protocol"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
