<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>protection</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protection</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Protection, KS (city, FIPS 57850)
  Location: 37.20016 N, 99.48034 W
  Population (1990): 625 (307 housing units)
  Area: 2.5 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 67127
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protection</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Protection \Pro*tec"tion\, n. [L. protectio: cf. F. protection.]
   1. The act of protecting, or the state of being protected;
      preservation from loss, injury, or annoyance; defense;
      shelter; as, the weak need protection.
      [1913 Webster]

            To your protection I commend me, gods. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which protects or preserves from injury; a defense; a
      shield; a refuge.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let them rise up . . . and be your protection.
                                                  --Deut. xxxii.
                                                  38.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A writing that protects or secures from molestation or
      arrest; a pass; a safe-conduct; a passport.
      [1913 Webster]

            He . . . gave them protections under his hand.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Polit. Econ.) A theory, or a policy, of protecting the
      producers in a country from foreign competition in the
      home market by the imposition of such discriminating
      duties on goods of foreign production as will restrict or
      prevent their importation; -- opposed to {free trade}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Writ of protection}. (Law)
      (a) A writ by which the king formerly exempted a person
          from arrest; -- now disused. [Eng.] --Blackstone.
      (b) A judicial writ issued to a person required to attend
          court, as party, juror, etc., intended to secure him
          from arrest in coming, staying, and returning.
          [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Preservation; defense; guard; shelter; refuge; security;
        safety.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>protection</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>protection
     n 1: the activity of protecting someone or something; "the
          witnesses demanded police protection"
     2: a covering that is intend to protect from damage or injury;
        "they had no protection from the fallout"; "wax provided
        protection for the floors" [syn: {protective covering}, {protective
        cover}]
     3: defense against financial failure; financial independence;
        "his pension gave him security in his old age"; "insurance
        provided protection against loss of wages due to illness"
        [syn: {security}]
     4: the condition of being protected; "they were huddled
        together for protection"; "he enjoyed a sense of peace and
        protection in his new home" [syn: {shelter}]
     5: kindly endorsement and guidance; "the tournament was held
        under the auspices of the city council" [syn: {auspices},
        {aegis}]
     6: the imposition of duties or quotas on imports in order to
        protect domestic industry against foreign competition; "he
        made trade protection a plank in the party platform" [syn:
         {trade protection}]
     7: payment extorted by gangsters on threat of violence; "every
        store in the neighborhood had to pay him protection" [syn:
         {tribute}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
