<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>proving</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proving</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Prove \Prove\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Proved}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Proving}.] [OE. prover, F. prouver, fr. L. probare to try,
   approve, prove, fr. probus good, proper. Cf. {Probable},
   {Proof}, {Probe}.]
   1. To try or to ascertain by an experiment, or by a test or
      standard; to test; as, to prove the strength of gunpowder
      or of ordnance; to prove the contents of a vessel by a
      standard measure.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou hast proved mine heart.          --Ps. xvii. 3.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To evince, establish, or ascertain, as truth, reality, or
      fact, by argument, testimony, or other evidence.
      [1913 Webster]

            They have inferred much from slender premises, and
            conjectured when they could not prove. --J. H.
                                                  Newman.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To ascertain or establish the genuineness or validity of;
      to verify; as, to prove a will.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To gain experience of the good or evil of; to know by
      trial; to experience; to suffer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Where she, captived long, great woes did prove.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Arith.) To test, evince, ascertain, or verify, as the
      correctness of any operation or result; thus, in
      subtraction, if the difference between two numbers, added
      to the lesser number, makes a sum equal to the greater,
      the correctness of the subtraction is proved.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Printing) To take a trial impression of; to take a proof
      of; as, to prove a page.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To try; verify; justify; confirm; establish; evince;
        manifest; show; demonstrate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
