<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>provide</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>provide</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Provide \Pro*vide"\, v. i.
   1. To procure supplies or means in advance; to take measures
      beforehand in view of an expected or a possible future
      need, especially a danger or an evil; -- followed by
      against or for; as, to provide against the inclemency of
      the weather; to provide for the education of a child.
      [1913 Webster]

            Government is a contrivance of human wisdom to
            provide for human wants.              --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To stipulate previously; to condition; as, the agreement
      provides for an early completion of the work.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>provide</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Provide \Pro*vide"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Provided}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Providing}.] [L. providere, provisum; pro before +
   videre to see. See {Vision}, and cf. {Prudent}, {Purvey}.]
   1. To look out for in advance; to procure beforehand; to get,
      collect, or make ready for future use; to prepare.
      ``Provide us all things necessary.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To supply; to afford; to contribute.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bring me berries, or such cooling fruit
            As the kind, hospitable woods provide. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To furnish; to supply; -- formerly followed by of, now by
      with. ``And yet provided him of but one.'' --Jer. Taylor.
      ``Rome . . . was well provided with corn.'' --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To establish as a previous condition; to stipulate; as,
      the contract provides that the work be well done.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To foresee.

   Note: [A Latinism] [Obs.] --B. Jonson.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. To appoint to an ecclesiastical benefice before it is
      vacant. See {Provisor}. --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>provide</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>provide
     v 1: provide or furnish with; "We provided the room with an
          electrical heater" [syn: {supply}, {render}, {furnish}]
     2: provide what is desired or needed, especially support, food
        or sustenance; "The hostess provided lunch for all the
        guests" [syn: {supply}, {ply}, {cater}]
     3: determine (what is to happen in certain contingencies),
        especially by including a proviso condition or
        stipulation; "The will provides that each child should
        receive half of the money"; "The Constitution provides for
        the right to free speech"
     4: mount or put up; "put up a good fight"; "offer resistance"
        [syn: {put up}, {offer}]
     5: make a possibility or provide opportunity for; permit to be
        attainable or cause to remain; "This leaves no room for
        improvement"; "The evidence allows only one conclusion";
        "allow for mistakes"; "leave lots of time for the trip";
        "This procedure provides for lots of leeway" [syn: {leave},
         {allow for}, {allow}]
     6: supply means of subsistence; earn a living; "He provides for
        his large family by working three jobs"; "Women nowadays
        not only take care of the household but also bring home
        the bacon" [syn: {bring home the bacon}]
     7: take measures in preparation for; "provide for the proper
        care of the passengers on the cruise ship"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
