<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>province</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>province</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Province \Prov"ince\, n. [F., fr. L. provincia; prob. fr. pro
   before, for + the root of vincere to conquer. See {Victor}.]
   1. (Roman Hist.) A country or region, more or less remote
      from the city of Rome, brought under the Roman government;
      a conquered country beyond the limits of Italy. --Wyclif
      (Acts xiii. 34). Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A country or region dependent on a distant authority; a
      portion of an empire or state, esp. one remote from the
      capital. ``Kingdoms and provinces.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A region of country; a tract; a district.
      [1913 Webster]

            Over many a tract
            of heaven they marched, and many a province wide.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Other provinces of the intellectual world. --I.
                                                  Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A region under the supervision or direction of any special
      person; the district or division of a country, especially
      an ecclesiastical division, over which one has
      jurisdiction; as, the province of Canterbury, or that in
      which the archbishop of Canterbury exercises
      ecclesiastical authority.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The proper or appropriate business or duty of a person or
      body; office; charge; jurisdiction; sphere.
      [1913 Webster]

            The woman'sprovince is to be careful in her economy,
            and chaste in her affection.          --Tattler.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Specif.: Any political division of the Dominion of Canada,
      having a governor, a local legislature, and representation
      in the Dominion parliament. Hence, colloquially, The
      Provinces, the Dominion of Canada.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>province</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>province
     n 1: the territory occupied by one of the constituent
          administrative districts of a nation; "his state is in
          the deep south" [syn: {state}]
     2: the proper sphere or extent of your activities; "it was his
        province to take care of himself" [syn: {responsibility}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
