<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>proximate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proximate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Proximate \Prox"i*mate\, a. [L. proximatus, p. p. of proximare
   to come near, to approach, fr. proximus the nearest, nest,
   superl. of propior nearer, and prope, adv., near.]
   Nearest; next immediately preceding or following. ``Proximate
   ancestors.'' --J. S. Harford.
   [1913 Webster]

         The proximate natural causes of it [the deluge]. --T.
                                                  Burnet.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Proximate analysis} (Chem.), an analysis which determines
      the proximate principles of any substance, as contrasted
      with an ultimate analysis.

   {Proximate cause}.
   (a) A cause which immediately precedes and produces the
       effect, as distinguished from the remote, mediate, or
       predisposing cause. --I. Watts.
   (b) That which in ordinary natural sequence produces a
       specific result, no independent disturbing agencies
       intervening.

   {Proximate principle} (Physiol. Chem.), one of a class of
      bodies existing ready formed in animal and vegetable
      tissues, and separable by chemical analysis, as albumin,
      sugar, collagen, fat, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Nearest; next; closest; immediate; direct.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proximate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Analysis \A*nal"y*sis\, n.; pl. {Analyses}. [Gr. ?, fr. ? to
   unloose, to dissolve, to resolve into its elements; ? up + ?
   to loose. See {Loose}.]
   1. A resolution of anything, whether an object of the senses
      or of the intellect, into its constituent or original
      elements; an examination of the component parts of a
      subject, each separately, as the words which compose a
      sentence, the tones of a tune, or the simple propositions
      which enter into an argument. It is opposed to
      {synthesis}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Chem.) The separation of a compound substance, by
      chemical processes, into its constituents, with a view to
      ascertain either (a) what elements it contains, or (b) how
      much of each element is present. The former is called
      {qualitative}, and the latter {quantitative analysis}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Logic) The tracing of things to their source, and the
      resolving of knowledge into its original principles.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Math.) The resolving of problems by reducing the
      conditions that are in them to equations.
      [1913 Webster]

   5.
      (a) A syllabus, or table of the principal heads of a
          discourse, disposed in their natural order.
      (b) A brief, methodical illustration of the principles of
          a science. In this sense it is nearly synonymous with
          synopsis.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Nat. Hist.) The process of ascertaining the name of a
      species, or its place in a system of classification, by
      means of an analytical table or key.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Ultimate}, {Proximate}, {Qualitative}, {Quantitative}, and
   {Volumetric analysis}. (Chem.) See under {Ultimate},
      {Proximate}, {Qualitative}, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>proximate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>proximate
     adj 1: closest in degree or order (space or time) especially in a
            chain of causes and effects; "news of his proximate
            arrival"; "interest in proximate rather than ultimate
            goals" [ant: {ultimate}]
     2: very close in space or time; "proximate words"; "proximate
        houses"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
