<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pulling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pull \Pull\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Pulled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Pulling}.] [AS. pullian; cf. LG. pulen, and Gael. peall,
   piol, spiol.]
   1. To draw, or attempt to draw, toward one; to draw forcibly.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ne'er pull your hat upon your brows.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He put forth his hand . . . and pulled her in.
                                                  --Gen. viii.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw apart; to tear; to rend.
      [1913 Webster]

            He hath turned aside my ways, and pulled me in
            pieces; he hath made me desolate.     --Lam. iii.
                                                  11.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To gather with the hand, or by drawing toward one; to
      pluck; as, to pull fruit; to pull flax; to pull a finch.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To move or operate by the motion of drawing towards one;
      as, to pull a bell; to pull an oar.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Horse Racing) To hold back, and so prevent from winning;
      as, the favorite was pulled.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Print.) To take or make, as a proof or impression; --
      hand presses being worked by pulling a lever.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Cricket) To strike the ball in a particular manner. See
      {Pull}, n., 8.
      [1913 Webster]

            Never pull a straight fast ball to leg. --R. H.
                                                  Lyttelton.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To pull and haul}, to draw hither and thither. `` Both are
      equally pulled and hauled to do that which they are unable
      to do. '' --South.

   {To pull down}, to demolish; to destroy; to degrade; as, to
      pull down a house. `` In political affairs, as well as
      mechanical, it is easier to pull down than build up.''
      --Howell. `` To raise the wretched, and pull down the
      proud.'' --Roscommon.

   {To pull a finch}. See under {Finch}.

   {To pull off}, take or draw off.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pulling
     n : the act of pulling; applying force to move something toward
         or with you; "the pull up the hill had him breathing
         harder"; "his strenuous pulling strained his back" [syn:
         {pull}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
