<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pulse</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pulse
   (Dan. 1:12, 16), R.V. "herbs," vegetable food in general.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pulse \Pulse\, n. [OE. pous, OF. pous, F. pouls, fr. L. pulsus
   (sc. venarum), the beating of the pulse, the pulse, from
   pellere, pulsum, to beat, strike; cf. Gr. ? to swing, shake,
   ? to shake. Cf. {Appeal}, {Compel}, {Impel}, {Push}.]
   1. (Physiol.) The beating or throbbing of the heart or blood
      vessels, especially of the arteries.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In an artery the pulse is due to the expansion and
         contraction of the elastic walls of the artery by the
         action of the heart upon the column of blood in the
         arterial system. On the commencement of the diastole of
         the ventricle, the semilunar valves are closed, and the
         aorta recoils by its elasticity so as to force part of
         its contents into the vessels farther onwards. These,
         in turn, as they already contain a certain quantity of
         blood, expand, recover by an elastic recoil, and
         transmit the movement with diminished intensity. Thus a
         series of movements, gradually diminishing in
         intensity, pass along the arterial system (see the Note
         under {Heart}). For the sake of convenience, the radial
         artery at the wrist is generally chosen to detect the
         precise character of the pulse. The pulse rate varies
         with age, position, sex, stature, physical and
         psychical influences, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Any measured or regular beat; any short, quick motion,
      regularly repeated, as of a medium in the transmission of
      light, sound, etc.; oscillation; vibration; pulsation;
      impulse; beat; movement.
      [1913 Webster]

            The measured pulse of racing oars.    --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the ear receives any simple sound, it is struck
            by a single pulse of the air, which makes the
            eardrum and the other membranous parts vibrate
            according to the nature and species of the stroke.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Pulse glass}, an instrument consisting to a glass tube with
      terminal bulbs, and containing ether or alcohol, which the
      heat of the hand causes to boil; -- so called from the
      pulsating motion of the liquid when thus warmed.

   {Pulse wave} (Physiol.), the wave of increased pressure
      started by the ventricular systole, radiating from the
      semilunar valves over the arterial system, and gradually
      disappearing in the smaller branches.
      [1913 Webster]

            the pulse wave travels over the arterial system at
            the rate of about 29.5 feet in a second. --H. N.
                                                  Martin.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To feel one's pulse}.
      (a) To ascertain, by the sense of feeling, the condition
          of the arterial pulse.
      (b) Hence, to sound one's opinion; to try to discover
          one's mind.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pulse \Pulse\, n. [OE. puls, L. puls, pultis, a thick pap or
   pottage made of meal, pulse, etc. See {Poultice}, and cf.
   {Pousse}.]
   Leguminous plants, or their seeds, as beans, pease, etc.
   [1913 Webster]

         If all the world
         Should, in a pet of temperance, feed on pulse.
                                                  --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pulse \Pulse\, v. i.
   To beat, as the arteries; to move in pulses or beats; to
   pulsate; to throb. --Ray.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pulse \Pulse\, v. t. [See {Pulsate}, {Pulse} a beating.]
   To drive by a pulsation; to cause to pulsate. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pulse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pulse
     n 1: (electronics) a sharp transient wave in the normal
          electrical state (or a series of such transients); "the
          pulsations seemed to be coming from a star" [syn: {pulsation},
           {pulsing}, {impulse}]
     2: the rhythmic contraction and expansion of the arteries with
        each beat of the heart; "he could feel the beat of her
        heart" [syn: {pulsation}, {heartbeat}, {beat}]
     3: the rate at which the heart beats; usually measured to
        obtain a quick evaluation of a person's health [syn: {pulse
        rate}, {heart rate}]
     4: edible seeds of various pod-bearing plants (peas or beans or
        lentils etc.)
     v 1: expand and contract rhythmically; beat rhythmically; "The
          baby's heart was pulsating again after the surgeon
          massaged it" [syn: {pulsate}, {throb}]
     2: produce or modulate (as electromagnetic waves) in the form
        of short bursts or pulses or cause an apparatus to produce
        pulses; "pulse waves"; "a transmitter pulsed by an
        electronic tube" [syn: {pulsate}]
     3: drive by or as if by pulsation; "A soft breeze pulsed the
        air"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
