<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>puppet</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>puppet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Puppet \Pup"pet\, n. [OE. popet, OF. poupette; akin to F.
   poup['e]e a doll, probably from L. puppa, pupa, a girl, doll,
   puppet. Cf. {Poupeton}, {Pupa}, {Pupil}, {Puppy}.] [Written
   also {poppet}.]
   1. A small image in the human form; a doll.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A similar figure moved by the hand or by a wire in a mock
      drama; a marionette; a wooden actor in a play.
      [1913 Webster]

            At the pipes of some carved organ move,
            The gilded puppets dance.             --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One controlled in his action by the will of another; a
      tool; -- so used in contempt. --Sir W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mach.) The upright support for the bearing of the spindle
      in a lathe.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Puppet master}. Same as {Puppetman}.

   {Puppet play}, a puppet show.

   {Puppet player}, one who manages the motions of puppets.

   {Puppet show}, a mock drama performed by puppets moved by
      wires.

   {Puppet valve}, a valve in the form of a circular disk, which
      covers a hole in its seat, and opens by moving bodily away
      from the seat while remaining parallel with it, -- used in
      steam engines, pumps, safety valves, etc. Its edge is
      often beveled, and fits in a conical recess in the seat
      when the valve is closed. See the valves shown in Illusts.
      of {Plunger pump}, and {Safety valve}, under {Plunger},
      and {Safety}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>puppet</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>puppet
     n 1: a small figure of a person operated from above with strings
          by a puppeteer [syn: {marionette}]
     2: a person who is controlled by others and is used to perform
        unpleasant or dishonest tasks for someone else [syn: {creature},
         {tool}]
     3: a doll with a hollow head of a person or animal and a cloth
        body; intended to fit over the hand and be manipulated
        with the fingers
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
