<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>purchase</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>purchase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Purchase, NY
  Zip code(s): 10577
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>purchase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Purchase \Pur"chase\ (?; 48), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Purchased};
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Purchasing}.] [OE. purchasen, porchacen, OF.
   porchacier, purchacier, to pursue, to seek eagerly, F.
   pourchasser; OF. pour, por, pur, for (L. pro) + chacier to
   pursue, to chase. See {Chase}.]
   1. To pursue and obtain; to acquire by seeking; to gain,
      obtain, or acquire. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            That loves the thing he can not purchase. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your accent is Something finer than you could
            purchase in so removed a dwelling.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            His faults . . . hereditary
            Rather than purchased.                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To obtain by paying money or its equivalent; to buy for a
      price; as, to purchase land, or a house.
      [1913 Webster]

            The field which Abraham purchased of the sons of
            Heth.                                 --Gen. xxv.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To obtain by any outlay, as of labor, danger, or
      sacrifice, etc.; as, to purchase favor with flattery.
      [1913 Webster]

            One poor retiring minute . . .
            Would purchase thee a thousand thousand friends.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A world who would not purchase with a bruise?
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To expiate by a fine or forfeit. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Not tears nor prayers shall purchase out abuses.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law)
      (a) To acquire by any means except descent or inheritance.
          --Blackstone.
      (b) To buy for a price.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. To apply to (anything) a device for obtaining a mechanical
      advantage; to get a purchase upon, or apply a purchase to;
      as, to purchase a cannon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>purchase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Purchase \Pur"chase\, v. i.
   1. To put forth effort to obtain anything; to strive; to
      exert one's self. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Duke John of Brabant purchased greatly that the Earl
            of Flanders should have his daughter in marriage.
                                                  --Ld. Berners.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To acquire wealth or property. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Sure our lawyers
            Would not purchase half so fast.      --J. Webster.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>purchase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Purchase \Pur"chase\ (?; 48), n. [OE. purchds, F. pourchas eager
   pursuit. See {Purchase}, v. t.]
   1. The act of seeking, getting, or obtaining anything. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll . . . get meat to have thee,
            Or lose my life in the purchase.      --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of seeking and acquiring property.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The acquisition of title to, or properly in, anything for
      a price; buying for money or its equivalent.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is foolish to lay out money in the purchase of
            repentance.                           --Franklin.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is obtained, got, or acquired, in any manner,
      honestly or dishonestly; property; possession;
      acquisition. --Chaucer. B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

            We met with little purchase upon this coast, except
            two small vessels of Golconda.        --De Foe.
      [1913 Webster]

            A beauty-waning and distressed widow . . .
            Made prize and purchase of his lustful eye. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which is obtained for a price in money or its
      equivalent. ``The scrip was complete evidence of his right
      in the purchase.'' --Wheaton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Any mechanical hold, or advantage, applied to the raising
      or removing of heavy bodies, as by a lever, a tackle,
      capstan, and the like; also, the apparatus, tackle, or
      device by which the advantage is gained.
      [1913 Webster]

            A politician, to do great things, looks for a power
            -- what our workmen call a purchase.  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) Acquisition of lands or tenements by other means
      than descent or inheritance, namely, by one's own act or
      agreement. --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Purchase criminal}, robbery. [Obs.] --Spenser.

   {Purchase money}, the money paid, or contracted to be paid,
      for anything bought. --Berkeley.

   {Worth [so many] years' purchase}, or {At [so many] years'
   purchase}, a phrase by which the value or cost of a thing is
      expressed in the length of time required for the income to
      amount to the purchasing price; as, he bought the estate
      at a twenty years' purchase. To say one's life is

   {not worth a day's purchase} in the same as saying one will
      not live a day, or is in imminent peril.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>purchase</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>purchase
     n 1: the acquisition of something for payment; "they closed the
          purchase with a handshake"
     2: something acquired by purchase
     3: a means of exerting influence or gaining advantage; "he
        could get no purchase on the situation"
     4: the mechanical advantage gained by being in a position to
        use a lever [syn: {leverage}]
     v : obtain by purchase; acquire by means of a financial
         transaction; "The family purchased a new car"; "The
         conglomerate acquired a new company"; "She buys for the
         big department store" [syn: {buy}] [ant: {sell}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
