<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pursuit</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pursuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pursuit \Pur*suit"\, n. [F. poursuite, fr. poursuivre. See
   {Pursue}, v. t.]
   1. The act of following or going after; esp., a following
      with haste, either for sport or in hostility; chase;
      prosecution; as, the pursuit of game; the pursuit of an
      enemy. --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Weak we are, and can not shun pursuit. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A following with a view to reach, accomplish, or obtain;
      endeavor to attain to or gain; as, the pursuit of
      knowledge; the pursuit of happiness or pleasure.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Course of business or occupation; continued employment
      with a view to same end; as, mercantile pursuits; a
      literary pursuit.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) Prosecution. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            That pursuit for tithes ought, and of ancient time
            did pertain to the spiritual court.   --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Curve of pursuit} (Geom.), a curve described by a point
      which is at each instant moving towards a second point,
      which is itself moving according to some specified law.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pursuit</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pursuit
     n 1: the act of pursuing in an effort to overtake or capture;
          "the culprit started to run and the cop took off in
          pursuit" [syn: {chase}, {following}]
     2: a search for an alternative that meets cognitive criteria;
        "the pursuit of love"; "life is more than the pursuance of
        fame"; "a quest for wealth" [syn: {pursuance}, {quest}]
     3: a diversion that occupies one's time and thoughts (usually
        pleasantly); "sailing is her favorite pastime"; "his main
        pastime is gambling"; "he counts reading among his
        interests"; "they criticized the boy for his limited
        pursuits" [syn: {pastime}, {interest}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
