<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>pyramid</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pyramid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pyramid \Pyr"a*mid\, n. [L. pyramis, -idis, fr. Gr. ?, ?, of
   Egyptian origin: cf. F. pyramide.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A solid body standing on a triangular, square, or
      polygonal base, and terminating in a point at the top;
      especially, a structure or edifice of this shape.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geom.) A solid figure contained by a plane rectilineal
      figure as base and several triangles which have a common
      vertex and whose bases are sides of the base.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. (Billiards) The game of pool in which the balls are
      placed in the form of a triangle at spot. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Finance) a fraudulent investment scheme in which the
      manager promises high profits, but instead of investing
      the money in a genuine profit-making activity, uses the
      money from later investors to pay the profits to earlier
      investors; -- also called {pyramid scheme} or {pyramid
      operation}. This process inevitably collapses when
      insufficient new investors are available, leaving the
      later investors with total or near-total losses of their
      investments. The managers usually blame government
      regulations or interference for the collapse of the
      scheme, rather than admit fraud.
      [PJC]

   {Altitude of a pyramid} (Geom.), the perpendicular distance
      from the vertex to the plane of the base.

   {Axis of a pyramid} (Geom.), a straight line drawn from the
      vertex to the center of the base.

   {Earth pyramid}. (Geol.) See {Earth pillars}, under {Earth}.
      

   {Right pyramid} (Geom.) a pyramid whose axis is perpendicular
      to the base.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pyramid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pyramid \Pyr"a*mid\, v. i. (Speculation)
   To enlarge one's holding or interest in a series of
   operations on a continued rise or decline by using the
   profits to buy or sell additional amounts on a margin, as
   where one buys on a 10% margin 100 shares of stock quoted at
   100, holds it till it rises to 105, and then uses the paper
   profit to buy 50 shares more, etc. The series of operations
   constitutes a pyramid. A similar process of reinvesting gains
   or winnings (as of a gamble), but not involving operation on
   margin, is called a {parlay}.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pyramid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Pyramid \Pyr"a*mid\, v. t. (Speculation)
   To use, or to deal in, in a pyramiding transaction. See
   {Pyramid}, v. i.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>pyramid</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>pyramid
     n 1: a polyhedron having a polygonal base and triangular sides
          with a common vertex
     2: (stock market) a series of transactions in which the
        speculator increases his holdings by using the rising
        market value of those holdings as margin for further
        purchases
     3: a massive memorial with a square base and four triangular
        sides; built as royal tombs in ancient Egypt [syn: {Great
        Pyramid}]
     v 1: enlarge one's holdings on an exchange on a continued rise by
          using paper profits as margin to buy additional amounts
     2: use or deal in (as of stock or commercial transaction) in a
        pyramid deal
     3: arrange or build up as if on the base of a pyramid
     4: increase rapidly and progressively step by step on a broad
        base
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
