<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>zone</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>zone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>zone
     
        A logical group of {network} devices on {AppleTalk}.
     
        (1994-11-30)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>zone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Zone \Zone\ (z[=o]n), n. [F. zone, L. zona, Gr. zw`nh; akin to
   zwnny`nai to gird, Lith. j[*u]sta a girdle, j[*u]sti to gird,
   Zend y[=a]h.]
   1. A girdle; a cincture. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            An embroidered zone surrounds her waist. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Loose were her tresses seen, her zone unbound.
                                                  --Collins.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geog.) One of the five great divisions of the earth, with
      respect to latitude and temperature.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The zones are five: the torrid zone, extending from
         tropic to tropic 46[deg] 56[min], or 23[deg] 28[min] on
         each side of the equator; two temperate or variable
         zones, situated between the tropics and the polar
         circles; and two frigid zones, situated between the
         polar circles and the poles.
         [1913 Webster]

               Commerce . . . defies every wind, outrides every
               tempest, and invades.              --Bancroft.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Math.) The portion of the surface of a sphere included
      between two parallel planes; the portion of a surface of
      revolution included between two planes perpendicular to
      the axis. --Davies &amp; Peck (Math. Dict.)
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Nat. Hist.)
      (a) A band or stripe extending around a body.
      (b) A band or area of growth encircling anything; as, a
          zone of evergreens on a mountain; the zone of animal
          or vegetable life in the ocean around an island or a
          continent; the Alpine zone, that part of mountains
          which is above the limit of tree growth.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Crystallog.) A series of planes having mutually parallel
      intersections.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Circuit; circumference. [R.] --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Biogeography) An area or part of a region characterized
      by uniform or similar animal and plant life; a life zone;
      as, Littoral zone, Austral zone, etc.

   Note: The zones, or life zones, commonly recognized for North
         America are Arctic, Hudsonian, Canadian, Transition,
         Upper Austral, Lower Austral, and Tropical.
         [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. (Cryst.) A series of faces whose intersection lines with
      each other are parallel.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. (Railroad Econ.)
      (a) The aggregate of stations, in whatsoever direction or
          on whatsoever line of railroad, situated between
          certain maximum and minimum limits from a point at
          which a shipment of traffic originates.
      (b) Any circular or ring-shaped area within which the
          street-car companies make no differences of fare.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. any area to or within which a shipment or transportation
       cost is constant; specifically, in the United States
       parcel-post system, any of the areas about any point of
       shipment for which but one rate of postage is charged for
       a parcel post shipment from that point. The rate
       increases from within outwards. The first zone includes
       the unit of area ``(a quadrangle 30 minutes square)'' in
       which the place of shipment is situated and the 8
       contiguous units; the outer limits of the second to the
       seventh zones, respectively, are approximately 150, 300,
       600, 1000, 1400, and 1800 miles from the point of
       shipment; the eighth zone includes all units of area
       outside the seventh zone.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   {Abyssal zone}. (Phys. Geog.) See under {Abyssal}.

   {Zone axis} (Crystallog.), a straight line passing through
      the center of a crystal, to which all the planes of a
      given zone are parallel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>zone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Zone \Zone\, v. t.
   To girdle; to encircle. [R.] --Keats.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>zone</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>zone
     n 1: a circumscribed geographical region characterized by some
          distinctive features
     2: any of the regions of the surface of the Earth loosely
        divided according to latitude or longitude [syn: {geographical
        zone}]
     3: an area or region distinguished from adjacent parts by a
        distinctive feature or characteristic
     4: (anatomy) any encircling or beltlike structure [syn: {zona}]
     v 1: regulate housing in; of certain areas of towns [syn: {district}]
     2: separate or apportion into sections; "partition a room off"
        [syn: {partition}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
