<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>race</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>RACE
     
        &lt;programming&gt; {Requirements Acquisition and
        Controlled Evolution}.
     
        (1995-11-21)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Race \Race\ (r[=a]s), v. t.
   To raze. [Obs.] --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Race \Race\ (r[=a]s), n. [OF. ra["i]z, L. radix, -icis. See
   {Radix}.]
   A root. ``A race or two of ginger.'' --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Race ginger}, ginger in the root, or not pulverized.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Race \Race\, n. [F. race; cf. Pr. &amp; Sp. raza, It. razza; all
   from OHG. reiza line, akin to E. write. See {Write}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The descendants of a common ancestor; a family, tribe,
      people, or nation, believed or presumed to belong to the
      same stock; a lineage; a breed.
      [1913 Webster]

            The whole race of mankind.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whence the long race of Alban fathers come.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Naturalists and ethnographers divide mankind into
         several distinct varieties, or races. Cuvier refers
         them all to three, Pritchard enumerates seven, Agassiz
         eight, Pickering describes eleven. One of the common
         classifications is that of Blumenbach, who makes five
         races: the Caucasian, or white race, to which belong
         the greater part of the European nations and those of
         Western Asia; the Mongolian, or yellow race, occupying
         Tartary, China, Japan, etc.; the Ethiopian, or negro
         race, occupying most of Africa (except the north),
         Australia, Papua, and other Pacific Islands; the
         American, or red race, comprising the Indians of North
         and South America; and the Malayan, or brown race,
         which occupies the islands of the Indian Archipelago,
         etc. Many recent writers classify the Malay and
         American races as branches of the Mongolian. See
         Illustration in Appendix.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Company; herd; breed.
      [1913 Webster]

            For do but note a wild and wanton herd,
            Or race of youthful and unhandled colts,
            Fetching mad bounds.                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) A variety of such fixed character that it may be
      propagated by seed.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Peculiar flavor, taste, or strength, as of wine; that
      quality, or assemblage of qualities, which indicates
      origin or kind, as in wine; hence, characteristic flavor;
      smack. ``A race of heaven.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Is it [the wine] of the right race ?  --Massinger.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, characteristic quality or disposition. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            And now I give my sensual race the rein. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Some . . . great race of fancy or judgment. --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Lineage; line; family; house; breed; offspring; progeny;
        issue.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Race \Race\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Raced} (r[=a]st); p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Racing} (r[=a]"s[i^]ng).]
   1. To run swiftly; to contend in a race; as, the animals
      raced over the ground; the ships raced from port to port.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Steam Mach.) To run too fast at times, as a marine engine
      or screw, when the screw is lifted out of water by the
      action of a heavy sea.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Race \Race\, n. [OE. ras, res, rees, AS. r[=ae]s a rush,
   running; akin to Icel. r[=a]s course, race. [root]118.]
   1. A progress; a course; a movement or progression.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Esp., swift progress; rapid course; a running.
      [1913 Webster]

            The flight of many birds is swifter than the race of
            any beasts.                           --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: The act or process of running in competition; a
      contest of speed in any way, as in running, riding,
      driving, skating, rowing, sailing; in the plural, usually,
      a meeting for contests in the running of horses; as, he
      attended the races.
      [1913 Webster]

            The race is not to the swift.         --Eccl. ix.
                                                  11.
      [1913 Webster]

            I wield the gauntlet, and I run the race. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Competitive action of any kind, especially when prolonged;
      hence, career; course of life.
      [1913 Webster]

            My race of glory run, and race of shame. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A strong or rapid current of water, or the channel or
      passage for such a current; a powerful current or heavy
      sea, sometimes produced by the meeting of two tides; as,
      the Portland Race; the Race of Alderney.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The current of water that turns a water wheel, or the
      channel in which it flows; a mill race.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The part of the channel above the wheel is sometimes
         called the headrace, the part below, the tailrace.
         [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mach.) A channel or guide along which a shuttle is driven
      back and forth, as in a loom, sewing machine, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Race cloth}, a cloth worn by horses in racing, having
      pockets to hold the weights prescribed.

   {Race course}.
      (a) The path, generally circular or elliptical, over which
          a race is run.
      (b) Same as {Race way}, below.

   {Race cup}, a cup given as a prize to the victor in a race.
      

   {Race glass}, a kind of field glass.

   {Race horse}.
      (a) A horse that runs in competition; specifically, a
          horse bred or kept for running races.
      (b) A breed of horses remarkable for swiftness in running.
      (c) (Zo["o]l.) The steamer duck.
      (d) (Zo["o]l.) A mantis.

   {Race knife}, a cutting tool with a blade that is hooked at
      the point, for marking outlines, on boards or metals, as
      by a pattern, -- used in shipbuilding.

   {Race saddle}, a light saddle used in racing.

   {Race track}. Same as {Race course}
      (a), above.

   {Race way}, the canal for the current that drives a water
      wheel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Race \Race\, v. t.
   1. To cause to contend in a race; to drive at high speed; as,
      to race horses.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To run a race with.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Consolation game \Con`so*la"tion game\, match \match\, pot
\pot\, race \race\, etc.
   A game, match, etc., open only to losers in early stages of
   contests.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.] ||
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>RACE
     Research and technology development in Advanced Communications
     technologies in Europe (Europe, predecessor, CORDIS)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>RACE
     Rowbased ASCII Compatible Encoding (ASCII, Internet, DOMAIN,
     VeriSign/NSI)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>race</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>race
     n 1: any competition; "the race for the presidency"
     2: people who are believed to belong to the same genetic stock;
        "some biologists doubt that there are important genetic
        differences between races of human beings"
     3: a contest of speed; "the race is to the swift"
     4: the flow of air that is driven backwards by an aircraft
        propeller [syn: {slipstream}, {airstream}, {backwash}, {wash}]
     5: (biology) a taxonomic group that is a division of a species;
        usually arises as a consequence of geographical isolation
        within a species [syn: {subspecies}]
     6: a canal for a current of water [syn: {raceway}]
     v 1: step on it; "He rushed down the hall to receive his guests";
          "The cars raced down the street" [syn: {rush}, {hotfoot},
           {hasten}, {hie}, {speed}, {pelt along}, {rush along}, {cannonball
          along}, {bucket along}, {belt along}] [ant: {linger}]
     2: compete in a race; "he is running the Marathon this year";
        "let's race and see who gets there first" [syn: {run}]
     3: to work as fast as possible towards a goal, sometimes in
        competition with others; "We are racing to find a cure for
        AIDS"
     4: cause to move fast or to rush or race; "The psychologist
        raced the rats through a long maze" [syn: {rush}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
