<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>radiant</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>radiant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Radiant, VA
  Zip code(s): 22732
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>radiant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Radiant \Ra"di*ant\ (r[=a]"d[i^]*ant), a. [L. radians, -antis,
   p. pr. of radiare to emit rays or beams, fr. radius ray: cf.
   F. radiant. See {Radius}, {Ray} a divergent line.]
   1. Emitting or proceeding as from a center; resembling rays;
      radiating; radiate.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially, emitting or darting rays of light or heat;
      issuing in beams or rays; beaming with brightness;
      emitting a vivid light or splendor; as, the radiant sun.
      [1913 Webster]

            Mark what radiant state she spreads.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Beaming with vivacity and happiness; as, a radiant face.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Her.) Giving off rays; -- said of a bearing; as, the sun
      radiant; a crown radiant.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Bot.) Having a raylike appearance, as the large marginal
      flowers of certain umbelliferous plants; -- said also of
      the cluster which has such marginal flowers.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Physics) Emitted or transmitted by radiation; as, a
      radiant energy; radiant heat.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Radiant energy} (Physics), energy given out or transmitted
      by radiation, as in the case of light and radiant heat.

   {Radiant heat}, heat proceeding in right lines, or directly
      from the heated body, after the manner of light, in
      distinction from heat conducted or carried by intervening
      media.

   {Radiant point}. (Astron.) See {Radiant}, n., 3.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>radiant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Radiant \Ra"di*ant\, n.
   1. (Opt.) The luminous point or object from which light
      emanates; also, a body radiating light brightly.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Geom.) A straight line proceeding from a given point, or
      fixed pole, about which it is conceived to revolve.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Astron.) The point in the heavens at which the apparent
      paths of shooting stars meet, when traced backward, or
      whence they appear to radiate.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>radiant</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>radiant
     adj : radiating or as if radiating light; "the beaming sun"; "the
           effulgent daffodils"; "a radiant sunrise"; "a refulgent
           sunset" [syn: {beaming}, {beamy}, {effulgent}, {refulgent}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
