<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>raised</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>raised</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Raise \Raise\ (r[=a]z), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Raised} (r[=a]zd);
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Raising}.] [OE. reisen, Icel. reisa,
   causative of r[=i]sa to rise. See {Rise}, and cf. {Rear} to
   raise.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To cause to rise; to bring from a lower to a higher place;
      to lift upward; to elevate; to heave; as, to raise a stone
      or weight. Hence, figuratively: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To bring to a higher condition or situation; to
          elevate in rank, dignity, and the like; to increase
          the value or estimation of; to promote; to exalt; to
          advance; to enhance; as, to raise from a low estate;
          to raise to office; to raise the price, and the like.
          [1913 Webster]

                This gentleman came to be raised to great
                titles.                           --Clarendon.
          [1913 Webster]

                The plate pieces of eight were raised three
                pence in the piece.               --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To increase the strength, vigor, or vehemence of; to
          excite; to intensify; to invigorate; to heighten; as,
          to raise the pulse; to raise the voice; to raise the
          spirits or the courage; to raise the heat of a
          furnace.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To elevate in degree according to some scale; as, to
          raise the pitch of the voice; to raise the temperature
          of a room.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to rise up, or assume an erect position or
      posture; to set up; to make upright; as, to raise a mast
      or flagstaff. Hence: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To cause to spring up from a recumbent position, from
          a state of quiet, or the like; to awaken; to arouse.
          [1913 Webster]

                They shall not awake, nor be raised out of their
                sleep.                            --Job xiv. 12.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To rouse to action; to stir up; to incite to tumult,
          struggle, or war; to excite.
          [1913 Webster]

                He commandeth, and raiseth the stormy wind.
                                                  --Ps. cvii.
                                                  25.
          [1913 Webster]

                [AE]neas . . . employs his pains,
                In parts remote, to raise the Tuscan swains.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To bring up from the lower world; to call up, as a
          spirit from the world of spirits; to recall from
          death; to give life to.
          [1913 Webster]

                Why should it be thought a thing incredible with
                you, that God should raise the dead ? --Acts
                                                  xxvi. 8.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to arise, grow up, or come into being or to
      appear; to give rise to; to originate, produce, cause,
      effect, or the like. Hence, specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To form by the accumulation of materials or
          constituent parts; to build up; to erect; as, to raise
          a lofty structure, a wall, a heap of stones.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will raise forts against thee.  --Isa. xxix.
                                                  3.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To bring together; to collect; to levy; to get
          together or obtain for use or service; as, to raise
          money, troops, and the like. ``To raise up a rent.''
          --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To cause to grow; to procure to be produced, bred, or
          propagated; to grow; as, to raise corn, barley, hops,
          etc.; toraise cattle. ``He raised sheep.'' ``He raised
          wheat where none grew before.'' --Johnson's Dict.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: In some parts of the United States, notably in the
         Southern States, raise is also commonly applied to the
         rearing or bringing up of children.
         [1913 Webster]

               I was raised, as they say in Virginia, among the
               mountains of the North.            --Paulding.
         [1913 Webster]
      (d) To bring into being; to produce; to cause to arise,
          come forth, or appear; -- often with up.
          [1913 Webster]

                I will raise them up a prophet from among their
                brethren, like unto thee.         --Deut. xviii.
                                                  18.
          [1913 Webster]

                God vouchsafes to raise another world
                From him [Noah], and all his anger to forget.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To give rise to; to set agoing; to occasion; to start;
          to originate; as, to raise a smile or a blush.
          [1913 Webster]

                Thou shalt not raise a false report. --Ex.
                                                  xxiii. 1.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) To give vent or utterance to; to utter; to strike up.
          [1913 Webster]

                Soon as the prince appears, they raise a cry.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) To bring to notice; to submit for consideration; as,
          to raise a point of order; to raise an objection.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. To cause to rise, as by the effect of leaven; to make
      light and spongy, as bread.
      [1913 Webster]

            Miss Liddy can dance a jig, and raise paste.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.)
      (a) To cause (the land or any other object) to seem higher
          by drawing nearer to it; as, to raise Sandy Hook
          light.
      (b) To let go; as in the command, Raise tacks and sheets,
          i. e., Let go tacks and sheets.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law) To create or constitute; as, to raise a use, that
      is, to create it. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To raise a blockade} (Mil.), to remove or break up a
      blockade, either by withdrawing the ships or forces
      employed in enforcing it, or by driving them away or
      dispersing them.

   {To raise a check}, {note}, {bill of exchange}, etc., to
      increase fraudulently its nominal value by changing the
      writing, figures, or printing in which the sum payable is
      specified.

   {To raise a siege}, to relinquish an attempt to take a place
      by besieging it, or to cause the attempt to be
      relinquished.

   {To raise steam}, to produce steam of a required pressure.

   {To raise the wind}, to procure ready money by some temporary
      expedient. [Colloq.]

   {To raise Cain}, or {To raise the devil}, to cause a great
      disturbance; to make great trouble. [Slang]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To lift; exalt; elevate; erect; originate; cause;
        produce; grow; heighten; aggravate; excite.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>raised</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Raised \Raised\ (r[=a]zd), a.
   1. Lifted up; showing above the surroundings; as, raised or
      embossed metal work.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Leavened; made with leaven, or yeast; -- used of bread,
      cake, etc., as distinguished from that made with cream of
      tartar, soda, etc. See {Raise}, v. t., 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Raised beach}. See under {Beach}, n.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>raised</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>raised
     adj 1: above the surround or above the normal position; "a raised
            design"; "raised eyebrows" [ant: {lowered}]
     2: embellished with a raised pattern created by pressure or
        embroidery; "brocaded silk"; "an embossed satin";
        "embossed leather"; "raised needlework"; "raised
        metalwork" [syn: {brocaded}, {embossed}]
     3: leavened usually with yeast; "raised bread"
     4: increased especially to abnormal levels; "the raised prices
        frightened away customers"; "inflated wages"; "an inflated
        economy" [syn: {raised(a)}, {inflated}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
