<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rat</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rat \Rat\ (r[a^]t), n. [AS. r[ae]t; akin to D. rat, OHG. rato,
   ratta, G. ratte, ratze, OLG. ratta, LG. &amp; Dan. rotte, Sw.
   r[*a]tta, F. rat, Ir. &amp; Gael radan, Armor. raz, of unknown
   origin. Cf. {Raccoon}.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) One of several species of small rodents of the
      genus {Rattus} (formerly included in {Mus}) and allied
      genera, of the family {Muridae}, distinguished from mice
      primarily by being larger. They infest houses, stores, and
      ships, especially the Norway rat, also called {brown rat},
      ({Rattus norvegicus} formerly {Mus decumanus}), the black
      rat ({Rattus rattus} formerly {Mus rattus}), and the roof
      rat (formerly {Mus Alexandrinus}, now included in {Rattus
      rattus}). These were introduced into America from the Old
      World. The white rat used most commonly in laboratories is
      primarily a strain derived from {Rattus rattus}.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. A round and tapering mass of hair, or similar material,
      used by women to support the puffs and rolls of their
      natural hair. [Local, U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who deserts his party or associates; hence, in the
      trades, one who works for lower wages than those
      prescribed by a trades union. [Cant]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: ``It so chanced that, not long after the accession of
         the house of Hanover, some of the brown, that is the
         German or Norway, rats, were first brought over to this
         country (in some timber as is said); and being much
         stronger than the black, or, till then, the common,
         rats, they in many places quite extirpated the latter.
         The word (both the noun and the verb to rat) was first,
         as we have seen, leveled at the converts to the
         government of George the First, but has by degrees
         obtained a wider meaning, and come to be applied to any
         sudden and mercenary change in politics.'' --Lord
         Mahon.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Bamboo rat} (Zo["o]l.), any Indian rodent of the genus
      {Rhizomys}.

   {Beaver rat}, {Coast rat}. (Zo["o]l.) See under {Beaver} and
      {Coast}.

   {Blind rat} (Zo["o]l.), the mole rat.

   {Cotton rat} (Zo["o]l.), a long-haired rat ({Sigmodon
      hispidus}), native of the Southern United States and
      Mexico. It makes its nest of cotton and is often injurious
      to the crop.

   {Ground rat}. See {Ground Pig}, under {Ground}.

   {Hedgehog rat}. See under {Hedgehog}.

   {Kangaroo rat} (Zo["o]l.), the potoroo.

   {Norway rat} (Zo["o]l.), the common brown rat. See {Rat}.

   {Pouched rat}. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) See {Pocket Gopher}, under {Pocket}.
      (b) Any African rodent of the genus {Cricetomys}.

   {Rat Indians} (Ethnol.), a tribe of Indians dwelling near
      Fort Ukon, Alaska. They belong to the Athabascan stock.

   {Rat mole}. (Zo["o]l.) See {Mole rat}, under {Mole}.

   {Rat pit}, an inclosed space into which rats are put to be
      killed by a dog for sport.

   {Rat snake} (Zo["o]l.), a large colubrine snake ({Ptyas
      mucosus}) very common in India and Ceylon. It enters
      dwellings, and destroys rats, chickens, etc.

   {Spiny rat} (Zo["o]l.), any South American rodent of the
      genus {Echinomys}.

   {To smell a rat}. See under {Smell}.

   {Wood rat} (Zo["o]l.), any American rat of the genus
      {Neotoma}, especially {Neotoma Floridana}, common in the
      Southern United States. Its feet and belly are white.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rat \Rat\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Ratted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Ratting}.]
   1. In English politics, to desert one's party from interested
      motives; to forsake one's associates for one's own
      advantage; in the trades, to work for less wages, or on
      other conditions, than those established by a trades
      union.
      [1913 Webster]

            Coleridge . . . incurred the reproach of having
            ratted, solely by his inability to follow the
            friends of his early days.            --De Quincey.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To catch or kill rats.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be an informer (against an associate); to inform (on an
      associate); to squeal; -- used commonly in the phrase to
      rat on.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rat
     n 1: any of various long-tailed rodents similar to but larger
          than a mouse
     2: someone who works (or provides workers) during a strike
        [syn: {scab}, {strikebreaker}, {blackleg}]
     3: a person who is deemed to be despicable or contemptible;
        "only a rotter would do that"; "kill the rat"; "throw the
        bum out"; "you cowardly little pukes!"; "the British call
        a contemptible person a `git'" [syn: {rotter}, {dirty dog},
         {skunk}, {stinker}, {stinkpot}, {bum}, {puke}, {crumb}, {lowlife},
         {scum bag}, {so-and-so}, {git}]
     4: one who reveals confidential information in return for money
        [syn: {informer}, {betrayer}, {squealer}, {blabber}]
     5: a pad (usually made of hair) worn as part of a woman's
        coiffure
     v 1: desert one's party or group of friends, for example, for
          one's personal advantage
     2: employ scabs or strike breakers in
     3: take the place of work of someone on strike [syn: {scab}, {blackleg}]
     4: give (hair) the appearance of being fuller by using a rat
     5: catch rats, especially with dogs
     6: give away information about somebody; "He told on his
        classmate who had cheated on the exam" [syn: {denounce}, {tell
        on}, {betray}, {give away}, {grass}, {shit}, {shop}, {snitch},
         {stag}]
     [also: {ratting}, {ratted}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
