<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rate</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rate \Rate\ (r[=a]t), v. t. &amp; i. [Perh. fr. E. rate, v. t., to
   value at a certain rate, to estimate, but more prob. fr. Sw.
   rata to find fault, to blame, to despise, to hold cheap; cf.
   Icel. hrat refuse, hrati rubbish.]
   To chide with vehemence; to scold; to censure violently; to
   berate. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster +PJC]

         Go, rate thy minions, proud, insulting boy! --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         Conscience is a check to beginners in sin, reclaiming
         them from it, and rating them for it.    --Barrow.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rate \Rate\, n. [OF., fr. L. rata (sc. pars), fr. ratus
   reckoned, fixed by calculation, p. p. of reri to reckon, to
   calculate. Cf. {Reason}.]
   1. Established portion or measure; fixed allowance.
      [1913 Webster]

            The one right feeble through the evil rate
            Of food which in her duress she had found.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is established as a measure or criterion;
      degree; standard; rank; proportion; ratio; as, a slow rate
      of movement; rate of interest is the ratio of the interest
      to the principal, per annum.
      [1913 Webster]

            Heretofore the rate and standard of wit was
            different from what it is nowadays.   --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            In this did his holiness and godliness appear above
            the rate and pitch of other men's, in that he was so
            . . . merciful.                       --Calamy.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many of the horse could not march at that rate, nor
            come up soon enough.                  --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Valuation; price fixed with relation to a standard; cost;
      charge; as, high or low rates of transportation.
      [1913 Webster]

            They come at dear rates from Japan.   --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A tax or sum assessed by authority on property for public
      use, according to its income or value; esp., in England, a
      local tax; as, parish rates; town rates.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Order; arrangement. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus sat they all around in seemly rate. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Ratification; approval. [R.] --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Horol.) The gain or loss of a timepiece in a unit of
      time; as, daily rate; hourly rate; etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Naut.)
      (a) The order or class to which a war vessel belongs,
          determined according to its size, armament, etc.; as,
          first rate, second rate, etc.
      (b) The class of a merchant vessel for marine insurance,
          determined by its relative safety as a risk, as A1,
          A2, etc.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rate \Rate\, v. i.
   1. To be set or considered in a class; to have rank; as, the
      ship rates as a ship of the line.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make an estimate.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rate \Rate\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rated}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Rating}.]
   1. To set a certain estimate on; to value at a certain price
      or degree.
      [1913 Webster]

            To rate a man by the nature of his companions is a
            rule frequent indeed, but not infallible. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            You seem not high enough your joys to rate.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To assess for the payment of a rate or tax.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To settle the relative scale, rank, position, amount,
      value, or quality of; as, to rate a ship; to rate a
      seaman; to rate a pension.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To ratify. [Obs.] ``To rate the truce.'' --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To rate a chronometer}, to ascertain the exact rate of its
      gain or loss as compared with true time, so as to make an
      allowance or computation dependent thereon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To value; appraise; estimate; reckon.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rate</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rate
     n 1: amount of a charge or payment relative to some basis; "a
          10-minute phone call at that rate would cost $5" [syn: {charge
          per unit}]
     2: a magnitude or frequency relative to a time unit; "they
        traveled at a rate of 55 miles per hour"; "the rate of
        change was faster than expected"
     3: the relative speed of progress or change; "he lived at a
        fast pace"; "he works at a great rate"; "the pace of
        events accelerated" [syn: {pace}]
     v 1: assign a rank or rating to; "how would you rank these
          students?"; "The restaurant is rated highly in the food
          guide" [syn: {rank}, {range}, {order}, {grade}, {place}]
     2: be worthy of or have a certain rating; "This bond rates
        highly"
     3: estimate the value of; "How would you rate his chances to
        become President?"; "Gold was rated highly among the
        Romans" [syn: {value}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
