<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ray</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ray, MN
  Zip code(s): 56669
Ray, ND (city, FIPS 65580)
  Location: 48.34131 N, 103.16267 W
  Population (1990): 603 (316 housing units)
  Area: 2.5 sq km (land), 0.1 sq km (water)
Ray, OH
  Zip code(s): 45672
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ray \Ray\ (r[=a]), v. t. [An aphetic form of array; cf.
   {Beray}.]
   1. To array. [Obs.] --Sir T. More.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mark, stain, or soil; to streak; to defile. [Obs.]
      ``The filth that did it ray.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ray \Ray\, n.
   Array; order; arrangement; dress. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         And spoiling all her gears and goodly ray. --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ray \Ray\, n. [OF. rai, F. rais, fr. L. radius a beam or ray,
   staff, rod, spoke of a wheel. Cf. {Radius}.]
   1. One of a number of lines or parts diverging from a common
      point or center, like the radii of a circle; as, a star of
      six rays.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) A radiating part of a flower or plant; the marginal
      florets of a compound flower, as an aster or a sunflower;
      one of the pedicels of an umbel or other circular flower
      cluster; radius. See {Radius}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) One of the radiating spines, or cartilages, supporting
          the fins of fishes.
      (b) One of the spheromeres of a radiate, especially one of
          the arms of a starfish or an ophiuran.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Physics)
      (a) A line of light or heat proceeding from a radiant or
          reflecting point; a single element of light or heat
          propagated continuously; as, a solar ray; a polarized
          ray.
      (b) One of the component elements of the total radiation
          from a body; any definite or limited portion of the
          spectrum; as, the red ray; the violet ray. See Illust.
          under {Light}.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. Sight; perception; vision; -- from an old theory of
      vision, that sight was something which proceeded from the
      eye to the object seen.
      [1913 Webster]

            All eyes direct their rays
            On him, and crowds turn coxcombs as they gaze.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Geom.) One of a system of diverging lines passing through
      a point, and regarded as extending indefinitely in both
      directions. See {Half-ray}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bundle of rays}. (Geom.) See {Pencil of rays}, below.

   {Extraordinary ray} (Opt.), that one of two parts of a ray
      divided by double refraction which does not follow the
      ordinary law of refraction.

   {Ordinary ray} (Opt.) that one of the two parts of a ray
      divided by double refraction which follows the usual or
      ordinary law of refraction.

   {Pencil of rays} (Geom.), a definite system of rays.

   {Ray flower}, or {Ray floret} (Bot.), one of the marginal
      flowers of the capitulum in such composite plants as the
      aster, goldenrod, daisy, and sunflower. They have an
      elongated, strap-shaped corolla, while the corollas of the
      disk flowers are tubular and five-lobed.

   {Ray point} (Geom.), the common point of a pencil of rays.

   {R["o]ntgen ray} (r[~e]nt"g[e^]n r[=a]`) (Phys.), a kind of
      ray generated in a very highly exhausted vacuum tube by
      the electrical discharge; now more commonly called
      {X-ray}. It is composed of electromagnetic radiation of
      wavelength shorter than that of ultraviolet light, and is
      capable of passing through many bodies opaque to light,
      and producing photographic and fluorescent effects by
      which means pictures showing the internal structure of
      opaque objects are made, called radiographs, sciagraphs,
      X-ray photographs, radiograms, or X-rays. So called from
      the discoverer, W. C. R["o]ntgen.

   {X ray}, the R["o]ntgen ray; -- so called by its discoverer
      because of its enigmatical character, x being an algebraic
      symbol for an unknown quantity.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ray \Ray\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rayed} (r[=a]d); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Raying}.] [Cf. OF. raier, raiier, rayer, L. radiare to
   irradiate. See {Ray}, n., and cf. {Radiate}.]
   1. To mark with long lines; to streak. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [From {Ray}, n.] To send forth or shoot out; to cause to
      shine out; as, to ray smiles. [R.] --Thomson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ray \Ray\, v. i.
   To shine, as with rays. --Mrs. Browning.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ray \Ray\, n. [F. raie, L. raia. Cf. {Roach}.] (Zo["o]l.)
   (a) Any one of numerous elasmobranch fishes of the order
       Rai[ae], including the skates, torpedoes, sawfishes, etc.
   (b) In a restricted sense, any of the broad, flat,
       narrow-tailed species, as the skates and sting rays. See
       {Skate}.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Bishop ray}, a yellow-spotted, long-tailed eagle ray
      ({Stoasodon n[`a]rinari}) of the Southern United States
      and the West Indies.

   {Butterfly ray}, a short-tailed American sting ray
      ({Pteroplatea Maclura}), having very broad pectoral fins.
      

   {Devil ray}. See {Sea Devil}.

   {Eagle ray}, any large ray of the family {Myliobatid[ae]}, or
      {[AE]tobatid[ae]}. The common European species
      ({Myliobatis aquila}) is called also {whip ray}, and
      {miller}.

   {Electric ray}, or {Cramp ray}, a torpedo.

   {Starry ray}, a common European skate ({Raia radiata}).

   {Sting ray}, any one of numerous species of rays of the
      family {Trygonid[ae]} having one or more large, sharp,
      barbed dorsal spines on the whiplike tail. Called also
      {stingaree}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ray</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ray
     n 1: a column of light (as from a beacon) [syn: {beam}, {beam of
          light}, {light beam}, {ray of light}, {shaft}, {shaft of
          light}, {irradiation}]
     2: a branch of an umbel or an umbelliform inflorescence
     3: (mathematics) a straight line extending from a point
     4: a group of nearly parallel lines of electromagnetic
        radiation [syn: {beam}, {electron beam}]
     5: the syllable naming the second (supertonic) note of any
        major scale in solmization [syn: {re}]
     6: any of the stiff bony rods in the fin of a fish
     7: cartilaginous fishes having horizontally flattened bodies
        and enlarged winglike pectoral fins with gills on the
        underside; most swim by moving the pectoral fins
     v 1: emit as rays; "That tower rays a laser beam for miles across
          the sky"
     2: extend or spread outward from a center or focus or inward
        towards a center; "spokes radiate from the hub of the
        wheel"; "This plants radiates spines in all directions"
        [syn: {radiate}]
     3: expose to radiation; "irradiate food" [syn: {irradiate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
