<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reaching</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reaching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reach \Reach\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Reached} (r[=e]cht)
   ({Raught}, the old preterit, is obsolete); p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Reaching}.] [OE. rechen, AS. r[=ae]can, r[=ae]cean, to
   extend, stretch out; akin to D. reiken, G. reichen, and
   possibly to AS. r[=i]ce powerful, rich, E. rich. [root]115.]
   1. To extend; to stretch; to thrust out; to put forth, as a
      limb, a member, something held, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her tresses yellow, and long straughten,
            Unto her heeles down they raughten.   --Rom. of R.
      [1913 Webster]

            Reach hither thy hand and thrust it into my side.
                                                  --John xx. 27.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fruit trees, over woody, reached too far
            Their pampered boughs.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to deliver by stretching out a member, especially
      the hand; to give with the hand; to pass to another; to
      hand over; as, to reach one a book.
      [1913 Webster]

            He reached me a full cup.             --2 Esd. xiv.
                                                  39.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To attain or obtain by stretching forth the hand; to
      extend some part of the body, or something held by one, so
      as to touch, strike, grasp, or the like; as, to reach an
      object with the hand, or with a spear.
      [1913 Webster]

            O patron power, . . . thy present aid afford,
            Than I may reach the beast.           --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To strike, hit, or touch with a missile; as, to reach an
      object with an arrow, a bullet, or a shell.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, to extend an action, effort, or influence to; to
      penetrate to; to pierce, or cut, as far as.
      [1913 Webster]

            If these examples of grown men reach not the case of
            children, let them examine.           --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To extend to; to stretch out as far as; to touch by virtue
      of extent; as, his land reaches the river.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy desire . . . leads to no excess
            That reaches blame.                   --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To arrive at; to come to; to get as far as.
      [1913 Webster]

            Before this letter reaches your hands. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To arrive at by effort of any kind; to attain to; to gain;
      to be advanced to.
      [1913 Webster]

            The best account of the appearances of nature which
            human penetration can reach, comes short of its
            reality.                              --Cheyne.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To understand; to comprehend. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Do what, sir? I reach you not.        --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To overreach; to deceive. [Obs.] --South.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reaching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reaching
     n 1: the act of physically reaching or thrusting out [syn: {reach},
           {stretch}]
     2: accomplishment of an objective [syn: {arrival}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
