<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reaction</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reaction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reaction \Re*ac"tion\ (r[-e]*[a^]k"sh[u^]n), n. [Cf. F.
   r['e]action.]
   1. Any action in resisting other action or force; counter
      tendency; movement in a contrary direction; reverse
      action.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Chem.) The mutual or reciprocal action of chemical agents
      upon each other, or the action upon such chemical agents
      of some form of energy, as heat, light, or electricity,
      resulting in a chemical change in one or more of these
      agents, with the production of new compounds or the
      manifestation of distinctive characters. See {Blowpipe
      reaction}, {Flame reaction}, under {Blowpipe}, and
      {Flame}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Med.) An action induced by vital resistance to some other
      action; depression or exhaustion of vital force consequent
      on overexertion or overstimulation; heightened activity
      and overaction succeeding depression or shock.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mech.) The force which a body subjected to the action of
      a force from another body exerts upon the latter body in
      the opposite direction.
      [1913 Webster]

            Reaction is always equal and opposite to action,
            that is to say, the actions of two bodies upon each
            other are always equal and in opposite directions.
                                                  --Sir I.
                                                  Newton (3d Law
                                                  of Motion).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Politics) Backward tendency or movement after revolution,
      reform, or great progress in any direction.
      [1913 Webster]

            The new king had, at the very moment at which his
            fame and fortune reached the highest point,
            predicted the coming reaction.        --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Psycophysics) A regular or characteristic response to a
      stimulation of the nerves.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. An action by a person or people in response to an event.
      The reaction may be primarily mental (`` a reaction of
      surprise'') but is usually manifested by some activity.
      [PJC]

   {Reaction time} (Physiol.), in nerve physiology, the interval
      between the application of a stimulus to an end organ of
      sense and the reaction or resulting movement; -- called
      also {physiological time}.

   {Reaction wheel} (Mech.), a water wheel driven by the
      reaction of water, usually one in which the water,
      entering it centrally, escapes at its periphery in a
      direction opposed to that of its motion by orifices at
      right angles, or inclined, to its radii.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reaction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reaction
     n 1: a response that reveals a person's feelings or attitude; "he
          was pleased by the audience's reaction to his
          performance"; "John feared his mother's reaction when
          she saw the broken lamp"
     2: a bodily process occurring due to the effect of some
        foregoing stimulus or agent; "a bad reaction to the
        medicine"; "his responses have slowed with age" [syn: {response}]
     3: (chemistry) a process in which one or more substances are
        changed into others; "there was a chemical reaction of the
        lime with the ground water" [syn: {chemical reaction}]
     4: an idea evoked by some experience; "his reaction to the news
        was to start planning what to do"
     5: doing something in opposition to another way of doing it
        that you don't like; "his style of painting was a reaction
        against cubism"
     6: extreme conservatism in political or social matters; "the
        forces of reaction carried the election"
     7: (mechanics) the equal and opposite force that is produced
        when any force is applied to a body; "every action has an
        equal and opposite reaction"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
