<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reason</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reason</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>REASON, v.i.  To weight probabilities in the scales of desire.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reason</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>REASON, n.  Propensitate of prejudice.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reason</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reason \Rea"son\ (r[=e]"z'n), n. [OE. resoun, F. raison, fr. L.
   ratio (akin to Goth. ra[thorn]j[=o] number, account,
   gara[thorn]jan to count, G. rede speech, reden to speak), fr.
   reri, ratus, to reckon, believe, think. Cf. {Arraign},
   {Rate}, {Ratio}, {Ration}.]
   1. A thought or a consideration offered in support of a
      determination or an opinion; a just ground for a
      conclusion or an action; that which is offered or accepted
      as an explanation; the efficient cause of an occurrence or
      a phenomenon; a motive for an action or a determination;
      proof, more or less decisive, for an opinion or a
      conclusion; principle; efficient cause; final cause;
      ground of argument.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll give him reasons for it.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The reason of the motion of the balance in a wheel
            watch is by the motion of the next wheel. --Sir M.
                                                  Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

            This reason did the ancient fathers render, why the
            church was called ``catholic.''       --Bp. Pearson.
      [1913 Webster]

            Virtue and vice are not arbitrary things; but there
            is a natural and eternal reason for that goodness
            and virtue, and against vice and wickedness.
                                                  --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The faculty or capacity of the human mind by which it is
      distinguished from the intelligence of the inferior
      animals; the higher as distinguished from the lower
      cognitive faculties, sense, imagination, and memory, and
      in contrast to the feelings and desires. Reason comprises
      conception, judgment, reasoning, and the intuitional
      faculty. Specifically, it is the intuitional faculty, or
      the faculty of first truths, as distinguished from the
      understanding, which is called the discursive or
      ratiocinative faculty.
      [1913 Webster]

            We have no other faculties of perceiving or knowing
            anything divine or human, but by our five senses and
            our reason.                           --P. Browne.
      [1913 Webster]

            In common and popular discourse, reason denotes that
            power by which we distinguish truth from falsehood,
            and right from wrong, and by which we are enabled to
            combine means for the attainment of particular ends.
                                                  --Stewart.
      [1913 Webster]

            Reason is used sometimes to express the whole of
            those powers which elevate man above the brutes, and
            constitute his rational nature, more especially,
            perhaps, his intellectual powers; sometimes to
            express the power of deduction or argumentation.
                                                  --Stewart.
      [1913 Webster]

            By the pure reason I mean the power by which we
            become possessed of principles.       --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

            The sense perceives; the understanding, in its own
            peculiar operation, conceives; the reason, or
            rationalized understanding, comprehends.
                                                  --Coleridge.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Due exercise of the reasoning faculty; accordance with, or
      that which is accordant with and ratified by, the mind
      rightly exercised; right intellectual judgment; clear and
      fair deductions from true principles; that which is
      dictated or supported by the common sense of mankind;
      right conduct; right; propriety; justice.
      [1913 Webster]

            I was promised, on a time,
            To have reason for my rhyme.          --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            But law in a free nation hath been ever public
            reason; the enacted reason of a parliament, which he
            denying to enact, denies to govern us by that which
            ought to be our law; interposing his own private
            reason, which to us is no law.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The most probable way of bringing France to reason
            would be by the making an attempt on the Spanish
            West Indies.                          --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Math.) Ratio; proportion. [Obs.] --Barrow.
      [1913 Webster]

   {By reason of}, by means of; on account of; because of.
      ``Spain is thin sown of people, partly by reason of the
      sterility of the soil.'' --Bacon.

   {In reason},

   {In all reason}, in justice; with rational ground; in a right
      view.
      [1913 Webster]

            When anything is proved by as good arguments as a
            thing of that kind is capable of, we ought not, in
            reason, to doubt of its existence.    --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {It is reason}, it is reasonable; it is right. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Yet it were great reason, that those that have
            children should have greatest care of future times.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Motive; argument; ground; consideration; principle;
        sake; account; object; purpose; design. See {Motive},
        {Sense}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reason</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reason \Rea"son\, v. t.
   1. To arrange and present the reasons for or against; to
      examine or discuss by arguments; to debate or discuss; as,
      I reasoned the matter with my friend.
      [1913 Webster]

            When they are clearly discovered, well digested, and
            well reasoned in every part, there is beauty in such
            a theory.                             --T. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To support with reasons, as a request. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To persuade by reasoning or argument; as, to reason one
      into a belief; to reason one out of his plan.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men that will not be reasoned into their senses.
                                                  --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To overcome or conquer by adducing reasons; -- with down;
      as, to reason down a passion.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To find by logical processes; to explain or justify by
      reason or argument; -- usually with out; as, to reason out
      the causes of the librations of the moon.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reason</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reason \Rea"son\ (r[=e]"z'n), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Reasoned}
   (r[=e]"z'nd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Reasoning}.] [Cf. F.
   raisonner. See {Reason}, n.]
   1. To exercise the rational faculty; to deduce inferences
      from premises; to perform the process of deduction or of
      induction; to ratiocinate; to reach conclusions by a
      systematic comparison of facts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: To carry on a process of deduction or of induction,
      in order to convince or to confute; to formulate and set
      forth propositions and the inferences from them; to argue.
      [1913 Webster]

            Stand still, that I may reason with you, before the
            Lord, of all the righteous acts of the Lord. --1
                                                  Sam. xii. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To converse; to compare opinions. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reason</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reason
     n 1: a rational motive for a belief or action; "the reason that
          war was declared"; "the grounds for their declaration"
          [syn: {ground}]
     2: an explanation of the cause of some phenomenon; "the reason
        a steady state was never reached was that the back
        pressure built up too slowly"
     3: the capacity for rational thought or inference or
        discrimination; "we are told that man is endowed with
        reason and capable of distinguishing good from evil" [syn:
         {understanding}, {intellect}]
     4: the state of having good sense and sound judgment; "his
        rationality may have been impaired"; "he had to rely less
        on reason than on rousing their emotions" [syn: {rationality},
         {reasonableness}]
     5: a justification for something existing or happening; "he had
        no cause to complain"; "they had good reason to rejoice"
        [syn: {cause}, {grounds}]
     6: a fact that logically justifies some premise or conclusion;
        "there is reason to believe he is lying"
     v 1: decide by reasoning; draw or come to a conclusion; "We
          reasoned that it was cheaper to rent than to buy a
          house" [syn: {reason out}, {conclude}]
     2: present reasons and arguments [syn: {argue}]
     3: think logically; "The children must learn to reason"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
