<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>recall</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Recall \Re*call"\ (r[-e]*k[add]l"), v. t.
   1. To call back; to summon to return; as, to recall troops;
      to recall an ambassador.
      [1913 Webster]

            If Henry were recalled to life again. --Shak.

   2. To revoke; to annul by a subsequent act; to take back; to
      withdraw; as, to recall words, or a decree.
      [1913 Webster]

            Passed sentence may not be recall'd.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To call back to mind; to revive in memory; to recollect;
      to remember; as, to recall bygone days.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Recall \Re*call"\, n.
   1. A calling back; a revocation.
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is done, and since 't is done, 't is past recall.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mil.) A call on the trumpet, bugle, or drum, by which
      soldiers are recalled from duty, labor, etc. --Wilhelm.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Political Science)
      (a) The right or procedure by which a public official,
          commonly a legislative or executive official, may be
          removed from office, before the end of his term of
          office, by a vote of the people to be taken on the
          filing of a petition signed by a required number or
          percentage of qualified voters.
      (b) Short for

   {recall of judicial decisions}, the right or procedure by
      which the decision of a court may be directly reversed or
      annulled by popular vote, as was advocated, in 1912, in
      the platform of the Progressive party for certain cases
      involving the police power of the state.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recall</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>recall
     n 1: a request by the manufacturer of a defective product to
          return the product (as for replacement or repair) [syn:
          {callback}]
     2: a call to return; "the recall of our ambassador"
     3: a bugle call that signals troops to return
     4: the process of remembering (especially the process of
        recovering information by mental effort); "he has total
        recall of the episode" [syn: {recollection}, {reminiscence}]
     5: the act of removing an official by petition
     v 1: recall knowledge from memory; have a recollection; "I can't
          remember saying any such thing"; "I can't think what her
          last name was"; "can you remember her phone number?";
          "Do you remember that he once loved you?"; "call up
          memories" [syn: {remember}, {retrieve}, {call back}, {call
          up}, {recollect}, {think}] [ant: {forget}]
     2: go back to something earlier; "This harks back to a previous
        remark of his" [syn: {hark back}, {return}, {come back}]
     3: call to mind; "His words echoed John F. Kennedy" [syn: {echo}]
     4: summon to return; "The ambassador was recalled to his
        country"; "The company called back many of the workers it
        had laid off during the recession" [syn: {call back}]
     5: cause one's (or someone else's) thoughts or attention to
        return from a reverie or digression; "She was recalled by
        a loud laugh"
     6: make unavailable; bar from sale or distribution; "The
        company recalled the product when it was found to be
        faulty" [ant: {issue}]
     7: cause to be returned; "recall the defective auto tires";
        "The manufacturer tried to call back the spoilt yoghurt"
        [syn: {call in}, {call back}, {withdraw}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
