<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>received</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>received</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Receive \Re*ceive"\ (r[-e]*s[=e]v"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Received} (r[-e]*s[=e]vd"); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Receiving}.]
   [OF. receveir, recevoir, F. recevoir, fr. L. recipere; pref.
   re- re- + capere to take, seize. See {Capable}, {Heave}, and
   cf. {Receipt}, {Reception}, {Recipe}.]
   1. To take, as something that is offered, given, committed,
      sent, paid, or the like; to accept; as, to receive money
      offered in payment of a debt; to receive a gift, a
      message, or a letter.
      [1913 Webster]

            Receyven all in gree that God us sent. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence: To gain the knowledge of; to take into the mind by
      assent to; to give admission to; to accept, as an opinion,
      notion, etc.; to embrace.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our hearts receive your warnings.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The idea of solidity we receive by our touch.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To allow, as a custom, tradition, or the like; to give
      credence or acceptance to.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many other things there be which they have received
            to hold, as the washing of cups, and pots. --Mark
                                                  vii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To give admittance to; to permit to enter, as into one's
      house, presence, company, and the like; as, to receive a
      lodger, visitor, ambassador, messenger, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            They kindled a fire, and received us every one.
                                                  --Acts xxviii.
                                                  2.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To admit; to take in; to hold; to contain; to have
      capacity for; to be able to take in.
      [1913 Webster]

            The brazen altar that was before the Lord was too
            little to receive the burnt offerings. --1 Kings
                                                  viii. 64.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To be affected by something; to suffer; to be subjected
      to; as, to receive pleasure or pain; to receive a wound or
      a blow; to receive damage.
      [1913 Webster]

            Against his will he can receive no harm. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To take from a thief, as goods known to be stolen.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Lawn Tennis) To bat back (the ball) when served.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Receiving ship}, one on board of which newly recruited
      sailors are received, and kept till drafted for service.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To accept; take; allow; hold; retain; admit.

   Usage: {Receive}, {Accept}. To receive describes simply the
          act of taking. To accept denotes the taking with
          approval, or for the purposes for which a thing is
          offered. Thus, we receive a letter when it comes to
          hand; we receive news when it reaches us; we accept a
          present when it is offered; we accept an invitation to
          dine with a friend.
          [1913 Webster]

                Who, if we knew
                What we receive, would either not accept
                Life offered, or soon beg to lay it down.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>received</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>received
     adj 1: conforming to the established language usage of educated
            native speakers; "standard English" (American);
            "received standard English is sometimes called the
            King's English" (British) [syn: {standard}] [ant: {nonstandard}]
     2: widely accepted as true or worthy; "the accepted wisdom
        about old age"; "a received moral idea"; "Received
        political wisdom says not; surveys show otherwise"-
        Economist [syn: {accepted}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
