<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reckoning</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reckoning</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reckon \Reck"on\ (r[e^]k"'n), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Reckoned}
   (r[e^]k"'nd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Reckoning}.] [OE. rekenen, AS.
   gerecenian to explain; akin to D. rekenen to reckon, G.
   rechnen, OHG. rehhan[=o]n (cf. Goth. rahnjan), and to E.
   reck, rake an implement; the original sense probably being,
   to bring together, count together. See {Reck}, v. t.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To count; to enumerate; to number; also, to compute; to
      calculate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The priest shall reckon to him the money according
            to the years that remain.             --Lev. xxvii.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

            I reckoned above two hundred and fifty on the
            outside of the church.                --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To count as in a number, rank, or series; to estimate by
      rank or quality; to place by estimation; to account; to
      esteem; to repute.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was reckoned among the transgressors. --Luke
                                                  xxii. 37.
      [1913 Webster]

            For him I reckon not in high estate.  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To charge, attribute, or adjudge to one, as having a
      certain quality or value.
      [1913 Webster]

            Faith was reckoned to Abraham for righteousness.
                                                  --Rom. iv. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            Without her eccentricities being reckoned to her for
            a crime.                              --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To conclude, as by an enumeration and balancing of
      chances; hence, to think; to suppose; -- followed by an
      objective clause; as, I reckon he won't try that again.
      [Prov. Eng. &amp; Colloq. U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To number; enumerate; compute; calculate; estimate;
        value; esteem; account; repute. See {Calculate},
        {Guess}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reckoning</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reckoning \Reck"on*ing\, n.
   1. The act of one who reckons, counts, or computes; the
      result of reckoning or counting; calculation.
      Specifically:
      (a) An account of time. --Sandys.
      (b) Adjustment of claims and accounts; settlement of
          obligations, liabilities, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

                Even reckoning makes lasting friends, and the
                way to make reckonings even is to make them
                often.                            --South.
          [1913 Webster]

                He quitted London, never to return till the day
                of a terrible and memorable reckoning had
                arrived.                          --Macaulay.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. The charge or account made by a host at an inn.
      [1913 Webster]

            A coin would have a nobler use than to pay a
            reckoning.                            --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Esteem; account; estimation.
      [1913 Webster]

            You make no further reckoning of it [beauty] than of
            an outward fading benefit nature bestowed. --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Navigation)
      (a) The calculation of a ship's position, either from
          astronomical observations, or from the record of the
          courses steered and distances sailed as shown by
          compass and log, -- in the latter case called {dead
          reckoning} (see under {Dead}); -- also used for dead
          reckoning in contradistinction to {observation}.
      (b) The position of a ship as determined by calculation.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To be out of her reckoning}, to be at a distance from the
      place indicated by the reckoning; -- said of a ship.

   {day of reckoning} the day or time when one must pay one's
      debts, fulfill one's obligations, or be punished for one's
      transgressions.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reckoning</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reckoning
     n 1: problem solving that involves numbers or quantities [syn: {calculation},
           {computation}, {figuring}]
     2: a bill for an amount due [syn: {tally}]
     3: the act of counting; "the counting continued for several
        hours" [syn: {count}, {counting}, {numeration}, {enumeration},
         {tally}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
