<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>record</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>record</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>record
     
        &lt;data, database, programming&gt; An {ordered set} of {fields},
        usually stored contiguously.  The term is used with similar
        meaning in several different contexts.  In a file, a "record"
        probably has some fixed length, in contrast to a "line" which
        may have any length and is terminated by some {End Of Line}
        sequence).  A {database} record is also called a "row".  In a
        {spreadsheet} it is always called a "row".  Some programming
        languages use the term to mean a type composed of fields of
        several other types ({C} calls this a "{struct}").
     
        In all these cases, a record represents an entity with certain
        field values.
     
        Fields may be of a fixed width ({bit}s or {characters}) or
        they may be separated by a {delimiter} character, often
        {comma} ({CSV}) or {HT} ({TSV}).
     
        In a database the list of values of a given field from all
        records is called a column.
     
        (2002-03-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>record</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Record \Re*cord"\, v. i.
   1. To reflect; to ponder. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Praying all the way, and recording upon the words
            which he before had read.             --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To sing or repeat a tune. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whether the birds or she recorded best. --W. Browne.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>record</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Record \Re*cord"\ (r?*k?rd"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Recorded}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Recording}.] [OE. recorden to repeat, remind,
   F. recorder, fr. L. recordari to remember; pref. re- re- +
   cor, cordis, the heart or mind. See {Cordial}, {Heart}.]
   1. To recall to mind; to recollect; to remember; to meditate.
      [Obs.] ``I it you record.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To repeat; to recite; to sing or play. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They longed to see the day, to hear the lark
            Record her hymns, and chant her carols blest.
                                                  --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To preserve the memory of, by committing to writing, to
      printing, to inscription, or the like; to make note of; to
      write or enter in a book or on parchment, for the purpose
      of preserving authentic evidence of; to register; to
      enroll; as, to record the proceedings of a court; to
      record historical events.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those things that are recorded of him . . . are
            written in the chronicles of the kings. --1 Esd. i.
                                                  42.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To record a deed}, {mortgage}, {lease}, etc., to have a copy
      of the same entered in the records of the office
      designated by law, for the information of the public.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>record</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Record \Rec"ord\ (r[e^]k"[~e]rd), n. [OF. recort, record,
   remembrance, attestation, record. See {Record}, v. t.]
   1. A writing by which some act or event, or a number of acts
      or events, is recorded; a register; as, a record of the
      acts of the Hebrew kings; a record of the variations of
      temperature during a certain time; a family record.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Especially:
      (a) An official contemporaneous writing by which the acts
          of some public body, or public officer, are recorded;
          as, a record of city ordinances; the records of the
          receiver of taxes.
      (b) An authentic official copy of a document which has
          been entered in a book, or deposited in the keeping of
          some officer designated by law.
      (c) An official contemporaneous memorandum stating the
          proceedings of a court of justice; a judicial record.
      (d) The various legal papers used in a case, together with
          memoranda of the proceedings of the court; as, it is
          not permissible to allege facts not in the record.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Testimony; witness; attestation.
      [1913 Webster]

            John bare record, saying.             --John i. 32.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which serves to perpetuate a knowledge of acts or
      events; a monument; a memorial.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That which has been, or might be, recorded; the known
      facts in the course, progress, or duration of anything, as
      in the life of a public man; as, a politician with a good
      or a bad record.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That which has been publicly achieved in any kind of
      competitive sport as recorded in some authoritative
      manner, as the time made by a winning horse in a race.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Court of record} (pron. r?*k?rd" in Eng.), a court whose
      acts and judicial proceedings are written on parchment or
      in books for a perpetual memorial.

   {Debt of record}, a debt which appears to be due by the
      evidence of a court of record, as upon a judgment or a
      cognizance.

   {Trial by record}, a trial which is had when a matter of
      record is pleaded, and the opposite party pleads that
      there is no such record. In this case the trial is by
      inspection of the record itself, no other evidence being
      admissible. --Blackstone.

   {To beat the record}, or {To break the record} (Sporting), to
      surpass any performance of like kind as authoritatively
      recorded; as, to break the record in a walking match.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>record</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>record
     n 1: anything (such as a document or a phonograph record or a
          photograph) providing permanent evidence of or
          information about past events; "the film provided a
          valuable record of stage techniques"
     2: the number of wins versus losses and ties a team has had;
        "at 9-0 they have the best record in their league"
     3: an extreme attainment; the best (or worst) performance ever
        attested (as in a sport); "he tied the Olympic record";
        "coffee production last year broke all previous records";
        "Chicago set the homicide record"
     4: sound recording consisting of a disc with continuous
        grooves; formerly used to reproduce music by rotating
        while a phonograph needle tracked in the grooves [syn: {phonograph
        record}, {phonograph recording}, {disk}, {disc}, {platter}]
     5: the sum of recognized accomplishments; "the lawyer has a
        good record"; "the track record shows that he will be a
        good president" [syn: {track record}]
     6: a list of crimes for which an accused person has been
        previously convicted; "he ruled that the criminal record
        of the defendant could not be disclosed to the court";
        "the prostitute had a record a mile long" [syn: {criminal
        record}]
     7: a compilation of the known facts regarding something or
        someone; "Al Smith used to say, `Let's look at the
        record'"; "his name is in all the recordbooks" [syn: {record
        book}, {book}]
     8: a document that can serve as legal evidence of a
        transaction; "they could find no record of the purchase"
     v 1: make a record of; set down in permanent form [syn: {enter},
          {put down}]
     2: register electronically; "They recorded her singing" [syn: {tape}]
        [ant: {erase}]
     3: indicate a certain reading; of gauges and instruments; "The
        thermometer showed thirteen degrees below zero"; "The
        gauge read `empty'" [syn: {read}, {register}, {show}]
     4: be aware of; "Did you register any change when I pressed the
        button?" [syn: {register}]
     5: be or provide a memorial to a person or an event; "This
        sculpture commemorates the victims of the concentration
        camps"; "We memorialized the Dead" [syn: {commemorate}, {memorialize},
         {memorialise}, {immortalize}, {immortalise}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
