<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>recording</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recording</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Record \Re*cord"\ (r?*k?rd"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Recorded}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Recording}.] [OE. recorden to repeat, remind,
   F. recorder, fr. L. recordari to remember; pref. re- re- +
   cor, cordis, the heart or mind. See {Cordial}, {Heart}.]
   1. To recall to mind; to recollect; to remember; to meditate.
      [Obs.] ``I it you record.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To repeat; to recite; to sing or play. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            They longed to see the day, to hear the lark
            Record her hymns, and chant her carols blest.
                                                  --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To preserve the memory of, by committing to writing, to
      printing, to inscription, or the like; to make note of; to
      write or enter in a book or on parchment, for the purpose
      of preserving authentic evidence of; to register; to
      enroll; as, to record the proceedings of a court; to
      record historical events.
      [1913 Webster]

            Those things that are recorded of him . . . are
            written in the chronicles of the kings. --1 Esd. i.
                                                  42.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To record a deed}, {mortgage}, {lease}, etc., to have a copy
      of the same entered in the records of the office
      designated by law, for the information of the public.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recording</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Recording \Re*cord"ing\, a.
   Keeping a record or a register; as, a recording secretary; --
   applied to numerous instruments with an automatic appliance
   which makes a record of their action; as, a recording gauge
   or telegraph.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recording</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>recording
     n 1: signal encoding something (e.g., picture or sound) that has
          been recorded
     2: the act of making a record (especially an audio record);
        "she watched the recording from a sound-proof booth" [syn:
         {transcription}]
     3: a storage device on which information (sounds or images)
        have been recorded
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
