<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>recovering</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recovering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Recover \Re*cov"er\ (r?*k?v"?r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Recovered}
   (-?rd); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Recovering}. ] [OE. recoveren, OF.
   recovrer, F. recouvrer, from L. recuperare; pref. re- re + a
   word of unknown origin. Cf.{Recuperate}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To get or obtain again; to get renewed possession of; to
      win back; to regain.
      [1913 Webster]

            David recovered all that the Amalekites had carried
            away.                                 --1. Sam. xxx.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make good by reparation; to make up for; to retrieve;
      to repair the loss or injury of; as, to recover lost time.
      ``Loss of catel may recovered be.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Even good men have many failings and lapses to
            lament and recover.                   --Rogers.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To restore from sickness, faintness, or the like; to bring
      back to life or health; to cure; to heal.
      [1913 Webster]

            The wine in my bottle will recover him. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To overcome; to get the better of, -- as a state of mind
      or body.
      [1913 Webster]

            I do hope to recover my late hurt.    --Cowley.
      [1913 Webster]

            When I had recovered a little my first surprise.
                                                  --De Foe.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To rescue; to deliver.
      [1913 Webster]

            That they may recover themselves out of the snare of
            the devil, who are taken captive by him. --2. Tim.
                                                  ii. 26.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To gain by motion or effort; to obtain; to reach; to come
      to. [Archaic]
      [1913 Webster]

            The forest is not three leagues off;
            If we recover that, we're sure enough. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Except he could recover one of the Cities of Refuge
            he was to die.                        --Hales.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) To gain as a compensation; to obtain in return for
      injury or debt; as, to recover damages in trespass; to
      recover debt and costs in a suit at law; to obtain title
      to by judgement in a court of law; as, to recover lands in
      ejectment or common recovery; to gain by legal process;
      as, to recover judgement against a defendant.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Recover arms} (Mil. Drill), a command whereby the piece is
      brought from the position of ``aim'' to that of ``ready.''
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To regain; repossess; resume; retrieve; recruit; heal;
        cure.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>recovering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>recovering
     adj : returning to health after illness or debility; "convalescent
           children are difficult to keep in bed" [syn: {convalescent}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
