<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>refine</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>refine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>REFINE
     
        1. "Research on Knowledge-Based Software Environments at
        Kestrel Institute", D.R. Smith et al, IEEE Trans Soft Eng,
        SE-11(11) (1985).  E-mail: &lt;maria@kestrel.edu&gt;.
     
        2. Cordell Green et al, Stanford U.  Uses logic to specify and
        evolve programs.  [same as 1?] Reasoning Systems, Inc.
        E-mail: &lt;help@reasoning.com&gt;.
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>refine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Refine \Re*fine"\, v. i.
   1. To become pure; to be cleared of feculent matter.
      [1913 Webster]

            So the pure, limpid stream, when foul with stains,
            Works itself clear, and, as it runs, refines.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To improve in accuracy, delicacy, or excellence.
      [1913 Webster]

            Chaucer refined on Boccace, and mended his stories.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            But let a lord once own the happy lines,
            How the wit brightens! How the style refines!
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To affect nicety or subtilty in thought or language. ``He
      makes another paragraph about our refining in
      controversy.'' --Atterbury.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>refine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Refine \Re*fine"\ (r?*f?n"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Refined}
   (-find"); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Refining}.] [Pref. re- + fine to
   make fine: cf. F. raffiner.]
   1. To reduce to a fine, unmixed, or pure state; to free from
      impurities; to free from dross or alloy; to separate from
      extraneous matter; to purify; to defecate; as, to refine
      gold or silver; to refine iron; to refine wine or sugar.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will bring the third part through the fire, and
            will refine them as silver is refined. --Zech. xiii.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To purify from what is gross, coarse, vulgar, inelegant,
      low, and the like; to make elegant or exellent; to polish;
      as, to refine the manners, the language, the style, the
      taste, the intellect, or the moral feelings.
      [1913 Webster]

            Love refines
            The thoughts, and heart enlarges.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To purify; clarify; polish; ennoble.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>refine</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>refine
     v 1: improve or perfect by pruning or polishing; "refine one's
          style of writing" [syn: {polish}, {fine-tune}, {down}]
     2: make more complex, intricate, or richer; "refine a design or
        pattern" [syn: {complicate}, {rarify}, {elaborate}]
     3: treat or prepare so as to put in a usable condition; "refine
        paper stock"; "refine pig iron"; "refine oil"
     4: reduce to a fine, unmixed, or pure state; separate from
        extraneous matter or cleanse from impurities; "refine
        sugar" [syn: {rectify}]
     5: attenuate or reduce in vigor, strength, or validity by
        polishing or purifying; "many valuable nutrients are
        refined out of the foods in our modern diet"
     6: make more precise or increase the discriminatory powers of;
        "refine a method of analysis"; "refine the constant in the
        equation"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
