<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reflect</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reflect</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reflect \Re*flect"\ v. i.
   1. To throw back light, heat, or the like; to return rays or
      beams.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be sent back; to rebound as from a surface; to revert;
      to return.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whose virtues will, I hope,
            Reflect on Rome, as Titan's rays on earth. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To throw or turn back the thoughts upon anything; to
      contemplate. Specifically: To attend earnestly to what
      passes within the mind; to attend to the facts or
      phenomena of consciousness; to use attention or earnest
      thought; to meditate; especially, to think in relation to
      moral truth or rules.
      [1913 Webster]

            We can not be said to reflect upon any external
            object, except so far as that object has been
            previously perceived, and its image become part and
            parcel of our intellectual furniture. --Sir W.
                                                  Hamilton.
      [1913 Webster]

            All men are concious of the operations of their own
            minds, at all times, while they are awake, but there
            few who reflect upon them, or make them objects of
            thought.                              --Reid.
      [1913 Webster]

            As I much reflected, much I mourned.  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To cast reproach; to cause censure or dishonor.
      [1913 Webster]

            Errors of wives reflect on husbands still. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Neither do I reflect in the least upon the memory of
            his late majesty.                     --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To consider; think; cogitate; mediate; contemplate;
        ponder; muse; ruminate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reflect</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reflect \Re*flect"\ (r?*fl?kt"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p.
   {Reflected}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Reflecting}.] [L. reflectere,
   reflexum; pref. re- re- + flectere to bend or turn. See
   {Flexible}, and cf. {Reflex}, v.]
   1. To bend back; to give a backwa?d turn to; to throw back;
      especially, to cause to return after striking upon any
      surface; as, a mirror reflects rays of light; polished
      metals reflect heat.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let me mind the reader to reflect his eye on our
            quotations.                           --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

            Bodies close together reflect their own color.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give back an image or likeness of; to mirror.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nature is the glass reflecting God,
            As by the sea reflected is the sun.   --Young.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reflect</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reflect
     v 1: manifest or bring back; "This action reflects his true
          beliefs"
     2: to throw or bend back or reflect (from a surface); "A mirror
        in the sun can reflect light into a person's eyes"; "Sound
        is reflected well in this auditorium" [syn: {reverberate}]
     3: reflect deeply on a subject; "I mulled over the events of
        the afternoon"; "philosophers have speculated on the
        question of God for thousands of years"; "The scientist
        must stop to observe and start to excogitate" [syn: {chew
        over}, {think over}, {meditate}, {ponder}, {excogitate}, {contemplate},
         {muse}, {mull}, {mull over}, {ruminate}, {speculate}]
     4: be bright by reflecting or casting light; "Drive
        carefully--the wet road reflects" [syn: {shine}]
     5: give evidence of a certain behavior; "His lack of interest
        in the project reflects badly on him"
     6: give evidence of the quality of; "The mess in his dorm room
        reflects on the student"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
