<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>regard</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>regard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Regard \Re*gard"\ (r?*g?rd"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Regarded}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Regarding}.] [F. regarder; pref. re- re +
   garder to guard, heed, keep. See {Guard}, and cf. {Reward}.]
   1. To keep in view; to behold; to look at; to view; to gaze
      upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your niece regards me with an eye of favor. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to look or front toward; to face. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            It is peninsula which regardeth the mainland.
                                                  --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

            That exceedingly beatiful seat, on the ass?ent of a
            hill, flanked with wood and regarding the river.
                                                  --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To look closely at; to observe attentively; to pay
      attention to; to notice or remark particularly.
      [1913 Webster]

            If much you note him,
            You offened him; . . . feed, and regard him not.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To look upon, as in a certain relation; to hold as an
      popinion; to consider; as, to regard abstinence from wine
      as a duty; to regard another as a friend or enemy.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To consider and treat; to have a certain feeling toward;
      as, to regard one with favor or dislike.
      [1913 Webster]

            His associates seem to have regarded him with
            kindness.                             --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To pay respect to; to treat as something of peculiar
      value, sanctity, or the like; to care for; to esteem.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that regardeth thae day, regardeth it into the
            LOrd.                                 --Rom. xiv. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here's Beaufort, that regards nor God nor king.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To take into consideration; to take account of, as a fact
      or condition. ``Nether regarding that she is my child, nor
      fearing me as if II were her father.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To have relation to, as bearing upon; to respect; to
      relate to; to touch; as, an argument does not regard the
      question; -- often used impersonally; as, I agree with you
      as regards this or that.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To consider; observe; remark; heed; mind; respect;
        esteem; estimate; value. See {Attend}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>regard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Regard \Re*gard"\ (r?*g?rd"), v. i.
   To look attentively; to consider; to notice. [Obs.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>regard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Regard \Re*gard"\, n. [F. regard See {Regard}, v. t.]
   1. A look; aspect directed to another; view; gaze.
      [1913 Webster]

            But her, with stern regard, he thus repelled.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Attention of the mind with a feeling of interest;
      observation; heed; notice.
      [1913 Webster]

            Full many a lady
            I have eyed with best regard.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That view of the mind which springs from perception of
      value, estimable qualities, or anything that excites
      admiration; respect; esteem; reverence; affection; as, to
      have a high regard for a person; -- often in the plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            He has rendered himself worthy of their most
            favorable regards.                    --A. Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

            Save the long-sought regards of woman, nothing is
            sweeter than those marks of childish preference.
                                                  --Hawthorne.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. State of being regarded, whether favorably or otherwise;
      estimation; repute; note; account.
      [1913 Webster]

            A man of meanest regard amongst them, neither having
            wealth or power.                      --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Consideration; thought; reflection; heed.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sad pause and deep regard become the sage. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Matter for consideration; account; condition. [Obs.]
      ``Reason full of good regard.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Respect; relation; reference.
      [1913 Webster]

            Persuade them to pursue and persevere in virtue,
            with regard to themselves; in justice and goodness
            with regard to their neighbors; and piefy toward
            God.                                  --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The phrase in regard of was formerly used as equivalent
         in meaning to on account of, but in modern usage is
         often improperly substituted for in respect to, or in
         regard to. --G. P. Marsh.
         [1913 Webster]

               Change was thought necessary in regard of the
               injury the church did receive by a number of
               things then in use.                --Hooker.
         [1913 Webster]

               In regard of its security, it had a great
               advantage over the bandboxes.      --Dickens.
         [1913 Webster]

   8. Object of sight; scene; view; aspect. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Throw out our eyes for brave Othello,
            Even till we make the main and the a["e]rial blue
            An indistinct regard.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (O.Eng.Law) Supervision; inspection.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At regard of}, in consideration of; in comparison with.
      [Obs.] ``Bodily penance is but short and little at regard
      of the pains of hell.'' --Chaucer.

   {Court of regard}, a forest court formerly held in England
      every third year for the lawing, or expeditation, of dogs,
      to prevent them from running after deer; -- called also
      {survey of dogs}. --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Respect; consideration; notice; observance; heed; care;
        concern; estimation; esteem; attachment; reverence.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>regard</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>regard
     n 1: (usually preceded by `in') a detail or point; "it differs in
          that respect" [syn: {respect}]
     2: paying particular notice (as to children or helpless
        people); "his attentiveness to her wishes"; "he spends
        without heed to the consequences" [syn: {attentiveness}, {heed},
         {paying attention}] [ant: {inattentiveness}]
     3: (usually plural) a polite expression of desire for someone's
        welfare; "give him my kind regards"; "my best wishes"
        [syn: {wish}, {compliments}]
     4: a long fixed look; "he fixed his paternal gaze on me" [syn:
        {gaze}]
     5: the condition of being honored (esteemed or respected or
        well regarded); "it is held in esteem"; "a man who has
        earned high regard" [syn: {esteem}, {respect}] [ant: {disesteem}]
     6: a feeling of friendship and esteem; "she mistook his manly
        regard for love"; "he inspires respect" [syn: {respect}]
     7: an attitude of admiration or esteem; "she lost all respect
        for him" [syn: {respect}, {esteem}] [ant: {disrespect}]
     v 1: deem to be; "She views this quite differently from me"; "I
          consider her to be shallow"; "I don't see the situation
          quite as negatively as you do" [syn: {see}, {consider},
          {reckon}, {view}]
     2: look at attentively [syn: {consider}]
     3: connect closely and often incriminatingly; "This new ruling
        affects your business" [syn: {involve}, {affect}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
