<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>regarded</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>regarded</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Regard \Re*gard"\ (r?*g?rd"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Regarded}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Regarding}.] [F. regarder; pref. re- re +
   garder to guard, heed, keep. See {Guard}, and cf. {Reward}.]
   1. To keep in view; to behold; to look at; to view; to gaze
      upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your niece regards me with an eye of favor. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to look or front toward; to face. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            It is peninsula which regardeth the mainland.
                                                  --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

            That exceedingly beatiful seat, on the ass?ent of a
            hill, flanked with wood and regarding the river.
                                                  --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To look closely at; to observe attentively; to pay
      attention to; to notice or remark particularly.
      [1913 Webster]

            If much you note him,
            You offened him; . . . feed, and regard him not.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To look upon, as in a certain relation; to hold as an
      popinion; to consider; as, to regard abstinence from wine
      as a duty; to regard another as a friend or enemy.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To consider and treat; to have a certain feeling toward;
      as, to regard one with favor or dislike.
      [1913 Webster]

            His associates seem to have regarded him with
            kindness.                             --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To pay respect to; to treat as something of peculiar
      value, sanctity, or the like; to care for; to esteem.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that regardeth thae day, regardeth it into the
            LOrd.                                 --Rom. xiv. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            Here's Beaufort, that regards nor God nor king.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To take into consideration; to take account of, as a fact
      or condition. ``Nether regarding that she is my child, nor
      fearing me as if II were her father.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To have relation to, as bearing upon; to respect; to
      relate to; to touch; as, an argument does not regard the
      question; -- often used impersonally; as, I agree with you
      as regards this or that.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To consider; observe; remark; heed; mind; respect;
        esteem; estimate; value. See {Attend}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
