<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>region</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>region</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Region \Re"gion\ (r?"j?n), n. [F. r['e]gion, from L. regio a
   direction, a boundary line, region, fr. regere to guide,
   direct. See {Regimen}.]
   1. One of the grand districts or quarters into which any
      space or surface, as of the earth or the heavens, is
      conceived of as divided; hence, in general, a portion of
      space or territory of indefinite extent; country;
      province; district; tract.
      [1913 Webster]

            If thence he 'scappe, into whatever world,
            Or unknown region.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Tract, part, or space, lying about and including anything;
      neighborhood; vicinity; sphere. ``Though the fork invade
      the region of my heart.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Philip, tetrarch of .. the region of Trachonitis.
                                                  --Luke iii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The upper air; the sky; the heavens. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Anon the dreadful thunder
            Doth rend the region.                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The inhabitants of a district. --Matt. iii. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Place; rank; station. [Obs. or R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He is of too high a region.           --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>region</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Domain \Do*main"\, n. [F. domaine, OF. demaine, L. dominium,
   property, right of ownership, fr. dominus master, owner. See
   {Dame}, and cf {Demesne}, {Dungeon}.]
   1. Dominion; empire; authority.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The territory over which dominion or authority is exerted;
      the possessions of a sovereign or commonwealth, or the
      like. Also used figuratively. [WordNet sense 2]
      [1913 Webster]

            The domain of authentic history.      --E. Everett.
      [1913 Webster]

            The domain over which the poetic spirit ranges. --J.
                                                  C. Shairp.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Landed property; estate; especially, the land about the
      mansion house of a lord, and in his immediate occupancy;
      demesne. [WordNet sense 2] --Shenstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Law) Ownership of land; an estate or patrimony which one
      has in his own right; absolute proprietorship; paramount
      or sovereign ownership.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) the set of values which the independent variable
      of a function may take. Contrasted to {range}, which is
      the set of values taken by the dependent variable.
      [WordNet sense 3]
      [PJC]

   6. (Math.) a connected set of points, also called a {region}.
      [PJC]

   7. (Physics) a region within a ferromagnetic material,
      composed of a number of atoms whose magnetic poles are
      pointed in the same direction, and which may move together
      in a coordinated manner when disturbed, as by heating. The
      direction of polarity of adjacent domains may be
      different, but may be aligned by a strong external
      magnetic field.
      [PJC]

   8. (Computers) an address within the internet computer
      network, which may be a single computer, a network of
      computers, or one of a number of accounts on a multiuser
      computer. The domain specifies the location (host
      computer) to which communications on the internet are
      directed. Each domain has a corresponding 32-bit number
      usually represented by four numbers separated by periods,
      as 128.32.282.56. Each domain may also have an
      alphabetical name, usually composed of a name plus an
      extension separated by a period, as worldsoul.org; the
      alphabetical name is referred to as a domain name.
      [PJC]

   9. (Immunology) the three-dimensional structure within an
      immunoglobulin which is formed by one of the homology
      regions of a heavy or light chain. --Dict. Sci. Tech.
      [PJC]

   10. the field of knowledge, expertise, or interest of a
       person; as, he had a limited domain of discourse; I can't
       comment on that, it's outside my domain. [WordNet sense
       5]

   Syn: domain, realm, field, area. [PJC]

   11. a particular environment or walk of life. [WordNet sense
       1]

   Syn: sphere, domain, area, orbit, field, arena. [PJC]

   12. people in general; especially a distinctive group of
       people with some shared interest. [WordNet sense 4]

   Syn: world, domain. [PJC]

   {Public domain},

   1. the territory belonging to a State or to the general
      government; public lands. [U.S.]

   2. the situation or status of intellectual property which is
      not protected by copyright, patent or other restriction on
      use. Anything

   {in the public domain} may be used by anyone without
      restriction. The effective term of force of copyrights and
      patents are limited by statute, and after the term
      expires, the writings and inventions thus protected go
      into the public domain and are free for use by all.

   {Right of eminent domain}, that superior dominion of the
      sovereign power over all the property within the state,
      including that previously granted by itself, which
      authorizes it to appropriate any part thereof to a
      necessary public use, reasonable compensation being made.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>region</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>region
     n 1: the extended spatial location of something; "the farming
          regions of France"; "religions in all parts of the
          world"; "regions of outer space" [syn: {part}]
     2: a part of an animal that has a special function or is
        supplied by a given artery or nerve; "in the abdominal
        region" [syn: {area}]
     3: a large indefinite location on the surface of the Earth;
        "penguins inhabit the polar regions"
     4: the approximate amount of something (usually used
        prepositionally as in `in the region of'); "it was going
        to take in the region of two or three months to finish the
        job"; "the price is in the neighborhood of $100" [syn: {neighborhood}]
     5: a knowledge domain that you are interested in or are
        communicating about; "it was a limited domain of
        discourse"; "here we enter the region of opinion"; "the
        realm of the occult" [syn: {domain}, {realm}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
