<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>relative</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>RELATIVE
     
        Early system on IBM 650.  Listed in CACM 2(5):16 (May 1959).
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Relative \Rel"a*tive\ (r?l"?-t?v), a. [F. relatif, L. relativus.
   See {Relate}.]
   1. Having relation or reference; referring; respecting;
      standing in connection; pertaining; as, arguments not
      relative to the subject.
      [1913 Webster]

            I'll have grounds
            More relative than this.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Arising from relation; resulting from connection with, or
      reference to, something else; not absolute.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every thing sustains both an absolute and a relative
            capacity: an absolute, as it is such a thing, endued
            with such a nature; and a relative, as it is a part
            of the universe, and so stands in such a relations
            to the whole.                         --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Gram.) Indicating or expressing relation; refering to an
      antecedent; as, a relative pronoun.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mus.) Characterizing or pertaining to chords and keys,
      which, by reason of the identify of some of their tones,
      admit of a natural transition from one to the other.
      --Moore (Encyc. of Music).
      [1913 Webster]

   {Relative clause} (Gram.), a clause introduced by a relative
      pronoun.

   {Relative term}, a term which implies relation to, as
      guardian to ward, matter to servant, husband to wife. Cf.
      {Correlative}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Relative \Rel"a*tive\, n.
   One who, or that which, relates to, or is considered in its
   relation to, something else; a relative object or term; one
   of two object or term; one of two objects directly connected
   by any relation. Specifically:
   (a) A person connected by blood or affinity; strictly, one
       allied by blood; a relation; a kinsman or kinswoman.
       ``Confining our care . . . to ourselves and relatives.''
       --Bp. Fell.
   (b) (Gram.) A relative pronoun; a word which relates to, or
       represents, another word or phrase, called its
       antecedent; as, the relatives ``who'', ``which'',
       ``that''.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relative</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>relative
     adj 1: not absolute or complete; "a relative stranger" [ant: {absolute}]
     2: properly related in size or degree or other measurable
        characteristics; usually followed by `to'; "punishment
        oughtt to be proportional to the crime"; "earnings
        relative to production" [syn: {proportional}]
     n 1: a person related by blood or marriage; "police are searching
          for relatives of the deceased"; "he has distant
          relations back in New Jersey" [syn: {relation}]
     2: an animal or plant that bears a relationship to another (as
        related by common descent or by membership in the same
        genus) [syn: {congener}, {congenator}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
