<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>relief</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relief</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Relief \Re*lief"\ (r?-l?f"), n. [OE. relef, F. relief, properly,
   a lifting up, a standing out. See {Relieve}, and cf.
   {Basrelief}, {Rilievi}.]
   1. The act of relieving, or the state of being relieved; the
      removal, or partial removal, of any evil, or of anything
      oppressive or burdensome, by which some ease is obtained;
      succor; alleviation; comfort; ease; redress.
      [1913 Webster]

            He sees the dire contagion spread so fast,
            That, where it seizes, all relief is vain. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Release from a post, or from the performance of duty, by
      the intervention of others, by discharge, or by relay; as,
      a relief of a sentry.
      [1913 Webster]

            For this relief much thanks; 'tis bitter cold.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which removes or lessens evil, pain, discomfort,
      uneasiness, etc.; that which gives succor, aid, or
      comfort; also, the person who relieves from performance of
      duty by taking the place of another; a relay.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Feudal Law) A fine or composition which the heir of a
      deceased tenant paid to the lord for the privilege of
      taking up the estate, which, on strict feudal principles,
      had lapsed or fallen to the lord on the death of the
      tenant.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Sculp. &amp; Arch.) The projection of a figure above the
      ground or plane on which it is formed.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Relief is of three kinds, namely, {high relief}
         ({altorilievo}), {low relief}, ({basso-rilievo}), and
         {demirelief} ({mezzo-rilievo}). See these terms in the
         Vocabulary.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. (Paint.) The appearance of projection given by shading,
      shadow, etc., to any figure.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Fort.) The height to which works are raised above the
      bottom of the ditch. --Wilhelm.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Physical Geog.) The elevations and surface undulations of
      a country. --Guyot.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Relief valve}, a valve arranged for relieving pressure of
      steam, gas, or liquid; an escape valve.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Alleviation; mitigation; aid; help; succor; assistance;
        remedy; redress; indemnification.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relief</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>relief
     n 1: the feeling that comes when something burdensome is removed
          or reduced; "as he heard the news he was suddenly
          flooded with relief" [syn: {alleviation}, {assuagement}]
     2: the condition of being comfortable or relieved (especially
        after being relieved of distress); "he enjoyed his relief
        from responsibility"; "getting it off his conscience gave
        him some ease" [syn: {ease}]
     3: (law) redress awarded by a court; "was the relief supposed
        to be protection from future harm or compensation for past
        injury?"
     4: someone who takes the place of another (as when things get
        dangerous or difficult); "the star had a stand-in for
        dangerous scenes"; "we need extra employees for summer
        fill-ins" [syn: {stand-in}, {substitute}, {reliever}, {backup},
         {backup man}, {fill-in}]
     5: assistance in time of difficulty; "the contributions
        provided some relief for the victims" [syn: {succor}, {succour},
         {ministration}]
     6: a pause for relaxation; "people actually accomplish more
        when they take time for short rests" [syn: {respite}, {rest},
         {rest period}]
     7: a change for the better [syn: {easing}, {moderation}]
     8: aid for the aged or indigent or handicapped; "he has been on
        relief for many years"
     9: the act of reducing something unpleasant (as pain or
        annoyance); "he asked the nurse for relief from the
        constant pain" [syn: {easing}, {easement}, {alleviation}]
     10: sculpture consisting of shapes carved on a surface so as to
         stand out from the surrounding background [syn: {relievo},
          {rilievo}, {embossment}, {sculptural relief}]
     11: the act of freeing a city or town that has been besieged;
         "he asked for troops for the relief of Atlanta"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
