<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>relieved</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relieved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Relieve \Re*lieve"\ (r?-l?v"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Relieved}
   (-l?vd"); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Relieving}.] [OE. releven, F.
   relever to raise again, discharge, relieve, fr. L. relevare
   to lift up, raise, make light, relieve; pref. re- re- +
   levare to raise, fr. levis light. See {Levity}, and cf.
   {Relevant}, {Relief}.]
   1. To lift up; to raise again, as one who has fallen; to
      cause to rise. [Obs.] --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to seem to rise; to put in relief; to give
      prominence or conspicuousness to; to set off by contrast.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her tall figure relieved against the blue sky;
            seemed almost of supernatural height. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To raise up something in; to introduce a contrast or
      variety into; to remove the monotony or sameness of.
      [1913 Webster]

            The poet must . . . sometimes relieve the subject
            with a moral reflection.              --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To raise or remove, as anything which depresses, weighs
      down, or crushes; to render less burdensome or afflicting;
      to alleviate; to abate; to mitigate; to lessen; as, to
      relieve pain; to relieve the wants of the poor.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To free, wholly or partly, from any burden, trial, evil,
      distress, or the like; to give ease, comfort, or
      consolation to; to give aid, help, or succor to; to
      support, strengthen, or deliver; as, to relieve a besieged
      town.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now lend assistance and relieve the poor. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To release from a post, station, or duty; to put another
      in place of, or to take the place of, in the bearing of
      any burden, or discharge of any duty.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who hath relieved you?                --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To ease of any imposition, burden, wrong, or oppression,
      by judicial or legislative interposition, as by the
      removal of a grievance, by indemnification for losses, or
      the like; to right.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To alleviate; assuage; succor; assist; aid; help;
        support; substain; ease; mitigate; lighten; diminish;
        remove; free; remedy; redress; indemnify.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>relieved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>relieved
     adj : (of pain or sorrow) made easier to bear [syn: {alleviated},
           {eased}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
