<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>remark</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>remark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Re-mark \Re-mark"\ (r?-m?rk"), v. t. [Pref. re- + mark.]
   To mark again, or a second time; to mark anew.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>remark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Remark \Re*mark"\ (r?-m?rk"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Remarked}
   (-m?rkt"); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Remarking}.] [F. remarquer; pref.
   re- re- + marquer to mark, marque a mark, of German origin,
   akin to E. mark. See {Mark}, v. &amp; n.]
   1. To mark in a notable manner; to distinquish clearly; to
      make noticeable or conspicuous; to piont out. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou art a man remarked to taste a mischief. --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

            His manacles remark him; there he sits. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take notice of, or to observe, mentally; as, to remark
      the manner of a speaker.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To express in words or writing, as observed or noticed; to
      state; to say; -- often with a substantive clause; as, he
      remarked that it was time to go.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To observe; notice; heed; regard; note; say.

   Usage: {Remark}, {Observe}, {Notice}. To observe is to keep
          or hold a thing distinctly before the mind. To remark
          is simply to mark or take note of whatever may come
          up. To notice implies still less continuity of
          attention. When we turn from these mental states to
          the expression of them in language, we find the same
          distinction. An observation is properly the result of
          somewhat prolonged thought; a remark is usually
          suggested by some passing occurence; a notice is in
          most cases something cursory and short. This
          distinction is not always maintained as to remark and
          observe, which are often used interchangeably.
          ``Observing men may form many judgments by the rules
          of similitude and proportion.'' --I. Watts. ''He can
          not distinguish difficult and noble speculations from
          trifling and vulgar remarks.'' --Collier. ''The thing
          to be regarded, in taking notice of a child's
          miscarriage, is what root it springs from.'' --Locke.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>remark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Remarque \Re*marque"\, n. Also Remark \Remark\ (Engraving)
   (a) A small design etched on the margin of a plate and
       supposed to be removed after the earliest proofs have
       been taken; also, any feature distinguishing a particular
       stage of the plate.
   (b) A print or proof so distinguished; -- commonly called a
       {Remarque proof}.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>remark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Remark \Re*mark"\ (r?-m?rk"), v. i.
   To make a remark or remarks; to comment.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>remark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Remark \Re*mark"\, n. [Cf. F. remarque.]
   1. Act of remarking or attentively noticing; notice or
      observation.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cause, though worth the search, may yet elude
            Conjecture and remark, however shrewd. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The expression, in speech or writing, of something
      remarked or noticed; the mention of that which is worthy
      of attention or notice; hence, also, a casual observation,
      comment, or statement; as, a pertinent remark.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Observation; note; comment; annotation.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>remark</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>remark
     n 1: a statement that expresses a personal opinion or belief;
          "from time to time she contributed a personal comment on
          his account" [syn: {comment}]
     2: explicit notice; "it passed without remark"
     v 1: make mention of; "She observed that his presentation took up
          too much time"; "They noted that it was a fine day to go
          sailing" [syn: {note}, {observe}, {mention}]
     2: make or write a comment on; "he commented the paper of his
        colleague" [syn: {comment}, {notice}, {point out}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
