<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rendering</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rendering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rendering
     
        &lt;graphics, text&gt; The conversion of a high-level object-based
        description into a graphical image for display.
     
        For example, {ray-tracing} takes a mathematical model of a
        three-dimensional object or scene and converts it into a
        {bitmap} image.  Another example is the process of converting
        {HTML} into an image for display to the user.
     
        (2001-02-06)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rendering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Render \Ren"der\ (r?n"d?r), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rendered}
   (-d?rd);p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Rendering}.] [F. rendre, LL. rendre,
   fr. L. reddere; pref. red-, re-, re- + dare to give. See
   {Date}time, and cf. {Reddition}, {Rent}.]
   1. To return; to pay back; to restore.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whose smallest minute lost, no riches render may.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To inflict, as a retribution; to requite.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will render vengeance to mine enemies. --Deut.
                                                  xxxii. 41.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give up; to yield; to surrender.
      [1913 Webster]

            I 'll make her render up her page to me. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, to furnish; to contribute.
      [1913 Webster]

            Logic renders its daily service to wisdom and
            virtue.                               --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To furnish; to state; to deliver; as, to render an
      account; to render judgment.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cause to be, or to become; as, to render a person more
      safe or more unsafe; to render a fortress secure.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To translate from one language into another; as, to render
      Latin into English.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To interpret; to set forth, represent, or exhibit; as, an
      actor renders his part poorly; a singer renders a passage
      of music with great effect; a painter renders a scene in a
      felicitous manner.
      [1913 Webster]

            He did render him the most unnatural
            That lived amongst men.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To try out or extract (oil, lard, tallow, etc.) from fatty
      animal substances; as, to render tallow.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To plaster, as a wall of masonry, without the use of
       lath.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rendering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rendering \Ren"der*ing\, n.
   The act of one who renders, or that which is rendered.
   Specifically:
   (a) A version; translation; as, the rendering of the Hebrew
       text. --Lowth.
   (b) In art, the presentation, expression, or interpretation
       of an idea, theme, or part.
   (c) The act of laying the first coat of plaster on brickwork
       or stonework.
   (d) The coat of plaster thus laid on. --Gwilt.
   (e) The process of trying out or extracting lard, tallow,
       etc., from animal fat.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rendering</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rendering
     n 1: a performance of a musical composition or a dramatic role
          etc.; "they heard a live rendition of three pieces by
          Schubert" [syn: {rendition}]
     2: an explanation of something that is not immediately obvious;
        "the edict was subject to many interpretations"; "he
        annoyed us with his interpreting of parables"; "often
        imitations are extended to provide a more accurate
        rendition of the child's intended meaning" [syn: {interpretation},
         {interpreting}, {rendition}]
     3: the act of interpreting something as expressed in an
        artistic performance; "her rendition of Milton's verse was
        extraordinarily moving" [syn: {rendition}, {interpretation}]
     4: a written communication in a second language having the same
        meaning as the written communication in a first language
        [syn: {translation}, {interlingual rendition}, {version}]
     5: a coat of stucco applied to a masonry wall
     6: perspective drawing of an architect's design
     7: giving in acknowledgment of obligation
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
