<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>repeating</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>repeating</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Repeat \Re*peat"\ (-p?t"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Repeated}; p.
   pr. &amp; vb. n. {Repeating}.] [F. r['e]p['e]ter, L. repetere;
   pref. re- re- + petere to fall upon, attack. See {Petition}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To go over again; to attempt, do, make, or utter again; to
      iterate; to recite; as, to repeat an effort, an order, or
      a poem. ``I will repeat our former communication.''
      --Robynson (More's Utopia).
      [1913 Webster]

            Not well conceived of God; who, though his power
            Creation could repeat, yet would be loth
            Us to abolish.                        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make trial of again; to undergo or encounter again.
      [Obs.] --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Scots Law) To repay or refund (an excess received).
      [1913 Webster]

   {To repeat one's self}, to do or say what one has already
      done or said.

   {To repeat signals}, to make the same signals again;
      specifically, to communicate, by repeating them, the
      signals shown at headquarters.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To reiterate; iterate; renew; recite; relate; rehearse;
        recapitulate. See {Reiterate}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>repeating</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Repeating \Re*peat"ing\, a.
   Doing the same thing over again; accomplishing a given result
   many times in succession; as, a repeating firearm; a
   repeating watch.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Repeating circle}. See the Note under {Circle}, n., 3.

   {Repeating decimal} (Arith.), a circulating decimal. See
      under {Decimal}.

   {Repeating firearm}, a firearm that may be discharged many
      times in quick succession; especially:
   (a) A form of firearm so constructed that by the action of
       the mechanism the charges are successively introduced
       from a chamber containing them into the breech of the
       barrel, and fired.
   (b) A form in which the charges are held in, and discharged
       from, a revolving chamber at the breech of the barrel.
       See {Revolver}, and {Magazine gun}, under {Magazine}.

   {Repeating instruments} (Astron. &amp; Surv.), instruments for
      observing angles, as a circle, theodolite, etc., so
      constructed that the angle may be measured several times
      in succession, and different, but successive and
      contiguous, portions of the graduated limb, before reading
      off the aggregate result, which aggregate, divided by the
      number of measurements, gives the angle, freed in a
      measure from errors of eccentricity and graduation.

   {Repeating watch}. See {Repeater}
   (a)
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>repeating</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>repeating
     n : the act of doing or performing again [syn: {repetition}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
