<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>representation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>representation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Representation \Rep`re*sen*ta"tion\ (-z?n-t?"sh?n), n. [F.
   repr?sentation, L. representatio.]
   1. The act of representing, in any sense of the verb.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which represents. Specifically:
      (a) A likeness, a picture, or a model; as, a
          representation of the human face, or figure, and the
          like.
      (b) A dramatic performance; as, a theatrical
          representation; a representation of Hamlet.
      (c) A description or statement; as, the representation of
          an historian, of a witness, or an advocate.
      (d) The body of those who act as representatives of a
          community or society; as, the representation of a
          State in Congress.
      (e) (Insurance Law) Any collateral statement of fact, made
          orally or in writing, by which an estimate of the risk
          is affected, or either party is influenced.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. The state of being represented.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Description; show; delineaton; portraiture; likeness;
        resemblance; exhibition; sight.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>representation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Re-presentation \Re-pres`en*ta"tion\ (r?-prez`?n-t?"sh?n), n.
   [See {Re-present}.]
   The act of re-presenting, or the state of being presented
   again; a new presentation; as, re-presentation of facts
   previously stated.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>representation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>representation
     n 1: a presentation to the mind in the form of an idea or image
          [syn: {mental representation}, {internal representation}]
     2: a creation that is a visual or tangible rendering of someone
        or something
     3: the act of representing; standing in for someone or some
        group and speaking with authority in their behalf
     4: the state of serving as an official and authorized delegate
        or agent [syn: {delegacy}, {agency}]
     5: a body of legislators that serve in behalf of some
        constituency; "a Congressional vacancy occurred in the
        representation from California"
     6: a factual statement made by one party in order to induce
        another party to enter into a contract; "the sales
        contract contains several representations by the vendor"
     7: a performance of play [syn: {theatrical performance}, {theatrical},
         {histrionics}]
     8: a statement of facts and reasons made in appealing or
        protesting; "certain representations were made concerning
        police brutality"
     9: the right of being representated by delegates who have a
        voice in some legislative body
     10: an activity that stands as an equivalent of something or
         results in an equivalent
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
