<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reserved</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reserved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reserve \Re*serve"\ (r?-z?rv"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Reserved}.
   (z?rvd");p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Reserving}.] [F. r['e]server, L.
   reservare, reservatum; pref. re- re- + servare to keep. See
   {Serve}.]
   1. To keep back; to retain; not to deliver, make over, or
      disclose. ``I have reserved to myself nothing.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to keep in store for future or special use; to
      withhold from present use for another purpose or time; to
      keep; to retain; to make a reservation[7]. --Gen. xxvii.
      35.

   Note: In cases where one person or party makes a request to
         an agent that some accommodation (such as a hotel room
         or place at a restaurant) be kept (reserved) for their
         use at a particular time, the word reserve applies both
         to the action of the person making the request, and to
         the action of the agent who takes the approproriate
         action (such as a notation in a book of reservations)
         to be certain that the accommodation is available at
         that time.
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

               Hast thou seen the treasures of the hail, which I
               have reserved against the time of trouble? --Job
                                                  xxxviii.
                                                  22,23.
         [1913 Webster]

               Reserve your kind looks and language for private
               hours.                             --Swift.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. To make an exception of; to except. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reserved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reserved \Re*served"\ (-z?rvd"), a.
   1. Kept for future or special use, or for an exigency; as,
      reserved troops; a reserved seat in a theater.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Restrained from freedom in words or actions; backward, or
      cautious, in communicating one's thoughts and feelings;
      not free or frank.
      [1913 Webster]

            To all obliging, yet reserved to all. --Walsh.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing reserved or sullen was to see. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster] -- {Re*serv"ed*ly} (r?-z?rv"?d-l?), adv. --
      {Re*serv"ed*ness}, n.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reserved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reserved
     adj 1: set aside for the use of a particular person or party [ant:
            {unreserved}]
     2: marked by self-restraint and reticence; "was habitually
        reserved in speech, withholding her opinion"-Victoria
        Sackville-West [ant: {unreserved}]
     3: cool and formal in manner [syn: {restrained}, {reticent}, {unemotional}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
