<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reservation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reservation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reservation \Res`er*va"tion\ (r?z`?r-v?"sh?n), n. [Cf. F.
   r['e]servation, LL. reservatio. See {Reserve}.]
   1. The act of reserving, or keeping back; concealment, or
      withholding from disclosure; reserve. --A. Smith.
      [1913 Webster]

            With reservation of an hundred knights. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Make some reservation of your wrongs. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Something withheld, either not expressed or disclosed, or
      not given up or brought forward. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A tract of the public land reserved for some special use,
      as for schools, for the use of Indians, etc. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The state of being reserved, or kept in store. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law)
      (a) A clause in an instrument by which some new thing is
          reserved out of the thing granted, and not in esse
          before.
      (b) A proviso. --Kent.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: This term is often used in the same sense with
         exception, the technical distinction being disregarded.
         [1913 Webster]

   6. (Eccl.)
      (a) The portion of the sacramental elements reserved for
          purposes of devotion and for the communion of the
          absent and sick.
      (b) A term of canon law, which signifies that the pope
          reserves to himself appointment to certain benefices.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. an agreement to have some space, service or other
      acommodation, as at a hotel, a restaurant, or on a public
      transport system, held for one's future use; also, the
      record or receipt for such an agreement, or the
      contractual obligation to retain that accommodation; as, a
      hotel reservation; a reservation on a flight to Dallas; to
      book a reservation at the Ritz.
      [PJC]

   {Mental reservation}, the withholding, or failing to
      disclose, something that affects a statement, promise,
      etc., and which, if disclosed, would materially change its
      import.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reservation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reservation
     n 1: a district that is reserved for particular purpose [syn: {reserve}]
     2: a statement that limits or restricts some claim; "he
        recommended her without any reservations" [syn: {qualification}]
     3: an unstated doubt that prevents you from accepting something
        wholeheartedly [syn: {mental reservation}, {arriere pensee}]
     4: the act of reserving (a place or passage) or engaging the
        services of (a person or group); "wondered who had made
        the booking" [syn: {booking}]
     5: the written record or promise of an arrangement by which
        accommodations are secured in advance
     6: something reserved in advance (as a hotel accommodation or a
        seat on a plane etc.)
     7: the act of keeping back or setting aside for some future
        occasion
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
