<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>resistance</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resistance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Resistance \Re*sist"ance\ (-ans), n. [F. r['e]sistance, LL.
   resistentia, fr. resistens, -entis, p. pr. See {Resist}.]
   1. The act of resisting; opposition, passive or active.
      [1913 Webster]

            When King Demetrius saw that . . . no resistance was
            made against him, he sent away all his forces. --1.
                                                  Macc. xi. 38.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Physics) The quality of not yielding to force or external
      pressure; that power of a body which acts in opposition to
      the impulse or pressure of another, or which prevents the
      effect of another power; as, the resistance of the air to
      a body passing through it; the resistance of a target to
      projectiles.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A means or method of resisting; that which resists.
      [1913 Webster]

            Unfold to us some warlike resistance. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Elec.) A certain hindrance or opposition to the passage
      of an electrical current or discharge offered by
      conducting bodies. It bears an inverse relation to the
      conductivity, -- good conductors having a small
      resistance, while poor conductors or insulators have a
      very high resistance. The unit of resistance is the ohm.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Resistance box} (Elec.), a rheostat consisting of a box or
      case containing a number of resistance coils of standard
      values so arranged that they can be combined in various
      ways to afford more or less resistance.

   {Resistance coil} (Elec.), a coil of wire introduced into an
      electric circuit to increase the resistance.

   {Solid of least resistance} (Mech.), a solid of such a form
      as to experience, in moving in a fluid, less resistance
      than any other solid having the same base, height, and
      volume.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resistance</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>resistance
     n 1: the action of opposing something that you disapprove or
          disagree with; "he encountered a general feeling of
          resistance from many citizens"; "despite opposition from
          the newspapers he went ahead" [syn: {opposition}]
     2: any mechanical force that tends to retard or oppose motion
     3: a material's opposition to the flow of electric current;
        measured in ohms [syn: {electric resistance}, {electrical
        resistance}, {impedance}, {resistivity}, {ohmic resistance}]
     4: the military action of resisting the enemy's advance; "the
        enemy offered little resistance"
     5: (medicine) the condition in which an organism can resist
        disease [syn: {immunity}]
     6: a secret group organized to overthrow a government or
        occupation force [syn: {underground}]
     7: the degree of unresponsiveness of a disease-causing
        microorganism to antibiotics or other drugs (as in
        penicillin-resistant bacteria)
     8: (psychiatry) an unwillingness to bring repressed feelings
        into conscious awareness
     9: an electrical device that resists the flow of electrical
        current [syn: {resistor}]
     10: group action in opposition to those in power
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
