<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>residue</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>residue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Residue \Res"i*due\ (r?z"?-d?), n. [F. r['e]sidu, L. residuum,
   fr. residuus that is left behind, remaining, fr. residere to
   remain behind. See {Reside}, and cf. {Residuum}.]
   1. That which remains after a part is taken, separated,
      removed, or designated; remnant; remainder.
      [1913 Webster]

            The residue of them will I deliver to the sword.
                                                  --Jer. xv. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            If church power had then prevailed over its victims,
            not a residue of English liberty would have been
            saved.                                --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) That part of a testeator's estate wwhich is not
      disposed of in his will by particular and special legacies
      and devises, and which remains after payment of debts and
      legacies.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Chem.) That which remains of a molecule after the removal
      of a portion of its constituents; hence, an atom or group
      regarded as a portion of a molecule; a {moiety} or
      {group}; -- used as nearly equivalent to {radical}, but in
      a more general sense.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   Note: The term radical is sometimes restricted to groups
         containing carbon, the term residue and {moiety} being
         applied to the others.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. (Theory of Numbers) Any positive or negative number that
      differs from a given number by a multiple of a given
      modulus; thus, if 7 is the modulus, and 9 the given
      number, the numbers -5, 2, 16, 23, etc., are residues.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Rest; remainder; remnant; balance; residuum; remains;
        leavings; relics.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>residue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>residue
     n 1: matter that remains after something has been removed
     2: something left after other parts have been taken away;
        "there was no remainder"; "he threw away the rest"; "he
        took what he wanted and I got the balance" [syn: {remainder},
         {balance}, {residual}, {residuum}, {rest}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
