<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>resigned</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resigned</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Resign \Re*sign"\ (r?-z?n"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Resigned}
   (-z?nd"); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Resigning}.] [F. r['e]signer, L.
   resignare to unseal, annul, assign, resign; pref. re- re- +
   signare to seal, stamp. See {Sign}, and cf. {Resignation}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To sign back; to return by a formal act; to yield to
      another; to surrender; -- said especially of office or
      emolument. Hence, to give up; to yield; to submit; -- said
      of the wishes or will, or of something valued; -- also
      often used reflexively.
      [1913 Webster]

            I here resign my government to thee.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Lament not, Eve, but patiently resign
            What justly thou hast lost.           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            What more reasonable, than that we should in all
            things resign up ourselves to the will of God?
                                                  --Tiilotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To relinquish; to abandon.
      [1913 Webster]

            He soon resigned his former suit.     --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To commit to the care of; to consign. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Gentlement of quality have been sent beyong the
            seas, resigned and concredited to the conduct of
            such as they call governors.          --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To abdicate; surrender; submit; leave; relinquish;
        forego; quit; forsake; abandon; renounce.

   Usage: {Resign}, {Relinquish}. To resign is to give up, as if
          breaking a seal and yielding all it had secured;
          hence, it marks a formal and deliberate surrender. To
          relinquish is less formal, but always implies
          abandonment and that the thing given up has been long
          an object of pursuit, and, usually, that it has been
          prized and desired. We resign what we once held or
          considered as our own, as an office, employment, etc.
          We speak of relinquishing a claim, of relinquishing
          some advantage we had sought or enjoyed, of
          relinquishing seme right, privilege, etc. ``Men are
          weary with the toil which they bear, but can not find
          it in their hearts to relinquish it.'' --Steele. See
          {Abdicate}.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resigned</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Resigned \Re*signed"\ (r[-e]*z[imac]nd"), a.
   Submissive; yielding; not disposed to resist or murmur.
   [1913 Webster]

         A firm, yet cautious mind;
         Sincere, though prudent; constant, yet resigned.
                                                  --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resigned</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>resigned
     adj 1: (followed by `to') having come to accept; "resigned to his
            fate" [syn: {resigned(p)}]
     2: showing utter resignation or hopelessness; "abject
        surrender" [syn: {abject}, {unhopeful}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
