<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>resolution</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resolution</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>resolution
     
        1. &lt;hardware&gt; the maximum number of {pixels} that can be
        displayed on a {monitor}, expressed as (number of horizontal
        pixels) x (number of vertical pixels), i.e., 1024x768.  The
        ratio of horizontal to vertical resolution is usually 4:3, the
        same as that of conventional television sets.
     
        2. &lt;logic&gt; A mechanical method for proving statements of
        {first order logic}, introduced by J. A. Robinson in 1965.
        Resolution is applied to two {clauses} in a {sentence}.  It
        eliminates, by {unification}, a {literal} that occurs
        "positive" in one and "negative" in the other to produce a new
        clause, the {resolvent}.
     
        For example, given the sentence:
     
        	(man(X) =&gt; mortal(X))  AND  man(socrates).
     
        The literal "man(X)" is "negative".  The literal
        "man(socrates)" could be considered to be on the right hand
        side of the degenerate implication
     
        	True =&gt; man(socrates)
     
        and is therefore "positive".  The two literals can be unified
        by the binding X = socrates.
     
        The {truth table} for the implication function is
     
        	A | B | A =&gt; B
        	--+---+-------
        	F | F |   T
        	F | T |   T
        	T | F |   F
        	T | T |   T
     
        (The implication only fails if its premise is true but its
        conclusion is false).  From this we can see that
     
        	A =&gt; B   ==   (NOT A) OR B
     
        Which is why the left hand side of the implication is said to
        be negative and the right positive.  The sentence above could
        thus be written
     
        	((NOT man(socrates)) OR mortal(socrates))
        	AND
        	man(socrates)
     
        Distributing the AND over the OR gives
     
        	((NOT man(socrates)) AND man(socrates))
        	OR
        	mortal(socrates) AND man(socrates)
     
        And since (NOT A) AND A == False, and False OR A == A we can
        simplify to just
     
        	mortal(socrates) AND man(socrates)
     
        So we have proved the new literal, mortal(socrates).
     
        Resolution with {backtracking} is the basic control mechanism
        of {Prolog}.
     
        See also {modus ponens}, {SLD Resolution}.
     
        3. &lt;networking&gt; {address resolution}.
     
        (1996-02-09)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resolution</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Resolution \Res`o*lu"tion\ (-l?"sh?n), n. [F. r['e]solution. L.
   resolutio a loosening, solution. See {Resolve}.]
   1. The act, operation, or process of resolving. Specifically:
      (a) The act of separating a compound into its elements or
          component parts.
      (b) The act of analyzing a complex notion, or solving a
          vexed question or difficult problem.
          [1913 Webster]

                The unraveling and resolution of the
                difficulties that are met with in the execution
                of the design are the end of an action.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. The state of being relaxed; relaxation. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The state of being resolved, settled, or determined;
      firmness; steadiness; constancy; determination.
      [1913 Webster]

            Be it with resolution then to fight.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is resolved or determined; a settled purpose;
      determination. Specifically: A formal expression of the
      opinion or will of an official body or a public assembly,
      adopted by vote; as, a legislative resolution; the
      resolutions of a public meeting.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The state of being resolved or firm in opinion or thought;
      conviction; assurance. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Little resolution and certainty there is as touching
            the islands of Mauritania.            --Holland.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Math.) The act or process of solving; solution; as, the
      resolution of an equation or problem.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Med.) A breaking up, disappearance; or termination, as of
      a fever, a tumor, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mus.) The passing of a dissonant into a consonant chord
      by the rising or falling of the note which makes the
      discord.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Technical) The act of distinguishing between two close
      but not identical objects, or, when taking a measurement,
      bbetween two close values of the property measured.
      [PJC]

   10. (Technical) a measure of the ability to distinguish
       between two close but not identical values of the
       property being measured; it is expressed as the
       difference in values of a property necessary to make such
       a distinction; as, a microscope with a resolution of one
       micron; a thermometer with a resolution of one-tenth of a
       degree. Also called {resolving power}.
       [PJC]

   {Joint resolution}. See under {Joint}, a.

   {Resolution of a force} or {Resolution of a motion} (Mech.),
      the separation of a single force or motion into two or
      more which have different directions, and, taken together,
      are an equivalent for the single one; -- the opposite of
      {composition of a force}.

   {Resolution of a nebula} (Astron.), the exhibition of it to
      the eye by a telescope of such power as to show it to be
      composed of small stars.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Decision; analysis; separation; disentanglement;
        dissolution; resolvedness; resoluteness; firmness;
        constancy; perseverance; steadfastness; fortitude;
        boldness; purpose; resolve. See {Decision}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resolution</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>resolution
     n 1: a formal expression by a meeting; agreed to by a vote [syn:
          {declaration}, {resolve}]
     2: the ability of a microscope or telescope to measure the
        angular separation of images that are close together [syn:
         {resolving power}]
     3: the trait of being resolute; firmness of purpose; "his
        resoluteness carried him through the battle"; "it was his
        unshakeable resolution to finish the work" [syn: {resoluteness},
         {firmness}, {resolve}] [ant: {irresoluteness}]
     4: finding a solution to a problem [syn: {solving}]
     5: something settled or resolved; the outcome of decision
        making; "the finally reached a settlement with the union";
        "they never did achieve a final resolution of their
        differences"; "he needed to grieve before he could achieve
        a sense of closure" [syn: {settlement}, {closure}]
     6: analysis into clear-cut components [syn: {resolving}]
     7: (computer science) the number of pixels per square inch on a
        computer-generated display; the greater the resolution,
        the better the picture
     8: the subsidence of swelling or others signs of inflammation
        (especially in a lung)
     9: (music) a dissonant chord is followed by a consonant chord
        [ant: {preparation}]
     10: a statement that solves a problem or explains how to solve
         the problem; "they were trying to find a peaceful
         solution"; "the answers were in the back of the book";
         "he computed the result to four decimal places" [syn: {solution},
          {answer}, {result}, {solvent}]
     11: a decision to do something or to behave in a certain manner;
         "he always wrote down his New Year's resolutions"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
