<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>resolved</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resolved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Resolve \Re*solve"\ (r?*z?lv"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Resolved}
   (-z?lvd"); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Resolving}.] [L. resolvere,
   resolutum, to untie, loosen, relax, enfeeble; pref. re- re- +
   solvere to loosen, dissolve: cf. F. r['e]soudare to resolve.
   See {Solve}, and cf. {Resolve}, v. i., {Resolute},
   {Resolution}.]
   1. To separate the component parts of; to reduce to the
      constituent elements; -- said of compound substances;
      hence, sometimes, to melt, or dissolve.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, that this too too solid flesh would melt,
            Thaw, and resolve itself into a dew!  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye immortal souls, who once were men,
            And now resolved to elements again.   --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To reduce to simple or intelligible notions; -- said of
      complex ideas or obscure questions; to make clear or
      certain; to free from doubt; to disentangle; to unravel;
      to explain; hence, to clear up, or dispel, as doubt; as,
      to resolve a riddle. ``Resolve my doubt.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To the resolving whereof we must first know that the
            Jews were commanded to divorce an unbelieving
            Gentile.                              --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to perceive or understand; to acquaint; to
      inform; to convince; to assure; to make certain.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sir, be resolved. I must and will come. --Beau. &amp;
                                                  Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

            Resolve me, Reason, which of these is worse,
            Want with a full, or with an empty purse? --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            In health, good air, pleasure, riches, I am resolved
            it can not be equaled by any region.  --Sir W.
                                                  Raleigh.
      [1913 Webster]

            We must be resolved how the law can be pure and
            perspicuous, and yet throw a polluted skirt over
            these Eleusinian mysteries.           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To determine or decide in purpose; to make ready in mind;
      to fix; to settle; as, he was resolved by an unexpected
      event.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To express, as an opinion or determination, by resolution
      and vote; to declare or decide by a formal vote; --
      followed by a clause; as, the house resolved (or, it was
      resolved by the house) that no money should be apropriated
      (or, to appropriate no money).
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To change or convert by resolution or formal vote; -- used
      only reflexively; as, the house resolved itself into a
      committee of the whole.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Math.) To solve, as a problem, by enumerating the several
      things to be done, in order to obtain what is required; to
      find the answer to, or the result of. --Hutton.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Med.) To dispere or scatter; to discuss, as an
      inflammation or a tumor.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mus.) To let the tones (as of a discord) follow their
      several tendencies, resulting in a concord.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To relax; to lay at ease. [Obs.] --B. Jonson.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To resolve a nebula}.(Astron.) See {Resolution of a nebula},
      under {Resolution}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To solve; analyze; unravel; disentangle.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resolved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Resolved \Re*solved"\ (r?-z?lvd"), p. p. &amp; a.
   Having a fixed purpose; determined; resolute; -- usually
   placed after its noun; as, a man resolved to be rich.
   [1913 Webster]

         That makes him a resolved enemy.         --Jer. Taylor.
   [1913 Webster]

         I am resolved she shall not settle here. --Fielding.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>resolved</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>resolved
     adj 1: determined; "she was firmly resolved to be a doctor";
            "single-minded in his determination to stop smoking"
            [syn: {single-minded}]
     2: explained or answered; "mysteries solved and unsolved;
        problems resolved and unresolved" [syn: {solved}] [ant: {unsolved}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
