<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>restriction</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>restriction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>restriction
     
        A {bug} or design error that limits a program's capabilities,
        and which is sufficiently egregious that nobody can quite work
        up enough nerve to describe it as a {feature}.  Often used
        (especially by {marketroid} types) to make it sound as though
        some crippling bogosity had been intended by the designers all
        along, or was forced upon them by arcane technical constraints
        of a nature no mere user could possibly comprehend (these
        claims are almost invariably false).
     
        Old-time hacker Joseph M. Newcomer advises that whenever
        choosing a quantifiable but arbitrary restriction, you should
        make it either a power of 2 or a power of 2 minus 1.  If you
        impose a limit of 17 items in a list, everyone will know it is
        a random number - on the other hand, a limit of 15 or 16
        suggests some deep reason (involving 0- or 1-based indexing in
        binary) and you will get less {flamage} for it.  Limits which
        are round numbers in base 10 are always especially suspect.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>restriction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Restriction \Re*stric"tion\, n. [F. restriction, L. restrictio.]
   1. The act of restricting, or state of being restricted;
      confinement within limits or bounds.
      [1913 Webster]

            This is to have the same restriction with all other
            recreations,that it be made a divertisement. --Giv.
                                                  of Tonque.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which restricts; limitation; restraint; as,
      restrictions on trade.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>restriction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>restriction n. A {bug} or design error that limits a program's
   capabilities, and which is sufficiently egregious that nobody can quite
   work up enough nerve to describe it as a {feature}. Often used (esp. by
   {marketroid} types) to make it sound as though some crippling bogosity
   had been intended by the designers all along, or was forced upon them by
   arcane technical constraints of a nature no mere user could possibly
   comprehend (these claims are almost invariably false).

   Old-time hacker Joseph M. Newcomer advises that whenever choosing a
   quantifiable but arbitrary restriction, you should make it either a
   power of 2 or a power of 2 minus 1. If you impose a limit of 107 items
   in a list, everyone will know it is a random number -- on the other
   hand, a limit of 15 or 16 suggests some deep reason (involving 0- or
   1-based indexing in binary) and you will get less {flamage} for it.
   Limits which are round numbers in base 10 are always especially suspect.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>restriction</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>restriction
     n 1: a principle that limits the extent of something; "I am
          willing to accept certain restrictions on my movements"
          [syn: {limitation}]
     2: an act of limiting or restricting (as by regulation) [syn: {limitation}]
     3: the act of keeping something within specified bounds (by
        force if necessary)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
