<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rest</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rest
   (1.) Gr. katapausis, equivalent to the Hebrew word _noah_ (Heb.
   4:1).
   
     (2.) Gr. anapausis, "rest from weariness" (Matt. 11:28).
   
     (3.) Gr. anesis, "relaxation" (2 Thess. 1:7).
   
     (4.) Gr. sabbatismos, a Sabbath rest, a rest from all work
   (Heb. 4:9; R.V., "sabbath"), a rest like that of God when he had
   finished the work of creation.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rest \Rest\ (r[e^]st), v. t. [For arrest.]
   To arrest. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rest \Rest\, n. [AS. rest, r[ae]st, rest; akin to D. rust, G.
   rast. OHG. rasta, Dan. &amp; Sw. rast rest, repose, Icel. r["o]st
   the distance between two resting places, a mole, Goth. rasta
   a mile, also to Goth. razn house, Icel. rann, and perhaps to
   G. ruhe rest, repose, AS. r[=o]w, Gr. 'erwh`. Cf. {Ransack}.]
   1. A state of quiet or repose; a cessation from motion or
      labor; tranquillity; as, rest from mental exertion; rest
      of body or mind. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sleep give thee all his rest!         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, freedom from everything which wearies or disturbs;
      peace; security.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the land had rest fourscore years. --Judges iii.
                                                  30.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Sleep; slumber; hence, poetically, death.
      [1913 Webster]

            How sleep the brave who sink to rest,
            By all their country's wishes blest.  --Collins.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That on which anything rests or leans for support; as, a
      rest in a lathe, for supporting the cutting tool or
      steadying the work.
      [1913 Webster]

            He made narrowed rests round about, that the beams
            should not be fastened in the walls of the house.
                                                  --1 Kings vi.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Anc. Armor) A projection from the right side of the
      cuirass, serving to support the lance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their visors closed, their lances in the rest.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A place where one may rest, either temporarily, as in an
      inn, or permanently, as, in an abode. ``Halfway houses and
      travelers' rests.'' --J. H. Newman.
      [1913 Webster]

            In dust our final rest, and native home. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ye are not as yet come to the rest and to the
            inheritance which the Lord your God giveth you.
                                                  --Deut. xii.
                                                  9.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Pros.) A short pause in reading verse; a c[ae]sura.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. The striking of a balance at regular intervals in a
      running account. ``An account is said to be taken with
      annual or semiannual rests.'' --Abbott.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A set or game at tennis. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mus.) Silence in music or in one of its parts; the name
       of the character that stands for such silence. They are
       named as notes are, whole, half, quarter,etc.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Rest house}, an empty house for the accomodation of
      travelers; a caravansary. [India]

   {To set one's rest} or {To set up one's rest}, to have a
      settled determination; -- from an old game of cards, when
      one so expressed his intention to stand or rest upon his
      hand. [Obs.] --Shak. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Cessation; pause; intermission; stop; stay; repose;
        slumber; quiet; ease; quietness; stillness;
        tranquillity; peacefulness; peace.

   Usage: {Rest}, {Repose}. Rest is a ceasing from labor or
          exertion; repose is a mode of resting which gives
          relief and refreshment after toil and labor. The words
          are commonly interchangeable.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rest \Rest\ (r[e^]st), v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rested}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Resting}.] [AS. restan. See {Rest}, n.]
   1. To cease from action or motion, especially from action
      which has caused weariness; to desist from labor or
      exertion.
      [1913 Webster]

            God . . . rested on the seventh day from all his
            work which he had made.               --Gen. ii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

            Six days thou shalt do thy work, and on the seventh
            day thou shalt rest.                  --Ex. xxiii.
                                                  12.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be free from whanever wearies or disturbs; to be quiet
      or still.
      [1913 Webster]

            There rest, if any rest can harbor there. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To lie; to repose; to recline; to lan; as, to rest on a
      couch.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To stand firm; to be fixed; to be supported; as, a column
      rests on its pedestal.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To sleep; to slumber; hence, poetically, to be dead.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fancy . . . then retries
            Into her private cell when Nature rests. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To lean in confidence; to trust; to rely; to repose
      without anxiety; as, to rest on a man's promise.
      [1913 Webster]

            On him I rested, after long debate,
            And not without considering, fixed ?? fate.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To be satisfied; to acquiesce.
      [1913 Webster]

            To rest in Heaven's determination.    --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To rest with}, to be in the power of; to depend upon; as, it
      rests with him to decide.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rest \Rest\, v. t.
   1. To lay or place at rest; to quiet.
      [1913 Webster]

            Your piety has paid
            All needful rites, to rest my wandering shade.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To place, as on a support; to cause to lean.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her weary head upon your bosom rest.  --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rest \Rest\, v. i. [F. rester. See {Rest} remainder.]
   To be left; to remain; to continue to be.
   [1913 Webster]

         The affairs of men rest still uncertain. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rest \Rest\, n. [F. reste, fr. rester to remain, L. restare to
   stay back, remain; pref. re- re- + stare to stand, stay. See
   {Stand}, and cf. {Arrest}, {Restive}.] (With the definite
   article.)
   1. That which is left, or which remains after the separation
      of a part, either in fact or in contemplation; remainder;
      residue.
      [1913 Webster]

            Religion gives part of its reward in hand, the
            present comfort of having done our duty, and, for
            the rest, it offers us the best security that Heaven
            can give.                             --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Those not included in a proposition or description; the
      remainder; others. ``Plato and the rest of the
      philosophers.'' --Bp. Stillingfleet.
      [1913 Webster]

            Armed like the rest, the Trojan prince appears.
                                                  --DRyden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Com.) A surplus held as a reserved fund by a bank to
      equalize its dividends, etc.; in the Bank of England, the
      balance of assets above liabilities. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Remainder; overplus; surplus; remnant; residue; reserve;
        others.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rest</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rest
     n 1: something left after other parts have been taken away;
          "there was no remainder"; "he threw away the rest"; "he
          took what he wanted and I got the balance" [syn: {remainder},
           {balance}, {residual}, {residue}, {residuum}]
     2: freedom from activity (work or strain or responsibility);
        "took his repose by the swimming pool" [syn: {ease}, {repose},
         {relaxation}]
     3: a pause for relaxation; "people actually accomplish more
        when they take time for short rests" [syn: {respite}, {relief},
         {rest period}]
     4: a state of inaction; "a body will continue in a state of
        rest until acted upon"
     5: euphemisms for death (based on an analogy between lying in a
        bed and in a tomb); "she was laid to rest beside her
        husband"; "they had to put their family pet to sleep"
        [syn: {eternal rest}, {sleep}, {eternal sleep}, {quietus}]
     6: a support on which things can be put; "the gun was steadied
        on a special rest"
     7: a musical notation indicating a silence of a specified
        duration
     v 1: not move; be in a resting position
     2: take a short break from one's activities in order to relax
        [syn: {breathe}, {catch one's breath}, {take a breather}]
     3: give a rest to; "He rested his bad leg"; "Rest the dogs for
        a moment"
     4: have a place in relation to something else; "The fate of
        Bosnia lies in the hands of the West"; "The responsibility
        rests with the Allies" [syn: {lie}]
     5: be at rest [ant: {be active}]
     6: stay the same; remain in a certain state; "The dress
        remained wet after repeated attempts to dry it"; "rest
        assured"; "stay alone"; "He remained unmoved by her
        tears"; "The bad weather continued for another week" [syn:
         {stay}, {remain}] [ant: {change}]
     7: be inherent or innate in; [syn: {reside}, {repose}]
     8: put something in a resting position, as for support or
        steadying; "Rest your head on my shoulder"
     9: sit, as on a branch; "The birds perched high in the treee"
        [syn: {perch}, {roost}]
     10: rest on or as if on a pillow; "pillow your head" [syn: {pillow}]
     11: be inactive, refrain from acting; "The committee is resting
         over the summer"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
