<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>restored</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>restored</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Restore \Re*store"\ (r?*st?r"), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Restored}
   (r?-st?rd"); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Restoring}.] [OE. restoren, OF.
   restorer, F. restaurer, fr. L. restaurare; pref. re- re- + an
   unused word; cf. Gr. ???? an upright pale or stake, Skr.
   sth?vara fixed, firm. Cf. {Restaurant}, {Store}.]
   To bring back to its former state; to bring back from a state
   of ruin, decay, disease, or the like; to repair; to renew; to
   recover. ``To restore and to build Jerusalem.'' --Dan. ix.
   25.
   [1913 Webster]

         Our fortune restored after the severest afflictions.
                                                  --Prior.
   [1913 Webster]

         And his hand was restored whole as the other. --Mark
                                                  iii. 5.
   [1913 Webster]

   2. To give or bring back, as that which has been lost., or
      taken away; to bring back to the owner; to replace.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now therefore restore the man his wife. --Gen. xx.
                                                  7.
      [1913 Webster]

            Loss of Eden, till one greater man
            Restore us, and regain the blissful seat. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The father banished virtue shall restore. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To renew; to re["e]stablish; as, to restore harmony among
      those who are variance.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To give in place of, or as satisfaction for.
      [1913 Webster]

            He shall restore five oxen for an ox, and four sheep
            for a sheep.                          --Ex. xxii. 1.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To make good; to make amends for.
      [1913 Webster]

            But if the while I think on thee, dear friend,
            All losses are restored, and sorrows end. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Fine Arts)
      (a) To bring back from a state of injury or decay, or from
          a changed condition; as, to restore a painting,
          statue, etc.
      (b) To form a picture or model of, as of something lost or
          mutilated; as, to restore a ruined building, city, or
          the like.
          [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To return; replace; refund; repay; reinstate; rebuild;
        re["e]stablish; renew; repair; revive; recover; heal;
        cure.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>restored</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>restored
     adj : brought back to original condition; "a restored painting";
           "felt a restored faith in human beings" [ant: {unrestored}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
