<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>retreat</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>retreat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Retreat, TX (town, FIPS 61616)
  Location: 32.05130 N, 96.47709 W
  Population (1990): 334 (131 housing units)
  Area: 12.9 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>retreat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Retreat \Re*treat"\, n. [F. retraite, fr. retraire to withdraw,
   L. retrahere; pref. re- re- + trahere to draw. See {Trace},
   and cf. {Retract}, {Retrace}.]
   1. The act of retiring or withdrawing one's self, especially
      from what is dangerous or disagreeable.
      [1913 Webster]

            In a retreat he o?truns any lackey.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The place to which anyone retires; a place or privacy or
      safety; a refuge; an asylum.
      [1913 Webster]

            He built his son a house of pleasure, and spared no
            cost to make a delicious retreat.     --L'Estrange.
      [1913 Webster]

            That pleasing shade they sought, a soft retreat
            From sudden April showers, a shelter from the heat.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil. &amp; Naval.)
      (a) The retiring of an army or body of men from the face
          of an enemy, or from any ground occupied to a greater
          distance from the enemy, or from an advanced position.
      (b) The withdrawing of a ship or fleet from an enemy for
          the purpose of avoiding an engagement or escaping
          after defeat.
      (c) A signal given in the army or navy, by the beat of a
          drum or the sounding of trumpet or bugle, at sunset
          (when the roll is called), or for retiring from
          action.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: A retreat is properly an orderly march, in which
         circumstance it differs from a flight.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. (Eccl.)
      (a) A special season of solitude and silence to engage in
          religious exercises.
      (b) A period of several days of withdrawal from society to
          a religious house for exclusive occupation in the
          duties of devotion; as, to appoint or observe a
          retreat.
          [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Retirement; departure; withdrawment; seclusion;
        solitude; privacy; asylum; shelter; refuge.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>retreat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Retreat \Re*treat"\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Retreated}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Retreating}.]
   To make a retreat; to retire from any position or place; to
   withdraw; as, the defeated army retreated from the field.
   [1913 Webster]

         The rapid currents drive
         Towards the retreating sea their furious tide.
                                                  --Milton.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>retreat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>retreat
     n 1: (military) withdrawal of troops to a more favorable position
          to escape the enemy's superior forces or after a defeat;
          "the disorderly retreat of French troops"
     2: a place of privacy; a place affording peace and quiet
     3: (military) a signal to begin a withdrawal from a dangerous
        position
     4: (military) a bugle call signaling the lowering of the flag
        at sunset
     5: an area where you can be alone [syn: {hideaway}]
     6: withdrawal for prayer and study and meditation; "a religious
        retreat" [syn: {retirement}]
     v 1: pull back or move away or backward; "The enemy withdrew";
          "The limo pulled away from the curb" [syn: {withdraw}, {pull
          away}, {draw back}, {recede}, {pull back}, {retire}, {move
          back}]
     2: move away, as for privacy; "The Pope retreats to
        Castelgondolfo every summer"
     3: move back; "The glacier retrogrades" [syn: {retrograde}]
     4: make a retreat from an earlier commitment or activity;
        "We'll have to crawfish out from meeting with him"; "He
        backed out of his earlier promise"; "The aggressive
        investment company pulled in its horns" [syn: {pull back},
         {back out}, {back away}, {crawfish}, {crawfish out}, {pull
        in one's horns}, {withdraw}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
