<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>return</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>return</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Return \Re*turn"\, v. t.
   1. To bring, carry, send, or turn, back; as, to return a
      borrowed book, or a hired horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            Both fled attonce, ne ever back returned eye.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To repay; as, to return borrowed money.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give in requital or recompense; to requite.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord shall return thy wickedness upon thine own
            head.                                 --1 Kings ii.
                                                  44.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To give back in reply; as, to return an answer; to return
      thanks.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To retort; to throw back; as, to return the lie.
      [1913 Webster]

            If you are a malicious reader, you return upon me,
            that I affect to be thought more impartial than I
            am.                                   --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To report, or bring back and make known.
      [1913 Webster]

            And all the people answered together, . . . and
            Moses returned the words of the people unto the
            Lord.                                 --Ex. xix. 8.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To render, as an account, usually an official account, to
      a superior; to report officially by a list or statement;
      as, to return a list of stores, of killed or wounded; to
      return the result of an election.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Hence, to elect according to the official report of the
      election officers. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To bring or send back to a tribunal, or to an office, with
      a certificate of what has been done; as, to return a writ.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To convey into official custody, or to a general
       depository.
       [1913 Webster]

             Instead of a ship, he should levy money, and return
             the same to the treasurer for his majesty's use.
                                                  --Clarendon.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Tennis) To bat (the ball) back over the net.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Card Playing) To lead in response to the lead of one's
       partner; as, to return a trump; to return a diamond for a
       club.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To return a lead} (Card Playing), to lead the same suit led
      by one's partner.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To restore; requite; repay; recompense; render; remit;
        report.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>return</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Re-turn \Re-turn"\, v. t. &amp; i.
   To turn again.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>return</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Return \Re*turn"\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Returned}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Returning}.] [OE. returnen, retournen, F. retourner;
   pref. re- re- + tourner to turn. See {Turn}.]
   1. To turn back; to go or come again to the same place or
      condition. ``Return to your father's house.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            On their embattled ranks the waves return. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            If they returned out of bondage, it must be into a
            state of freedom.                     --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

            Dust thou art, and unto dust shalt thou return.
                                                  --Gen. iii.
                                                  19.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To come back, or begin again, after an interval, regular
      or irregular; to appear again.
      [1913 Webster]

            With the year
            Seasons return; but not me returns
            Day or the sweet approach of even or morn. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To speak in answer; to reply; to respond.
      [1913 Webster]

            He said, and thus the queen of heaven returned.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To revert; to pass back into possession.
      [1913 Webster]

            And Jeroboam said in his heart, Now shall the
            kingdom return to the house of David. --1Kings xii.
                                                  26.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To go back in thought, narration, or argument. ``But to
      return to my story.'' --Fielding.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>return</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Return \Re*turn"\, n.
   1. The act of returning (intransitive), or coming back to the
      same place or condition; as, the return of one long
      absent; the return of health; the return of the seasons,
      or of an anniversary.
      [1913 Webster]

            At the return of the year the king of Syria will
            come up against thee.                 --1 Kings xx.
                                                  22.
      [1913 Webster]

            His personal return was most required and necessary.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of returning (transitive), or sending back to the
      same place or condition; restitution; repayment; requital;
      retribution; as, the return of anything borrowed, as a
      book or money; a good return in tennis.
      [1913 Webster]

            You made my liberty your late request:
            Is no return due from a grateful breast? --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is returned. Specifically:
      (a) A payment; a remittance; a requital.
          [1913 Webster]

                I do expect return
                Of thrice three times the value of this bond.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) An answer; as, a return to one's question.
      (c) An account, or formal report, of an action performed,
          of a duty discharged, of facts or statistics, and the
          like; as, election returns; a return of the amount of
          goods produced or sold; especially, in the plural, a
          set of tabulated statistics prepared for general
          information.
      (d) The profit on, or advantage received from, labor, or
          an investment, undertaking, adventure, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

                The fruit from many days of recreation is very
                little; but from these few hours we spend in
                prayer, the return is great.      --Jer. Taylor.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Arch.) The continuation in a different direction, most
      often at a right angle, of a building, face of a building,
      or any member, as a molding or mold; -- applied to the
      shorter in contradistinction to the longer; thus, a facade
      of sixty feet east and west has a return of twenty feet
      north and south.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Law)
      (a) The rendering back or delivery of writ, precept, or
          execution, to the proper officer or court.
      (b) The certificate of an officer stating what he has done
          in execution of a writ, precept, etc., indorsed on the
          document.
      (c) The sending back of a commission with the certificate
          of the commissioners.
      (d) A day in bank. See {Return day}, below. --Blackstone.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mil. &amp; Naval) An official account, report, or statement,
      rendered to the commander or other superior officer; as,
      the return of men fit for duty; the return of the number
      of the sick; the return of provisions, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. (Fort. &amp; Mining) The turnings and windings of a trench
      or mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Return ball}, a ball held by an elastic string so that it
      returns to the hand from which it is thrown, -- used as a
      plaything.

   {Return bend}, a pipe fitting for connecting the contiguous
      ends of two nearly parallel pipes lying alongside or one
      above another.

   {Return day} (Law), the day when the defendant is to appear
      in court, and the sheriff is to return the writ and his
      proceedings.

   {Return flue}, in a steam boiler, a flue which conducts flame
      or gases of combustion in a direction contrary to their
      previous movement in another flue.

   {Return pipe} (Steam Heating), a pipe by which water of
      condensation from a heater or radiator is conveyed back
      toward the boiler.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>return</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>return
     n 1: document giving the tax collector information about the
          taxpayer's tax liability; "his gross income was enough
          that he had to file a tax return" [syn: {tax return}, {income
          tax return}]
     2: a coming to or returning home; "on his return from Australia
        we gave him a welcoming party" [syn: {homecoming}]
     3: the occurrence of a change in direction back in the opposite
        direction [syn: {coming back}]
     4: getting something back again; "upon the restitution of the
        book to its rightful owner the child was given a tongue
        lashing" [syn: {restitution}, {restoration}, {regaining}]
     5: the act of returning to a prior location; "they set out on
        their return to the base camp"
     6: the income arising from land or other property; "the average
        return was about 5%" [syn: {issue}, {proceeds}, {take}, {takings},
         {yield}, {payoff}]
     7: happening again (especially at regular intervals); "the
        return of spring" [syn: {recurrence}]
     8: a quick reply to a question or remark (especially a witty or
        critical one); "it brought a sharp rejoinder from the
        teacher" [syn: {rejoinder}, {retort}, {riposte}, {replication},
         {comeback}, {counter}]
     9: the key on electric typewriters or computer keyboards that
        causes a carriage return and a line feed [syn: {return key}]
     10: a reciprocal group action; "in return we gave them as good
         as we got" [syn: {paying back}, {getting even}]
     11: a tennis stroke that returns the ball to the other player;
         "he won the point on a cross-court return"
     12: (American football) the act of running back the ball after a
         kickoff or punt or interception or fumble
     13: the act of someone appearing again; "his reappearance as
         Hamlet has been long awaited" [syn: {reappearance}]
     v 1: come back to place where one has been before, or return to a
          previous activity [syn: {go back}, {get back}, {come
          back}]
     2: give back; "render money" [syn: {render}]
     3: go back to a previous state; "We reverted to the old rules"
        [syn: {revert}, {retrovert}, {regress}, {turn back}]
     4: go back to something earlier; "This harks back to a previous
        remark of his" [syn: {hark back}, {come back}, {recall}]
     5: bring back to the point of departure [syn: {take back}, {bring
        back}]
     6: return in kind; "return a compliment"; "return her love"
     7: make a return; "return a kickback"
     8: answer back [syn: {retort}, {come back}, {repay}, {riposte},
         {rejoin}]
     9: be restored; "Her old vigor returned" [syn: {come back}]
     10: pay back; "Please refund me my money" [syn: {refund}, {repay},
          {give back}]
     11: pass down; "render a verdict"; "deliver a judgment" [syn: {render},
          {deliver}]
     12: elect again [syn: {reelect}]
     13: be inherited by; "The estate fell to my sister"; "The land
         returned to the family"; "The estate devolved to an heir
         that everybody had assumed to be dead" [syn: {fall}, {pass},
          {devolve}]
     14: return to a previous position; in mathematics; "The point
         returned to the interior of the figure"
     15: give or supply; "The cow brings in 5 liters of milk"; "This
         year's crop yielded 1,000 bushels of corn"; "The estate
         renders some revenue for the family" [syn: {render}, {yield},
          {give}, {generate}]
     16: submit (a report, etc.) to someone in authority; "submit a
         bill to a legislative body"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
