<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>reverse</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reverse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reverse \Re*verse"\ (r[-e]*v[~e]rs"), n. [Cf. F. revers. See
   {Reverse}, a.]
   1. That which appears or is presented when anything, as a
      lance, a line, a course of conduct, etc., is reverted or
      turned contrary to its natural direction.
      [1913 Webster]

            He did so with the reverse of the lance. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is directly opposite or contrary to something
      else; a contrary; an opposite. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            And then mistook reverse of wrong for right. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            To make everything the reverse of what they have
            seen, is quite as easy as to destroy. --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The act of reversing; complete change; reversal; hence,
      total change in circumstances or character; especially, a
      change from better to worse; misfortune; a check or
      defeat; as, the enemy met with a reverse.
      [1913 Webster]

            The strange reverse of fate you see;
            I pitied you, now you may pity me.    --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            By a reverse of fortune, Stephen becomes rich.
                                                  --Lamb.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The back side; as, the reverse of a drum or trench; the
      reverse of a medal or coin, that is, the side opposite to
      the {obverse}. See {Obverse}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A thrust in fencing made with a backward turn of the hand;
      a backhanded stroke. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Surg.) A turn or fold made in bandaging, by which the
      direction of the bandage is changed.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reverse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reverse \Re*verse"\, a. [OE. revers, OF. revers, L. reversus, p.
   p. of revertere. See {Revert}.]
   1. Turned backward; having a contrary or opposite direction;
      hence; opposite or contrary in kind; as, the reverse order
      or method. ``A vice reverse unto this.'' --Gower.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Turned upside down; greatly disturbed. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            He found the sea diverse
            With many a windy storm reverse.      --Gower.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot. &amp; Zo["o]l.) Reversed; as, a reverse shell.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Reverse bearing} (Surv.), the bearing of a back station as
      observed from the station next in advance.

   {Reverse curve} (Railways), a curve like the letter S, formed
      of two curves bending in opposite directions.

   {Reverse fire} (Mil.), a fire in the rear.

   {Reverse operation} (Math.), an operation the steps of which
      are taken in a contrary order to that in which the same or
      similar steps are taken in another operation considered as
      direct; an operation in which that is sought which in
      another operation is given, and that given which in the
      other is sought; as, finding the length of a pendulum from
      its time of vibration is the reverse operation to finding
      the time of vibration from the length.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reverse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reverse \Re*verse"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Reversed}
   (r[-e]*v[~e]rst");p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Reversing}.] [See
   {Reverse}, a., and cf. {Revert}.]
   1. To turn back; to cause to face in a contrary direction; to
      cause to depart.
      [1913 Webster]

            And that old dame said many an idle verse,
            Out of her daughter's heart fond fancies to reverse.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to return; to recall. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            And to his fresh remembrance did reverse
            The ugly view of his deformed crimes. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To change totally; to alter to the opposite.
      [1913 Webster]

            Reverse the doom of death.            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            She reversed the conduct of the celebrated vicar of
            Bray.                                 --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To turn upside down; to invert.
      [1913 Webster]

            A pyramid reversed may stand upon his point if
            balanced by admirable skill.          --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence, to overthrow; to subvert.
      [1913 Webster]

            These can divide, and these reverse, the state.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            Custom . . . reverses even the distinctions of good
            and evil.                             --Rogers.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law) To overthrow by a contrary decision; to make void;
      to under or annual for error; as, to reverse a judgment,
      sentence, or decree.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Reverse arms} (Mil.), a position of a soldier in which the
      piece passes between the right elbow and the body at an
      angle of 45[deg], and is held as in the illustration.

   {To reverse an engine} or {To reverse a machine}, to cause it
      to perform its revolutions or action in the opposite
      direction.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To overturn; overset; invert; overthrow; subvert;
        repeal; annul; revoke; undo.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reverse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Reverse \Re*verse"\, v. i.
   1. To return; to revert. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To become or be reversed.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>reverse</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>reverse
     adj 1: directed or moving toward the rear; "a rearward glance"; "a
            rearward movement" [syn: {rearward}]
     2: reversed (turned backward) in order or nature or effect
        [syn: {inverse}]
     3: of the transmission gear causing backward movement in a
        motor vehicle; "in reverse gear" [ant: {forward}]
     n 1: a relation of direct opposition; "we thought Sue was older
          than Bill but just the reverse was true" [syn: {contrary},
           {opposite}]
     2: the gears by which the motion of a machine can be reversed
     3: an unfortunate happening that hinders of impedes; something
        that is thwarting or frustrating [syn: {reversal}, {setback},
         {blow}, {black eye}]
     4: the side of a coin or medal that does not bear the principal
        design [syn: {verso}] [ant: {obverse}]
     5: (American football) a running play in which a back running
        in one direction hands the ball to a back running in the
        opposite direction
     6: turning in the opposite direction [syn: {reversion}, {reversal},
         {turnabout}, {turnaround}]
     v 1: change to the contrary; "The trend was reversed"; "the tides
          turned against him"; "public opinion turned when it was
          revealed that the president had an affair with a White
          House intern" [syn: {change by reversal}, {turn}]
     2: turn inside out or upside down [syn: {invert}]
     3: rule against; "The Republicans were overruled when the House
        voted on the bill" [syn: {overrule}, {overturn}, {override},
         {overthrow}]
     4: annul by recalling or rescinding; "He revoked the ban on
        smoking"; "lift an embargo"; "vacate a death sentence"
        [syn: {revoke}, {annul}, {lift}, {countermand}, {repeal},
        {overturn}, {rescind}, {vacate}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
