<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>revelation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>revelation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>REVELATION, n.  A famous book in which St. John the Divine concealed
all that he knew.  The revealing is done by the commentators, who know
nothing.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>revelation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Revelation
   an uncovering, a bringing to light of that which had been
   previously wholly hidden or only obscurely seen. God has been
   pleased in various ways and at different times (Heb. 1:1) to
   make a supernatural revelation of himself and his purposes and
   plans, which, under the guidance of his Spirit, has been
   committed to writing. (See WORD OF {GOD}.) The
   Scriptures are not merely the "record" of revelation; they are
   the revelation itself in a written form, in order to the
   accurate presevation and propagation of the truth.
   
     Revelation and inspiration differ. Revelation is the
   supernatural communication of truth to the mind; inspiration
   (q.v.) secures to the teacher or writer infallibility in
   communicating that truth to others. It renders its subject the
   spokesman or prophet of God in such a sense that everything he
   asserts to be true, whether fact or doctrine or moral principle,
   is true, infallibly true.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>revelation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Revelation \Rev`e*la"tion\, n. [F. r['e]v['e]lation, L.
   revelatio. See {Reveal}.]
   1. The act of revealing, disclosing, or discovering to others
      what was before unknown to them.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which is revealed.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Theol.)
      (a) The act of revealing divine truth.
      (b) That which is revealed by God to man; esp., the Bible.
          [1913 Webster]

                By revelation he made known unto me the mystery,
                as I wrote afore in few words.    --Eph. iii. 3.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically, the last book of the sacred canon,
      containing the prophecies of St. John; the {Apocalypse} or
      {Book of Revelation} or {The Revelation of Saint John}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>revelation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>revelation
     n 1: the speech act of making something evident [syn: {disclosure},
           {revealing}]
     2: an enlightening or astonishing disclosure
     3: communication of knowledge to man by a divine or
        supernatural agency
     4: the last book of the New Testament; contains visionary
        descriptions of heaven and of conflicts between good and
        evil and of the end of the world; attributed to Saint John
        the apostle [syn: {Revelation of Saint John the Divine}, {Apocalypse},
         {Book of Revelation}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
