<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>review</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>review</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>REVIEW, v.t.

    To set your wisdom (holding not a doubt of it,
        Although in truth there's neither bone nor skin to it)
    At work upon a book, and so read out of it
        The qualities that you have first read into it.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>review</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Review \Re*view"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Review?d}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Reveiwing}.] [Pref. re- + view. Cf. {Review}, n. ]
   1. To view or see again; to look back on. [R.] ``I shall
      review Sicilia.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To go over and examine critically or deliberately.
      Specifically:
      (a) To reconsider; to revise, as a manuscript before
          printing it, or a book for a new edition.
      (b) To go over with critical examination, in order to
          discover exellences or defects; hence, to write a
          critical notice of; as, to review a new novel.
      (c) To make a formal or official examination of the state
          of, as troops, and the like; as, to review a regiment.
      (d) (Law) To re["e]xamine judically; as, a higher court
          may review the proceedings and judgments of a lower
          one.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. To retrace; to go over again.
      [1913 Webster]

            Shall I the long, laborious scene review? --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>review</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Review \Re*view"\, v. i.
   To look back; to make a review.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>review</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Review \Re*view"\, n. [F. revue, fr. revu, p. p. of revoir to
   see again, L. revidere; pref. re- re- + videre to see. See
   {View}, and cf. {Revise}.]
   1. A second or repeated view; a re["e]xamination; a
      retrospective survey; a looking over again; as, a review
      of one's studies; a review of life.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An examination with a view to amendment or improvement;
      revision; as, an author's review of his works.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A critical examination of a publication, with remarks; a
      criticism; a critique.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A periodical containing critical essays upon matters of
      interest, as new productions in literature, art, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An inspection, as of troops under arms or of a naval
      force, by a high officer, for the purpose of ascertaining
      the state of discipline, equipments, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Law) The judicial examination of the proceedings of a
      lower court by a higher.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A lesson studied or recited for a second time.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bill of review} (Equity), a bill, in the nature of
      proceedings in error, filed to procure an examination and
      alteration or reversal of a final decree which has been
      duly signed and enrolled. --Wharton.

   {Commission of review} (Eng. Eccl. Law), a commission
      formerly granted by the crown to revise the sentence of
      the court of delegates.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Re["e]xamination; resurvey; retrospect; survey;
        reconsideration; revisal; revise; revision.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>review</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>review
     n 1: a new appraisal or evaluation [syn: {reappraisal}, {revaluation},
           {reassessment}]
     2: an essay or article that gives a critical evaluation (as of
        a book or play) [syn: {critique}, {critical review}, {review
        article}]
     3: a subsequent examination of a patient for the purpose of
        monitoring earlier treatment [syn: {follow-up}, {followup},
         {reexamination}]
     4: (accounting) a service (less exhaustive than an audit) that
        provides some assurance to interested parties as to the
        reliability of financial data [syn: {limited review}]
     5: a variety show with topical sketches and songs and dancing
        and comedians [syn: {revue}]
     6: a periodical that publishes critical essays on current
        affairs or literature or art
     7: a summary at the end that repeats the substance of a longer
        discussion [syn: {recapitulation}, {recap}]
     8: (law) a judicial reexamination of the proceedings of a court
        (especially by an appellate court)
     9: practice intended to polish performance or refresh the
        memory [syn: {brushup}]
     10: a formal or official examination; "the platoon stood ready
         for review"; "we had to wait for the inspection before we
         could use the elevator" [syn: {inspection}]
     v 1: look at again; examine again; "let's review your situation"
          [syn: {reexamine}]
     2: appraise critically; "She reviews books for the New York
        Times"; "Please critique this performance" [syn: {critique}]
     3: hold a review (of troops) [syn: {go over}, {survey}]
     4: refresh one's memory; "I reviewed the material before the
        test" [syn: {brush up}, {refresh}]
     5: look back upon (a period of time, sequence of events, etc.);
        remember; "she reviewed her achievements with pride" [syn:
         {look back}, {retrospect}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
