<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rich</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rich</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>RICH, adj.  Holding in trust and subject to an accounting the property
of the indolent, the incompetent, the unthrifty, the envious and the
luckless.  That is the view that prevails in the underworld, where the
Brotherhood of Man finds its most logical development and candid
advocacy.  To denizens of the midworld the word means good and wise.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rich</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rich \Rich\, (r[i^]ch), a. [Compar. {Richer}; superl.
   {Richest}.] [OE. riche, AS. r[=i]ce rich, powerful; akin to
   OS. r[=i]ki, D. rijk, G. reich, OHG. r[=i]hhi, Icel. r[=i]kr,
   Sw. rik, Dan. rig, Goth. reiks; from a word meaning, ruler,
   king, probably borrowed from Celtic, and akin to L. rex,
   regis, king, regere to guide, rule. [root]283. See {Right},
   and cf. {Derrick}, {Enrich}, {Rajah}, {Riches}, {Royal}.]
   1. Having an abundance of material possessions; possessed of
      a large amount of property; well supplied with land,
      goods, or money; wealthy; opulent; affluent; -- opposed to
      {poor}. ``Rich merchants.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rich [person] hath many friends.  --Prov. xiv.
                                                  20.
      [1913 Webster]

            As a thief, bent to unhoard the cash
            Of some rich burgher.                 --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, in general, well supplied; abounding; abundant;
      copious; bountiful; as, a rich treasury; a rich
      entertainment; a rich crop.
      [1913 Webster]

            If life be short, it shall be glorious;
            Each minute shall be rich in some great action.
                                                  --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gorgeous East with richest hand
            Showers on her kings barbaric pearl and gold.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Yielding large returns; productive or fertile; fruitful;
      as, rich soil or land; a rich mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Composed of valuable or costly materials or ingredients;
      procured at great outlay; highly valued; precious;
      sumptuous; costly; as, a rich dress; rich silk or fur;
      rich presents.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like to rich and various gems.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Abounding in agreeable or nutritive qualities; --
      especially applied to articles of food or drink which are
      high-seasoned or abound in oleaginous ingredients, or are
      sweet, luscious, and high-flavored; as, a rich dish; rich
      cream or soup; rich pastry; rich wine or fruit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sauces and rich spices are fetched from India.
                                                  --Baker.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Not faint or delicate; vivid; as, a rich color.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Full of sweet and harmonius sounds; as, a rich voice; rich
      music.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Abounding in beauty; gorgeous; as, a rich landscape; rich
      scenery.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Abounding in humor; exciting amusement; entertaining; as,
      the scene was a rich one; a rich incident or character.
      [Colloq.] --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Rich is sometimes used in the formation of
         self-explaining compounds; as, rich-fleeced,
         rich-jeweled, rich-laden, rich-stained.
         [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Wealthy; affluent; opulent; ample; copious; abundant;
        plentiful; fruitful; costly; sumptuous; precious;
        generous; luscious.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rich</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rich \Rich\, v. t.
   To enrich. [Obs.] --Gower.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rich</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rich
     adj 1: possessing material wealth; "her father is extremely rich";
            "many fond hopes are pinned on rich uncles" [ant: {poor}]
     2: having an abundant supply of desirable qualities or
        substances (especially natural resources); "blessed with a
        land rich in minerals"; "rich in ideas"; "rich with
        cultural interest" [ant: {poor}]
     3: of great worth or quality; "a rich collection of antiques"
     4: marked by great fruitfulness; "fertile farmland"; "a fat
        land"; "a productive vineyard"; "rich soil" [syn: {fat}, {fertile},
         {productive}]
     5: strong; intense; "deep purple"; "a rich red" [syn: {deep}]
     6: very productive; "rich seams of coal"
     7: high in mineral content; having a a high proportion of fuel
        to air; "a rich vein of copper", "a rich gas mixture"
        [ant: {lean}]
     8: suggestive of or characterized by great expense; "a rich
        display" [ant: {poor}]
     9: marked by richness and fullness of flavor; "a rich ruby
        port"; "full-bodied wines"; "a robust claret"; "the robust
        flavor of fresh-brewed coffee" [syn: {full-bodied}, {robust}]
     10: highly seasoned or containing large amounts of choice
         ingredients such as butter or sugar or eggs; "kept
         gorging on rich foods"; "rich pastries"; "rich eggnogg"
     11: pleasantly full and mellow; "a rich tenor voice"
     12: affording an abundant supply; "had ample food for the
         party"; "copious provisions"; "food is plentiful"; "a
         plenteous grape harvest"; "a rich supply" [syn: {ample},
         {copious}, {plenteous}, {plentiful}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
