<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>richer</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>richer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rich \Rich\, (r[i^]ch), a. [Compar. {Richer}; superl.
   {Richest}.] [OE. riche, AS. r[=i]ce rich, powerful; akin to
   OS. r[=i]ki, D. rijk, G. reich, OHG. r[=i]hhi, Icel. r[=i]kr,
   Sw. rik, Dan. rig, Goth. reiks; from a word meaning, ruler,
   king, probably borrowed from Celtic, and akin to L. rex,
   regis, king, regere to guide, rule. [root]283. See {Right},
   and cf. {Derrick}, {Enrich}, {Rajah}, {Riches}, {Royal}.]
   1. Having an abundance of material possessions; possessed of
      a large amount of property; well supplied with land,
      goods, or money; wealthy; opulent; affluent; -- opposed to
      {poor}. ``Rich merchants.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rich [person] hath many friends.  --Prov. xiv.
                                                  20.
      [1913 Webster]

            As a thief, bent to unhoard the cash
            Of some rich burgher.                 --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, in general, well supplied; abounding; abundant;
      copious; bountiful; as, a rich treasury; a rich
      entertainment; a rich crop.
      [1913 Webster]

            If life be short, it shall be glorious;
            Each minute shall be rich in some great action.
                                                  --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gorgeous East with richest hand
            Showers on her kings barbaric pearl and gold.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Yielding large returns; productive or fertile; fruitful;
      as, rich soil or land; a rich mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Composed of valuable or costly materials or ingredients;
      procured at great outlay; highly valued; precious;
      sumptuous; costly; as, a rich dress; rich silk or fur;
      rich presents.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like to rich and various gems.        --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Abounding in agreeable or nutritive qualities; --
      especially applied to articles of food or drink which are
      high-seasoned or abound in oleaginous ingredients, or are
      sweet, luscious, and high-flavored; as, a rich dish; rich
      cream or soup; rich pastry; rich wine or fruit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sauces and rich spices are fetched from India.
                                                  --Baker.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Not faint or delicate; vivid; as, a rich color.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Full of sweet and harmonius sounds; as, a rich voice; rich
      music.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Abounding in beauty; gorgeous; as, a rich landscape; rich
      scenery.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Abounding in humor; exciting amusement; entertaining; as,
      the scene was a rich one; a rich incident or character.
      [Colloq.] --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Rich is sometimes used in the formation of
         self-explaining compounds; as, rich-fleeced,
         rich-jeweled, rich-laden, rich-stained.
         [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Wealthy; affluent; opulent; ample; copious; abundant;
        plentiful; fruitful; costly; sumptuous; precious;
        generous; luscious.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
