<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rider</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rider \Rid"er\ (r[imac]d"[~e]r), n.
   1. One who, or that which, rides.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Formerly, an agent who went out with samples of goods to
      obtain orders; a commercial traveler. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who breaks or manages a horse. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An addition or amendment to a manuscript or other
      document, which is attached on a separate piece of paper;
      in legislative practice, an additional clause annexed to a
      bill while in course of passage; something extra or
      burdensome that is imposed.
      [1913 Webster]

            After the third reading, a foolish man stood up to
            propose a rider.                      --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

            This [question] was a rider which Mab found
            difficult to answer.                  --A. S. Hardy.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Math.) A problem of more than usual difficulty added to
      another on an examination paper.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. [D. rijder.] A Dutch gold coin having the figure of a man
      on horseback stamped upon it.
      [1913 Webster]

            His moldy money ! half a dozen riders. --J.
                                                  Fletcher.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining) Rock material in a vein of ore, dividing it.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Shipbuilding) An interior rib occasionally fixed in a
      ship's hold, reaching from the keelson to the beams of the
      lower deck, to strengthen her frame. --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) The second tier of casks in a vessel's hold.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A small forked weight which straddles the beam of a
       balance, along which it can be moved in the manner of the
       weight on a steelyard.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A robber. [Obs. or Prov. Eng.] --Drummond.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Rider's bone} (Med.), a bony deposit in the muscles of the
      upper and inner part of the thigh, due to the pressure and
      irritation caused by the saddle in riding.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rider</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rider
     n 1: a traveler who actively rides an animal (as a horse or
          camel)
     2: a clause that is appended to a legislative bill
     3: a traveler who actively rides a vehicle (as a bicycle or
        motorcycle)
     4: a traveler riding in a vehicle (a boat or bus or car or
        plane or train etc) who is not operating it [syn: {passenger}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
