<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>right</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>right</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>RIGHT, n.  Legitimate authority to be, to do or to have; as the right
to be a king, the right to do one's neighbor, the right to have
measles, and the like.  The first of these rights was once universally
believed to be derived directly from the will of God; and this is
still sometimes affirmed _in partibus infidelium_ outside the
enlightened realms of Democracy; as the well known lines of Sir
Abednego Bink, following:

        By what right, then, do royal rulers rule?
            Whose is the sanction of their state and pow'r?
        He surely were as stubborn as a mule
            Who, God unwilling, could maintain an hour
    His uninvited session on the throne, or air
    His pride securely in the Presidential chair.

        Whatever is is so by Right Divine;
            Whate'er occurs, God wills it so.  Good land!
        It were a wondrous thing if His design
            A fool could baffle or a rogue withstand!
    If so, then God, I say (intending no offence)
    Is guilty of contributory negligence.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>right</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Right \Right\ (r[imac]t), a. [OE. right, riht, AS. riht; akin to
   D. regt, OS. &amp; OHG. reht, G. recht, Dan. ret, Sw. r["a]tt,
   Icel. r["e]ttr, Goth. ra['i]hts, L. rectus, p. p. of regere
   to guide, rule; cf. Skr. [.r]ju straight, right. [root]115.
   Cf. {Adroit},{Alert}, {Correct}, {Dress}, {Regular},
   {Rector}, {Recto}, {Rectum}, {Regent}, {Region}, {Realm},
   {Rich}, {Royal}, {Rule}.]
   1. Straight; direct; not crooked; as, a right line. ``Right
      as any line.'' --Chaucer
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Upright; erect from a base; having an upright axis; not
      oblique; as, right ascension; a right pyramid or cone.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Conformed to the constitution of man and the will of God,
      or to justice and equity; not deviating from the true and
      just; according with truth and duty; just; true.
      [1913 Webster]

            That which is conformable to the Supreme Rule is
            absolutely right, and is called right simply without
            relation to a special end.            --Whately.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fit; suitable; proper; correct; becoming; as, the right
      man in the right place; the right way from London to
      Oxford.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Characterized by reality or genuineness; real; actual; not
      spurious. ``His right wife.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            In this battle, . . . the Britons never more plainly
            manifested themselves to be right barbarians.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. According with truth; passing a true judgment; conforming
      to fact or intent; not mistaken or wrong; not erroneous;
      correct; as, this is the right faith.
      [1913 Webster]

            You are right, Justice, and you weigh this well.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            If there be no prospect beyond the grave, the
            inference is . . . right, ``Let us eat and drink,
            for to-morrow we die.''               --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Most favorable or convenient; fortunate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lady has been disappointed on the right side.
                                                  --Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Of or pertaining to that side of the body in man on which
      the muscular action is usually stronger than on the other
      side; -- opposed to left when used in reference to a part
      of the body; as, the right side, hand, arm. Also applied
      to the corresponding side of the lower animals.
      [1913 Webster]

            Became the sovereign's favorite, his right hand.
                                                  --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In designating the banks of a river, right and left are
         used always with reference to the position of one who
         is facing in the direction of the current's flow.
         [1913 Webster]

   9. Well placed, disposed, or adjusted; orderly; well
      regulated; correctly done.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Designed to be placed or worn outward; as, the right side
       of a piece of cloth.
       [1913 Webster]

   {At right angles}, so as to form a right angle or right
      angles, as when one line crosses another perpendicularly.
      

   {Right and left}, in both or all directions. [Colloq.]

   {Right and left coupling} (Pipe fitting), a coupling the
      opposite ends of which are tapped for a right-handed screw
      and a left-handed screw, respectivelly.

   {Right angle}.
       (a) The angle formed by one line meeting another
           perpendicularly, as the angles ABD, DBC.
       (b) (Spherics) A spherical angle included between the
           axes of two great circles whose planes are
           perpendicular to each other.

   {Right ascension}. See under {Ascension}.

   {Right Center} (Politics), those members belonging to the
      Center in a legislative assembly who have sympathies with
      the Right on political questions. See {Center}, n., 5.

   {Right cone}, {Right cylinder}, {Right prism}, {Right
   pyramid} (Geom.), a cone, cylinder, prism, or pyramid, the
      axis of which is perpendicular to the base.

   {Right line}. See under {Line}.

   {Right sailing} (Naut.), sailing on one of the four cardinal
      points, so as to alter a ship's latitude or its longitude,
      but not both. --Ham. Nav. Encyc.

   {Right sphere} (Astron. &amp; Geol.), a sphere in such a position
      that the equator cuts the horizon at right angles; in
      spherical projections, that position of the sphere in
      which the primitive plane coincides with the plane of the
      equator.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Right is used elliptically for it is right, what you
         say is right, true.
         [1913 Webster]

               ``Right,'' cries his lordship.     --Pope.
         [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Straight; direct; perpendicular; upright; lawful;
        rightful; true; correct; just; equitable; proper;
        suitable; becoming.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>right</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Right \Right\, adv.
   1. In a right manner.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. In a right or straight line; directly; hence; straightway;
      immediately; next; as, he stood right before me; it went
      right to the mark; he came right out; he followed right
      after the guide.
      [1913 Webster]

            Unto Dian's temple goeth she right.   --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let thine eyes look right on.         --Prov. iv.
                                                  25.
      [1913 Webster]

            Right across its track there lay,
            Down in the water, a long reef of gold. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Exactly; just. [Obs. or Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Came he right now to sing a raven's note? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. According to the law or will of God; conforming to the
      standard of truth and justice; righteously; as, to live
      right; to judge right.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. According to any rule of art; correctly.
      [1913 Webster]

            You with strict discipline instructed right.
                                                  --Roscommon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. According to fact or truth; actually; truly; really;
      correctly; exactly; as, to tell a story right. ``Right at
      mine own cost.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Right as it were a steed of Lumbardye. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            His wounds so smarted that he slept right naught.
                                                  --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. In a great degree; very; wholly; unqualifiedly; extremely;
      highly; as, right humble; right noble; right valiant. ``He
      was not right fat''. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            For which I should be right sorry.    --Tyndale.
      [1913 Webster]

            [I] return those duties back as are right fit.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In this sense now chiefly prefixed to titles; as, right
         honorable; right reverend.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Right honorable}, a title given in England to peers and
      peeresses, to the eldest sons and all daughters of such
      peers as have rank above viscounts, and to all privy
      councilors; also, to certain civic officers, as the lord
      mayor of London, of York, and of Dublin.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Right is used in composition with other adverbs, as
         upright, downright, forthright, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Right along}, without cessation; continuously; as, to work
      right along for several hours. [Colloq. U.S.]

   {Right away}, or {Right off}, at once; straightway; without
      delay. [Colloq. U.S.] ``We will . . . shut ourselves up in
      the office and do the work right off.'' --D. Webster.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>right</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Right \Right\, n. [AS. right. See {Right}, a.]
   1. That which is right or correct. Specifically:
      (a) The straight course; adherence to duty; obedience to
          lawful authority, divine or human; freedom from guilt,
          -- the opposite of moral wrong.
      (b) A true statement; freedom from error of falsehood;
          adherence to truth or fact.
          [1913 Webster]

                Seldom your opinions err;
                Your eyes are always in the right. --Prior.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) A just judgment or action; that which is true or
          proper; justice; uprightness; integrity.
          [1913 Webster]

                Long love to her has borne the faithful knight,
                And well deserved, had fortune done him right.
                                                  --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. That to which one has a just claim. Specifically:
      (a) That which one has a natural claim to exact.
          [1913 Webster]

                There are no rights whatever, without
                corresponding duties.             --Coleridge.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) That which one has a legal or social claim to do or to
          exact; legal power; authority; as, a sheriff has a
          right to arrest a criminal.
      (c) That which justly belongs to one; that which one has a
          claim to possess or own; the interest or share which
          anyone has in a piece of property; title; claim;
          interest; ownership.
          [1913 Webster]

                Born free, he sought his right.   --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

                Hast thou not right to all created things?
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                Men have no right to what is not reasonable.
                                                  --Burke.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) Privilege or immunity granted by authority.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. The right side; the side opposite to the left.
      [1913 Webster]

            Led her to the Souldan's right.       --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. In some legislative bodies of Europe (as in France), those
      members collectively who are conservatives or monarchists.
      See {Center}, 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The outward or most finished surface, as of a piece of
      cloth, a carpet, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   {At all right}, at all points; in all respects. [Obs.]
      --Chaucer.

   {Bill of rights}, a list of rights; a paper containing a
      declaration of rights, or the declaration itself. See
      under {Bill}.

   {By right}, {By rights}, or {By good rights}, rightly;
      properly; correctly.
      [1913 Webster]

            He should himself use it by right.    --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I should have been a woman by right.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Divine right}, or

   {Divine right of kings}, a name given to the patriarchal
      theory of government, especially to the doctrine that no
      misconduct and no dispossession can forfeit the right of a
      monarch or his heirs to the throne, and to the obedience
      of the people.

   {To rights}.
      (a) In a direct line; straight. [R.] --Woodward.
      (b) At once; directly. [Obs. or Colloq.] --Swift.

   {To set to rights}, {To put to rights}, to put in good order;
      to adjust; to regulate, as what is out of order.

   {Writ of right} (Law), a writ which lay to recover lands in
      fee simple, unjustly withheld from the true owner.
      --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>right</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Right \Right\, v. i.
   1. To recover the proper or natural condition or position; to
      become upright.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) Hence, to regain an upright position, as a ship or
      boat, after careening.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>right</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Right \Right\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Righted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Righting}.] [AS. rihtan. See {Right}, a.]
   1. To bring or restore to the proper or natural position; to
      set upright; to make right or straight (that which has
      been wrong or crooked); to correct.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To do justice to; to relieve from wrong; to restore rights
      to; to assert or regain the rights of; as, to right the
      oppressed; to right one's self; also, to vindicate.
      [1913 Webster]

            So just is God, to right the innocent. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            All experience hath shown that mankind are more
            disposed to suffer while evils are sufferable, than
            to right themselves by abolishing the forms to which
            they are accustomed.                  --Jefferson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To right a vessel} (Naut.), to restore her to an upright
      position after careening.

   {To right the helm} (Naut.), to place it in line with the
      keel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>right</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>right
     adj 1: free from error; especially conforming to fact or truth;
            "the correct answer"; "the correct version"; "the
            right answer"; "took the right road"; "the right
            decision" [syn: {correct}] [ant: {incorrect}, {incorrect}]
     2: being or located on or directed toward the side of the body
        to the east when facing north; "my right hand"; "right
        center field"; "a right-hand turn"; "the right bank of a
        river is the bank on your right side when you are facing
        downstream" [ant: {left}]
     3: socially right or correct; "it isn't right to leave the
        party without saying goodbye"; "correct behavior" [syn: {correct}]
     4: in conformance with justice or law or morality; "do the
        right thing and confess" [ant: {wrong}]
     5: correct in opinion or judgment; "time proved him right"
        [syn: {correct}] [ant: {wrong}]
     6: appropriate for a condition or occasion; "everything in its
        proper place"; "the right man for the job"; "she is not
        suitable for the position" [syn: {proper}, {suitable}]
     7: of or belonging to the political or intellectual right [ant:
         {left}, {center}]
     8: in or into a satisfactory condition; "things are right again
        now"; "put things right"
     9: intended for the right hand; "a right-hand glove" [syn: {right(a)},
         {right-hand(a)}]
     10: in accord with accepted standards of usage or procedure;
         "what's the right word for this?"; "the right way to open
         oysters" [syn: {correct}]
     11: having the axis perpendicular to the base; "a right angle"
     12: of the side of cloth or clothing intended to face outward;
         "the right side of the cloth showed the pattern"; "be
         sure your shirt is right side out" [syn: {right(a)}]
     13: most suitable or right for a particular purpose; "a good
         time to plant tomatoes"; "the right time to act"; "the
         time is ripe for great sociological changes" [syn: {good},
          {ripe}]
     n 1: an abstract idea of that which is due to a person or
          governmental body by law or tradition or nature; "they
          are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable
          Rights"; "Certain rights can never be granted to the
          government but must be kept in the hands of the people"-
          Eleanor Roosevelt; "a right is not something that
          somebody gives you; it is something that nobody can take
          away"
     2: (frequently plural) the interest possessed by law or custom
        in some intangible thing; "mineral rights"; "film rights"
     3: location near or direction toward the right side; i.e. the
        side to the south when a person or object faces east; "he
        stood on the right" [ant: {left}]
     4: a turn to the right; "take a right at the corner"
     5: those who support political or social or economic
        conservatism; those who believe that things are better
        left unchanged [syn: {right wing}]
     6: anything in accord with principles of justice; "he feels he
        is in the right"; "the rightfulness of his claim" [syn: {rightfulness}]
        [ant: {wrong}, {wrong}]
     7: the hand that is on the right side of the body; "he writes
        with his right hand but pitches with his left"; "hit him
        with quick rights to the body" [syn: {right hand}]
     8: the piece of ground in the outfield on the catcher's right
        [syn: {right field}]
     adv 1: precisely, exactly; "stand right here!"
     2: immediately; "she called right after dinner"
     3: exactly; "he fell flop on his face" [syn: {flop}]
     4: toward or on the right; also used figuratively; "he looked
        right and left"; "the party has moved right" [ant: {left}]
     5: in the right manner; "please do your job properly!"; "can't
        you carry me decent?" [syn: {properly}, {decently}, {decent},
         {in good order}, {the right way}] [ant: {improperly}]
     6: an interjection expressing agreement [syn: {right on}]
     7: completely; "she felt right at home"; "he fell right into
        the trap"
     8: (Southern regional intensive) very; "the baby is mighty
        cute"; "he's mighty tired"; "it is powerful humid"; "that
        boy is powerful big now"; "they have a right nice place"
        [syn: {mighty}, {powerful}]
     9: in accordance with moral or social standards; "that serves
        him right"; "do right by him" [syn: {justly}]
     10: in a correct manner; "he guessed right" [syn: {correctly}, {aright}]
         [ant: {incorrectly}, {incorrectly}]
     v 1: make reparations or amends for; "right a wrongs done to the
          victims of the Holocaust" [syn: {compensate}, {redress},
           {correct}] [ant: {wrong}]
     2: put in or restore to an upright position; "They righted the
        sailboat that had capsized"
     3: regain an upright or proper position; "The capsized boat
        righted again"
     4: make right or correct; "Correct the mistakes"; "rectify the
        calculation" [syn: {correct}, {rectify}] [ant: {falsify}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
