<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>road</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>road</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ROAD, n.  A strip of land along which one may pass from where it is
too tiresome to be to where it is futile to go.

    All roads, howsoe'er they diverge, lead to Rome,
    Whence, thank the good Lord, at least one leads back home.
                                                        Borey the Bald


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>road</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Road
   (1 Sam. 27:10; R.V., "raid"), an inroad, an incursion. This word
   is never used in Scripture in the sense of a way or path.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>road</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Road \Road\ (r[=o]), n. [AS. r[=a]d a riding, that on which one
   rides or travels, a road, fr. r[=i]dan to ride. See {Ride},
   and cf. {Raid}.]
   1. A journey, or stage of a journey. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            With easy roads he came to Leicester. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An inroad; an invasion; a raid. [Obs.] --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A place where one may ride; an open way or public passage
      for vehicles, persons, and animals; a track for travel,
      forming a means of communication between one city, town,
      or place, and another.
      [1913 Webster]

            The most villainous house in all the London road.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The word is generally applied to highways, and as a
         generic term it includes highway, street, and lane.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. [Possibly akin to Icel. rei[eth]i the rigging of a ship,
      E. ready.] A place where ships may ride at anchor at some
      distance from the shore; a roadstead; -- often in the
      plural; as, Hampton Roads. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now strike your saile, ye jolly mariners,
            For we be come unto a quiet rode [road]. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   {On the road}, or {Uponthe road}, traveling or passing over a
      road; coming or going; traveling; on the way.
      [1913 Webster]

            My hat and wig will soon be here,
            They are upon the road.               --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Road agent}, a highwayman, especially on the stage routes of
      the unsettled western parts of the United States; -- a
      humorous euphemism. [Western U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The highway robber -- road agent he is quaintly
            called.                               --The century.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Road book}, a guidebook in respect to roads and distances.
      

   {road kill} See {roadkill} in the vocabulary.

   {Road metal}, the broken, stone used in macadamizing roads.
      

   {Road roller}, a heavy roller, or combinations of rollers,
      for making earth, macadam, or concrete roads smooth and
      compact. -- often driven by steam.

   {Road runner} (Zo["o]l.), the chaparral cock.

   {Road steamer}, a locomotive engine adapted to running on
      common roads.

   {To go on the road}, to engage in the business of a
      commercial traveler. [Colloq.]

   {To take the road}, to begin or engage in traveling.

   {To take to the road}, to engage in robbery upon the
      highways.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Way; highway; street; lane; pathway; route; passage;
        course. See {Way}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>road</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Break \Break\ (br[=a]k), v. t. [imp. {broke} (br[=o]k), (Obs.
   {Brake}); p. p. {Broken} (br[=o]"k'n), (Obs. {Broke}); p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Breaking}.] [OE. breken, AS. brecan; akin to OS.
   brekan, D. breken, OHG. brehhan, G. brechen, Icel. braka to
   creak, Sw. braka, br["a]kka to crack, Dan. br[ae]kke to
   break, Goth. brikan to break, L. frangere. Cf. {Bray} to
   pound, {Breach}, {Fragile}.]
   1. To strain apart; to sever by fracture; to divide with
      violence; as, to break a rope or chain; to break a seal;
      to break an axle; to break rocks or coal; to break a lock.
      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To lay open as by breaking; to divide; as, to break a
      package of goods.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To lay open, as a purpose; to disclose, divulge, or
      communicate.
      [1913 Webster]

            Katharine, break thy mind to me.      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To infringe or violate, as an obligation, law, or promise.
      [1913 Webster]

            Out, out, hyena! these are thy wonted arts . . .
            To break all faith, all vows, deceive, betray.
                                                  --Milton
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To interrupt; to destroy the continuity of; to dissolve or
      terminate; as, to break silence; to break one's sleep; to
      break one's journey.
      [1913 Webster]

            Go, release them, Ariel;
            My charms I'll break, their senses I'll restore.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To destroy the completeness of; to remove a part from; as,
      to break a set.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To destroy the arrangement of; to throw into disorder; to
      pierce; as, the cavalry were not able to break the British
      squares.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To shatter to pieces; to reduce to fragments.
      [1913 Webster]

            The victim broke in pieces the musical instruments
            with which he had solaced the hours of captivity.
                                                  --Prescott.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To exchange for other money or currency of smaller
      denomination; as, to break a five dollar bill.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To destroy the strength, firmness, or consistency of; as,
       to break flax.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To weaken or impair, as health, spirit, or mind.
       [1913 Webster]

             An old man, broken with the storms of state.
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To diminish the force of; to lessen the shock of, as a
       fall or blow.
       [1913 Webster]

             I'll rather leap down first, and break your fall.
                                                  --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To impart, as news or information; to broach; -- with to,
       and often with a modified word implying some reserve; as,
       to break the news gently to the widow; to break a purpose
       cautiously to a friend.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. To tame; to reduce to subjection; to make tractable; to
       discipline; as, to break a horse to the harness or
       saddle. ``To break a colt.'' --Spenser.
       [1913 Webster]

             Why, then thou canst not break her to the lute?
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. To destroy the financial credit of; to make bankrupt; to
       ruin.
       [1913 Webster]

             With arts like these rich Matho, when he speaks,
             Attracts all fees, and little lawyers breaks.
                                                  --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. To destroy the official character and standing of; to
       cashier; to dismiss.
       [1913 Webster]

             I see a great officer broken.        --Swift.
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: With prepositions or adverbs: 
         [1913 Webster]

   {To break down}.
       (a) To crush; to overwhelm; as, to break down one's
           strength; to break down opposition.
       (b) To remove, or open a way through, by breaking; as, to
           break down a door or wall.

   {To break in}.
       (a) To force in; as, to break in a door.
       (b) To train; to discipline; as, a horse well broken in.
           

   {To break of}, to rid of; to cause to abandon; as, to break
      one of a habit.

   {To break off}.
       (a) To separate by breaking; as, to break off a twig.
       (b) To stop suddenly; to abandon. ``Break off thy sins by
           righteousness.'' --Dan. iv. 27.

   {To break open}, to open by breaking. ``Open the door, or I
      will break it open.'' --Shak.

   {To break out}, to take or force out by breaking; as, to
      break out a pane of glass.

   {To break out a cargo}, to unstow a cargo, so as to unload it
      easily.

   {To break through}.
       (a) To make an opening through, as, as by violence or the
           force of gravity; to pass violently through; as, to
           break through the enemy's lines; to break through the
           ice.
       (b) To disregard; as, to break through the ceremony.

   {To break up}.
       (a) To separate into parts; to plow (new or fallow
           ground). ``Break up this capon.'' --Shak. ``Break up
           your fallow ground.'' --Jer. iv. 3.
       (b) To dissolve; to put an end to. ``Break up the
           court.'' --Shak.

   {To break} (one) {all up}, to unsettle or disconcert
      completely; to upset. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: With an immediate object: 
         [1913 Webster]

   {To break the back}.
       (a) To dislocate the backbone; hence, to disable totally.
       (b) To get through the worst part of; as, to break the
           back of a difficult undertaking.

   {To break bulk}, to destroy the entirety of a load by
      removing a portion of it; to begin to unload; also, to
      transfer in detail, as from boats to cars.

   {To break a code} to discover a method to convert coded
      messages into the original understandable text.

   {To break cover}, to burst forth from a protecting
      concealment, as game when hunted.

   {To break a deer} or {To break a stag}, to cut it up and
      apportion the parts among those entitled to a share.

   {To break fast}, to partake of food after abstinence. See
      {Breakfast}.

   {To break ground}.
       (a) To open the earth as for planting; to commence
           excavation, as for building, siege operations, and
           the like; as, to break ground for a foundation, a
           canal, or a railroad.
       (b) Fig.: To begin to execute any plan.
       (c) (Naut.) To release the anchor from the bottom.

   {To break the heart}, to crush or overwhelm (one) with grief.
      

   {To break a house} (Law), to remove or set aside with
      violence and a felonious intent any part of a house or of
      the fastenings provided to secure it.

   {To break the ice}, to get through first difficulties; to
      overcome obstacles and make a beginning; to introduce a
      subject.

   {To break jail}, to escape from confinement in jail, usually
      by forcible means.

   {To break a jest}, to utter a jest. ``Patroclus . . . the
      livelong day breaks scurril jests.'' --Shak.

   {To break joints}, to lay or arrange bricks, shingles, etc.,
      so that the joints in one course shall not coincide with
      those in the preceding course.

   {To break a lance}, to engage in a tilt or contest.

   {To break the neck}, to dislocate the joints of the neck.

   {To break no squares}, to create no trouble. [Obs.]

   {To break a path}, {road}, etc., to open a way through
      obstacles by force or labor.

   {To break upon a wheel}, to execute or torture, as a criminal
      by stretching him upon a wheel, and breaking his limbs
      with an iron bar; -- a mode of punishment formerly
      employed in some countries.

   {To break wind}, to give vent to wind from the anus.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To dispart; rend; tear; shatter; batter; violate;
        infringe; demolish; destroy; burst; dislocate.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>road</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>road
     adj 1: taking place over public roads; "road racing" [syn: {road(a)}]
            [ant: {cross-country}]
     2: working for a short time in different places; "itinerant
        laborers"; "a road show"; "traveling salesman"; "touring
        company" [syn: {itinerant}, {touring}, {traveling}]
     n 1: an open way (generally public) for travel or transportation
          [syn: {route}]
     2: a way or means to achieve something; "the road to fame"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
