<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rocket</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rocket \Rock"et\, n. [F. roquette (cf. Sp. ruqueta, It
   ruchetta), fr. L. eruca.] (Bot.)
   (a) A cruciferous plant ({Eruca sativa}) sometimes eaten in
       Europe as a salad.
   (b) Damewort.
   (c) Rocket larkspur. See below.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Dyer's Rocket}. (Bot.) See {Dyer's broom}, under {Broom}.

   {Rocket larkspur} (Bot.), an annual plant with showy flowers
      in long racemes ({Delphinium Ajacis}).

   {Sea rocket} (Bot.), either of two fleshy cruciferous plants
      ({Cakile maritima} and {Cakile Americana}) found on the
      seashore of Europe and America.

   {Yellow rocket} (Bot.), a common cruciferous weed with yellow
      flowers ({Barbarea vulgaris}).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rocket \Rock"et\, n. [It. rocchetta, fr. rocca a distaff, of
   German origin. Named from the resemblance in shape to a
   distaff. See {Rock} a distaff.]
   1. An artificial firework consisting of a cylindrical case of
      paper or metal filled with a composition of combustible
      ingredients, as niter, charcoal, and sulphur, and fastened
      to a guiding stick. The rocket is projected through the
      air by the force arising from the expansion of the gases
      liberated by combustion of the composition. Rockets are
      used as projectiles for various purposes, for signals, and
      also for pyrotechnic display.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A blunt lance head used in the joust.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. any flying device propelled by the reactive force of hot
      gases expelled in the direction opposite its motion. The
      fuel used to generate the expelled gases in rockets may be
      solid or liquid; rockets propelled by liquid fuels
      typically have a combustible fuel (such as hydrogen or
      kerosene) which is combined inside the rocket engine with
      an oxidizer, such as liquid oxygen. Single liquid fuels
      (called monopropellants) are also known. Since rocket
      engines do not depend on a surrounding fluid medium to
      generate their thrust, as do airplanes with propellers or
      jet engines, they may be used for propulsion in the vacuum
      of space.
      [PJC]

   {Congreve rocket}, a powerful form of rocket for use in war,
      invented by Sir William Congreve. It may be used either in
      the field or for bombardment; in the former case, it is
      armed with shells or case shot; in the latter, with a
      combustible material inclosed in a metallic case, which is
      inextinguishable when kindled, and scatters its fire on
      every side.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rocket \Rock"et\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rocketed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Rocketing}.] (Sporting)
   To rise straight up; said of birds; usually in the present
   participle or as an adjective. [Eng.]
   [1913 Webster]

         An old cock pheasant came rocketing over me. --H. R.
                                                  Haggard.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Damewort \Dame"wort`\, n. (Bot.)
   A cruciferrous plant ({Hesperis matronalis}), remarkable for
   its fragrance, especially toward the close of the day; --
   called also {rocket} and {dame's violet}. --Loudon.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rocket
     n 1: any vehicle propelled by a rocket engine
     2: a jet engine containing its own propellant and driven by
        reaction propulsion [syn: {rocket engine}]
     3: erect European annual often grown as a salad crop to be
        harvested when young and tender [syn: {roquette}, {garden
        rocket}, {rocket salad}, {arugula}, {Eruca sativa}, {Eruca
        vesicaria sativa}]
     4: propels bright light high in the sky, or used to propel a
        lifesaving line or harpoon [syn: {skyrocket}]
     5: sends a firework display high into the sky [syn: {skyrocket}]
     v 1: shoot up abruptly, like a rocket; "prices skyrocketed" [syn:
           {skyrocket}]
     2: propel with a rocket
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
