<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rocker</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rocker \Rock"er\, n.
   1. One who rocks; specifically, one who rocks a cradle.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was I, sir, said the rocker, who had the honor,
            some thirty years since, to attend on your highness
            in your infancy.                      --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. One of the curving pieces of wood or metal on which a
      cradle, chair, etc., rocks.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any implement or machine working with a rocking motion, as
      a trough mounted on rockers for separating gold dust from
      gravel, etc., by agitation in water.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A play horse on rockers; a rocking-horse.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A chair mounted on rockers; a rocking-chair.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A skate with a curved blade, somewhat resembling in shape
      the rocker of a cradle.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mach.) Same as {Rock shaft}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Rocker arm} (Mach.), an arm borne by a rock shaft.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rock shaft \Rock" shaft`\ [Cf. {Rock}, v. i.] (Mach.)
   A shaft that oscillates on its journals, instead of
   revolving, -- usually carrying levers by means of which it
   receives and communicates reciprocating motion, as in the
   valve gear of some steam engines; -- called also {rocker},
   {rocking shaft}, and {way shaft}.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Cradle \Cra"dle\ (kr[=a]d'l), n. [AS. cradel, cradol, prob. from
   Celtic; cf. Gael. creathall, Ir. craidhal, W. cryd a shaking
   or rocking, a cradle; perh. akin to E. crate.]
   1. A bed or cot for a baby, oscillating on rockers or
      swinging on pivots; hence, the place of origin, or in
      which anything is nurtured or protected in the earlier
      period of existence; as, a cradle of crime; the cradle of
      liberty.
      [1913 Webster]

            The cradle that received thee at thy birth.
                                                  --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

            No sooner was I crept out of my cradle
            But I was made a king, at nine months old. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Infancy, or very early life.
      [1913 Webster]

            From their cradles bred together.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            A form of worship in which they had been educated
            from their cradles. --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Agric.) An implement consisting of a broad scythe for
      cutting grain, with a set of long fingers parallel to the
      scythe, designed to receive the grain, and to lay it
      evenly in a swath.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Engraving) A tool used in mezzotint engraving, which, by
      a rocking motion, raises burrs on the surface of the
      plate, so preparing the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A framework of timbers, or iron bars, moving upon ways or
      rollers, used to support, lift, or carry ships or other
      vessels, heavy guns, etc., as up an inclined plane, or
      across a strip of land, or in launching a ship.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Med.)
      (a) A case for a broken or dislocated limb.
      (b) A frame to keep the bedclothes from contact with the
          person.
          [1913 Webster]

   7. (Mining)
      (a) A machine on rockers, used in washing out auriferous
          earth; -- also called a {rocker}. [U.S.]
      (b) A suspended scaffold used in shafts.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Carp.) The ribbing for vaulted ceilings and arches
      intended to be covered with plaster. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) The basket or apparatus in which, when a line has
      been made fast to a wrecked ship from the shore, the
      people are brought off from the wreck.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Cat's cradle}. See under {Cat}.

   {Cradle hole}, a sunken place in a road, caused by thawing,
      or by travel over a soft spot.

   {Cradle scythe}, a broad scythe used in a cradle for cutting
      grain.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rocker</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rocker
     n 1: an attendant who rocks a child in a cradle
     2: a performer or composer or fan of rock music [syn: {rock 'n'
        roll musician}]
     3: a teenager or young adult in the 1960s who wore leather
        jackets and rode motorcycles
     4: a chair mounted on rockers [syn: {rocking chair}]
     5: a trough on rockers used by gold miners to shake earth in
        water in order to separate the gold [syn: {cradle}]
     6: an ice skate with a curved blade
     7: a curved support that permits the supported object to rock
        to and fro
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
