<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rogue</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rogue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rogue
     
        &lt;games&gt; [Unix] A Dungeons-and-Dragons-like game using
        character graphics, written under BSD Unix and subsequently
        ported to other Unix systems.  The original BSD "curses(3)"
        screen-handling package was hacked together by Ken Arnold to
        support "rogue(6)" and has since become one of Unix's most
        important and heavily used application libraries.  Nethack,
        Omega, Larn, and an entire subgenre of computer dungeon games
        all took off from the inspiration provided by "rogue(6)".  See
        also {nethack}.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rogue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rogue \Rogue\, n. [F. rogue proud, haughty, supercilious; cf.
   Icel. hr?kr a rook, croaker (cf. {Rook} a bird), or Armor.
   rok, rog, proud, arogant.]
   1. (Eng.Law) A vagrant; an idle, sturdy beggar; a vagabond; a
      tramp.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The phrase rogues and vagabonds is applied to a large
         class of wandering, disorderly, or dissolute persons.
         They were formerly punished by being whipped and having
         the gristle of the right ear bored with a hot iron.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. A deliberately dishonest person; a knave; a cheat.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rogue and fool by fits is fair and wise. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. One who is pleasantly mischievous or frolicsome; hence,
      often used as a term of endearment.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ah, you sweet little rogue, you!      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An elephant that has separated from a herd and roams about
      alone, in which state it is very savage.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Hort.) A worthless plant occuring among seedlings of some
      choice variety.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Rogues' gallery}, a collection of portraits of rogues or
      criminals, for the use of the police authorities.

   {Rogue's march}, derisive music performed in driving away a
      person under popular indignation or official sentence, as
      when a soldier is drummed out of a regiment.

   {Rogue's yarn}, yarn of a different twist and color from the
      rest, inserted into the cordage of the British navy, to
      identify it if stolen, or for the purpose of tracing the
      maker in case of defect. Different makers are required to
      use yarns of different colors.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rogue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rogue \Rogue\, v. i.
   To wander; to play the vagabond; to play knavish tricks.
   [Obs.] --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rogue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rogue \Rogue\, v. t.
   1. To give the name or designation of rogue to; to decry.
      [Obs.] --Cudworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Hort.) To destroy (plants that do not come up to a
      required standard).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rogue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rogue 1. [Unix] n. A Dungeons-and-Dragons-like game using character
   graphics, written under BSD Unix and subsequently ported to other Unix
   systems. The original BSD `curses(3)' screen-handling package was hacked
   together by Ken Arnold primarily to support games, and the development
   of `rogue(6)' popularized its use; it has since become one of Unix's
   most important and heavily used application libraries. Nethack, Omega,
   Larn, Angband, and an entire subgenre of computer dungeon games (all
   known as `roguelikes') all took off from the inspiration provided by
   `rogue(6)'; the popular Windows game Diablo, though graphics-intensive,
   has very similar play logic. See also {nethack}, {moria}, {Angband}. 2.
   [Usenet] adj. An {ISP} which permits net abuse (usually in the form of
   {spam}ming) by its customers, or which itself engages in such
   activities. Rogue ISPs are sometimes subject to {IDP}s or {UDP}s.
   Sometimes deliberately misspelled as "rouge".


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rogue</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rogue
     n : a deceitful and unreliable scoundrel [syn: {knave}, {rascal},
          {rapscallion}, {scalawag}, {scallywag}, {varlet}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
