<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>roller</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roller</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Roller \Roll"er\, n.
   1. One who, or that which, rolls; especially, a cylinder,
      sometimes grooved, of wood, stone, metal, etc., used in
      husbandry and the arts.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A bandage; a fillet; properly, a long and broad bandage
      used in surgery.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) One of series of long, heavy waves which roll in
      upon a coast, sometimes in calm weather.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A long, belt-formed towel, to be suspended on a rolling
      cylinder; -- called also {roller towel}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Print.) A cylinder coated with a composition made
      principally of glue and molassess, with which forms of
      type are inked previously to taking an impression from
      them. --W. Savage.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A long cylinder on which something is rolled up; as, the
      roller of a map.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A small wheel, as of a caster, a roller skate, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Zo["o]l.) ANy insect whose larva rolls up leaves; a leaf
      roller. see {Tortrix}.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. [CF. F. rollier.] (Zo["o]l.) Any one of numerous species
      of Old World picarian birds of the family {Coraciad[ae]}.
      The name alludes to their habit of suddenly turning over
      or ``tumbling'' in flight.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Many of the species are brilliantly colored. The common
         European species ({Coracias garrula}) has the head,
         neck, and under parts light blue varied with green, the
         scapulars chestnut brown, and the tail blue, green, and
         black. The broad-billed rollers of India and Africa
         belong to the genus {Eurystomus}, as the oriental
         roller ({Eurystomus orientalis}), and the Australian
         roller, or dollar bird ({Eurystomus Pacificus}). The
         latter is dark brown on the head and neck, sea green on
         the back, and bright blue on the throat, base of the
         tail, and parts of the wings. It has a silvery-white
         spot on the middle of each wing. The {lilac-breasted
         roller} of Africa is {Corcia caudata} caudata, a
         brightly colored bird of the family {Corciidae} having
         malachite green, blue, purple-lilac, brown and
         sea-green feathers from head to tail; it is a popular
         sight with tourists in Africa.
         [1913 Webster +PJC]

   10. (Zo["o]l.) Any species of small ground snakes of the
       family {Tortricid[ae]}.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Ground roller} (Zo["o]l.), any one of several species of
      Madagascar rollers belonging to {Atelornis} and allied
      genera. They are nocturnal birds, and feed on the ground.
      

   {Roller bolt}, the bar in a carriage to which the traces are
      attached; a whiffletree. [Eng.]

   {Roller gin}, a cotton gin inn which rolls are used for
      separating the seeds from the fiber.

   {Roller mill}. See under {Mill}.

   {Roller skate}, a skate which has small wheels in the place
      of the metallic runner; -- designed for use in skating
      upon a smooth, hard surface, other than ice.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roller</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>roller
     n 1: a grounder that rolls along the infield
     2: a long heavy sea wave as it advances towards the shore [syn:
         {roll}, {rolling wave}]
     3: a small wheel without spokes (as on a roller skate)
     4: a cylinder that revolves
     5: a mechanical device consisting of a cylindrical tube around
        which the hair is wound to curl it; "a woman with her head
        full of curlers is not a pretty sight" [syn: {curler}, {hair
        curler}, {crimper}]
     6: Old World bird that tumbles or rolls in flight; related to
        kingfishers
     7: pigeon that executes backward somersaults in flight or on
        the ground [syn: {tumbler}, {tumbler pigeon}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
