<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rolling</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rolling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Roll \Roll\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rolled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Rolling}.] [OF. roeler, roler, F. rouler, LL. rotulare, fr.
   L. royulus, rotula, a little wheel, dim. of rota wheel; akin
   to G. rad, and to Skr. ratha car, chariot. Cf. {Control},
   {Roll}, n., {Rotary}.]
   1. To cause to revolve by turning over and over; to move by
      turning on an axis; to impel forward by causing to turn
      over and over on a supporting surface; as, to roll a
      wheel, a ball, or a barrel.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To wrap round on itself; to form into a spherical or
      cylindrical body by causing to turn over and over; as, to
      roll a sheet of paper; to roll parchment; to roll clay or
      putty into a ball.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bind or involve by winding, as in a bandage; to inwrap;
      -- often with up; as, to roll up a parcel.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To drive or impel forward with an easy motion, as of
      rolling; as, a river rolls its waters to the ocean.
      [1913 Webster]

            The flood of Catholic reaction was rolled over
            Europe.                               --J. A.
                                                  Symonds.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To utter copiously, esp. with sounding words; to utter
      with a deep sound; -- often with forth, or out; as, to
      roll forth some one's praises; to roll out sentences.
      [1913 Webster]

            Who roll'd the psalm to wintry skies. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To press or level with a roller; to spread or form with a
      roll, roller, or rollers; as, to roll a field; to roll
      paste; to roll steel rails, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To move, or cause to be moved, upon, or by means of,
      rollers or small wheels.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To beat with rapid, continuous strokes, as a drum; to
      sound a roll upon.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Geom.) To apply (one line or surface) to another without
      slipping; to bring all the parts of (one line or surface)
      into successive contact with another, in suck manner that
      at every instant the parts that have been in contact are
      equal.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To turn over in one's mind; to revolve.
       [1913 Webster]

             Full oft in heart he rolleth up and down
             The beauty of these florins new and bright.
                                                  --Chaucer.
       [1913 Webster]
       [1913 Webster]

   {To roll one's self}, to wallow.

   {To roll the eye}, to direct its axis hither and thither in
      quick succession.

   {To roll one's r's}, to utter the letter r with a trill.
      [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rolling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rolling \Roll"ing\, a.
   1. Rotating on an axis, or moving along a surface by
      rotation; turning over and over as if on an axis or a
      pivot; as, a rolling wheel or ball.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Moving on wheels or rollers, or as if on wheels or
      rollers; as, a rolling chair.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Having gradual, rounded undulations of surface; as, a
      rolling country; rolling land. [U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Rolling bridge}. See the Note under {Drawbridge}.

   {Rolling circle of a paddle wheel}, the circle described by
      the point whose velocity equals the velocity of the ship.
      --J. Bourne.

   {Rolling fire} (Mil.), a discharge of firearms by soldiers in
      line, in quick succession, and in the order in which they
      stand.

   {Rolling friction}, that resistance to motion experienced by
      one body rolling upon another which arises from the
      roughness or other quality of the surfaces in contact.

   {Rolling mill}, a mill furnished with heavy rolls, between
      which heated metal is passed, to form it into sheets,
      rails, etc.

   {Rolling press}.
      (a) A machine for calendering cloth by pressure between
          revolving rollers.
      (b) A printing press with a roller, used in copperplate
          printing.

   {Rolling stock}, or {Rolling plant}, the locomotives and
      vehicles of a railway.

   {Rolling tackle} (Naut.), tackle used to steady the yards
      when the ship rolls heavily. --R. H. Dana, Jr.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rolling</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rolling
     adj 1: characterized by reverberation; "a resonant voice"; "hear
            the rolling thunder" [syn: {resonant}, {resonating}, {resounding},
             {reverberating}, {reverberative}]
     2: uttered with a trill; "she used rolling r's as in Spanish"
        [syn: {rolled}, {trilled}]
     3: moving in surges and billows and rolls; "billowing smoke
        from burning houses"; "the rolling fog"; "the rolling
        sea"; "the tumbling water of the rapids" [syn: {billowing},
         {tumbling}]
     n 1: a deep prolonged sound (as of thunder or large bells) [syn:
          {peal}, {pealing}, {roll}]
     2: the act of robbing a helpless person; "he was charged with
        rolling drunks in the park"
     3: propelling something on wheels [syn: {wheeling}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
