<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rome</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rome</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rome
   the most celebrated city in the world at the time of Christ. It
   is said to have been founded B.C. 753. When the New Testament
   was written, Rome was enriched and adorned with the spoils of
   the world, and contained a population estimated at 1,200,000, of
   which the half were slaves, and including representatives of
   nearly every nation then known. It was distinguished for its
   wealth and luxury and profligacy. The empire of which it was the
   capital had then reached its greatest prosperity.
   
     On the day of Pentecost there were in Jerusalem "strangers
   from Rome," who doubtless carried with them back to Rome tidings
   of that great day, and were instrumental in founding the church
   there. Paul was brought to this city a prisoner, where he
   remained for two years (Acts 28:30, 31) "in his own hired
   house." While here, Paul wrote his epistles to the Philippians,
   to the Ephesians, to the Colossians, to Philemon, and probably
   also to the Hebrews. He had during these years for companions
   Luke and Aristarchus (Acts 27:2), Timothy (Phil. 1:1; Col. 1:1),
   Tychicus (Eph. 6: 21), Epaphroditus (Phil. 4:18), and John Mark
   (Col. 4:10). (See {PAUL}.)
   
     Beneath this city are extensive galleries, called "catacombs,"
   which were used from about the time of the apostles (one of the
   inscriptions found in them bears the date A.D. 71) for some
   three hundred years as places of refuge in the time of
   persecution, and also of worship and burial. About four thousand
   inscriptions have been found in the catacombs. These give an
   interesting insight into the history of the church at Rome down
   to the time of Constantine.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rome</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ROME
     
        An experimental {object-oriented} language.
     
        ["The Point of View Notion for {Multiple Inheritance}",
        B. Carre et al, SIGPLAN Notices 25(10):312-321 (OOPSLA/ECOOP
        '90) (Oct 1990)].
     
        (1994-11-30)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rome</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rome, GA (city, FIPS 66668)
  Location: 34.26267 N, 85.18667 W
  Population (1990): 30326 (13099 housing units)
  Area: 62.7 sq km (land), 0.9 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 30161, 30165
Rome, IA (city, FIPS 68565)
  Location: 40.98331 N, 91.68074 W
  Population (1990): 124 (56 housing units)
  Area: 0.3 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Rome, IL (CDP, FIPS 65403)
  Location: 40.87838 N, 89.51171 W
  Population (1990): 1902 (735 housing units)
  Area: 5.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
Rome, IN
  Zip code(s): 47574
Rome, NY (city, FIPS 63418)
  Location: 43.22552 N, 75.48926 W
  Population (1990): 44350 (16661 housing units)
  Area: 194.1 sq km (land), 1.9 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 13440
Rome, OH (village, FIPS 68196)
  Location: 38.66481 N, 83.37907 W
  Population (1990): 99 (56 housing units)
  Area: 0.7 sq km (land), 0.1 sq km (water)
Rome, PA (borough, FIPS 65944)
  Location: 41.85791 N, 76.34163 W
  Population (1990): 475 (191 housing units)
  Area: 1.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 18837
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rome</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rome, strength; power

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rome</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rome
     n 1: capital and largest city of Italy; on the Tiber; seat of the
          Roman Catholic Church; formerly the capital of the Roman
          Republic and the Roman Empire [syn: {Roma}, {Eternal
          City}, {Italian capital}, {capital of Italy}]
     2: the leadership of the Roman Catholic Church
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
