<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>roulette</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roulette</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Roulette, PA
  Zip code(s): 16746
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roulette</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Roulette \Rou*lette"\, v. t.
   To make short incisions in with a roulette; to separate by
   incisions made with a roulette; as, to roulette a sheet of
   postage stamps.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roulette</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Roulette \Rou*lette"\, n. [F., properly, a little wheel or ball.
   See {Rouleau}, {Roll}.]
   1. A game of chance, in which a small ball is made to move
      round rapidly on a circle divided off into numbered red
      and black spaces, the one on which it stops indicating the
      result of a variety of wagers permitted by the game.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Fine Arts)
      (a) A small toothed wheel used by engravers to roll over a
          plate in order to order to produce rows of dots.
      (b) A similar wheel used to roughen the surface of a
          plate, as in making alterations in a mezzotint.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Geom.) the curve traced by any point in the plane of a
      given curve when the latter rolls, without sliding, over
      another fixed curve. See {Cycloid}, and {Epycycloid}.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A small toothed wheel used to make short incisions in
      paper, as a sheet of postage stamps to facilitate their
      separation.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roulette</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>roulette
     n 1: a line generated by a point on one figure rolling around a
          second figure [syn: {line roulette}]
     2: a wheel with teeth for making a row of perforations [syn: {toothed
        wheel}]
     3: a gambling game in which players bet on which compartment of
        a revolving wheel a small ball will come to rest in
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
