<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>round</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\, v. i. &amp; t. [From {Roun}.]
   To whisper. [obs.] --Shak. Holland.
   [1913 Webster]

         The Bishop of Glasgow rounding in his ear, ``Ye are not
         a wise man,'' . . . he rounded likewise to the bishop,
         and said, ``Wherefore brought ye me here?''
                                                  --Calderwood.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\, a. [OF. roond, roont, reond, F. rond, fr. L.
   rotundus, fr. rota wheel. See {Rotary}, and cf. {Rotund},
   {roundel}, {Rundlet}.]
   1. Having every portion of the surface or of the
      circumference equally distant from the center; spherical;
      circular; having a form approaching a spherical or a
      circular shape; orbicular; globular; as, a round ball.
      ``The big, round tears.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon the firm opacous globe
            Of this round world.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Having the form of a cylinder; cylindrical; as, the barrel
      of a musket is round.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Having a curved outline or form; especially, one like the
      arc of a circle or an ellipse, or a portion of the surface
      of a sphere; rotund; bulging; protuberant; not angular or
      pointed; as, a round arch; round hills. ``Their round
      haunches gored.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Full; complete; not broken; not fractional; approximately
      in even units, tens, hundreds, thousands, etc.; -- said of
      numbers.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pliny put a round number near the truth, rather than
            the fraction.                         --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Not inconsiderable; large; hence, generous; free; as, a
      round price.
      [1913 Webster]

            Three thousand ducats; 'tis a good round sum.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Round was their pace at first, but slackened soon.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Uttered or emitted with a full tone; as, a round voice; a
      round note.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Phonetics) Modified, as a vowel, by contraction of the
      lip opening, making the opening more or less round in
      shape; rounded; labialized; labial. See Guide to
      Pronunciation, [sect] 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Outspoken; plain and direct; unreserved; unqualified; not
      mincing; as, a round answer; a round oath. ``The round
      assertion.'' --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sir Toby, I must be round with you.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Full and smoothly expanded; not defective or abrupt;
      finished; polished; -- said of style, or of authors with
      reference to their style. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            In his satires Horace is quick, round, and pleasant.
                                                  --Peacham.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Complete and consistent; fair; just; -- applied to
       conduct.
       [1913 Webster]

             Round dealing is the honor of man's nature.
                                                  --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

   {At a round rate}, rapidly. --Dryden.

   {In round numbers}, approximately in even units, tens,
      hundreds, etc.; as, a bin holding 99 or 101 bushels may be
      said to hold in round numbers 100 bushels.

   {Round bodies} (Geom.), the sphere right cone, and right
      cylinder.

   {Round clam} (Zo["o]l.), the quahog.

   {Round dance} one which is danced by couples with a whirling
      or revolving motion, as the waltz, polka, etc.

   {Round game}, a game, as of cards, in which each plays on his
      own account.

   {Round hand}, a style of penmanship in which the letters are
      formed in nearly an upright position, and each separately
      distinct; -- distinguished from running hand.

   {Round robin}. [Perhaps F. round round + ruban ribbon.]
       (a) A written petition, memorial, remonstrance, protest,
           etc., the signatures to which are made in a circle so
           as not to indicate who signed first. ``No round
           robins signed by the whole main deck of the Academy
           or the Porch.'' --De Quincey.
       (b) (Zo["o]l.) The cigar fish.

   {Round shot}, a solid spherical projectile for ordnance.

   {Round Table}, the table about which sat King Arthur and his
      knights. See {Knights of the Round Table}, under {Knight}.
      

   {Round tower}, one of certain lofty circular stone towers,
      tapering from the base upward, and usually having a
      conical cap or roof, which crowns the summit, -- found
      chiefly in Ireland. They are of great antiquity, and vary
      in heigh from thirty-five to one hundred and thiry feet.
      

   {Round trot}, one in which the horse throws out his feet
      roundly; a full, brisk, quick trot. --Addison.

   {Round turn} (Naut.), one turn of a rope round a timber, a
      belaying pin, etc.

   {To bring up with a round turn}, to stop abruptly. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Circular; spherical; globular; globase; orbicular;
        orbed; cylindrical; full; plump; rotund.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\ (round), n.
   1. Anything round, as a circle, a globe, a ring. ``The golden
      round'' [the crown]. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            In labyrinth of many a round self-rolled. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A series of changes or events ending where it began; a
      series of like events recurring in continuance; a cycle; a
      periodical revolution; as, the round of the seasons; a
      round of pleasures.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence: A course ending where it began; a circuit; a beat;
      especially, one freguently or regulary traversed; also,
      the act of traversing a circuit; as, a watchman's round;
      the rounds of the postman.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A series of duties or tasks which must be performed in
      turn, and then repeated.
      [1913 Webster]

            the trivial round, the common task.   --Keble.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Hence: (Mining, Tunneling) One work cycle, consisting of
      drilling blast holes, loading them with explosive,
      blasting, mucking out, and, if necessary, installing
      temporary support.
      [RDH]

            . . . Inco is still much more advanced than other
            mining companies. He says that the LKAB mine in
            Sweden is the closest rival. He predicts that, by
            2008, Inco can reach a new productivity plateau,
            doubling the current mining productivity from 3,350
            tonnes to 6,350 tonnes per person per year. Another
            aim is to triple the mine cycle rate (the time to
            drill, blast and muck a round) from one cycle to
            three complete cycles per 24 hours.
                                                  --http://www.canadianminingjournal.com/issues/apr00/page10.asp
      [PJC]

   6. A course of action or conduct performed by a number of
      persons in turn, or one after another, as if seated in a
      circle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Women to cards may be compared: we play
            A round or two; which used, we throw away.
                                                  --Granville.
      [1913 Webster]

            The feast was served; the bowl was crowned;
            To the king's pleasure went the mirthful round.
                                                  --Prior.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence: A complete set of plays in a game or contest
      covering a standard number of individual plays or parts;
      as, a round of golf; a round of tennis.
      [PJC]

   8. Hence: One set of games in a tournament.
      [PJC]

   9. The time during which prize fighters or boxers are in
      actual contest without an intermission, as prescribed by
      their rules; a bout.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A circular dance.
       [1913 Webster]

             Come, knit hands, and beat the ground,
             In a light fantastic round.          --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. That which goes round a whole circle or company; as, a
       round of applause.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. Rotation, as in office; succession. --Holyday.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. The step of a ladder; a rundle or rung; also, a
       crosspiece which joins and braces the legs of a chair.
       [1913 Webster]

             All the rounds like Jacob's ladder rise. --Dryden.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Mil.)
       (a) A walk performed by a guard or an officer round the
           rampart of a garrison, or among sentinels, to see
           that the sentinels are faithful and all things safe;
           also, the guard or officer, with his attendants, who
           performs this duty; -- usually in the plural.
       (b) A general discharge of firearms by a body of troops
           in which each soldier fires once.
       (c) One piece of ammunition for a firearm, used by
           discharging one piece at a time; as, each soldier
           carried a hundred rounds of ammunition.
           [1913 Webster +PJC]

   15. (Mus.) A short vocal piece, resembling a catch in which
       three or four voices follow each other round in a species
       of canon in the unison.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. A brewer's vessel in which the fermentation is concluded,
       the yeast escaping through the bunghole.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. A vessel filled, as for drinking; as, to drink a round od
       ale together. [R.]
       [1913 Webster +PJC]

   18. An assembly; a group; a circle; as, a round of
       politicians. --Addison.
       [1913 Webster]

   19. (Naut.) See {Roundtop}.
       [1913 Webster]

   20. Same as {Round of beef}, below.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Gentlemen of the round}.
       (a) Gentlemen soldiers of low rank who made the rounds.
           See 10
       (a), above.
       (b) Disbanded soldiers who lived by begging. [Obs.]
           [1913 Webster]

                 Worm-eaten gentlemen of the round, such as have
                 vowed to sit on the skirts of the city, let
                 your provost and his half dozen of halberdiers
                 do what they can.                --B. Jonson.
           [1913 Webster]

   {Round of beef}, the part of the thigh below the aitchbone,
      or between the rump and the leg. See Illust. of {beef}.

   {Round steak}, a beefsteak cut from the round.

   {Sculpture in the round}, sculpture giving the full form, as
      of man; statuary, distinguished from relief.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\, prep.
   On every side of, so as to encompass or encircle; around;
   about; as, the people atood round him; to go round the city;
   to wind a cable round a windlass.
   [1913 Webster]

         The serpent Error twines round human hearts. --Cowper.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Round about}, an emphatic form for round or about. ``Moses .
      . . set them [The elders] round about the tabernacle.''
      --Num. xi. 24.

   {To come round}, to gain the consent of, or circumvent, (a
      person) by flattery or deception. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\, adv.
   1. On all sides; around.
      [1913 Webster]

            Round he throws his baleful eyes.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Circularly; in a circular form or manner; by revolving or
      reversing one's position; as, to turn one's head round; a
      wheel turns round.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. In circumference; as, a ball is ten inches round.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. From one side or party to another; as to come or turn
      round, -- that is, to change sides or opinions.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. By or in a circuit; by a course longer than the direct
      course; back to the starting point.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Through a circle, as of friends or houses.
      [1913 Webster]

            The invitations were sent round accordingly. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Roundly; fully; vigorously. [Obs.] --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   {All round}, over the whole place; in every direction.

   {All-round}, of general capacity; as, an all-round man.
      [Colloq.]

   {To bring one round}.
      (a) To cause one to change his opinions or line of
          conduct.
      (b) To restore one to health. [Colloq.]
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\, v. i.
   1. To grow round or full; hence, to attain to fullness,
      completeness, or perfection.
      [1913 Webster]

            The queen your mother rounds apace.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            So rounds he to a separate mind,
            From whence clear memory may begin.   --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To go round, as a guard. [Poetic]
      [1913 Webster]

            They . . . nightly rounding walk.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To go or turn round; to wheel about. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To round to} (Naut.), to turn the head of a ship toward the
      wind.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rounded}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Rounding}.]
   1. To make circular, spherical, or cylindrical; to give a
      round or convex figure to; as, to round a silver coin; to
      round the edges of anything.
      [1913 Webster]

            Worms with many feet, which round themselves into
            balls, are bred chiefly under logs of timber.
                                                  --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

            The figures on our modern medals are raised and
            rounded to a very great perfection.   --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To surround; to encircle; to encompass.
      [1913 Webster]

            The inclusive verge
            Of golden metal that must round my brow. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To bring to fullness or completeness; to complete; hence,
      to bring to a fit conclusion.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are such stuff
            As dreams are made on, and our little life
            Is rounded with a sleep.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To go round wholly or in part; to go about (a corner or
      point); as, to round a corner; to round Cape Horn.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To make full, smooth, and flowing; as, to round periods in
      writing. --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To round in} (Naut.) To haul up; usually, to haul the slack
      of (a rope) through its leading block, or to haul up (a
      tackle which hangs loose) by its fall. --Totten.
      (b) To collect together (cattle) by riding around them, as
          on cattle ranches. [Western U.S.]
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>round</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>round
     adj 1: having a circular shape [syn: {circular}] [ant: {square}]
     2: (of sounds) full and rich; "orotund tones"; "the rotund and
        reverberating phrase"; "pear-shaped vowels" [syn: {orotund},
         {rotund}, {pear-shaped}]
     3: (of numbers) to the nearest ten, hundred, or thousand; "in
        round numbers"
     n 1: a charge of ammunition for a single shot [syn: {unit of
          ammunition}, {one shot}]
     2: an interval during which a recurring sequence of events
        occurs; "the neverending cycle of the seasons" [syn: {cycle},
         {rhythm}]
     3: a regular route for a sentry or policeman; "in the old days
        a policeman walked a beat and knew all his people by name"
        [syn: {beat}]
     4: (often plural) a series of professional calls (usually in a
        set order); "the doctor goes on his rounds first thing
        every morning"; "the postman's rounds"; "we enjoyed our
        round of the local bars"
     5: the activity of playing 18 holes of golf; "a round of golf
        takes about 4 hours" [syn: {round of golf}]
     6: the usual activities in your day; "the doctor made his
        rounds" [syn: {daily round}]
     7: (sports) a period of play during which one team is on the
        offensive [syn: {turn}, {bout}]
     8: the course along which communications spread; "the story is
        going the rounds in Washington"
     9: a serving to each of a group (usually alcoholic); "he
        ordered a second round" [syn: {round of drinks}]
     10: a cut of beef between the rump and the lower leg
     11: a partsong in which voices follow each other; one voice
         starts and others join in one after another until all are
         singing different parts of the song at the same time;
         "they enjoyed singing rounds" [syn: {troll}]
     12: an outburst of applause; "there was a round of applause"
     13: a crosspiece between the legs of a chair [syn: {rung}, {stave}]
     14: any circular or rotating mechanism; "the machine punched out
         metal circles" [syn: {circle}]
     adv : from beginning to end; throughout; "It rains all year round
           on Skye"; "frigid weather the year around" [syn: {around}]
     v 1: wind around; move along a circular course; "round the bend"
     2: make round; "round the edges" [syn: {round out}, {round off}]
     3: be around; "Developments surround the town"; "The river
        encircles the village" [syn: {surround}, {environ}, {encircle},
         {circle}, {ring}]
     4: pronounce with rounded lips [syn: {labialize}, {labialise}]
     5: attack in speech or writing; "The editors of the
        left-leaning paper attacked the new House Speaker" [syn: {attack},
         {assail}, {lash out}, {snipe}, {assault}]
     6: bring to a highly developed, finished, or refined state;
        "polish your social manners" [syn: {polish}, {round off},
        {polish up}, {brush up}]
     7: express as a round number; "round off the amount" [syn: {round
        off}, {round down}, {round out}]
     8: become round, plump, or shapely; "The young woman is
        fleshing out" [syn: {flesh out}, {fill out}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
