<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>roundtable</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roundtable</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Round \Round\, a. [OF. roond, roont, reond, F. rond, fr. L.
   rotundus, fr. rota wheel. See {Rotary}, and cf. {Rotund},
   {roundel}, {Rundlet}.]
   1. Having every portion of the surface or of the
      circumference equally distant from the center; spherical;
      circular; having a form approaching a spherical or a
      circular shape; orbicular; globular; as, a round ball.
      ``The big, round tears.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon the firm opacous globe
            Of this round world.                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Having the form of a cylinder; cylindrical; as, the barrel
      of a musket is round.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Having a curved outline or form; especially, one like the
      arc of a circle or an ellipse, or a portion of the surface
      of a sphere; rotund; bulging; protuberant; not angular or
      pointed; as, a round arch; round hills. ``Their round
      haunches gored.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Full; complete; not broken; not fractional; approximately
      in even units, tens, hundreds, thousands, etc.; -- said of
      numbers.
      [1913 Webster]

            Pliny put a round number near the truth, rather than
            the fraction.                         --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Not inconsiderable; large; hence, generous; free; as, a
      round price.
      [1913 Webster]

            Three thousand ducats; 'tis a good round sum.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Round was their pace at first, but slackened soon.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Uttered or emitted with a full tone; as, a round voice; a
      round note.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Phonetics) Modified, as a vowel, by contraction of the
      lip opening, making the opening more or less round in
      shape; rounded; labialized; labial. See Guide to
      Pronunciation, [sect] 11.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Outspoken; plain and direct; unreserved; unqualified; not
      mincing; as, a round answer; a round oath. ``The round
      assertion.'' --M. Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]

            Sir Toby, I must be round with you.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Full and smoothly expanded; not defective or abrupt;
      finished; polished; -- said of style, or of authors with
      reference to their style. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            In his satires Horace is quick, round, and pleasant.
                                                  --Peacham.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. Complete and consistent; fair; just; -- applied to
       conduct.
       [1913 Webster]

             Round dealing is the honor of man's nature.
                                                  --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

   {At a round rate}, rapidly. --Dryden.

   {In round numbers}, approximately in even units, tens,
      hundreds, etc.; as, a bin holding 99 or 101 bushels may be
      said to hold in round numbers 100 bushels.

   {Round bodies} (Geom.), the sphere right cone, and right
      cylinder.

   {Round clam} (Zo["o]l.), the quahog.

   {Round dance} one which is danced by couples with a whirling
      or revolving motion, as the waltz, polka, etc.

   {Round game}, a game, as of cards, in which each plays on his
      own account.

   {Round hand}, a style of penmanship in which the letters are
      formed in nearly an upright position, and each separately
      distinct; -- distinguished from running hand.

   {Round robin}. [Perhaps F. round round + ruban ribbon.]
       (a) A written petition, memorial, remonstrance, protest,
           etc., the signatures to which are made in a circle so
           as not to indicate who signed first. ``No round
           robins signed by the whole main deck of the Academy
           or the Porch.'' --De Quincey.
       (b) (Zo["o]l.) The cigar fish.

   {Round shot}, a solid spherical projectile for ordnance.

   {Round Table}, the table about which sat King Arthur and his
      knights. See {Knights of the Round Table}, under {Knight}.
      

   {Round tower}, one of certain lofty circular stone towers,
      tapering from the base upward, and usually having a
      conical cap or roof, which crowns the summit, -- found
      chiefly in Ireland. They are of great antiquity, and vary
      in heigh from thirty-five to one hundred and thiry feet.
      

   {Round trot}, one in which the horse throws out his feet
      roundly; a full, brisk, quick trot. --Addison.

   {Round turn} (Naut.), one turn of a rope round a timber, a
      belaying pin, etc.

   {To bring up with a round turn}, to stop abruptly. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Circular; spherical; globular; globase; orbicular;
        orbed; cylindrical; full; plump; rotund.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roundtable</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Table \Ta"ble\, n. [F., fr. L. tabula a board, tablet, a
   painting. Cf. {Tabular}, {Taffrail}, {Tavern}.]
   1. A smooth, flat surface, like the side of a board; a thin,
      flat, smooth piece of anything; a slab.
      [1913 Webster]

            A bagnio paved with fair tables of marble. --Sandys.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A thin, flat piece of wood, stone, metal, or other
      material, on which anything is cut, traced, written, or
      painted; a tablet; pl. a memorandum book. ``The names . .
      . written on his tables.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            And the Lord said unto Moses, Hew thee two tables of
            stone like unto the first, and I will write upon
            these tables the words that were in the first
            tables, which thou brakest.           --Ex. xxxiv.
                                                  1.
      [1913 Webster]

            And stand there with your tables to glean
            The golden sentences.                 --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any smooth, flat surface upon which an inscription, a
      drawing, or the like, may be produced. ``Painted in a
      table plain.'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            The opposite walls are painted by Rubens, which,
            with that other of the Infanta taking leave of Don
            Philip, is a most incomparable table. --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

            St. Antony has a table that hangs up to him from a
            poor peasant.                         --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, in a great variety of applications: A condensed
      statement which may be comprehended by the eye in a single
      view; a methodical or systematic synopsis; the
      presentation of many items or particulars in one group; a
      scheme; a schedule. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) (Bibliog.) A view of the contents of a work; a
          statement of the principal topics discussed; an index;
          a syllabus; a synopsis; as, a table of contents.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) (Chem.) A list of substances and their properties;
          especially, the a list of the elementary substances
          with their atomic weights, densities, symbols, etc.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) (Mach.) Any collection and arrangement in a condensed
          form of many particulars or values, for ready
          reference, as of weights, measures, currency, specific
          gravities, etc.; also, a series of numbers following
          some law, and expressing particular values
          corresponding to certain other numbers on which they
          depend, and by means of which they are taken out for
          use in computations; as, tables of logarithms, sines,
          tangents, squares, cubes, etc.; annuity tables;
          interest tables; astronomical tables, etc.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) (Palmistry) The arrangement or disposition of the
          lines which appear on the inside of the hand.
          [1913 Webster]

                Mistress of a fairer table
                Hath not history for fable.       --B. Jonson.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. An article of furniture, consisting of a flat slab, board,
      or the like, having a smooth surface, fixed horizontally
      on legs, and used for a great variety of purposes, as in
      eating, writing, or working.
      [1913 Webster]

            We may again
            Give to our tables meat.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The nymph the table spread.           --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Hence, food placed on a table to be partaken of; fare;
      entertainment; as, to set a good table.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The company assembled round a table.
      [1913 Webster]

            I drink the general joy of the whole table. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Anat.) One of the two, external and internal, layers of
      compact bone, separated by diplo["e], in the walls of the
      cranium.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Arch.) A stringcourse which includes an offset; esp., a
      band of stone, or the like, set where an offset is
      required, so as to make it decorative. See {Water table}.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Games)
       (a) The board on the opposite sides of which backgammon
           and draughts are played.
       (b) One of the divisions of a backgammon board; as, to
           play into the right-hand table.
       (c) pl. The games of backgammon and of draughts. [Obs.]
           --Chaucer.
           [1913 Webster]

                 This is the ape of form, monsieur the nice,
                 That, when he plays at tables, chides the dice.
                                                  --Shak.
           [1913 Webster]

   11. (Glass Manuf.) A circular plate of crown glass.
       [1913 Webster]

             A circular plate or table of about five feet
             diameter weighs on an average nine pounds. --Ure.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Jewelry) The upper flat surface of a diamond or other
       precious stone, the sides of which are cut in angles.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Persp.) A plane surface, supposed to be transparent and
       perpendicular to the horizon; -- called also {perspective
       plane}.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Mach.) The part of a machine tool on which the work
       rests and is fastened.
       [1913 Webster]

   {Bench table}, {Card table}, {Communion table}, {Lord's
   table}, etc. See under {Bench}, {Card}, etc.

   {Raised table} (Arch. &amp; Sculp.), a raised or projecting
      member of a flat surface, large in proportion to the
      projection, and usually rectangular, -- especially
      intended to receive an inscription or the like.

   {Roller table} (Horology), a flat disk on the arbor of the
      balance of a watch, holding the jewel which rolls in and
      out of the fork at the end of the lever of the escapement.
      

   {Round table}. See Dictionary of Noted Names in Fiction.

   {Table anvil}, a small anvil to be fastened to a table for
      use in making slight repairs.

   {Table base}. (Arch.) Same as {Water table}.

   {Table bed}, a bed in the form of a table.

   {Table beer}, beer for table, or for common use; small beer.
      

   {Table bell}, a small bell to be used at table for calling
      servants.

   {Table cover}, a cloth for covering a table, especially at
      other than mealtimes.

   {Table diamond}, a thin diamond cut with a flat upper
      surface.

   {Table linen}, linen tablecloth, napkins, and the like.

   {Table money} (Mil. or Naut.), an allowance sometimes made to
      officers over and above their pay, for table expenses.

   {Table rent} (O. Eng. Law), rent paid to a bishop or
      religious, reserved or appropriated to his table or
      housekeeping. --Burrill.

   {Table shore} (Naut.), a low, level shore.

   {Table talk}, conversation at table, or at meals.

   {Table talker}, one who talks at table.

   {Table tipping}, {Table turning}, certain movements of
      tables, etc., attributed by some to the agency of departed
      spirits, and by others to the development of latent vital
      or spriritual forces, but more commonly ascribed to the
      muscular force of persons in connection with the objects
      moved, or to physical force applied otherwise.

   {Tables of a girder} or {Tables of a chord} (Engin.), the
      upper and lower horizontal members.

   {To lay on the table}, in parliamentary usage, to lay, as a
      report, motion, etc., on the table of the presiding
      officer, -- that is, to postpone the consideration of, by
      a vote; -- also called to {table} . It is a tactic often
      used with the intention of postponing consideration of a
      motion indefinitely, that is, to kill the motion.

   {To serve tables} (Script.), to provide for the poor, or to
      distribute provisions for their wants. --Acts vi. 2.

   {To turn the tables}, to change the condition or fortune of
      contending parties; -- a metaphorical expression taken
      from the vicissitudes of fortune in gaming.

   {Twelve tables} (Rom. Antiq.), a celebrated body of Roman
      laws, framed by decemvirs appointed 450 years before
      Christ, on the return of deputies or commissioners who had
      been sent to Greece to examine into foreign laws and
      institutions. They consisted partly of laws transcribed
      from the institutions of other nations, partly of such as
      were altered and accommodated to the manners of the
      Romans, partly of new provisions, and mainly, perhaps, of
      laws and usages under their ancient kings. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roundtable</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>round table
     n 1: a meeting of peers for discussion and exchange of views; "a
          roundtable on the future of computing" [syn: {roundtable},
           {round-table conference}]
     2: the legendary circular table for King Arthur and his knights
        [syn: {King Arthur's Round Table}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>roundtable</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>roundtable
     n : a meeting of peers for discussion and exchange of views; "a
         roundtable on the future of computing" [syn: {round table},
          {round-table conference}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
