<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>rub</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rub \Rub\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Rubbed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Rubbing}.] [Probably of Celtic origin; cf. W. rhwbiaw, gael.
   rub.]
   1. To subject (a body) to the action of something moving over
      its surface with pressure and friction, especially to the
      action of something moving back and forth; as, to rub the
      flesh with the hand; to rub wood with sandpaper.
      [1913 Webster]

            It shall be expedient, after that body is cleaned,
            to rub the body with a coarse linen cloth. --Sir T.
                                                  Elyot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move over the surface of (a body) with pressure and
      friction; to graze; to chafe; as, the boat rubs the
      ground.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause (a body) to move with pressure and friction along
      a surface; as, to rub the hand over the body.
      [1913 Webster]

            Two bones rubbed hard against one another.
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To spread a substance thinly over; to smear.
      [1913 Webster]

            The smoothed plank, . . .
            New rubbed with balm.                 --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To scour; to burnish; to polish; to brighten; to cleanse;
      -- often with up or over; as, to rub up silver.
      [1913 Webster]

            The whole business of our redemption is to rub over
            the defaced copy of the creation.     --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To hinder; to cross; to thwart. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            'T is the duke's pleasure,
            Whose disposition, all the world well knows,
            Will not be rubbed nor stopped.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To rub down}.
      (a) To clean by rubbing; to comb or curry; as, to down a
          horse.
      (b) To reduce or remove by rubbing; as, to rub down the
          rough points.

   {To rub off}, to clean anything by rubbing; to separate by
      friction; as, to rub off rust.

   {To rub out}, to remove or separate by friction; to erase; to
      obliterate; as, to rub out a mark or letter; to rub out a
      stain.

   {To rub up}.
      (a) To burnish; to polish; to clean.
      (b) To excite; to awaken; to rouse to action; as, to rub
          up the memory.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rub \Rub\, v. i.
   1. To move along the surface of a body with pressure; to
      grate; as, a wheel rubs against the gatepost.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fret; to chafe; as, to rub upon a sore.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To move or pass with difficulty; as, to rub through woods,
      as huntsmen; to rub through the world.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To rub along} or {on}, to go on with difficulty; as, they
      manage, with strict economy, to rub along. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Rub \Rub\, n. [Cf. W. rhwb. See Rub, v,t,]
   1. The act of rubbing; friction.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which rubs; that which tends to hinder or obstruct
      motion or progress; hindrance; obstruction, an impediment;
      especially, a difficulty or obstruction hard to overcome;
      a pinch.
      [1913 Webster]

            Every rub is smoothed on our way.     --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To sleep, perchance to dream; ay, there's the rub.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Upon this rub, the English ambassadors thought fit
            to demur.                             --Hayward.
      [1913 Webster]

            One knows not, certainly, what other rubs might have
            been ordained for us by a wise Providence. --W.
                                                  Besant.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Inequality of surface, as of the ground in the game of
      bowls; unevenness. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Something grating to the feelings; sarcasm; joke; as, a
      hard rub.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Imperfection; failing; fault. [Obs.] --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A chance. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Flight shall leave no Greek a rub.    --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A stone, commonly flat, used to sharpen cutting tools; a
      whetstone; -- called also {rubstone}.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Rub iron}, an iron guard on a wagon body, against which a
      wheel rubs when cramped too much.

   {Rub of the green} (Golf), anything happening to a ball in
      motion, such as its being deflected or stopped by any
      agency outside the match, or by the fore caddie.
      [1913 Webster + Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>rub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>rub
     n 1: an unforeseen obstacle [syn: {hang-up}, {hitch}, {snag}]
     2: the act of rubbing or wiping; "he gave the hood a quick rub"
        [syn: {wipe}]
     v 1: move over something with pressure; "rub my hands"; "rub oil
          into her skin"
     2: cause friction; "my sweater scratches" [syn: {fray}, {fret},
         {chafe}, {scratch}]
     3: scrape or rub as if to relieve itching; "Don't scratch your
        insect bites!" [syn: {scratch}, {itch}]
     [also: {rubbing}, {rubbed}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
