<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>run</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>run
     
        {execution}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Run \Run\, v. i. [imp. {Ran}or {Run}; p. p. {Run}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Running}.] [OE. rinnen, rennen (imp. ran, p. p. runnen,
   ronnen). AS. rinnan to flow (imp. ran, p. p. gerunnen), and
   iernan, irnan, to run (imp. orn, arn, earn, p. p. urnen);
   akin to D. runnen, rennen, OS. &amp; OHG. rinnan, G. rinnen,
   rennen, Icel. renna, rinna, Sw. rinna, r["a]nna, Dan. rinde,
   rende, Goth. rinnan, and perh. to L. oriri to rise, Gr. ? to
   stir up, rouse, Skr. ? (cf. {Origin}), or perh. to L. rivus
   brook (cf. {Rival}). [root]11. Cf. {Ember}, a., {Rennet}.]
   1. To move, proceed, advance, pass, go, come, etc., swiftly,
      smoothly, or with quick action; -- said of things animate
      or inanimate. Hence, to flow, glide, or roll onward, as a
      stream, a snake, a wagon, etc.; to move by quicker action
      than in walking, as a person, a horse, a dog.
      Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of voluntary or personal action:
      (a) To go swiftly; to pass at a swift pace; to hasten.
          [1913 Webster]

                ``Ha, ha, the fox!'' and after him they ran.
                                                  --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To flee, as from fear or danger.
          [1913 Webster]

                As from a bear a man would run for life. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To steal off; to depart secretly.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To contend in a race; hence, to enter into a contest;
          to become a candidate; as, to run for Congress.
          [1913 Webster]

                Know ye not that they which run in a race run
                all, but one receiveth the prize? So run, that
                ye may obtain.                    --1 Cor. ix.
                                                  24.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To pass from one state or condition to another; to
          come into a certain condition; -- often with in or
          into; as, to run into evil practices; to run in debt.
          [1913 Webster]

                Have I not cause to rave and beat my breast, to
                rend my heart with grief and run distracted?
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) To exert continuous activity; to proceed; as, to run
          through life; to run in a circle.
      (g) To pass or go quickly in thought or conversation; as,
          to run from one subject to another.
          [1913 Webster]

                Virgil, in his first Georgic, has run into a set
                of precepts foreign to his subject. --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (h) To discuss; to continue to think or speak about
          something; -- with on.
      (i) To make numerous drafts or demands for payment, as
          upon a bank; -- with on.
      (j) To creep, as serpents.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Of involuntary motion:
      (a) To flow, as a liquid; to ascend or descend; to course;
          as, rivers run to the sea; sap runs up in the spring;
          her blood ran cold.
      (b) To proceed along a surface; to extend; to spread.
          [1913 Webster]

                The fire ran along upon the ground. --Ex. ix.
                                                  23.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To become fluid; to melt; to fuse.
          [1913 Webster]

                As wax dissolves, as ice begins to run.
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

                Sussex iron ores run freely in the fire.
                                                  --Woodward.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To turn, as a wheel; to revolve on an axis or pivot;
          as, a wheel runs swiftly round.
      (e) To travel; to make progress; to be moved by mechanical
          means; to go; as, the steamboat runs regularly to
          Albany; the train runs to Chicago.
      (f) To extend; to reach; as, the road runs from
          Philadelphia to New York; the memory of man runneth
          not to the contrary.
          [1913 Webster]

                She saw with joy the line immortal run,
                Each sire impressed, and glaring in his son.
                                                  --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) To go back and forth from place to place; to ply; as,
          the stage runs between the hotel and the station.
      (h) To make progress; to proceed; to pass.
          [1913 Webster]

                As fast as our time runs, we should be very glad
                in most part of our lives that it ran much
                faster.                           --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (i) To continue in operation; to be kept in action or
          motion; as, this engine runs night and day; the mill
          runs six days in the week.
          [1913 Webster]

                When we desire anything, our minds run wholly on
                the good circumstances of it; when it is
                obtained, our minds run wholly on the bad ones.
                                                  --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
      (j) To have a course or direction; as, a line runs east
          and west.
          [1913 Webster]

                Where the generally allowed practice runs
                counter to it.                    --Locke.
          [1913 Webster]

                Little is the wisdom, where the flight
                So runs against all reason.       --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (k) To be in form thus, as a combination of words.
          [1913 Webster]

                The king's ordinary style runneth, ``Our
                sovereign lord the king.''        --Bp.
                                                  Sanderson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (l) To be popularly known; to be generally received.
          [1913 Webster]

                Men gave them their own names, by which they run
                a great while in Rome.            --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
          [1913 Webster]

                Neither was he ignorant what report ran of
                himself.                          --Knolles.
          [1913 Webster]
      (m) To have growth or development; as, boys and girls run
          up rapidly.
          [1913 Webster]

                If the richness of the ground cause turnips to
                run to leaves.                    --Mortimer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (n) To tend, as to an effect or consequence; to incline.
          [1913 Webster]

                A man's nature runs either to herbs or weeds.
                                                  --Bacon.
          [1913 Webster]

                Temperate climates run into moderate
                governments.                      --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
      (o) To spread and blend together; to unite; as, colors run
          in washing.
          [1913 Webster]

                In the middle of a rainbow the colors are . . .
                distinguished, but near the borders they run
                into one another.                 --I. Watts.
          [1913 Webster]
      (p) To have a legal course; to be attached; to continue in
          force, effect, or operation; to follow; to go in
          company; as, certain covenants run with the land.
          [1913 Webster]

                Customs run only upon our goods imported or
                exported, and that but once for all; whereas
                interest runs as well upon our ships as goods,
                and must be yearly paid.          --Sir J.
                                                  Child.
          [1913 Webster]
      (q) To continue without falling due; to hold good; as, a
          note has thirty days to run.
      (r) To discharge pus or other matter; as, an ulcer runs.
      (s) To be played on the stage a number of successive days
          or nights; as, the piece ran for six months.
      (t) (Naut.) To sail before the wind, in distinction from
          reaching or sailing closehauled; -- said of vessels.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically, of a horse: To move rapidly in a gait in
      which each leg acts in turn as a propeller and a
      supporter, and in which for an instant all the limbs are
      gathered in the air under the body. --Stillman (The Horse
      in Motion).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Athletics) To move rapidly by springing steps so that
      there is an instant in each step when neither foot touches
      the ground; -- so distinguished from walking in athletic
      competition.
      [1913 Webster]

   {As things run}, according to the usual order, conditions,
      quality, etc.; on the average; without selection or
      specification.

   {To let run} (Naut.), to allow to pass or move freely; to
      slacken or loosen.

   {To run after}, to pursue or follow; to search for; to
      endeavor to find or obtain; as, to run after similes.
      --Locke.

   {To run away}, to flee; to escape; to elope; to run without
      control or guidance.

   {To run away with}.
      (a) To convey away hurriedly; to accompany in escape or
          elopement.
      (b) To drag rapidly and with violence; as, a horse runs
          away with a carriage.

   {To run down}.
      (a) To cease to work or operate on account of the
          exhaustion of the motive power; -- said of clocks,
          watches, etc.
      (b) To decline in condition; as, to run down in health.

   {To run down a coast}, to sail along it.

   {To run for an office}, to stand as a candidate for an
      office.

   {To run in} or {To run into}.
      (a) To enter; to step in.
      (b) To come in collision with.

   {To run into} To meet, by chance; as, I ran into my brother
      at the grocery store.

   {To run in trust}, to run in debt; to get credit. [Obs.]

   {To run in with}.
      (a) To close; to comply; to agree with. [R.] --T. Baker.
      (b) (Naut.) To make toward; to near; to sail close to; as,
          to run in with the land.

   {To run mad}, {To run mad after} or {To run mad on}. See
      under {Mad}.

   {To run on}.
      (a) To be continued; as, their accounts had run on for a
          year or two without a settlement.
      (b) To talk incessantly.
      (c) To continue a course.
      (d) To press with jokes or ridicule; to abuse with
          sarcasm; to bear hard on.
      (e) (Print.) To be continued in the same lines, without
          making a break or beginning a new paragraph.

   {To run out}.
      (a) To come to an end; to expire; as, the lease runs out
          at Michaelmas.
      (b) To extend; to spread. ``Insectile animals . . . run
          all out into legs.'' --Hammond.
      (c) To expatiate; as, to run out into beautiful
          digressions.
      (d) To be wasted or exhausted; to become poor; to become
          extinct; as, an estate managed without economy will
          soon run out.
          [1913 Webster]

                And had her stock been less, no doubt
                She must have long ago run out.   --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To run over}.
      (a) To overflow; as, a cup runs over, or the liquor runs
          over.
      (b) To go over, examine, or rehearse cursorily.
      (c) To ride or drive over; as, to run over a child.

   {To run riot}, to go to excess.

   {To run through}.
      (a) To go through hastily; as to run through a book.
      (b) To spend wastefully; as, to run through an estate.

   {To run to seed}, to expend or exhaust vitality in producing
      seed, as a plant; figuratively and colloquially, to cease
      growing; to lose vital force, as the body or mind.

   {To run up}, to rise; to swell; to grow; to increase; as,
      accounts of goods credited run up very fast.
      [1913 Webster]

            But these, having been untrimmed for many years, had
            run up into great bushes, or rather dwarf trees.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To run with}.
      (a) To be drenched with, so that streams flow; as, the
          streets ran with blood.
      (b) To flow while charged with some foreign substance.
          ``Its rivers ran with gold.'' --J. H. Newman.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Run \Run\, v. i. [imp. {Ran}or {Run}; p. p. {Run}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Running}.] [OE. rinnen, rennen (imp. ran, p. p. runnen,
   ronnen). AS. rinnan to flow (imp. ran, p. p. gerunnen), and
   iernan, irnan, to run (imp. orn, arn, earn, p. p. urnen);
   akin to D. runnen, rennen, OS. &amp; OHG. rinnan, G. rinnen,
   rennen, Icel. renna, rinna, Sw. rinna, r["a]nna, Dan. rinde,
   rende, Goth. rinnan, and perh. to L. oriri to rise, Gr. ? to
   stir up, rouse, Skr. ? (cf. {Origin}), or perh. to L. rivus
   brook (cf. {Rival}). [root]11. Cf. {Ember}, a., {Rennet}.]
   1. To move, proceed, advance, pass, go, come, etc., swiftly,
      smoothly, or with quick action; -- said of things animate
      or inanimate. Hence, to flow, glide, or roll onward, as a
      stream, a snake, a wagon, etc.; to move by quicker action
      than in walking, as a person, a horse, a dog.
      Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of voluntary or personal action:
      (a) To go swiftly; to pass at a swift pace; to hasten.
          [1913 Webster]

                ``Ha, ha, the fox!'' and after him they ran.
                                                  --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To flee, as from fear or danger.
          [1913 Webster]

                As from a bear a man would run for life. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To steal off; to depart secretly.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To contend in a race; hence, to enter into a contest;
          to become a candidate; as, to run for Congress.
          [1913 Webster]

                Know ye not that they which run in a race run
                all, but one receiveth the prize? So run, that
                ye may obtain.                    --1 Cor. ix.
                                                  24.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To pass from one state or condition to another; to
          come into a certain condition; -- often with in or
          into; as, to run into evil practices; to run in debt.
          [1913 Webster]

                Have I not cause to rave and beat my breast, to
                rend my heart with grief and run distracted?
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) To exert continuous activity; to proceed; as, to run
          through life; to run in a circle.
      (g) To pass or go quickly in thought or conversation; as,
          to run from one subject to another.
          [1913 Webster]

                Virgil, in his first Georgic, has run into a set
                of precepts foreign to his subject. --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (h) To discuss; to continue to think or speak about
          something; -- with on.
      (i) To make numerous drafts or demands for payment, as
          upon a bank; -- with on.
      (j) To creep, as serpents.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Of involuntary motion:
      (a) To flow, as a liquid; to ascend or descend; to course;
          as, rivers run to the sea; sap runs up in the spring;
          her blood ran cold.
      (b) To proceed along a surface; to extend; to spread.
          [1913 Webster]

                The fire ran along upon the ground. --Ex. ix.
                                                  23.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To become fluid; to melt; to fuse.
          [1913 Webster]

                As wax dissolves, as ice begins to run.
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

                Sussex iron ores run freely in the fire.
                                                  --Woodward.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To turn, as a wheel; to revolve on an axis or pivot;
          as, a wheel runs swiftly round.
      (e) To travel; to make progress; to be moved by mechanical
          means; to go; as, the steamboat runs regularly to
          Albany; the train runs to Chicago.
      (f) To extend; to reach; as, the road runs from
          Philadelphia to New York; the memory of man runneth
          not to the contrary.
          [1913 Webster]

                She saw with joy the line immortal run,
                Each sire impressed, and glaring in his son.
                                                  --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) To go back and forth from place to place; to ply; as,
          the stage runs between the hotel and the station.
      (h) To make progress; to proceed; to pass.
          [1913 Webster]

                As fast as our time runs, we should be very glad
                in most part of our lives that it ran much
                faster.                           --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (i) To continue in operation; to be kept in action or
          motion; as, this engine runs night and day; the mill
          runs six days in the week.
          [1913 Webster]

                When we desire anything, our minds run wholly on
                the good circumstances of it; when it is
                obtained, our minds run wholly on the bad ones.
                                                  --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
      (j) To have a course or direction; as, a line runs east
          and west.
          [1913 Webster]

                Where the generally allowed practice runs
                counter to it.                    --Locke.
          [1913 Webster]

                Little is the wisdom, where the flight
                So runs against all reason.       --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (k) To be in form thus, as a combination of words.
          [1913 Webster]

                The king's ordinary style runneth, ``Our
                sovereign lord the king.''        --Bp.
                                                  Sanderson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (l) To be popularly known; to be generally received.
          [1913 Webster]

                Men gave them their own names, by which they run
                a great while in Rome.            --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
          [1913 Webster]

                Neither was he ignorant what report ran of
                himself.                          --Knolles.
          [1913 Webster]
      (m) To have growth or development; as, boys and girls run
          up rapidly.
          [1913 Webster]

                If the richness of the ground cause turnips to
                run to leaves.                    --Mortimer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (n) To tend, as to an effect or consequence; to incline.
          [1913 Webster]

                A man's nature runs either to herbs or weeds.
                                                  --Bacon.
          [1913 Webster]

                Temperate climates run into moderate
                governments.                      --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
      (o) To spread and blend together; to unite; as, colors run
          in washing.
          [1913 Webster]

                In the middle of a rainbow the colors are . . .
                distinguished, but near the borders they run
                into one another.                 --I. Watts.
          [1913 Webster]
      (p) To have a legal course; to be attached; to continue in
          force, effect, or operation; to follow; to go in
          company; as, certain covenants run with the land.
          [1913 Webster]

                Customs run only upon our goods imported or
                exported, and that but once for all; whereas
                interest runs as well upon our ships as goods,
                and must be yearly paid.          --Sir J.
                                                  Child.
          [1913 Webster]
      (q) To continue without falling due; to hold good; as, a
          note has thirty days to run.
      (r) To discharge pus or other matter; as, an ulcer runs.
      (s) To be played on the stage a number of successive days
          or nights; as, the piece ran for six months.
      (t) (Naut.) To sail before the wind, in distinction from
          reaching or sailing closehauled; -- said of vessels.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically, of a horse: To move rapidly in a gait in
      which each leg acts in turn as a propeller and a
      supporter, and in which for an instant all the limbs are
      gathered in the air under the body. --Stillman (The Horse
      in Motion).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Athletics) To move rapidly by springing steps so that
      there is an instant in each step when neither foot touches
      the ground; -- so distinguished from walking in athletic
      competition.
      [1913 Webster]

   {As things run}, according to the usual order, conditions,
      quality, etc.; on the average; without selection or
      specification.

   {To let run} (Naut.), to allow to pass or move freely; to
      slacken or loosen.

   {To run after}, to pursue or follow; to search for; to
      endeavor to find or obtain; as, to run after similes.
      --Locke.

   {To run away}, to flee; to escape; to elope; to run without
      control or guidance.

   {To run away with}.
      (a) To convey away hurriedly; to accompany in escape or
          elopement.
      (b) To drag rapidly and with violence; as, a horse runs
          away with a carriage.

   {To run down}.
      (a) To cease to work or operate on account of the
          exhaustion of the motive power; -- said of clocks,
          watches, etc.
      (b) To decline in condition; as, to run down in health.

   {To run down a coast}, to sail along it.

   {To run for an office}, to stand as a candidate for an
      office.

   {To run in} or {To run into}.
      (a) To enter; to step in.
      (b) To come in collision with.

   {To run into} To meet, by chance; as, I ran into my brother
      at the grocery store.

   {To run in trust}, to run in debt; to get credit. [Obs.]

   {To run in with}.
      (a) To close; to comply; to agree with. [R.] --T. Baker.
      (b) (Naut.) To make toward; to near; to sail close to; as,
          to run in with the land.

   {To run mad}, {To run mad after} or {To run mad on}. See
      under {Mad}.

   {To run on}.
      (a) To be continued; as, their accounts had run on for a
          year or two without a settlement.
      (b) To talk incessantly.
      (c) To continue a course.
      (d) To press with jokes or ridicule; to abuse with
          sarcasm; to bear hard on.
      (e) (Print.) To be continued in the same lines, without
          making a break or beginning a new paragraph.

   {To run out}.
      (a) To come to an end; to expire; as, the lease runs out
          at Michaelmas.
      (b) To extend; to spread. ``Insectile animals . . . run
          all out into legs.'' --Hammond.
      (c) To expatiate; as, to run out into beautiful
          digressions.
      (d) To be wasted or exhausted; to become poor; to become
          extinct; as, an estate managed without economy will
          soon run out.
          [1913 Webster]

                And had her stock been less, no doubt
                She must have long ago run out.   --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To run over}.
      (a) To overflow; as, a cup runs over, or the liquor runs
          over.
      (b) To go over, examine, or rehearse cursorily.
      (c) To ride or drive over; as, to run over a child.

   {To run riot}, to go to excess.

   {To run through}.
      (a) To go through hastily; as to run through a book.
      (b) To spend wastefully; as, to run through an estate.

   {To run to seed}, to expend or exhaust vitality in producing
      seed, as a plant; figuratively and colloquially, to cease
      growing; to lose vital force, as the body or mind.

   {To run up}, to rise; to swell; to grow; to increase; as,
      accounts of goods credited run up very fast.
      [1913 Webster]

            But these, having been untrimmed for many years, had
            run up into great bushes, or rather dwarf trees.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To run with}.
      (a) To be drenched with, so that streams flow; as, the
          streets ran with blood.
      (b) To flow while charged with some foreign substance.
          ``Its rivers ran with gold.'' --J. H. Newman.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Run \Run\, v. i. [imp. {Ran}or {Run}; p. p. {Run}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Running}.] [OE. rinnen, rennen (imp. ran, p. p. runnen,
   ronnen). AS. rinnan to flow (imp. ran, p. p. gerunnen), and
   iernan, irnan, to run (imp. orn, arn, earn, p. p. urnen);
   akin to D. runnen, rennen, OS. &amp; OHG. rinnan, G. rinnen,
   rennen, Icel. renna, rinna, Sw. rinna, r["a]nna, Dan. rinde,
   rende, Goth. rinnan, and perh. to L. oriri to rise, Gr. ? to
   stir up, rouse, Skr. ? (cf. {Origin}), or perh. to L. rivus
   brook (cf. {Rival}). [root]11. Cf. {Ember}, a., {Rennet}.]
   1. To move, proceed, advance, pass, go, come, etc., swiftly,
      smoothly, or with quick action; -- said of things animate
      or inanimate. Hence, to flow, glide, or roll onward, as a
      stream, a snake, a wagon, etc.; to move by quicker action
      than in walking, as a person, a horse, a dog.
      Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Of voluntary or personal action:
      (a) To go swiftly; to pass at a swift pace; to hasten.
          [1913 Webster]

                ``Ha, ha, the fox!'' and after him they ran.
                                                  --Chaucer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To flee, as from fear or danger.
          [1913 Webster]

                As from a bear a man would run for life. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To steal off; to depart secretly.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To contend in a race; hence, to enter into a contest;
          to become a candidate; as, to run for Congress.
          [1913 Webster]

                Know ye not that they which run in a race run
                all, but one receiveth the prize? So run, that
                ye may obtain.                    --1 Cor. ix.
                                                  24.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To pass from one state or condition to another; to
          come into a certain condition; -- often with in or
          into; as, to run into evil practices; to run in debt.
          [1913 Webster]

                Have I not cause to rave and beat my breast, to
                rend my heart with grief and run distracted?
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) To exert continuous activity; to proceed; as, to run
          through life; to run in a circle.
      (g) To pass or go quickly in thought or conversation; as,
          to run from one subject to another.
          [1913 Webster]

                Virgil, in his first Georgic, has run into a set
                of precepts foreign to his subject. --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (h) To discuss; to continue to think or speak about
          something; -- with on.
      (i) To make numerous drafts or demands for payment, as
          upon a bank; -- with on.
      (j) To creep, as serpents.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. Of involuntary motion:
      (a) To flow, as a liquid; to ascend or descend; to course;
          as, rivers run to the sea; sap runs up in the spring;
          her blood ran cold.
      (b) To proceed along a surface; to extend; to spread.
          [1913 Webster]

                The fire ran along upon the ground. --Ex. ix.
                                                  23.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To become fluid; to melt; to fuse.
          [1913 Webster]

                As wax dissolves, as ice begins to run.
                                                  --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]

                Sussex iron ores run freely in the fire.
                                                  --Woodward.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To turn, as a wheel; to revolve on an axis or pivot;
          as, a wheel runs swiftly round.
      (e) To travel; to make progress; to be moved by mechanical
          means; to go; as, the steamboat runs regularly to
          Albany; the train runs to Chicago.
      (f) To extend; to reach; as, the road runs from
          Philadelphia to New York; the memory of man runneth
          not to the contrary.
          [1913 Webster]

                She saw with joy the line immortal run,
                Each sire impressed, and glaring in his son.
                                                  --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) To go back and forth from place to place; to ply; as,
          the stage runs between the hotel and the station.
      (h) To make progress; to proceed; to pass.
          [1913 Webster]

                As fast as our time runs, we should be very glad
                in most part of our lives that it ran much
                faster.                           --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (i) To continue in operation; to be kept in action or
          motion; as, this engine runs night and day; the mill
          runs six days in the week.
          [1913 Webster]

                When we desire anything, our minds run wholly on
                the good circumstances of it; when it is
                obtained, our minds run wholly on the bad ones.
                                                  --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
      (j) To have a course or direction; as, a line runs east
          and west.
          [1913 Webster]

                Where the generally allowed practice runs
                counter to it.                    --Locke.
          [1913 Webster]

                Little is the wisdom, where the flight
                So runs against all reason.       --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (k) To be in form thus, as a combination of words.
          [1913 Webster]

                The king's ordinary style runneth, ``Our
                sovereign lord the king.''        --Bp.
                                                  Sanderson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (l) To be popularly known; to be generally received.
          [1913 Webster]

                Men gave them their own names, by which they run
                a great while in Rome.            --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
          [1913 Webster]

                Neither was he ignorant what report ran of
                himself.                          --Knolles.
          [1913 Webster]
      (m) To have growth or development; as, boys and girls run
          up rapidly.
          [1913 Webster]

                If the richness of the ground cause turnips to
                run to leaves.                    --Mortimer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (n) To tend, as to an effect or consequence; to incline.
          [1913 Webster]

                A man's nature runs either to herbs or weeds.
                                                  --Bacon.
          [1913 Webster]

                Temperate climates run into moderate
                governments.                      --Swift.
          [1913 Webster]
      (o) To spread and blend together; to unite; as, colors run
          in washing.
          [1913 Webster]

                In the middle of a rainbow the colors are . . .
                distinguished, but near the borders they run
                into one another.                 --I. Watts.
          [1913 Webster]
      (p) To have a legal course; to be attached; to continue in
          force, effect, or operation; to follow; to go in
          company; as, certain covenants run with the land.
          [1913 Webster]

                Customs run only upon our goods imported or
                exported, and that but once for all; whereas
                interest runs as well upon our ships as goods,
                and must be yearly paid.          --Sir J.
                                                  Child.
          [1913 Webster]
      (q) To continue without falling due; to hold good; as, a
          note has thirty days to run.
      (r) To discharge pus or other matter; as, an ulcer runs.
      (s) To be played on the stage a number of successive days
          or nights; as, the piece ran for six months.
      (t) (Naut.) To sail before the wind, in distinction from
          reaching or sailing closehauled; -- said of vessels.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. Specifically, of a horse: To move rapidly in a gait in
      which each leg acts in turn as a propeller and a
      supporter, and in which for an instant all the limbs are
      gathered in the air under the body. --Stillman (The Horse
      in Motion).
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Athletics) To move rapidly by springing steps so that
      there is an instant in each step when neither foot touches
      the ground; -- so distinguished from walking in athletic
      competition.
      [1913 Webster]

   {As things run}, according to the usual order, conditions,
      quality, etc.; on the average; without selection or
      specification.

   {To let run} (Naut.), to allow to pass or move freely; to
      slacken or loosen.

   {To run after}, to pursue or follow; to search for; to
      endeavor to find or obtain; as, to run after similes.
      --Locke.

   {To run away}, to flee; to escape; to elope; to run without
      control or guidance.

   {To run away with}.
      (a) To convey away hurriedly; to accompany in escape or
          elopement.
      (b) To drag rapidly and with violence; as, a horse runs
          away with a carriage.

   {To run down}.
      (a) To cease to work or operate on account of the
          exhaustion of the motive power; -- said of clocks,
          watches, etc.
      (b) To decline in condition; as, to run down in health.

   {To run down a coast}, to sail along it.

   {To run for an office}, to stand as a candidate for an
      office.

   {To run in} or {To run into}.
      (a) To enter; to step in.
      (b) To come in collision with.

   {To run into} To meet, by chance; as, I ran into my brother
      at the grocery store.

   {To run in trust}, to run in debt; to get credit. [Obs.]

   {To run in with}.
      (a) To close; to comply; to agree with. [R.] --T. Baker.
      (b) (Naut.) To make toward; to near; to sail close to; as,
          to run in with the land.

   {To run mad}, {To run mad after} or {To run mad on}. See
      under {Mad}.

   {To run on}.
      (a) To be continued; as, their accounts had run on for a
          year or two without a settlement.
      (b) To talk incessantly.
      (c) To continue a course.
      (d) To press with jokes or ridicule; to abuse with
          sarcasm; to bear hard on.
      (e) (Print.) To be continued in the same lines, without
          making a break or beginning a new paragraph.

   {To run out}.
      (a) To come to an end; to expire; as, the lease runs out
          at Michaelmas.
      (b) To extend; to spread. ``Insectile animals . . . run
          all out into legs.'' --Hammond.
      (c) To expatiate; as, to run out into beautiful
          digressions.
      (d) To be wasted or exhausted; to become poor; to become
          extinct; as, an estate managed without economy will
          soon run out.
          [1913 Webster]

                And had her stock been less, no doubt
                She must have long ago run out.   --Dryden.
          [1913 Webster]

   {To run over}.
      (a) To overflow; as, a cup runs over, or the liquor runs
          over.
      (b) To go over, examine, or rehearse cursorily.
      (c) To ride or drive over; as, to run over a child.

   {To run riot}, to go to excess.

   {To run through}.
      (a) To go through hastily; as to run through a book.
      (b) To spend wastefully; as, to run through an estate.

   {To run to seed}, to expend or exhaust vitality in producing
      seed, as a plant; figuratively and colloquially, to cease
      growing; to lose vital force, as the body or mind.

   {To run up}, to rise; to swell; to grow; to increase; as,
      accounts of goods credited run up very fast.
      [1913 Webster]

            But these, having been untrimmed for many years, had
            run up into great bushes, or rather dwarf trees.
                                                  --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To run with}.
      (a) To be drenched with, so that streams flow; as, the
          streets ran with blood.
      (b) To flow while charged with some foreign substance.
          ``Its rivers ran with gold.'' --J. H. Newman.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Run \Run\, v. t.
   1. To cause to run (in the various senses of {Run}, v. i.);
      as, to run a horse; to run a stage; to run a machine; to
      run a rope through a block.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pursue in thought; to carry in contemplation.
      [1913 Webster]

            To run the world back to its first original.
                                                  --South.
      [1913 Webster]

            I would gladly understand the formation of a soul,
            and run it up to its ``punctum saliens.'' --Collier.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To cause to enter; to thrust; as, to run a sword into or
      through the body; to run a nail into the foot.
      [1913 Webster]

            You run your head into the lion's mouth. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

            Having run his fingers through his hair. --Dickens.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To drive or force; to cause, or permit, to be driven.
      [1913 Webster]

            They ran the ship aground.            --Acts xxvii.
                                                  41.
      [1913 Webster]

            A talkative person runs himself upon great
            inconveniences by blabbing out his own or other's
            secrets.                              --Ray.
      [1913 Webster]

            Others, accustomed to retired speculations, run
            natural philosophy into metaphysical notions.
                                                  --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To fuse; to shape; to mold; to cast; as, to run bullets,
      and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            The purest gold must be run and washed. --Felton.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cause to be drawn; to mark out; to indicate; to
      determine; as, to run a line.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To cause to pass, or evade, offical restrictions; to
      smuggle; -- said of contraband or dutiable goods.
      [1913 Webster]

            Heavy impositions . . . are a strong temptation of
            running goods.                        --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To go through or accomplish by running; as, to run a race;
      to run a certain career.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To cause to stand as a candidate for office; to support
      for office; as, to run some one for Congress. [Colloq.
      U.S.]
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To encounter or incur, as a danger or risk; as, to run
       the risk of losing one's life. See To run the chances,
       below. ``He runneth two dangers.'' --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

             If we don't succeed, we run the risk of failure.
                                                  --Dan Quail
       .
       [PJC]

   11. To put at hazard; to venture; to risk.
       [1913 Webster]

             He would himself be in the Highlands to receive
             them, and run his fortune with them. --Clarendon.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To discharge; to emit; to give forth copiously; to be
       bathed with; as, the pipe or faucet runs hot water.
       [1913 Webster]

             At the base of Pompey's statua,
             Which all the while ran blood, great C[ae]sar fell.
                                                  --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To be charged with, or to contain much of, while flowing;
       as, the rivers ran blood.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. To conduct; to manage; to carry on; as, to run a factory
       or a hotel. [Colloq. U.S.]
       [1913 Webster]

   15. To tease with sarcasms and ridicule. [Colloq.]
       [1913 Webster]

   16. To sew, as a seam, by passing the needle through material
       in a continuous line, generally taking a series of
       stitches on the needle at the same time.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. To migrate or move in schools; -- said of fish; esp., to
       ascend a river in order to spawn.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. (Golf) To strike (the ball) in such a way as to cause it
       to run along the ground, as when approaching a hole.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To run a blockade}, to get to, or away from, a blockaded
      port in safety.

   {To run down}.
       (a) (Hunting) To chase till the object pursued is
           captured or exhausted; as, to run down a stag.
       (b) (Naut.) To run against and sink, as a vessel.
       (c) To crush; to overthrow; to overbear. ``Religion is
           run down by the license of these times.'' --Berkeley.
       (d) To disparage; to traduce. --F. W. Newman.

   {To run hard}.
       (a) To press in competition; as, to run one hard in a
           race.
       (b) To urge or press importunately.
       (c) To banter severely.

   {To run into the ground}, to carry to an absurd extreme; to
      overdo. [Slang, U.S.]
       (c) To erect hastily, as a building.
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Run \Run\, n.
   1. The act of running; as, a long run; a good run; a quick
      run; to go on the run.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A small stream; a brook; a creek.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which runs or flows in the course of a certain
      operation, or during a certain time; as, a run of must in
      wine making; the first run of sap in a maple orchard.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A course; a series; that which continues in a certain
      course or series; as, a run of good or bad luck.
      [1913 Webster]

            They who made their arrangements in the first run of
            misadventure . . . put a seal on their calamities.
                                                  --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. State of being current; currency; popularity.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is impossible for detached papers to have a
            general run, or long continuance, if not diversified
            with humor.                           --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Continued repetition on the stage; -- said of a play; as,
      to have a run of a hundred successive nights.
      [1913 Webster]

            A canting, mawkish play . . . had an immense run.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A continuing urgent demand; especially, a pressure on a
      bank or treasury for payment of its notes.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A range or extent of ground for feeding stock; as, a sheep
      run. --Howitt.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.)
      (a) The aftermost part of a vessel's hull where it narrows
          toward the stern, under the quarter.
      (b) The distance sailed by a ship; as, a good run; a run
          of fifty miles.
      (c) A voyage; as, a run to China.
          [1913 Webster]

   10. A pleasure excursion; a trip. [Colloq.]
       [1913 Webster]

             I think of giving her a run in London. --Dickens.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Mining) The horizontal distance to which a drift may be
       carried, either by license of the proprietor of a mine or
       by the nature of the formation; also, the direction which
       a vein of ore or other substance takes.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Mus.) A roulade, or series of running tones.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. (Mil.) The greatest degree of swiftness in marching. It
       is executed upon the same principles as the double-quick,
       but with greater speed.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. The act of migrating, or ascending a river to spawn; --
       said of fish; also, an assemblage or school of fishes
       which migrate, or ascend a river for the purpose of
       spawning.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Sport) In baseball, a complete circuit of the bases made
       by a player, which enables him to score one point; also,
       the point thus scored; in cricket, a passing from one
       wicket to the other, by which one point is scored; as, a
       player made three runs; the side went out with two
       hundred runs; the Yankees scored three runs in the
       seventh inning.
       [1913 Webster +PJC]

             The ``runs'' are made from wicket to wicket, the
             batsmen interchanging ends at each run. --R. A.
                                                  Proctor.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. A pair or set of millstones.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Piquet, Cribbage, etc.) A number of cards of the same
       suit in sequence; as, a run of four in hearts.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   18. (Golf)
       (a) The movement communicated to a golf ball by running.
       (b) The distance a ball travels after touching the ground
           from a stroke.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {At the long run}, now, commonly, {In the long run}, in or
      during the whole process or course of things taken
      together; in the final result; in the end; finally.
      [1913 Webster]

            [Man] starts the inferior of the brute animals, but
            he surpasses them in the long run.    --J. H.
                                                  Newman.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Home run}.
       (a) A running or returning toward home, or to the point
           from which the start was made. Cf. {Home stretch}.
       (b) (Baseball) See under {Home}.

   {The run}, or {The common run}, or {The run of the mill}
      etc., ordinary persons; the generality or average of
      people or things; also, that which ordinarily occurs;
      ordinary current, course, or kind.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            I saw nothing else that is superior to the common
            run of parks.                         --Walpole.
      [1913 Webster]

            Burns never dreamed of looking down on others as
            beneath him, merely because he was conscious of his
            own vast superiority to the common run of men.
                                                  --Prof.
                                                  Wilson.
      [1913 Webster]

            His whole appearance was something out of the common
            run.                                  --W. Irving.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To let go by the run} (Naut.), to loosen and let run freely,
      as lines; to let fall without restraint, as a sail.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Run \Run\, a.
   1. Melted, or made from molten material; cast in a mold; as,
      run butter; run iron or lead.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Smuggled; as, run goods. [Colloq.] --Miss Edgeworth.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Run steel}, malleable iron castings. See under {Malleable}.
      --Raymond.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>run</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>run
     n 1: a score in baseball made by a runner touching all four bases
          safely; "the Yankees scored 3 runs in the bottom of the
          9th"; "their first tally came in the 3rd inning" [syn: {tally}]
     2: the act of testing something; "in the experimental trials
        the amount of carbon was measured separately"; "he called
        each flip of the coin a new trial" [syn: {test}, {trial}]
     3: a race run on foot; "she broke the record for the half-mile
        run" [syn: {footrace}, {foot race}]
     4: an unbroken series of events; "had a streak of bad luck";
        "Nicklaus had a run of birdies" [syn: {streak}]
     5: (American football) a play in which a player runs with the
        ball; "the defensive line braced to stop the run"; "the
        coach put great emphasis on running" [syn: {running}, {running
        play}, {running game}]
     6: a regular trip; "the ship made its run in record time"
     7: the act of running; traveling on foot at a fast pace; "he
        broke into a run"; "his daily run keeps him fit" [syn: {running}]
     8: the continuous period of time during which something (a
        machine or a factory) operates or continues in operation;
        "the assembly line was on a 12-hour run"
     9: unrestricted freedom to use; "he has the run of the house"
     10: the production achieved during a continuous period of
         operation (of a machine or factory etc.); "a daily run of
         100,000 gallons of paint"
     11: a small stream [syn: {rivulet}, {rill}, {runnel}, {streamlet}]
     12: a race between candidates for elective office; "I managed
         his campaign for governor"; "he is raising money for a
         Senate run" [syn: {political campaign}, {campaign}]
     13: a row of unravelled stitches; "she got a run in her
         stocking" [syn: {ladder}, {ravel}]
     14: the pouring forth of a fluid [syn: {discharge}, {outpouring}]
     15: an unbroken chronological sequence; "the play had a long run
         on Broadway"; "the team enjoyed a brief run of victories"
     16: a short trip; "take a run into town"
     v 1: move fast by using one's feet, with one foot off the ground
          at any given time; "Don't run--you'll be out of breath";
          "The children ran to the store"
     2: flee; take to one's heels; cut and run; "If you see this
        man, run!"; "The burglars escaped before the police showed
        up" [syn: {scarper}, {turn tail}, {lam}, {run away}, {hightail
        it}, {bunk}, {head for the hills}, {take to the woods}, {escape},
         {fly the coop}, {break away}]
     3: stretch out over a distance, space, time, or scope; run or
        extend between two points or beyond a certain point;
        "Service runs all the way to Cranbury"; "His knowledge
        doesn't go very far"; "My memory extends back to my fourth
        year of life"; "The facts extend beyond a consideration of
        her personal assets" [syn: {go}, {pass}, {lead}, {extend}]
     4: direct or control; projects, businesses, etc.; "She is
        running a relief operation in the Sudan" [syn: {operate}]
     5: have a particular form; "the story or argument runs as
        follows"; "as the saying goes..." [syn: {go}]
     6: move along, of liquids; "Water flowed into the cave"; "the
        Missouri feeds into the Mississippi" [syn: {flow}, {feed},
         {course}]
     7: perform as expected when applied; "The washing machine won't
        go unless it's plugged in"; "Does this old car still run
        well?"; "This old radio doesn't work anymore" [syn: {function},
         {work}, {operate}, {go}] [ant: {malfunction}]
     8: change or be different within limits; "Estimates for the
        losses in the earthquake range as high as $2 billion";
        "Interest rates run from 5 to 10 percent"; "The
        instruments ranged from tuba to cymbals"; "My students
        range from very bright to dull" [syn: {range}]
     9: run, stand, or compete for an office or a position; "Who's
        running for treasurer this year?" [syn: {campaign}]
     10: cause to emit recorded sounds; "They ran the tapes over and
         over again"; "Can you play my favorite record?" [syn: {play}]
     11: move about freely and without restraint, or act as if
         running around in an uncontrolled way; "who are these
         people running around in the building?"; "She runs around
         telling everyone of her troubles"; "let the dogs run
         free"
     12: have a tendency or disposition to do or be something; be
         inclined; "She tends to be nervous before her lectures";
         "These dresses run small"; "He inclined to corpulence"
         [syn: {tend}, {be given}, {lean}, {incline}]
     13: carry out a process or program, as on a computer or a
         machine; "Run the dishwasher"; "run a new program on the
         Mac"; "the computer executed the instruction" [syn: {execute}]
     14: be operating, running or functioning; "The car is still
         running--turn it off!" [ant: {idle}]
     15: change from one state to another; "run amok"; "run rogue";
         "run riot"
     16: cause to perform; "run a subject"; "run a process"
     17: be affected by; be subjected to; "run a temperature"; "run a
         risk"
     18: continue to exist; "These stories die hard"; "The legend of
         Elvis endures" [syn: {prevail}, {persist}, {die hard}, {endure}]
     19: occur persistently; "Musical talent runs in the family"
     20: include as the content; broadcast or publicize; "We ran the
         ad three times"; "This paper carries a restaurant
         review"; "All major networks carried the press
         conference" [syn: {carry}]
     21: carry out; "run an errand"
     22: guide or pass over something; "He ran his eyes over her
         body"; "She ran her fingers along the carved figurine";
         "He drew her hair through his fingers" [syn: {guide}, {draw},
          {pass}]
     23: cause something to pass or lead somewhere; "Run the wire
         behind the cabinet" [syn: {lead}]
     24: make without a miss
     25: deal in illegally, such as arms or liquor [syn: {black
         market}]
     26: cause an animal to move fast; "run the dogs"
     27: be diffused; "These dyes and colors are guaranteed not to
         run" [syn: {bleed}]
     28: sail before the wind
     29: cover by running; run a certain distance; "She ran 10 miles
         that day"
     30: extend or continue for a certain period of time; "The film
         runs 5 hours" [syn: {run for}]
     31: set animals loose to graze
     32: keep company; "the heifers run with the bulls ot produce
         offspring" [syn: {consort}]
     33: run with the ball; in such sports as football
     34: travel rapidly, by any (unspecified) means; "Run to the
         store!"; "She always runs to Italy, because she has a
         lover there"
     35: travel a route regularly; "Ships ply the waters near the
         coast" [syn: {ply}]
     36: pursue for food or sport (as of wild animals); "Goering
         often hunted wild boars in Poland"; "The dogs are running
         deer"; "The Duke hunted in these woods" [syn: {hunt}, {hunt
         down}, {track down}]
     37: compete in a race; "he is running the Marathon this year";
         "let's race and see who gets there first" [syn: {race}]
     38: progress by being changed; "The speech has to go through
         several more drafts"; "run through your presentation
         before the meeting" [syn: {move}, {go}]
     39: reduce or cause to be reduced from a solid to a liquid
         state, usually by heating; "melt butter"; "melt down
         gold"; "The wax melted in the sun" [syn: {melt}, {melt
         down}]
     40: come unraveled or undone as if by snagging; "Her nylons were
         running" [syn: {ladder}]
     41: become undone; "the sweater unraveled" [syn: {unravel}]
     [also: {running}, {ran}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
