<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ruth</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ruth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ruth
   a friend, a Moabitess, the wife of Mahlon, whose father,
   Elimelech, had settled in the land of Moab. On the death of
   Elimelech and Mahlon, Naomi came with Ruth, her daughter-in-law,
   who refused to leave her, to Bethlehem, the old home from which
   Elimelech had migrated. There she had a rich relative, Boaz, to
   whom Ruth was eventually married. She became the mother of Obed,
   the grandfather of David. Thus Ruth, a Gentile, is among the
   maternal progenitors of our Lord (Matt. 1:5). The story of "the
   gleaner Ruth illustrates the friendly relations between the good
   Boaz and his reapers, the Jewish land system, the method of
   transferring property from one person to another, the working of
   the Mosaic law for the relief of distressed and ruined families;
   but, above all, handing down the unselfishness, the brave love,
   the unshaken trustfulness of her who, though not of the chosen
   race, was, like the Canaanitess Tamar (Gen. 38:29; Matt. 1:3)
   and the Canaanitess Rahab (Matt. 1:5), privileged to become the
   ancestress of David, and so of 'great David's greater Son'"
   (Ruth 4:18-22).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ruth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>RUTH
     
        D.A. Harrison at Newcastle University.  Real-time language
        based on LispKit.  Uses timestamps and real-time clocks.
     
        ["RUTH: A Functional Language for Real-Time Programming",
        D. Harrison in PARLE: Parallel Architectures and Languages
        Europe, LNCS 259, Springer 1987, pp.297-314].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ruth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ruth, CA
  Zip code(s): 95526
Ruth, MI
  Zip code(s): 48470
Ruth, MS
  Zip code(s): 39662
Ruth, NC (town, FIPS 58420)
  Location: 35.38373 N, 81.94541 W
  Population (1990): 366 (147 housing units)
  Area: 1.1 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ruth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ruth \Ruth\ (r[udd]th), n. [From {Rue}, v.: cf. Icel.
   hrygg[eth], hryg[eth].]
   1. Sorrow for the misery of another; pity; tenderness.
      [Poetic] ``They weep for ruth.'' --Chaucer. ``Have ruth of
      the poor.'' --Piers Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            To stir up gentle ruth,
            Both for her noble blood, and for her tender youth.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That which causes pity or compassion; misery; distress; a
      pitiful sight. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            It had been hard this ruth for to see. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            With wretched miseries and woeful ruth. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ruth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>hitchcock</Id>
        <Name>Hitchcock's Bible Names Dictionary (late 1800's)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ruth, drunk; satisfied

</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ruth</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ruth
     n 1: United States professional baseball player famous for
          hitting home runs (1895-1948) [syn: {Babe Ruth}, {George
          Herman Ruth}, {Sultan of Swat}]
     2: the great-grandmother of king David whose story is told in
        the Book of Ruth in the Old Testament
     3: a feeling of sympathy and sorrow for the misfortunes of
        others; "the blind are too often objects of pity" [syn: {commiseration},
         {pity}, {pathos}]
     4: a book of the Old Testament that tells the story of Ruth who
        was not an Israelite but who married an Israelite and who
        stayed with her mother-in-law Naomi after her husband died
        [syn: {Book of Ruth}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
