<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>t</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>t</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>\t
     
        {horizontal tabulation}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>t</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>T
     
        1. True.  A {Lisp} compiler by Johnathan A. Rees in 1982 at
        {Yale University}.  T has {static scope} and is a
        near-superset of {Scheme}.  {Unix} source is available.  T is
        written in itself and compiles to efficient native code.  Used
        as the basis for the Yale {Haskell} system.  Maintained by
        David Kranz &lt;kranz@masala.lcs.mit.edu&gt;.
     
        Current version: 3.1.
     
        {(ftp://ftp.ai.mit.edu/pub/systems/t3.1)}.
     
        A {multiprocessing} version of T is available
        {(ftp://masala.lcs.mit.edu/pub/mult)}.
     
        Runs on {Decstation}, {SPARC}, {Sun-3}, {Vax} under {Unix},
        {Encore}, {HP}, {Apollo}, {Macintosh} under {A/UX}.
     
        E-mail: &lt;t3-bugs@cs.yale.edu&gt; (bugs).
        E-mail: &lt;t-project@cs.yale.edu&gt;.
     
        (1991-11-26)
     
        ["The T Manual", Johnathan A. Rees &lt;jar@zurich.ai.mit.edu&gt; et
        al, Yale U, 1984].
     
        2. A {functional language}.
     
        ["T: A Simple Reduction Language Based on Combinatory Term
        Rewriting", Ida et al, Proc of Prog Future Generation
        Computers, 1988].
     
        3. (lower case) The {Lisp} {atom} used to represent "true",
        among other things.  "false" is represented using the same
        atom as an empty list, {nil}.  This {overloading} of the basic
        constants of the language helps to make Lisp {write-only
        code}.
     
        4. In transaction-processing circles, an abbreviation for
        "transaction".
     
        5. (Purdue) An alternative spelling of "{tee}".
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>t</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mute \Mute\, n.
   1. One who does not speak, whether from physical inability,
      unwillingness, or other cause. Specifically:
      (a) One who, from deafness, either congenital or from
          early life, is unable to use articulate language; a
          deaf-mute.
      (b) A person employed by undertakers at a funeral.
      (c) A person whose part in a play does not require him to
          speak.
      (d) Among the Turks, an officer or attendant who is
          selected for his place because he can not speak.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. (Phon.) A letter which represents no sound; a silent
      letter; also, a close articulation; an element of speech
      formed by a position of the mouth organs which stops the
      passage of the breath; as, {p}, {b}, {d}, {k}, {t}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mus.) A little utensil made of brass, ivory, or other
      material, so formed that it can be fixed in an erect
      position on the bridge of a violin, or similar instrument,
      in order to deaden or soften the tone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>t</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>T \T\ (t[=e]),
   the twentieth letter of the English alphabet, is a nonvocal
   consonant. With the letter h it forms the digraph th, which
   has two distinct sounds, as in thin, then. See Guide to
   Pronunciation, [sect][sect]262-264, and also [sect][sect]153,
   156, 169, 172, 176, 178-180.
   [1913 Webster] The letter derives its name and form from the
   Latin, the form of the Latin letter being further derived
   through the Greek from the Ph[oe]nician. The ultimate origin
   is probably Egyptian. It is etymologically most nearly
   related to d, s, th; as in tug, duke; two, dual, L. duo;
   resin, L. resina, Gr. "rhti`nh, tent, tense, a., tenuous,
   thin; nostril, thrill. See {D}, {S}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {T bandage} (Surg.), a bandage shaped like the letter T, and
      used principally for application to the groin, or
      perineum.

   {T cart}, a kind of fashionable two seated wagon for pleasure
      driving.

   {T iron}.
   (a) A rod with a short crosspiece at the end, -- used as a
       hook.
   (b) Iron in bars, having a cross section formed like the
       letter T, -- used in structures.

   {T rail}, a kind of rail for railroad tracks, having no
      flange at the bottom so that a section resembles the
      letter T.

   {T square}, a ruler having a crosspiece or head at one end,
      for the purpose of making parallel lines; -- so called
      from its shape. It is laid on a drawing board and guided
      by the crosspiece, which is pressed against the straight
      edge of the board. Sometimes the head is arranged to be
      set at different angles.

   {To a T}, exactly, perfectly; as, to suit to a T. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>t</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>T /T/ 1. [from LISP terminology for `true'] Yes. Used in reply to a
   question (particularly one asked using {The -P convention}). In LISP,
   the constant T means `true', among other things. Some Lisp hackers use
   `T' and `NIL' instead of `Yes' and `No' almost reflexively. This
   sometimes causes misunderstandings. When a waiter or flight attendant
   asks whether a hacker wants coffee, he may absently respond `T', meaning
   that he wants coffee; but of course he will be brought a cup of tea
   instead. Fortunately, most hackers (particularly those who frequent
   Chinese restaurants) like tea at least as well as coffee -- so it is not
   that big a problem. 2. See {time T} (also {since time T equals minus
   infinity}). 3. [techspeak] In transaction-processing circles, an
   abbreviation for the noun `transaction'. 4. [Purdue] Alternate spelling
   of {tee}. 5. A dialect of {LISP} developed at Yale. (There is an
   intended allusion to NIL, "New Implementation of Lisp", another dialect
   of Lisp developed for the {VAX})


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>t</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>T
     n 1: a base found in DNA (but not in RNA) and derived from
          pyrimidine; pairs with adenine [syn: {thymine}]
     2: one of the four nucleotides used in building DNA; all four
        nucleotides have a common phosphate group and a sugar
        (ribose) [syn: {deoxythymidine monophosphate}]
     3: a unit of weight equivalent to 1000 kilograms [syn: {metric
        ton}, {MT}, {tonne}]
     4: a unit of information equal to a trillion
        (1,099,511,627,776) bytes or 1024 gigabytes [syn: {terabyte},
         {TB}]
     5: the 20th letter of the Roman alphabet
     6: thyroid hormone similar to thyroxine but with one less
        iodine atom per molecule and produced in smaller quantity;
        exerts the same biological effects as thyroxine but is
        more potent and briefer [syn: {triiodothyronine}, {liothyronine}]
     7: hormone produced by the thyroid glands to regulate
        metabolism by controlling the rate of oxidation in cells;
        "thyroxine is 65% iodine" [syn: {thyroxine}, {thyroxin}, {tetraiodothyronine}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
