<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tackle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tackle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tackle \tac"kle\ n. (Football)
   1. An act of tackling[4]; as, brought down by a tackle by a
      lineman.
      [PJC]

   2. (Football) One of two linemen on a football team,
      occupying a position between the guard and an end; also,
      the position played by such a tackle.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tackle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tackle \Tac"kle\ (?; sometimes improperly pronounced ?,
   especially by seamen), n. [OE. takel, akin to LG. &amp; D. takel,
   Dan. takkel, Sw. tackel; perhaps akin to E. taw, v. t., or to
   take.]
   1. Apparatus for raising or lowering heavy weights,
      consisting of a rope and pulley blocks; sometimes, the
      rope and attachments, as distinct from the block, in which
      case the full appratus is referred to as a {block and
      tackle}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any instruments of action; an apparatus by which an object
      is moved or operated; gear; as, fishing tackle, hunting
      tackle; formerly, specifically, weapons. ``She to her
      tackle fell.'' --Hudibras.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: In Chaucer, it denotes usually an arrow or arrows.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. (Naut.) The rigging and apparatus of a ship; also, any
      purchase where more than one block is used.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Fall and tackle}. See the Note under {Pulley}.

   {Fishing tackle}. See under {Fishing}, a.

   {Ground tackle} (Naut.), anchors, cables, etc.

   {Gun tackle}, the apparatus or appliances for hauling cannon
      in or out.

   {Tackle fall}, the rope, or rather the end of the rope, of a
      tackle, to which the power is applied.

   {Tack tackle} (Naut.), a small tackle to pull down the tacks
      of the principal sails.

   {Tackle board}, {Tackle post} (Ropemaking), a board, frame,
      or post, at the end of a ropewalk, for supporting the
      spindels, or whirls, for twisting the yarns.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tackle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tackle \Tac"kle\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tackled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Tackling}.] [Cf. LG. takeln to equip. See {Tackle}, n.]
   1. To supply with tackle. --Beau. &amp; Fl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fasten or attach, as with a tackle; to harness; as, to
      tackle a horse into a coach or wagon. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To seize; to lay hold of; to grapple; as, a wrestler
      tackles his antagonist; a dog tackles the game.
      [1913 Webster]

            The greatest poetess of our day has wasted her time
            and strength in tackling windmills under conditions
            the most fitted to insure her defeat. --Dublin Univ.
                                                  Mag.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Football) To cause the ball carrier to fall to the
      ground, thus ending the forward motion of the ball and the
      play.
      [PJC]

   5. To begin to deal with; as, to tackle the problem.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tackle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tackle
     n 1: the person who plays that position on a football team; "the
          right tackle is a straight A student"
     2: gear consisting of ropes etc. supporting a ship's masts and
        sails [syn: {rigging}]
     3: gear used in fishing [syn: {fishing gear}, {fishing tackle},
         {fishing rig}, {rig}]
     4: a position on the line of scrimmage; "it takes a big man to
        play tackle"
     5: (American football) grasping an opposing player with the
        intention of stopping by throwing to the ground
     v 1: accept as a challenge; "I'll tackle this difficult task"
          [syn: {undertake}, {take on}]
     2: put a harness; "harness the horse" [syn: {harness}] [ant: {unharness}]
     3: seize and throw down an opponent player, who usually carries
        the ball
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
