<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tail</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TAIL, n.  The part of an animal's spine that has transcended its
natural limitations to set up an independent existence in a world of
its own.  Excepting in its foetal state, Man is without a tail, a
privation of which he attests an hereditary and uneasy consciousness
by the coat-skirt of the male and the train of the female, and by a
marked tendency to ornament that part of his attire where the tail
should be, and indubitably once was.  This tendency is most observable
in the female of the species, in whom the ancestral sense is strong
and persistent.  The tailed men described by Lord Monboddo are now
generally regarded as a product of an imagination unusually
susceptible to influences generated in the golden age of our pithecan
past.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tail \Tail\, a. (Law)
   Limited; abridged; reduced; curtailed; as, estate tail.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tail \Tail\, n. [AS. t[ae]gel, t[ae]gl; akin to G. zagel, Icel.
   tagl, Sw. tagel, Goth. tagl hair. [root]59.]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) The terminal, and usually flexible, posterior
      appendage of an animal.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The tail of mammals and reptiles contains a series of
         movable vertebr[ae], and is covered with flesh and
         hairs or scales like those of other parts of the body.
         The tail of existing birds consists of several more or
         less consolidated vertebr[ae] which supports a fanlike
         group of quills to which the term tail is more
         particularly applied. The tail of fishes consists of
         the tapering hind portion of the body ending in a
         caudal fin. The term tail is sometimes applied to the
         entire abdomen of a crustacean or insect, and sometimes
         to the terminal piece or pygidium alone.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Any long, flexible terminal appendage; whatever resembles,
      in shape or position, the tail of an animal, as a catkin.
      [1913 Webster]

            Doretus writes a great praise of the distilled
            waters of those tails that hang on willow trees.
                                                  --Harvey.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, the back, last, lower, or inferior part of
      anything, -- as opposed to the {head}, or the superior
      part.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord will make thee the head, and not the tail.
                                                  --Deut.
                                                  xxviii. 13.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A train or company of attendants; a retinue.
      [1913 Webster]

            ``Ah,'' said he, ``if you saw but the chief with his
            tail on.''                            --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The side of a coin opposite to that which bears the head,
      effigy, or date; the reverse; -- rarely used except in the
      expression ``heads or tails,'' employed when a coin is
      thrown up for the purpose of deciding some point by its
      fall.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Anat.) The distal tendon of a muscle.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Bot.) A downy or feathery appendage to certain achenes.
      It is formed of the permanent elongated style.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Surg.)
      (a) A portion of an incision, at its beginning or end,
          which does not go through the whole thickness of the
          skin, and is more painful than a complete incision; --
          called also {tailing}.
      (b) One of the strips at the end of a bandage formed by
          splitting the bandage one or more times.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. (Naut.) A rope spliced to the strap of a block, by which
      it may be lashed to anything.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. (Mus.) The part of a note which runs perpendicularly
       upward or downward from the head; the stem. --Moore
       (Encyc. of Music).
       [1913 Webster]

   11. pl. Same as {Tailing}, 4.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Arch.) The bottom or lower portion of a member or part,
       as a slate or tile.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. pl. (Mining) See {Tailing}, n., 5.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. (Astronomy) the long visible stream of gases, ions, or
       dust particles extending from the head of a comet in the
       direction opposite to the sun.
       [PJC]

   15. pl. (Rope Making) In some forms of rope-laying machine,
       pieces of rope attached to the iron bar passing through
       the grooven wooden top containing the strands, for
       wrapping around the rope to be laid.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   16. pl. A tailed coat; a tail coat. [Colloq. or Dial.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   17. (A["e]ronautics) In airplanes, an airfoil or group of
       airfoils used at the rear to confer stability.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   18. the buttocks. [slang or vulgar]
       [PJC]

   19. sexual intercourse, or a woman used for sexual
       intercourse; as, to get some tail; to find a piece of
       tail. See also {tailing[3]}. [slang and vulgar]
       [PJC]

   {Tail beam}. (Arch.) Same as {Tailpiece}.

   {Tail coverts} (Zo["o]l.), the feathers which cover the bases
      of the tail quills. They are sometimes much longer than
      the quills, and form elegant plumes. Those above the
      quills are called the {upper tail coverts}, and those
      below, the {under tail coverts}.

   {Tail end}, the latter end; the termination; as, the tail end
      of a contest. [Colloq.]

   {Tail joist}. (Arch.) Same as {Tailpiece}.

   {Tail of a comet} (Astron.), a luminous train extending from
      the nucleus or body, often to a great distance, and
      usually in a direction opposite to the sun.

   {Tail of a gale} (Naut.), the latter part of it, when the
      wind has greatly abated. --Totten.

   {Tail of a lock} (on a canal), the lower end, or entrance
      into the lower pond.

   {Tail of the trenches} (Fort.), the post where the besiegers
      begin to break ground, and cover themselves from the fire
      of the place, in advancing the lines of approach.

   {Tail spindle}, the spindle of the tailstock of a turning
      lathe; -- called also {dead spindle}.

   {To turn tail}, to run away; to flee.
      [1913 Webster]

            Would she turn tail to the heron, and fly quite out
            another way; but all was to return in a higher
            pitch.                                --Sir P.
                                                  Sidney.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tail \Tail\, n. [F. taille a cutting. See {Entail}, {Tally}.]
   (Law)
   Limitation; abridgment. --Burrill.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Estate in tail}, a limited, abridged, or reduced fee; an
      estate limited to certain heirs, and from which the other
      heirs are precluded; -- called also {estate tail}.
      --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tail \Tail\, v. t.
   1. To follow or hang to, like a tail; to be attached closely
      to, as that which can not be evaded. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Nevertheless his bond of two thousand pounds,
            wherewith he was tailed, continued uncanceled, and
            was called on the next Parliament.    --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To pull or draw by the tail. [R.] --Hudibras.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To tail in} or {To tail on} (Arch.), to fasten by one of the
      ends into a wall or some other support; as, to tail in a
      timber.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tail \Tail\, v. i.
   1. (Arch.) To hold by the end; -- said of a timber when it
      rests upon a wall or other support; -- with in or into.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) To swing with the stern in a certain direction; --
      said of a vessel at anchor; as, this vessel tails down
      stream.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tail on}. (Naut.) See {Tally on}, under {Tally}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tail
     n 1: the posterior part of the body of a vertebrate especially
          when elongated and extending beyond the trunk or main
          part of the body
     2: the time of the last part of something; "the fag end of this
        crisis-ridden century"; "the tail of the storm" [syn: {fag
        end}, {tail end}]
     3: any projection that resembles the tail of an animal [syn: {tail
        end}]
     4: the fleshy part of the human body that you sit on; "he
        deserves a good kick in the butt"; "are you going to sit
        on your fanny and do nothing?" [syn: {buttocks}, {nates},
        {arse}, {butt}, {backside}, {bum}, {buns}, {can}, {fundament},
         {hindquarters}, {hind end}, {keister}, {posterior}, {prat},
         {rear}, {rear end}, {rump}, {stern}, {seat}, {tail end},
        {tooshie}, {tush}, {bottom}, {behind}, {derriere}, {fanny},
         {ass}]
     5: a spy employed to follow someone and report their movements
        [syn: {shadow}, {shadower}]
     6: (usually plural) the reverse side of a coin that does not
        bear the representation of a person's head [ant: {head}]
     7: the rear part of an aircraft [syn: {tail assembly}, {empennage}]
     8: the rear part of a ship [syn: {stern}, {after part}, {quarter},
         {poop}]
     v 1: go after with the intent to catch; "The policeman chased the
          mugger down the alley"; "the dog chased the rabbit"
          [syn: {chase}, {chase after}, {trail}, {tag}, {give
          chase}, {dog}, {go after}, {track}]
     2: remove or shorten the tail of an animal [syn: {dock}, {bob}]
     3: remove the stalk of fruits or berries
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
