<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tank</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tank \Tank\ (t[a^][ng]k), n. [Pg. tanque, L. stangum a pool; or
   perhaps of East Indian origin. Cf. {Stank}, n.]
   1. A large basin or cistern; an artificial receptacle for
      liquids.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A pond, pool, or small lake, natural or artificial.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

            We stood in the afterglow on the bank of the tank
            and saw the ducks come home.          --F.
                                                  Remington.

            The tanks are full and the grass is high. --Lawson.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   3. (Mil.) a heavily armored combat vehicle which moves on
      caterpillar treads, rather than wheels. It typically
      carries a cannon and a heavy machine, and sometimes other
      weapons. It is the main distinguishing weapon of an
      armored division.
      [PJC]

   4. a jail cell for temporarily holding prisoners, as in a
      police station.
      [PJC]

   {Tank engine}, a locomotive which carries the water and fuel
      it requires, thus dispensing with a tender.

   {Tank iron}, plate iron thinner than boiler plate, and
      thicker than sheet iron or stovepipe iron.

   {Tank worm} (Zo["o]l.), a small nematoid worm found in the
      water tanks of India, supposed by some to be the young of
      the Guinea worm.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tank \Tank\ (t[a^][ng]k), n.
   A small Indian dry measure, averaging 240 grains in weight;
   also, a Bombay weight of 72 grains, for pearls. --Simmonds.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tank</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tank
     n 1: an enclosed armored military vehicle; has a cannon and moves
          on caterpillar treads [syn: {army tank}, {armored combat
          vehicle}, {armoured combat vehicle}]
     2: a large (usually metallic) vessel for holding gases or
        liquids [syn: {storage tank}]
     3: as much as a tank will hold [syn: {tankful}]
     4: a freight car that transports liquids or gases in bulk [syn:
         {tank car}]
     5: a cell for violent prisoners [syn: {cooler}]
     v 1: store in a tank by causing (something) to flow into it
     2: treat in a tank; "tank animal refuse"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
