<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tap</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TAP
     
        {Telocator Alphanumeric Protocol}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tap
     
        {hit}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tap \Tap\, n. [AS. t[ae]ppa, akin to D. tap, G. zapfen, OHG.
   zapfo, Dan. tap, Sw. tapp, Icel. tappi. Cf. {Tampion},
   {Tip}.]
   1. A hole or pipe through which liquor is drawn.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A plug or spile for stopping a hole pierced in a cask, or
      the like; a faucet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Liquor drawn through a tap; hence, a certain kind or
      quality of liquor; as, a liquor of the same tap. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A place where liquor is drawn for drinking; a taproom; a
      bar. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mech.) A tool for forming an internal screw, as in a nut,
      consisting of a hardened steel male screw grooved
      longitudinally so as to have cutting edges.
      [1913 Webster]

   {On tap}.
      (a) Ready to be drawn; as, ale on tap.
      (b) Broached, or furnished with a tap; as, a barrel on
          tap.

   {Plug tap} (Mech.), a screw-cutting tap with a slightly
      tapering end.

   {Tap bolt}, a bolt with a head on one end and a thread on the
      other end, to be screwed into some fixed part, instead of
      passing through the part and receiving a nut. See Illust.
      under {Bolt}.

   {Tap cinder} (Metal.), the slag of a puddling furnace.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tap \Tap\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tapped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Tapping}.] [F. taper to strike; of Teutonic origin; cf.
   dial. G. tapp, tapps, a blow, tappe a paw, fist, G. tappen to
   grope.]
   1. To strike with a slight or gentle blow; to touch gently;
      to rap lightly; to pat; as, to tap one with the hand or a
      cane.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To put a new sole or heel on; as, to tap shoes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tap \Tap\, n. [Cf. F. tape. See {Tap} to strike.]
   1. A gentle or slight blow; a light rap; a pat. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A piece of leather fastened upon the bottom of a boot or
      shoe in repairing or renewing the sole or heel.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. pl. (Mil.) A signal, by drum or trumpet, for extinguishing
      all lights in soldiers' quarters and retiring to bed, --
      usually given about a quarter of an hour after tattoo.
      --Wilhelm.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tap \Tap\, v. i.
   To strike a gentle blow.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tap \Tap\, v. t.
   1. To pierce so as to let out, or draw off, a fluid; as, to
      tap a cask, a tree, a tumor, a keg of beer, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to draw resources from (a reservoir) in any
      analogous way; as, to tap someone's knowledge of the Unix
      system; to tap the treasury.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To draw, or cause to flow, by piercing. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He has been tapping his liquors.      --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mech.) To form an internal screw in (anything) by means
      of a tool called a tap; as, to tap a nut, a pipe, or
      tubing.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. to connect a listening device to (a telephone or telegraph
      line) secretly, for the purpose of hearing private
      conversations; also, to obtain or record (information) by
      tapping; -- a technique used by law enforcement agencies
      investigating suspected criminals. In the United States it
      is illegal without a court order permitting it.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Faucet \Fau"cet\, n. [F. fausset, perh. fr. L. fauces throat.]
   1. A fixture for drawing a liquid, as water, molasses, oil,
      etc., from a pipe, cask, or other vessel, in such
      quantities as may be desired; -- called also {tap}, and
      {cock}. It consists of a tubular spout, stopped with a
      movable plug, spigot, valve, or slide.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The enlarged end of a section of pipe which receives the
      spigot end of the next section.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TAP
     Telocator Alphanumeric input Protocol (SNPP, PCIA, SMS, USA)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TAP
     Terminal Access Point (cable)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TAP
     Test Access Port (IC, IEEE 1149.1)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TAP
     The Ada Project
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TAP
     Transport und Archivierung Produktdefinierender daten (org., DIN, STEP,
     CIM)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tap
     n 1: the sound made by a gentle blow [syn: {pat}, {rap}]
     2: a faucet for drawing water from a pipe or cask [syn: {water
        faucet}, {water tap}, {spigot}, {hydrant}]
     3: a gentle blow [syn: {rap}, {strike}]
     4: a small metal plate that attaches to the toe or heel of a
        shoe (as in tap dancing)
     5: a tool for cutting female (internal) screw threads
     6: a plug for a bunghole in a cask [syn: {spigot}]
     7: the act of tapping a telephone or telegraph line to get
        information [syn: {wiretap}]
     8: a light touch or stroke [syn: {pat}, {dab}]
     v 1: cut a female screw thread with a tap
     2: draw from or dip into to get something; "tap one's memory";
        "tap a source of money"
     3: strike lightly; "He tapped me on the shoulder" [syn: {tip}]
     4: draw from; make good use of; "we must exploit the resources
        we are given wisely" [syn: {exploit}]
     5: tap a telephone or telegraph wire to get information; "The
        FBI was tapping the phone line of the suspected spy"; "Is
        this hotel room bugged?" [syn: {wiretap}, {intercept}, {bug}]
     6: furnish with a tap or spout, so as to be able to draw liquid
        from it; "tap a cask of wine"
     7: make light, repeated taps on a surface; "he was tapping his
        fingers on the table impatiently" [syn: {rap}, {knock}, {pink}]
     8: walk with a tapping sound
     9: dance and make rhythmic clicking sounds by means of metal
        plates nailed to the sole of the dance shoes; "Glover
        tapdances better than anybody" [syn: {tapdance}]
     10: draw (liquor) from a tap; "tap beer in a bar"
     11: pierce in order to draw a liquid from; "tap a maple tree for
         its syrup"; "tap a keg of beer"
     12: make a solicitation or entreaty for something; request
         urgently or persistently; "Henry IV solicited the Pope
         for a divorce"; "My neighbor keeps soliciting money for
         different charities" [syn: {solicit}, {beg}]
     [also: {tapping}, {tapped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
