<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>target</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>target</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Target
   (1 Sam. 17:6, A.V., after the LXX. and Vulg.), a kind of small
   shield. The margin has "gorget," a piece of armour for the
   throat. The Revised Version more correctly renders the Hebrew
   word (kidon) by "javelin." The same Hebrew word is used in Josh.
   8:18 (A.V., "spear;" R.V., "javelin"); Job 39:23 (A.V.,
   "shield;" R.V., "javelin"); 41:29 (A.V., "spear;" R.V.,
   "javelin").
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>target</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>target
     
        {SCSI target}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>target</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Target \Tar"get\, n. [OF. targette, dim. of OF. &amp; F. targe, of
   Teutonic origin; cf. AS. targe, OD. targie, G. zarge a frame,
   case, border, OHG. zarga, Icel. targa shield.]
   1. A kind of small shield or buckler, used as a defensive
      weapon in war.
      [1913 Webster]

   2.
      (a) A butt or mark to shoot at, as for practice, or to
          test the accuracy of a firearm, or the force of a
          projectile.
      (b) The pattern or arrangement of a series of hits made by
          a marksman on a butt or mark; as, he made a good
          target.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Surveying) The sliding crosspiece, or vane, on a leveling
      staff.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Railroad) A conspicuous disk attached to a switch lever
      to show its position, or for use as a signal.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A thin cut; a slice; specif., of lamb, a piece consisting
      of the neck and breast joints. [Eng.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. A tassel or pendent; also, a shred; tatter. [Obs. Scot.]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   7. A goal for an activity; as, the target of this year's
      fundraising drive is 2 million dollars.
      [PJC]

   8. A metallic object toward which a beam of electrons is
      aimed in a tube designed to generate X-rays; when the
      electrons strike the target, the impact causes emission of
      X-rays.
      [PJC]

   9. Any object toward which a beam of photons, a laser beam,
      an electron beam, or a beam of atomic or subatomic
      particles is aimed.
      [PJC]

   10. A person who is the subject of criticism or ridicule.
       [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>target</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>target
     n 1: a reference point to shoot at; "his arrow hit the mark"
          [syn: {mark}]
     2: a person who is the aim of an attack (especially a victim of
        ridicule or exploitation) by some hostile person or
        influence; "he fell prey to muggers"; "everyone was fair
        game"; "the target of a manhunt" [syn: {prey}, {quarry}, {fair
        game}]
     3: the location of the target that is to be hit [syn: {target
        area}]
     4: sports equipment consisting of an object set up for a
        marksman or archer to aim at [syn: {butt}]
     5: the goal intended to be attained (and which is believed to
        be attainable); "the sole object of her trip was to see
        her children" [syn: {aim}, {object}, {objective}]
     v : intend (something) to move towards a certain goal; "He aimed
         his fists towards his opponent's face"; "criticism
         directed at her superior"; "direct your anger towards
         others, not towards yourself" [syn: {aim}, {place}, {direct},
          {point}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
