<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tax</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tax</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tax \Tax\, n. [F. taxe, fr. taxer to tax, L. taxare to touch,
   sharply, to feel, handle, to censure, value, estimate, fr.
   tangere, tactum, to touch. See {Tangent}, and cf. {Task},
   {Taste}.]
   1. A charge, especially a pecuniary burden which is imposed
      by authority. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) A charge or burden laid upon persons or property for
          the support of a government.
          [1913 Webster]

                A farmer of taxes is, of all creditors,
                proverbially the most rapacious.  --Macaulay.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) Especially, the sum laid upon specific things, as upon
          polls, lands, houses, income, etc.; as, a land tax; a
          window tax; a tax on carriages, and the like.

   Note: Taxes are annual or perpetual, direct or indirect, etc.
         [1913 Webster]
      (c) A sum imposed or levied upon the members of a society
          to defray its expenses.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A task exacted from one who is under control; a
      contribution or service, the rendering of which is imposed
      upon a subject.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A disagreeable or burdensome duty or charge; as, a heavy
      tax on time or health.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Charge; censure. [Obs.] --Clarendon.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A lesson to be learned; a task. [Obs.] --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tax cart}, a spring cart subject to a low tax. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Impost; tribute; contribution; duty; toll; rate;
        assessment; exaction; custom; demand.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tax</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tax \Tax\ (t[a^]ks), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Taxed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Taxing}.] [Cf. F. taxer. See {Tax}, n.]
   1. To subject to the payment of a tax or taxes; to impose a
      tax upon; to lay a burden upon; especially, to exact money
      from for the support of government.
      [1913 Webster]

            We are more heavily taxed by our idleness, pride,
            and folly than we are taxed by government.
                                                  --Franklin.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) To assess, fix, or determine judicially, the amount
      of; as, to tax the cost of an action in court.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To charge; to accuse; also, to censure; -- often followed
      by with, rarely by of before an indirect object; as, to
      tax a man with pride.
      [1913 Webster]

            I tax you, you elements, with unkindness. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Men's virtues I have commended as freely as I have
            taxed their crimes.                   --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            Fear not now that men should tax thine honor. --M.
                                                  Arnold.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tax</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tax
     n : charge against a citizen's person or property or activity
         for the support of government [syn: {taxation}, {revenue
         enhancement}]
     v 1: levy a tax on; "The State taxes alcohol heavily"; "Clothing
          is not taxed in our state"
     2: set or determine the amount of (a payment such as a fine)
        [syn: {assess}]
     3: use to the limit; "you are taxing my patience" [syn: {task}]
     4: make a charge against or accuse; "They taxed him failure to
        appear in court"
     [also: {taxes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
