<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tension</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tension</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tension \Ten"sion\, n. [L. tensio, from tendere, tensum, to
   stretch: cf. F. tension. See {Tense}, a.]
   1. The act of stretching or straining; the state of being
      stretched or strained to stiffness; the state of being
      bent strained; as, the tension of the muscles, tension of
      the larynx.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: Extreme strain of mind or excitement of feeling;
      intense effort.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The degree of stretching to which a wire, cord, piece of
      timber, or the like, is strained by drawing it in the
      direction of its length; strain. --Gwilt.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mech.) The force by which a part is pulled when forming
      part of any system in equilibrium or in motion; as, the
      tension of a srting supporting a weight equals that
      weight.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A device for checking the delivery of the thread in a
      sewing machine, so as to give the stitch the required
      degree of tightness.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Physics) Expansive force; the force with which the
      particles of a body, as a gas, tend to recede from each
      other and occupy a larger space; elastic force;
      elasticity; as, the tension of vapor; the tension of air.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Elec.) The quality in consequence of which an electric
      charge tends to discharge itself, as into the air by a
      spark, or to pass from a body of greater to one of less
      electrical potential. It varies as the quantity of
      electricity upon a given area.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tension brace}, or {Tension member} (Engin.), a brace or
      member designed to resist tension, or subjected to
      tension, in a structure.

   {Tension rod} (Engin.), an iron rod used as a tension member
      to strengthen timber or metal framework, roofs, or the
      like.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tension</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tension
     n 1: feelings of hostility that are not manifest; "he could sense
          her latent hostility to him"; "the diplomats' first
          concern was to reduce international tensions" [syn: {latent
          hostility}]
     2: (psychology) a state of mental or emotional strain or
        suspense; "he suffered from fatigue and emotional
        tension"; "stress is a vasoconstrictor" [syn: {tenseness},
         {stress}]
     3: the physical condition of being stretched or strained; "it
        places great tension on the leg muscles"; "he could feel
        the tenseness of her body" [syn: {tensity}, {tenseness}, {tautness}]
     4: a balance between and interplay of opposing elements or
        tendencies (especially in art or literature); "there is a
        tension created between narrative time and movie time";
        "there is a tension between these approaches to
        understanding history"
     5: (physics) a stress that produces an elongation of an elastic
        physical body; "the direction of maximum tension moves
        asymptotically toward the direction of the shear"
     6: the action of stretching something tight; "tension holds the
        belt in the pulleys"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
