<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tenure</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tenure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tenure \Ten"ure\, n. [F. tenure, OF. teneure, fr. F. tenir to
   hold. See {Tenable}.]
   1. The act or right of holding, as property, especially real
      estate.
      [1913 Webster]

            That the tenure of estates might rest on equity, the
            Indian title to lands was in all cases to be
            quieted.                              --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Eng. Law) The manner of holding lands and tenements of a
      superior.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Tenure is inseparable from the idea of property in
         land, according to the theory of the English law; and
         this idea of tenure pervades, to a considerable extent,
         the law of real property in the United States, where
         the title to land is essentially allodial, and almost
         all lands are held in fee simple, not of a superior,
         but the whole right and title to the property being
         vested in the owner. Tenure, in general, then, is the
         particular manner of holding real estate, as by
         exclusive title or ownership, by fee simple, by fee
         tail, by courtesy, in dower, by copyhold, by lease, at
         will, etc.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. The consideration, condition, or service which the
      occupier of land gives to his lord or superior for the use
      of his land.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Manner of holding, in general; as, in absolute
      governments, men hold their rights by a precarious tenure.
      [1913 Webster]

            All that seems thine own,
            Held by the tenure of his will alone. --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tenure by fee alms}. (Law) See {Frankalmoigne}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tenure</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tenure
     n 1: the term during which some position is held [syn: {term of
          office}, {incumbency}]
     2: the right to hold property; part of an ancient hierarchical
        system of holding lands [syn: {land tenure}]
     v : give life-time employment to; "She was tenured after she
         published her book"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
