<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>terminal</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>terminal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>terminal
     
        1. &lt;hardware&gt; An electronic or electromechanical device for
        entering data into a computer or a communications system and
        displaying data received.  Early terminals were called
        {teletype}s, later ones {VDU}s.  Typically a terminal
        communicates with the computer via a {serial line}.
     
        2. &lt;electronics&gt; The end of a {line} where signals are either
        transmitted or received, or a point along the length of a line
        where the signals are made available to apparatus.
     
        3. &lt;electronics&gt; Apparatus to send and/or receive signals on a
        {line}.
     
        (1995-10-02)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>terminal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Terminal \Ter"mi*nal\ (-nal), a. [L. terminals: cf. F. terminal.
   See {Term}, n.]
   1. Of or pertaining to the end or extremity; forming the
      extremity; as, a terminal edge.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) Growing at the end of a branch or stem;
      terminating; as, a terminal bud, flower, or spike.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Railroads) Pertaining to a railroad terminal; connected
      with the receipt or delivery of freight; as, terminal
      charges.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Terminal moraine}. See the Note under {Moraine}.

   {Terminal statue}. See {Terminus}, n., 2 and 3.

   {Terminal velocity}.
      (a) The velocity acquired at the end of a body's motion.
      (b) The limit toward which the velocity of a body
          approaches, as of a body falling through the air.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>terminal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Terminal \Ter"mi*nal\, n.
   1. That which terminates or ends; termination; extremity.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Eccl.) Either of the ends of the conducting circuit of an
      electrical apparatus, as an inductorium, dynamo, or
      electric motor, usually provided with binding screws for
      the attachment of wires by which a current may be conveyed
      into or from the machine; a pole.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Railroads)
      (a) The end of a line of railroad, with the switches,
          stations, sheds, and other appliances pertaining
          thereto.
      (b) Any station for the delivery or receipt of freight
          lying too far from the main line to be served by mere
          sidings.
      (c) A rate charged on all freight, independent of the
          distance, and supposed to cover the expenses of
          station service, as distinct from {mileage rate},
          generally proportionate to the distance and intended
          to cover movement expenses; a terminal charge.
      (d) A town lying at the end of a railroad, in which the
          terminal is located; -- more properly called a
          {terminus}.
          [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   4. The station at either end of a bus line line which
      transports freight or passengers.
      [PJC]

   5. A station where passenger buses start or end a trip; --
      also called bus terminal.
      [PJC]

   6. The structure at an airport where passengers board or
      debark, and where ticket purchases and baggage pickup is
      performed; -- also called airline terminal.
      [PJC]

   7. (Computers) An electronic device where data may be entered
      into a computer, and information received from it, usually
      consisting of a keyboard and video display unit (monitor);
      the terminal may be integrated or connected directly to a
      computer, or connected by a communications circuit with a
      computer at a remote location; -- also called computer
      terminal.
      [PJC]

   {freight terminal}, a terminal used for loading or unloading
      of freight.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>terminal</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>terminal
     adj 1: being or situated at an end; "the endmost pillar"; "terminal
            buds on a branch"; "a terminal station"; "the terminal
            syllable" [syn: {endmost}]
     2: of or relating to or situated at the ends of a delivery
        route; "freight pickup is a terminal service"; "terminal
        charges"
     3: relating to or occurring in a term or fixed period of time;
        "terminal examinations"; "terminal payments"
     4: occurring at or forming an end or termination; "his
        concluding words came as a surprise"; "the final chapter";
        "the last days of the dinosaurs"; "terminal leave" [syn: {concluding},
         {final}, {last}]
     5: causing or ending in or approaching death; "a terminal
        patient"; "terminal cancer"
     n 1: station where transport vehicles load or unload passengers
          or goods [syn: {terminus}, {depot}]
     2: a contact on an electrical device (such as a battery) at
        which electric current enters or leaves [syn: {pole}]
     3: electronic equipment consisting of a device providing access
        to a computer; has a keyboard and display
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
