<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>text</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>text</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>text
     
        1. Executable code, especially a "pure code" portion shared
        between multiple instances of a program running in a
        {multitasking} {operating system}.
     
        Compare {English}.
     
        2. Textual material in the mainstream sense; data in ordinary
        {ASCII} or {EBCDIC} representation (see {flat ASCII}).  "Those
        are text files; you can review them using the editor."
     
        These two contradictory senses confuse hackers too.
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1995-03-16)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>text</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Text \Text\, v. t.
   To write in large characters, as in text hand. [Obs.] --Beau.
   &amp; Fl.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>text</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Text \Text\ (t[e^]kst), n. [F. texte, L. textus, texture,
   structure, context, fr. texere, textum, to weave, construct,
   compose; cf. Gr. te`ktwn carpenter, Skr. taksh to cut, carve,
   make. Cf. {Context}, {Mantle}, n., {Pretext}, {Tissue},
   {Toil} a snare.]
   1. A discourse or composition on which a note or commentary
      is written; the original words of an author, in
      distinction from a paraphrase, annotation, or commentary.
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (O. Eng. Law) The four Gospels, by way of distinction or
      eminence. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A verse or passage of Scripture, especially one chosen as
      the subject of a sermon, or in proof of a doctrine.
      [1913 Webster]

            How oft, when Paul has served us with a text,
            Has Epictetus, Plato, Tully, preached! --Cowper.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, anything chosen as the subject of an argument,
      literary composition, or the like; topic; theme.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A style of writing in large characters; text-hand also, a
      kind of type used in printing; as, German text.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That part of a document (printed or electronic) comprising
      the words, especially the main body of expository words,
      in contrast to the illustrations, pictures, charts,
      tables, or other formatted material which contain graphic
      elements as a major component.
      [PJC]

   7. Any communication composed of words.
      [PJC]

   8. a textbook.
      [PJC]

   {Text blindness}. (Physiol.) See {Word blindness}, under
      {Word}.

   {Text letter}, a large or capital letter. [Obs.]

   {Text pen}, a kind of metallic pen used in engrossing, or in
      writing text-hand.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>text</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>text n. 1. [techspeak] Executable code, esp. a `pure code' portion
   shared between multiple instances of a program running in a multitasking
   OS. Compare {English}. 2. Textual material in the mainstream sense; data
   in ordinary {{ASCII}} or {{EBCDIC}} representation (see {flat-ASCII}).
   "Those are text files; you can review them using the editor." These two
   contradictory senses confuse hackers, too.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>text</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>text
     n 1: the words of something written; "there were more than a
          thousand words of text"; "they handed out the printed
          text of the mayor's speech"; "he wants to reconstruct
          the original text" [syn: {textual matter}]
     2: a passage from the Bible that is used as the subject of a
        sermon; "the preacher chose a text from Psalms to
        introduce his sermon"
     3: a book prepared for use in schools or colleges; "his
        economics textbook is in its tenth edition"; "the
        professor wrote the text that he assigned students to buy"
        [syn: {textbook}, {text edition}, {schoolbook}, {school
        text}] [ant: {trade book}]
     4: the main body of a written work (as distinct from
        illustrations or footnotes etc.); "pictures made the text
        easier to understand"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
