<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>that</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>that</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>That \That\, pron., a., conj., &amp; adv. [AS. [eth][ae]t, neuter
   nom. &amp; acc. sing. of the article (originally a demonstrative
   pronoun). The nom. masc. s[=e], and the nom. fem. se['o] are
   from a different root. AS. [eth][ae]t is akin to D. dat, G.
   das, OHG. daz, Sw. &amp; Dan. det, Icel. [thorn]at (masc. s[=a],
   fem. s[=o]), Goth. [thorn]ata (masc. sa, fem. s[=o]), Gr. ?
   (masc. ?, fem. ?), Skr. tat (for tad, masc. sas, fem. s[=a]);
   cf. L. istud that. [root]184. Cf. {The}, {Their}, {They},
   {Them}, {This}, {Than}, {Since}.]
   1. As a demonstrative pronoun (pl. {Those}), that usually
      points out, or refers to, a person or thing previously
      mentioned, or supposed to be understood. That, as a
      demonstrative, may precede the noun to which it refers;
      as, that which he has said is true; those in the basket
      are good apples.
      [1913 Webster]

            The early fame of Gratian was equal to that of the
            most celebrated princes.              --Gibbon.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: That may refer to an entire sentence or paragraph, and
         not merely to a word. It usually follows, but sometimes
         precedes, the sentence referred to.
         [1913 Webster]

               That be far from thee, to do after this manner,
               to slay the righteous with the wicked. --Gen.
                                                  xviii. 25.
         [1913 Webster]

               And when Moses heard that, he was content. --Lev.
                                                  x. 20.
         [1913 Webster]

               I will know your business, Harry, that I will.
                                                  --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: That is often used in opposition to this, or by way of
         distinction, and in such cases this, like the Latin hic
         and French ceci, generally refers to that which is
         nearer, and that, like Latin ille and French cela, to
         that which is more remote. When they refer to foreign
         words or phrases, this generally refers to the latter,
         and that to the former.
         [1913 Webster]

               Two principles in human nature reign;
               Self-love, to urge, and Reason, to restrain;
               Nor this a good, nor that a bad we call. --Pope.
         [1913 Webster]

               If the Lord will, we shall live, and do this or
               that.                              --James iv.
                                                  16.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. As an adjective, that has the same demonstrative force as
      the pronoun, but is followed by a noun.
      [1913 Webster]

            It shall be more tolerable for Sodom and Gomorrah in
            the day of judgment, than for that city. --Matt. x.
                                                  15.
      [1913 Webster]

            The woman was made whole from that hour. --Matt. ix.
                                                  22.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: That was formerly sometimes used with the force of the
         article the, especially in the phrases that one, that
         other, which were subsequently corrupted into th'tone,
         th'tother (now written t'other).
         [1913 Webster]

               Upon a day out riden knightes two . . .
               That one of them came home, that other not.
                                                  --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. As a relative pronoun, that is equivalent to who or which,
      serving to point out, and make definite, a person or thing
      spoken of, or alluded to, before, and may be either
      singular or plural.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that reproveth a scorner getteth to himself
            shame.                                --Prov. ix. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

            A judgment that is equal and impartial must incline
            to the greater probabilities.         --Bp. Wilkins.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: If the relative clause simply conveys an additional
         idea, and is not properly explanatory or restrictive,
         who or which (rarely that) is employed; as, the king
         that (or who) rules well is generally popular;
         Victoria, who (not that) rules well, enjoys the
         confidence of her subjects. Ambiguity may in some cases
         be avoided in the use of that (which is restrictive)
         instead of who or which, likely to be understood in a
         co["o]rdinating sense. --Bain.
         [1913 Webster] That was formerly used for that which,
         as what is now; but such use is now archaic.
         [1913 Webster]

               We speak that we do know, and testify that we
               have seen.                         --John iii.
                                                  11.
         [1913 Webster]

               That I have done it is thyself to wite [blame].
                                                  --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster] That, as a relative pronoun, cannot be
         governed by a preposition preceding it, but may be
         governed by one at the end of the sentence which it
         commences.
         [1913 Webster]

               The ship that somebody was sailing in. --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
         [1913 Webster] In Old English, that was often used with
         the demonstratives he, his, him, etc., and the two
         together had the force of a relative pronoun; thus,
         that he = who; that his = whose; that him = whom.
         [1913 Webster]

               I saw to-day a corpse yborn to church
               That now on Monday last I saw him wirche [work].
                                                  --Chaucer.
         [1913 Webster] Formerly, that was used, where we now
         commonly use which, as a relative pronoun with the
         demonstrative pronoun that as its antecedent.
         [1913 Webster]

               That that dieth, let it die; and that that is to
               cut off, let it be cut off.        --Zech. xi. 9.
         [1913 Webster]

   4. As a conjunction, that retains much of its force as a
      demonstrative pronoun. It is used, specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) To introduce a clause employed as the object of the
          preceding verb, or as the subject or predicate
          nominative of a verb.
          [1913 Webster]

                She tells them 't is a causeless fantasy,
                And childish error, that they are afraid.
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                I have shewed before, that a mere possibility to
                the contrary, can by no means hinder a thing
                from being highly credible.       --Bp. Wilkins.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To introduce, a reason or cause; -- equivalent to for
          that, in that, for the reason that, because.
          [1913 Webster]

                He does hear me;
                And that he does, I weep.         --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To introduce a purpose; -- usually followed by may, or
          might, and frequently preceded by so, in order, to the
          end, etc.
          [1913 Webster]

                These things I say, that ye might be saved.
                                                  --John v. 34.
          [1913 Webster]

                To the end that he may prolong his days. --Deut.
                                                  xvii. 20.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) To introduce a consequence, result, or effect; --
          usually preceded by so or such, sometimes by that.
          [1913 Webster]

                The birds their notes renew, and bleating herds
                Attest their joy, that hill and valley rings.
                                                  --Milton.
          [1913 Webster]

                He gazed so long
                That both his eyes were dazzled.  --Tennyson.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) To introduce a clause denoting time; -- equivalent to
          in which time, at which time, when.
          [1913 Webster]

                So wept Duessa until eventide,
                That shining lamps in Jove's high course were
                lit.                              --Spenser.
          [1913 Webster]

                Is not this the day
                That Hermia should give answer of her choice?
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) In an elliptical sentence to introduce a dependent
          sentence expressing a wish, or a cause of surprise,
          indignation, or the like.
          [1913 Webster]

                Ha, cousin Silence, that thou hadst seen that
                that this knight and I have seen! --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

                O God, that right should thus overcome might!
                                                  --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: That was formerly added to other conjunctions or to
         adverbs to make them emphatic.
         [1913 Webster]

               To try if that our own be ours or no. --Shak.
         [1913 Webster] That is sometimes used to connect a
         clause with a preceding conjunction on which it
         depends.
         [1913 Webster]

               When he had carried Rome and that we looked
               For no less spoil than glory.      --Shak.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. As adverb: To such a degree; so; as, he was that
      frightened he could say nothing. [Archaic or in illiteral
      use.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {All that}, everything of that kind; all that sort.
      [1913 Webster]

            With singing, laughing, ogling, and all that.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            The rank is but the guinea's stamp,
            The man's the gowd [gold] for a'that. --Burns.
      [1913 Webster]

   {For that}. See under {For}, prep.

   {In that}. See under {In}, prep.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
