<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>theme</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>theme</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Theme \Theme\, n. [OE. teme, OF. teme, F. th[`e]me, L. thema,
   Gr. ?, fr. ? to set, place. See {Do}, and cf. {Thesis}.]
   1. A subject or topic on which a person writes or speaks; a
      proposition for discussion or argument; a text.
      [1913 Webster]

            My theme is alway one and ever was.   --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            And when a soldier was the theme, my name
            Was not far off.                      --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Discourse on a certain subject.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then ran repentance and rehearsed his theme. --Piers
                                                  Plowman.
      [1913 Webster]

            It was the subject of my theme.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A composition or essay required of a pupil. --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Gram.) A noun or verb, not modified by inflections; also,
      that part of a noun or verb which remains unchanged
      (except by euphonic variations) in declension or
      conjugation; stem.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. That by means of which a thing is done; means; instrument.
      [Obs.] --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mus.) The leading subject of a composition or a movement.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>theme</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>theme
     n 1: the subject matter of a conversation or discussion; "he
          didn't want to discuss that subject"; "it was a very
          sensitive topic"; "his letters were always on the theme
          of love" [syn: {subject}, {topic}]
     2: a unifying idea that is a recurrent element in a literary or
        artistic work; "it was the usual `boy gets girl' theme"
        [syn: {motif}]
     3: (music) melodic subject of a musical composition; "the theme
        is announced in the first measures"; "the accompanist
        picked up the idea and elaborated it" [syn: {melodic theme},
         {musical theme}, {idea}]
     4: an essay (especially one written as an assignment); "he got
        an A on his composition" [syn: {composition}, {paper}, {report}]
     5: (linguistics) the form of a word after all affixes are
        removed; "thematic vowels are part of the stem" [syn: {root},
         {root word}, {base}, {stem}, {radical}]
     v : provide with a particular theme or motive; "the restaurant
         often themes its menus"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
