<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>they</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>they</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>He \He\ (h[=e]), pron. [nom. {He}; poss. {His} (h[i^]z); obj.
   {Him} (h[i^]m); pl. nom. {They} ([th][=a]); poss. {Their} or
   {Theirs} ([th][^a]rz or [th][=a]rz); obj. {Them}
   ([th][e^]m).] [AS. h[=e], masc., he['o], fem., hit, neut.;
   pl. h[=i], or hie, hig; akin to OFries. hi, D. hij, OS. he,
   hi, G. heute to-day, Goth. himma, dat. masc., this, hina,
   accus. masc., and hita, accus. neut., and prob. to L. his
   this. [root]183. Cf. {It}.]
   1. The man or male being (or object personified to which the
      masculine gender is assigned), previously designated; a
      pronoun of the masculine gender, usually referring to a
      specified subject already indicated.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy desire shall be to thy husband, and he shall
            rule over thee.                       --Gen. iii.
                                                  16.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thou shalt fear the Lord thy God; him shalt thou
            serve.                                --Deut. x. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Any one; the man or person; -- used indefinitely, and
      usually followed by a relative pronoun.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that walketh with wise men shall be wise. --Prov.
                                                  xiii. 20.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Man; a male; any male person; -- in this sense used
      substantively. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            I stand to answer thee,
            Or any he, the proudest of thy sort.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: When a collective noun or a class is referred to, he is
         of common gender. In early English, he referred to a
         feminine or neuter noun, or to one in the plural, as
         well as to noun in the masculine singular. In
         composition, he denotes a male animal; as, a he-goat.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>they</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>She \She\, pron. [sing. nom. {She}; poss. {Her}. or {Hers}; obj.
   {Her}; pl. nom. {They}; poss. {Their}or {Theirs}; obj.
   {Them}.] [OE. she, sche, scheo, scho, AS. se['o], fem. of the
   definite article, originally a demonstrative pronoun; cf. OS.
   siu, D. zij, G. sie, OHG. siu, s[=i], si, Icel. s[=u],
   sj[=a], Goth. si she, s[=o], fem. article, Russ. siia, fem.,
   this, Gr. ?, fem. article, Skr. s[=a], sy[=a]. The possessive
   her or hers, and the objective her, are from a different
   root. See {Her}.]
   1. This or that female; the woman understood or referred to;
      the animal of the female sex, or object personified as
      feminine, which was spoken of.
      [1913 Webster]

            She loved her children best in every wise.
                                                  --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then Sarah denied, . . . for she was afraid. --Gen.
                                                  xviii. 15.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A woman; a female; -- used substantively. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Lady, you are the cruelest she alive. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: She is used in composition with nouns of common gender,
         for female, to denote an animal of the female sex; as,
         a she-bear; a she-cat.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>they</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>They \They\ ([th][=a]), pron. pl.; poss. {Theirs}; obj. {Them}.
   [Icel. [thorn]eir they, properly nom. pl. masc. of s[=a],
   s[=u], [thorn]at, a demonstrative pronoun, akin to the
   English definite article, AS. s[=e], se['o], [eth][ae]t, nom.
   pl. [eth][=a]. See {That}.]
   The plural of he, she, or it. They is never used adjectively,
   but always as a pronoun proper, and sometimes refers to
   persons without an antecedent expressed.
   [1913 Webster]

         Jolif and glad they went unto here [their] rest
         And casten hem [them] full early for to sail.
                                                  --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

         They of Italy salute you.                --Heb. xiii.
                                                  24.
   [1913 Webster]

         Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after
         righteousness.                           --Matt. v. 6.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: They is used indefinitely, as our ancestors used man,
         and as the French use on; as, they say (French on dit),
         that is, it is said by persons not specified.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
