<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>this</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>this</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>This \This\ ([th][i^]s), pron. &amp; a.; pl. {These} ([th][=e]z).
   [OE. this, thes, AS. [eth][=e]s, masc., [eth]e['o]s, fem.,
   [eth]is, neut.; akin to OS. these, D. deze, G. dieser, OHG.
   diser, deser, Icel. [thorn]essi; originally from the definite
   article + a particle -se, -si; cf. Goth. sai behold. See
   {The}, {That}, and cf. {These}, {Those}.]
   1. As a demonstrative pronoun, this denotes something that is
      present or near in place or time, or something just
      mentioned, or that is just about to be mentioned.
      [1913 Webster]

            When they heard this, they were pricked in their
            heart.                                --Acts ii. 37.
      [1913 Webster]

            But know this, that if the good man of the house had
            known in what watch the thief would come, he would
            have watched.                         --Matt. xxiv.
                                                  43.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. As an adjective, this has the same demonstrative force as
      the pronoun, but is followed by a noun; as, this book;
      this way to town.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: This may be used as opposed or correlative to that, and
         sometimes as opposed to other or to a second this. See
         the Note under {That}, 1.
         [1913 Webster]

               This way and that wavering sails they bend.
                                                  --Pope.
         [1913 Webster]

               A body of this or that denomination is produced.
                                                  --Boyle.
         [1913 Webster]

               Their judgment in this we may not, and in that we
               need not, follow.                  --Hooker.
         [1913 Webster]

               Consider the arguments which the author had to
               write this, or to design the other, before you
               arraign him.                       --Dryden.
         [1913 Webster]

               Thy crimes . . . soon by this or this will end.
                                                  --Addison.
         [1913 Webster]

   Note: This, like a, every, that, etc., may refer to a number,
         as of years, persons, etc., taken collectively or as a
         whole.
         [1913 Webster]

               This twenty years have I been with thee.. --Gen.
                                                  xxxi. 38.
         [1913 Webster]

               I have not wept this years; but now
               My mother comes afresh into my eyes. --Dryden.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
