<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>threw</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>threw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Threw \Threw\ (thr[udd]),
   imp. of {Throw}.
   [1913 Webster]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>threw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throw \Throw\, v. t. [imp. {Threw} (thr[udd]); p. p. {Thrown}
   (thr[=o]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Throwing}.] [OE. [thorn]rowen,
   [thorn]rawen, to throw, to twist, AS. [thorn]r[=a]wan to
   twist, to whirl; akin to D. draaijen, G. drehen, OHG.
   dr[=a]jan, L. terebra an auger, gimlet, Gr. ? to bore, to
   turn, ? to pierce, ? a hole. Cf. {Thread}, {Trite}, {Turn},
   v. t.]
   1. To fling, cast, or hurl with a certain whirling motion of
      the arm, to throw a ball; -- distinguished from to toss,
      or to bowl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fling or cast in any manner; to drive to a distance
      from the hand or from an engine; to propel; to send; as,
      to throw stones or dust with the hand; a cannon throws a
      ball; a fire engine throws a stream of water to extinguish
      flames.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To drive by violence; as, a vessel or sailors may be
      thrown upon a rock.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) To cause to take a strategic position; as, he threw
      a detachment of his army across the river.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To overturn; to prostrate in wrestling; as, a man throws
      his antagonist.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cast, as dice; to venture at dice.
      [1913 Webster]

            Set less than thou throwest.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To put on hastily; to spread carelessly.
      [1913 Webster]

            O'er his fair limbs a flowery vest he threw. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To divest or strip one's self of; to put off.
      [1913 Webster]

            There the snake throws her enameled skin. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Pottery) To form or shape roughly on a throwing engine,
      or potter's wheel, as earthen vessels.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To give forcible utterance to; to cast; to vent.
       [1913 Webster]

             I have thrown
             A brave defiance in King Henry's teeth. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To bring forth; to produce, as young; to bear; -- said
       especially of rabbits.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To twist two or more filaments of, as silk, so as to form
       one thread; to twist together, as singles, in a direction
       contrary to the twist of the singles themselves; --
       sometimes applied to the whole class of operations by
       which silk is prepared for the weaver. --Tomlinson.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To throw away}.
       (a) To lose by neglect or folly; to spend in vain; to
           bestow without a compensation; as, to throw away
           time; to throw away money.
       (b) To reject; as, to throw away a good book, or a good
           offer.

   {To throw back}.
       (a) To retort; to cast back, as a reply.
       (b) To reject; to refuse.
       (c) To reflect, as light.

   {To throw by}, to lay aside; to discard; to neglect as
      useless; as, to throw by a garment.

   {To throw down}, to subvert; to overthrow; to destroy; as, to
      throw down a fence or wall.

   {To throw in}.
       (a) To inject, as a fluid.
       (b) To put in; to deposit with others; to contribute; as,
           to throw in a few dollars to help make up a fund; to
           throw in an occasional comment.
       (c) To add without enumeration or valuation, as something
           extra to clinch a bargain.

   {To throw off}.
       (a) To expel; to free one's self from; as, to throw off a
           disease.
       (b) To reject; to discard; to abandon; as, to throw off
           all sense of shame; to throw off a dependent.
       (c) To make a start in a hunt or race. [Eng.]

   {To throw on}, to cast on; to load.

   {To throw one's self down}, to lie down neglectively or
      suddenly.

   {To throw one's self on} or {To throw one's self upon}.
       (a) To fall upon.
       (b) To resign one's self to the favor, clemency, or
           sustain power of (another); to repose upon.

   {To throw out}.
       (a) To cast out; to reject or discard; to expel. ``The
           other two, whom they had thrown out, they were
           content should enjoy their exile.'' --Swift. ``The
           bill was thrown out.'' --Swift.
       (b) To utter; to give utterance to; to speak; as, to
           throw out insinuation or observation. ``She throws
           out thrilling shrieks.'' --Spenser.
       (c) To distance; to leave behind. --Addison.
       (d) To cause to project; as, to throw out a pier or an
           abutment.
       (e) To give forth; to emit; as, an electric lamp throws
           out a brilliant light.
       (f) To put out; to confuse; as, a sudden question often
           throws out an orator.

   {To throw over}, to abandon the cause of; to desert; to
      discard; as, to throw over a friend in difficulties.

   {To throw up}.
       (a) To resign; to give up; to demit; as, to throw up a
           commission. ``Experienced gamesters throw up their
           cards when they know that the game is in the enemy's
           hand.'' --Addison.
       (b) To reject from the stomach; to vomit.
       (c) To construct hastily; as, to throw up a breastwork of
           earth.
           [1913 Webster]
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>threw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>throw
     n 1: the act of throwing (propelling something through the air
          with a rapid movement of the arm and wrist); "the
          catcher made a good throw to second base"
     2: a single chance or instance; "he couldn't afford $50 a
        throw"
     3: the maximum movement available to a pivoted or reciprocating
        piece by a cam [syn: {stroke}, {cam stroke}]
     4: the distance that something can be thrown; "it is just a
        stone's throw from here"
     5: bedclothes consisting of a lightweight cloth covering (an
        afghan or bedspread) that is casually thrown over
        something
     6: the throwing of an object in order to determine an outcome
        randomly; "he risked his fortune on a throw of the dice"
     v 1: project through the air; "throw a frisbee"
     2: move violently, energetically, or carelessly; "She threw
        herself forwards"
     3: get rid of; "he shed his image as a pushy boss"; "shed your
        clothes" [syn: {shed}, {cast}, {cast off}, {shake off}, {throw
        off}, {throw away}, {drop}]
     4: place or put with great energy; "She threw the blanket
        around the child"; "thrust the money in the hands of the
        beggar" [syn: {thrust}]
     5: convey or communicate; of a smile, a look, a physical
        gesture; "Throw a glance"; "She gave me a dirty look"
        [syn: {give}]
     6: cause to go on or to be engaged or set in operation; "switch
        on the light"; "throw the lever" [syn: {flip}, {switch}]
     7: put or send forth; "She threw the flashlight beam into the
        corner"; "The setting sun threw long shadows"; "cast a
        spell"; "cast a warm light" [syn: {project}, {cast}, {contrive}]
     8: to put into a state or activity hastily, suddenly, or
        carelessly; "Jane threw dinner together"; "throw the car
        into reverse"
     9: cause to be confused emotionally [syn: {bewilder}, {bemuse},
         {discombobulate}]
     10: utter with force; utter vehemently; "hurl insults"; "throw
         accusations at someone" [syn: {hurl}]
     11: organize or be responsible for; "hold a reception"; "have,
         throw, or make a party"; "give a course" [syn: {hold}, {have},
          {make}, {give}]
     12: make on a potter's wheel; "she threw a beautiful teapot"
     13: cause to fall off; "The horse threw its unexperienced rider"
     14: throw (a die) out onto a flat surface; "Throw a six"
     15: be confusing or perplexing to; cause to be unable to think
         clearly; "These questions confuse even the experts";
         "This question completely threw me"; "This question
         befuddled even the teacher" [syn: {confuse}, {fox}, {befuddle},
          {fuddle}, {bedevil}, {confound}, {discombobulate}]
     [also: {thrown}, {threw}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>threw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>threw
     See {throw}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
