<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>throat</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throat \Throat\ (thr[=o]t), n. [OE. throte, AS. [thorn]rote,
   [thorn]rotu; akin to OHG. drozza, G. drossel; cf. OFries. &amp;
   D. stort. Cf. {Throttle}.]
   1. (Anat.)
      (a) The part of the neck in front of, or ventral to, the
          vertebral column.
      (b) Hence, the passage through it to the stomach and
          lungs; the pharynx; -- sometimes restricted to the
          fauces.
          [1913 Webster]

                I can vent clamor from my throat. --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. A contracted portion of a vessel, or of a passage way; as,
      the throat of a pitcher or vase.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Arch.) The part of a chimney between the gathering, or
      portion of the funnel which contracts in ascending, and
      the flue. --Gwilt.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Naut.)
      (a) The upper fore corner of a boom-and-gaff sail, or of a
          staysail.
      (b) That end of a gaff which is next the mast.
      (c) The angle where the arm of an anchor is joined to the
          shank. --Totten.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Shipbuilding) The inside of a timber knee.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Bot.) The orifice of a tubular organ; the outer end of
      the tube of a monopetalous corolla; the faux, or fauces.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Throat brails} (Naut.), brails attached to the gaff close to
      the mast.

   {Throat halyards} (Naut.), halyards that raise the throat of
      the gaff.

   {Throat pipe} (Anat.), the windpipe, or trachea.

   {To give one the lie in his throat}, to accuse one pointedly
      of lying abominably.

   {To lie in one's throat}, to lie flatly or abominably.
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throat \Throat\, v. t.
   1. To utter in the throat; to mutter; as, to throat threats.
      [Obs.] --Chapman.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To mow, as beans, in a direction against their bending.
      [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>throat
     n 1: the passage to the stomach and lungs; in the front part of
          the neck below the chin and above the collarbone [syn: {pharynx}]
     2: an opening in the vamp of a shoe at the instep
     3: a passage resembling a throat in shape or function; "the
        throat of the vase"; "the throat of a chimney";
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
