<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>throw</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throw \Throw\, v. i.
   To perform the act of throwing or casting; to cast;
   specifically, to cast dice.
   [1913 Webster]

   {To throw about}, to cast about; to try expedients. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throw \Throw\, n.
   1. The act of hurling or flinging; a driving or propelling
      from the hand or an engine; a cast.
      [1913 Webster]

            He heaved a stone, and, rising to the throw,
            He sent it in a whirlwind at the foe. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A stroke; a blow. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Nor shield defend the thunder of his throws.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The distance which a missile is, or may be, thrown; as, a
      stone's throw.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A cast of dice; the manner in which dice fall when cast;
      as, a good throw.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An effort; a violent sally. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Your youth admires
            The throws and swellings of a Roman soul. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mach.) The extreme movement given to a sliding or
      vibrating reciprocating piece by a cam, crank, eccentric,
      or the like; travel; stroke; as, the throw of a slide
      valve. Also, frequently, the length of the radius of a
      crank, or the eccentricity of an eccentric; as, the throw
      of the crank of a steam engine is equal to half the stroke
      of the piston.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Pottery) A potter's wheel or table; a jigger. See 2d
      {Jigger}, 2
      (a) .
          [1913 Webster]

   8. A turner's lathe; a throwe. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Mining) The amount of vertical displacement produced by a
      fault; -- according to the direction it is designated as
      an upthrow, or a downthrow.
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throw \Throw\ (thr[=o]), n. [See {Throe}.]
   Pain; especially, pain of travail; throe. [Obs.] --Spenser.
   Dryden.
   [1913 Webster]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throw \Throw\, n. [AS. [thorn]r[=a]h, [thorn]r[=a]g.]
   Time; while; space of time; moment; trice. [Obs.] --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         I will with Thomas speak a little throw. --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Throw \Throw\, v. t. [imp. {Threw} (thr[udd]); p. p. {Thrown}
   (thr[=o]n); p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Throwing}.] [OE. [thorn]rowen,
   [thorn]rawen, to throw, to twist, AS. [thorn]r[=a]wan to
   twist, to whirl; akin to D. draaijen, G. drehen, OHG.
   dr[=a]jan, L. terebra an auger, gimlet, Gr. ? to bore, to
   turn, ? to pierce, ? a hole. Cf. {Thread}, {Trite}, {Turn},
   v. t.]
   1. To fling, cast, or hurl with a certain whirling motion of
      the arm, to throw a ball; -- distinguished from to toss,
      or to bowl.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fling or cast in any manner; to drive to a distance
      from the hand or from an engine; to propel; to send; as,
      to throw stones or dust with the hand; a cannon throws a
      ball; a fire engine throws a stream of water to extinguish
      flames.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To drive by violence; as, a vessel or sailors may be
      thrown upon a rock.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) To cause to take a strategic position; as, he threw
      a detachment of his army across the river.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To overturn; to prostrate in wrestling; as, a man throws
      his antagonist.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To cast, as dice; to venture at dice.
      [1913 Webster]

            Set less than thou throwest.          --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To put on hastily; to spread carelessly.
      [1913 Webster]

            O'er his fair limbs a flowery vest he threw. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To divest or strip one's self of; to put off.
      [1913 Webster]

            There the snake throws her enameled skin. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. (Pottery) To form or shape roughly on a throwing engine,
      or potter's wheel, as earthen vessels.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To give forcible utterance to; to cast; to vent.
       [1913 Webster]

             I have thrown
             A brave defiance in King Henry's teeth. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To bring forth; to produce, as young; to bear; -- said
       especially of rabbits.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To twist two or more filaments of, as silk, so as to form
       one thread; to twist together, as singles, in a direction
       contrary to the twist of the singles themselves; --
       sometimes applied to the whole class of operations by
       which silk is prepared for the weaver. --Tomlinson.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To throw away}.
       (a) To lose by neglect or folly; to spend in vain; to
           bestow without a compensation; as, to throw away
           time; to throw away money.
       (b) To reject; as, to throw away a good book, or a good
           offer.

   {To throw back}.
       (a) To retort; to cast back, as a reply.
       (b) To reject; to refuse.
       (c) To reflect, as light.

   {To throw by}, to lay aside; to discard; to neglect as
      useless; as, to throw by a garment.

   {To throw down}, to subvert; to overthrow; to destroy; as, to
      throw down a fence or wall.

   {To throw in}.
       (a) To inject, as a fluid.
       (b) To put in; to deposit with others; to contribute; as,
           to throw in a few dollars to help make up a fund; to
           throw in an occasional comment.
       (c) To add without enumeration or valuation, as something
           extra to clinch a bargain.

   {To throw off}.
       (a) To expel; to free one's self from; as, to throw off a
           disease.
       (b) To reject; to discard; to abandon; as, to throw off
           all sense of shame; to throw off a dependent.
       (c) To make a start in a hunt or race. [Eng.]

   {To throw on}, to cast on; to load.

   {To throw one's self down}, to lie down neglectively or
      suddenly.

   {To throw one's self on} or {To throw one's self upon}.
       (a) To fall upon.
       (b) To resign one's self to the favor, clemency, or
           sustain power of (another); to repose upon.

   {To throw out}.
       (a) To cast out; to reject or discard; to expel. ``The
           other two, whom they had thrown out, they were
           content should enjoy their exile.'' --Swift. ``The
           bill was thrown out.'' --Swift.
       (b) To utter; to give utterance to; to speak; as, to
           throw out insinuation or observation. ``She throws
           out thrilling shrieks.'' --Spenser.
       (c) To distance; to leave behind. --Addison.
       (d) To cause to project; as, to throw out a pier or an
           abutment.
       (e) To give forth; to emit; as, an electric lamp throws
           out a brilliant light.
       (f) To put out; to confuse; as, a sudden question often
           throws out an orator.

   {To throw over}, to abandon the cause of; to desert; to
      discard; as, to throw over a friend in difficulties.

   {To throw up}.
       (a) To resign; to give up; to demit; as, to throw up a
           commission. ``Experienced gamesters throw up their
           cards when they know that the game is in the enemy's
           hand.'' --Addison.
       (b) To reject from the stomach; to vomit.
       (c) To construct hastily; as, to throw up a breastwork of
           earth.
           [1913 Webster]
           [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Fault \Fault\, n. [OE. faut, faute, F. faute (cf. It., Sp., &amp;
   Pg. falta), fr. a verb meaning to want, fail, freq., fr. L.
   fallere to deceive. See {Fail}, and cf. {Default}.]
   1. Defect; want; lack; default.
      [1913 Webster]

            One, it pleases me, for fault of a better, to call
            my friend.                            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Anything that fails, that is wanting, or that impairs
      excellence; a failing; a defect; a blemish.
      [1913 Webster]

            As patches set upon a little breach
            Discredit more in hiding of the fault. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A moral failing; a defect or dereliction from duty; a
      deviation from propriety; an offense less serious than a
      crime.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Geol. &amp; Mining)
      (a) A dislocation of the strata of the vein.
      (b) In coal seams, coal rendered worthless by impurities
          in the seam; as, slate fault, dirt fault, etc.
          --Raymond.
          [1913 Webster]

   5. (Hunting) A lost scent; act of losing the scent.
      [1913 Webster]

            Ceasing their clamorous cry till they have singled,
            With much ado, the cold fault cleary out. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Tennis) Failure to serve the ball into the proper court.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Elec.) A defective point in an electric circuit due to a
      crossing of the parts of the conductor, or to contact with
      another conductor or the earth, or to a break in the
      circuit.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. (Geol. &amp; Mining) A dislocation caused by a slipping of
      rock masses along a plane of facture; also, the dislocated
      structure resulting from such slipping.

   Note: The surface along which the dislocated masses have
         moved is called the

   {fault plane}. When this plane is vertical, the fault is a

   {vertical fault}; when its inclination is such that the
      present relative position of the two masses could have
      been produced by the sliding down, along the fault plane,
      of the mass on its upper side, the fault is a

   {normal fault}, or {gravity fault}. When the fault plane is
      so inclined that the mass on its upper side has moved up
      relatively, the fault is then called a

   {reverse fault} (or {reversed fault}), {thrust fault}, or
   {overthrust fault}. If no vertical displacement has resulted,
      the fault is then called a

   {horizontal fault}. The linear extent of the dislocation
      measured on the fault plane and in the direction of
      movement is the

   {displacement}; the vertical displacement is the

   {throw}; the horizontal displacement is the

   {heave}. The direction of the line of intersection of the
      fault plane with a horizontal plane is the

   {trend} of the fault. A fault is a

   {strike fault} when its trend coincides approximately with
      the strike of associated strata (i.e., the line of
      intersection of the plane of the strata with a horizontal
      plane); it is a

   {dip fault} when its trend is at right angles to the strike;
      an

   {oblique fault} when its trend is oblique to the strike.
      Oblique faults and dip faults are sometimes called

   {cross faults}. A series of closely associated parallel
      faults are sometimes called

   {step faults} and sometimes

   {distributive faults}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {At fault}, unable to find the scent and continue chase;
      hence, in trouble or embarrassment, and unable to proceed;
      puzzled; thrown off the track.

   {To find fault}, to find reason for blaming or complaining;
      to express dissatisfaction; to complain; -- followed by
      with before the thing complained of; but formerly by at.
      ``Matter to find fault at.'' --Robynson (More's Utopia).

   Syn: -- Error; blemish; defect; imperfection; weakness;
        blunder; failing; vice.

   Usage: {Fault}, {Failing}, {Defect}, {Foible}. A fault is
          positive, something morally wrong; a failing is
          negative, some weakness or falling short in a man's
          character, disposition, or habits; a defect is also
          negative, and as applied to character is the absence
          of anything which is necessary to its completeness or
          perfection; a foible is a less important weakness,
          which we overlook or smile at. A man may have many
          failings, and yet commit but few faults; or his faults
          and failings may be few, while his foibles are obvious
          to all. The faults of a friend are often palliated or
          explained away into mere defects, and the defects or
          foibles of an enemy exaggerated into faults. ``I have
          failings in common with every human being, besides my
          own peculiar faults; but of avarice I have generally
          held myself guiltless.'' --Fox. ``Presumption and
          self-applause are the foibles of mankind.''
          --Waterland.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>throw</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>throw
     n 1: the act of throwing (propelling something through the air
          with a rapid movement of the arm and wrist); "the
          catcher made a good throw to second base"
     2: a single chance or instance; "he couldn't afford $50 a
        throw"
     3: the maximum movement available to a pivoted or reciprocating
        piece by a cam [syn: {stroke}, {cam stroke}]
     4: the distance that something can be thrown; "it is just a
        stone's throw from here"
     5: bedclothes consisting of a lightweight cloth covering (an
        afghan or bedspread) that is casually thrown over
        something
     6: the throwing of an object in order to determine an outcome
        randomly; "he risked his fortune on a throw of the dice"
     v 1: project through the air; "throw a frisbee"
     2: move violently, energetically, or carelessly; "She threw
        herself forwards"
     3: get rid of; "he shed his image as a pushy boss"; "shed your
        clothes" [syn: {shed}, {cast}, {cast off}, {shake off}, {throw
        off}, {throw away}, {drop}]
     4: place or put with great energy; "She threw the blanket
        around the child"; "thrust the money in the hands of the
        beggar" [syn: {thrust}]
     5: convey or communicate; of a smile, a look, a physical
        gesture; "Throw a glance"; "She gave me a dirty look"
        [syn: {give}]
     6: cause to go on or to be engaged or set in operation; "switch
        on the light"; "throw the lever" [syn: {flip}, {switch}]
     7: put or send forth; "She threw the flashlight beam into the
        corner"; "The setting sun threw long shadows"; "cast a
        spell"; "cast a warm light" [syn: {project}, {cast}, {contrive}]
     8: to put into a state or activity hastily, suddenly, or
        carelessly; "Jane threw dinner together"; "throw the car
        into reverse"
     9: cause to be confused emotionally [syn: {bewilder}, {bemuse},
         {discombobulate}]
     10: utter with force; utter vehemently; "hurl insults"; "throw
         accusations at someone" [syn: {hurl}]
     11: organize or be responsible for; "hold a reception"; "have,
         throw, or make a party"; "give a course" [syn: {hold}, {have},
          {make}, {give}]
     12: make on a potter's wheel; "she threw a beautiful teapot"
     13: cause to fall off; "The horse threw its unexperienced rider"
     14: throw (a die) out onto a flat surface; "Throw a six"
     15: be confusing or perplexing to; cause to be unable to think
         clearly; "These questions confuse even the experts";
         "This question completely threw me"; "This question
         befuddled even the teacher" [syn: {confuse}, {fox}, {befuddle},
          {fuddle}, {bedevil}, {confound}, {discombobulate}]
     [also: {thrown}, {threw}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
