<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>ticket</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ticket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ticket \Tick"et\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Ticketed}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Ticketing}.]
   1. To distinguish by a ticket; to put a ticket on; as, to
      ticket goods.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To furnish with a tickets; to book; as, to ticket
      passengers to California. [U. S.]
      [1913 Webster]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ticket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Ticket \Tick"et\, n. [F. ['e]tiquette a label, ticket, fr. OF.
   estiquette, or OF. etiquet, estiquet; both of Teutonic
   origin, and akin to E. stick. See {Stick}, n. &amp; v., and cf.
   {Etiquette}, {Tick} credit.]
   A small piece of paper, cardboard, or the like, serving as a
   notice, certificate, or distinguishing token of something.
   Specifically: 
   [1913 Webster]
   (a) A little note or notice. [Obs. or Local]
       [1913 Webster]

             He constantly read his lectures twice a week for
             above forty years, giving notice of the time to his
             auditors in a ticket on the school doors. --Fuller.
       [1913 Webster]
   (b) A tradesman's bill or account. [Obs.]
       [1913 Webster]

   Note: Hence the phrase on ticket, on account; whence, by
         abbreviation, came the phrase on tick. See 1st {Tick}.
         [1913 Webster]

               Your courtier is mad to take up silks and velvets
               On ticket for his mistress.        --J. Cotgrave.
         [1913 Webster]
   (c) A certificate or token of right of admission to a place
       of assembly, or of passage in a public conveyance; as, a
       theater ticket; a railroad or steamboat ticket.
       [1913 Webster]
   (d) A label to show the character or price of goods.
       [1913 Webster]
   (e) A certificate or token of a share in a lottery or other
       scheme for distributing money, goods, or the like.
       [1913 Webster]
   (f) (Politics) A printed list of candidates to be voted for
       at an election; a set of nominations by one party for
       election; a ballot. [U. S.]
       [1913 Webster]

             The old ticket forever! We have it by thirty-four
             votes.                               --Sarah
                                                  Franklin
                                                  (1766).
       [1913 Webster]

   {Scratched ticket}, a ticket from which the names of one or
      more of the candidates are scratched out.

   {Split ticket}, a ticket representing different divisions of
      a party, or containing candidates selected from two or
      more parties.

   {Straight ticket}, a ticket containing the regular
      nominations of a party, without change.

   {Ticket day} (Com.), the day before the settling or pay day
      on the stock exchange, when the names of the actual
      purchasers are rendered in by one stockbroker to another.
      [Eng.] --Simmonds.

   {Ticket of leave}, a license or permit given to a convict, or
      prisoner of the crown, to go at large, and to labor for
      himself before the expiration of his sentence, subject to
      certain specific conditions. [Eng.] --Simmonds.

   {Ticket porter}, a licensed porter wearing a badge by which
      he may be identified. [Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>ticket</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>ticket
     n 1: a commercial document showing that the holder is entitled to
          something (as to ride on public transportation or to
          enter a public entertainment)
     2: a summons issued to an offender (especially to someone who
        violates a traffic regulation)
     3: a list of candidates nominated by a political party to run
        for election to public offices [syn: {slate}]
     4: the appropriate or desirable thing; "this car could be just
        the ticket for a small family" [syn: {just the ticket}]
     v 1: issue a ticket or a fine to as a penalty; "I was fined for
          parking on the wrong side of the street"; "Move your car
          or else you will be ticketed!" [syn: {fine}]
     2: provide with a ticket for passage or admission; "Ticketed
        passengers can board now"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
