<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tie</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tie</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tie \Tie\, n.; pl. {Ties}. [AS. t[=e]ge, t?ge, t[=i]ge.
   [root]64. See {Tie}, v. t.]
   1. A knot; a fastening.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A bond; an obligation, moral or legal; as, the sacred ties
      of friendship or of duty; the ties of allegiance.
      [1913 Webster]

            No distance breaks the tie of blood.  --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A knot of hair, as at the back of a wig. --Young.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An equality in numbers, as of votes, scores, etc., which
      prevents either party from being victorious; equality in
      any contest, as a race.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Arch. &amp; Engin.) A beam or rod for holding two parts
      together; in railways, one of the transverse timbers which
      support the track and keep it in place.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mus.) A line, usually straight, drawn across the stems of
      notes, or a curved line written over or under the notes,
      signifying that they are to be slurred, or closely united
      in the performance, or that two notes of the same pitch
      are to be sounded as one; a bind; a ligature.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. pl. Low shoes fastened with lacings.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Bale tie}, a fastening for the ends of a hoop for a bale.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tie</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tie \Tie\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tied}(Obs. {Tight}); p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Tying}.] [OE. ti?en, teyen, AS. t[=i]gan, ti['e]gan,
   fr. te['a]g, te['a]h, a rope; akin to Icel. taug, and AS.
   te['o]n to draw, to pull. See {Tug}, v. t., and cf. {Tow} to
   drag.]
   1. To fasten with a band or cord and knot; to bind. ``Tie the
      kine to the cart.'' --1 Sam. vi. 7.
      [1913 Webster]

            My son, keep thy father's commandment, and forsake
            not the law of thy mother: bind them continually
            upon thine heart, and tie them about thy neck.
                                                  --Prov. vi.
                                                  20,21.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To form, as a knot, by interlacing or complicating a cord;
      also, to interlace, or form a knot in; as, to tie a cord
      to a tree; to knit; to knot. ``We do not tie this knot
      with an intention to puzzle the argument.'' --Bp. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To unite firmly; to fasten; to hold.
      [1913 Webster]

            In bond of virtuous love together tied. --Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To hold or constrain by authority or moral influence, as
      by knotted cords; to oblige; to constrain; to restrain; to
      confine.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not tied to rules of policy, you find
            Revenge less sweet than a forgiving mind. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Mus.) To unite, as notes, by a cross line, or by a curved
      line, or slur, drawn over or under them.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To make an equal score with, in a contest; to be even
      with.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To ride and tie}. See under {Ride}.

   {To tie down}.
      (a) To fasten so as to prevent from rising.
      (b) To restrain; to confine; to hinder from action.

   {To tie up}, to confine; to restrain; to hinder from motion
      or action.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tie</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tie \Tie\, v. i.
   To make a tie; to make an equal score.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tie</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TIE
     Terminal Interface Equipment
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tie</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tie
     n 1: neckwear consisting of a long narrow piece of material worn
          (mostly by men) under a collar and tied in knot at the
          front; "he stood in front of the mirror tightening his
          necktie"; "he wore a vest and tie" [syn: {necktie}]
     2: a social or business relationship; "a valuable financial
        affiliation"; "he was sorry he had to sever his ties with
        other members of the team"; "many close associations with
        England" [syn: {affiliation}, {association}, {tie-up}]
     3: the finish of a contest in which the score is tied and the
        winner is undecided; "the game ended in a draw"; "their
        record was 3 wins, 6 losses and a tie" [syn: {draw}, {standoff}]
     4: a horizontal beam used to prevent two other structural
        members from spreading apart or separating; "he nailed the
        rafters together with a tie beam" [syn: {tie beam}]
     5: a fastener that serves to join or link; "the walls are held
        together with metal links placed in the wet mortar during
        construction" [syn: {link}, {linkup}, {tie-in}]
     6: equality of score in a contest
     7: (music) a slur over two notes of the same pitch; indicates
        that the note is to be sustained for their combined time
        value
     8: one of the cross braces that support the rails on a railway
        track; "the British call a railroad tie a sleeper" [syn: {railroad
        tie}, {crosstie}, {sleeper}]
     9: a cord (or string or ribbon or wire etc.) with which
        something is tied; "he needed a tie for the packages"
     v 1: fasten or secure with a rope, string, or cord; "They tied
          their victim to the chair" [syn: {bind}] [ant: {untie}]
     2: finish a game with an equal number of points, goals, etc.;
        "The teams drew a tie" [syn: {draw}]
     3: limit or restrict to; "I am tied to UNIX"; "These big jets
        are tied to large airports"
     4: connect, fasten, or put together two or more pieces; "Can
        you connect the two loudspeakers?"; "Tie the ropes
        together"; "Link arms" [syn: {connect}, {link}, {link up}]
        [ant: {disconnect}]
     5: form a knot or bow in; "tie a necktie"
     6: create social or emotional ties; "The grandparents want to
        bond with the child" [syn: {bind}, {attach}, {bond}]
     7: perform a marriage ceremony; "The minister married us on
        Saturday"; "We were wed the following week"; "The couple
        got spliced on Hawaii" [syn: {marry}, {wed}, {splice}]
     8: make by tying pieces together; "The fishermen tied their
        flies"
     9: unite musical notes by a tie
     [also: {tying}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
