<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tin
   Heb. bedil (Num. 31:22; Ezek. 22:18, 20), a metal well known in
   ancient times. It is the general opinion that the Phoenicians of
   Tyre and Sidon obtained their supplies of tin from the British
   Isles. In Ezek. 27:12 it is said to have been brought from
   Tarshish, which was probably a commercial emporium supplied with
   commodities from other places. In Isa. 1:25 the word so rendered
   is generally understood of lead, the alloy with which the silver
   had become mixed (ver. 22). The fire of the Babylonish Captivity
   would be the means of purging out the idolatrous alloy that had
   corrupted the people.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>elements</Id>
        <Name>Elements database 20001107</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tin
Symbol: Sn
Atomic number: 50
Atomic weight: 118.69
Silvery malleable metallic element belonging to group 14 of the periodic
table. Twenty-six isotopes are known, five of which are radioactive.
Chemically reactive. Combines directly with chlorine and oxygen and
displaces hydrogen from dilute acids.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tin \Tin\, n. [As. tin; akin to D. tin, G. zinn, OHG. zin, Icel.
   &amp; Dan. tin, Sw. tenn; of unknown origin.]
   1. (Chem.) An elementary substance found as an oxide in the
      mineral cassiterite, and reduced as a soft silvery-white
      crystalline metal, with a tinge of yellowish-blue, and a
      high luster. It is malleable at ordinary temperatures, but
      brittle when heated. It is softer than gold and can be
      beaten out into very thin strips called tinfoil. It is
      ductile at 2120, when it can be drawn out into wire which
      is not very tenacious; it melts at 4420, and at a higher
      temperature burns with a brilliant white light. Air and
      moisture act on tin very slightly. The peculiar properties
      of tin, especially its malleability, its brilliancy and
      the slowness with which it rusts make it very serviceable.
      With other metals it forms valuable alloys, as bronze, gun
      metal, bell metal, pewter and solder. It is not easily
      oxidized in the air, and is used chiefly to coat iron to
      protect it from rusting, in the form of tin foil with
      mercury to form the reflective surface of mirrors, and in
      solder, bronze, speculum metal, and other alloys. Its
      compounds are designated as stannous, or stannic. Symbol
      Sn (Stannum). Atomic weight 117.4.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Thin plates of iron covered with tin; tin plate.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Money. [Cant] --Beaconsfield.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Block tin} (Metal.), commercial tin, cast into blocks, and
      partially refined, but containing small quantities of
      various impurities, as copper, lead, iron, arsenic, etc.;
      solid tin as distinguished from tin plate; -- called also
      {bar tin}.

   {Butter of tin}. (Old Chem.) See {Fuming liquor of Libavius},
      under {Fuming}.

   {Grain tin}. (Metal.) See under {Grain}.

   {Salt of tin} (Dyeing), stannous chloride, especially so
      called when used as a mordant.

   {Stream tin}. See under {Stream}.

   {Tin cry} (Chem.), the peculiar creaking noise made when a
      bar of tin is bent. It is produced by the grating of the
      crystal granules on each other.

   {Tin foil}, tin reduced to a thin leaf.

   {Tin frame} (Mining), a kind of buddle used in washing tin
      ore.

   {Tin liquor}, {Tin mordant} (Dyeing), stannous chloride, used
      as a mordant in dyeing and calico printing.

   {Tin penny}, a customary duty in England, formerly paid to
      tithingmen for liberty to dig in tin mines. [Obs.]
      --Bailey.

   {Tin plate}, thin sheet iron coated with tin.

   {Tin pyrites}. See {Stannite}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tin \Tin\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tinned}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Tinning}.]
   To cover with tin or tinned iron, or to overlay with tin
   foil.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Azotine \Az"o*tine\, n. Also -tin \-tin\ . [Azote + -ine.]
   1. An explosive consisting of sodium nitrate, charcoal,
      sulphur, and petroleum.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   2. same as 1st {Ammonite}, 2.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tin
     n 1: a silvery malleable metallic element that resists corrosion;
          used in many alloys and to coat other metals to prevent
          corrosion; obtained chiefly from cassiterite where it
          occurs as tin oxide [syn: {Sn}, {atomic number 50}]
     2: metal container for storing dry foods such as tea or flour
        [syn: {canister}, {cannister}]
     3: airtight sealed metal container for food or drink or paint
        etc. [syn: {can}, {tin can}]
     v 1: plate with tin
     2: preserve in a can or tin; "tinned foods are not very tasty"
        [syn: {can}, {put up}]
     3: prepare (a metal) for soldering or brazing by applying a
        thin layer of solder to the surface
     [also: {tinning}, {tinned}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
