<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>toe</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toe \Toe\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Toed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Toeing}.]
   To touch or reach with the toes; to come fully up to; as, to
   toe the mark.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toe \Toe\, v. i.
   To hold or carry the toes (in a certain way).
   [1913 Webster]

   {To toe in}, to stand or carry the feet in such a way that
      the toes of either foot incline toward the other.

   {To toe out}, to have the toes of each foot, in standing or
      walking, incline from the other foot.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toe \Toe\, n. [OE. too, taa, AS. t[=a]; akin to D. teen, G.
   zehe, OHG. z[=e]ha, Icel. t[=a], Sw. t[*a], Dan. taa; of
   uncertain origin. [root]60.]
   1. (Anat.) One of the terminal members, or digits, of the
      foot of a man or an animal. ``Each one, tripping on his
      toe.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Zo["o]l.) The fore part of the hoof or foot of an animal.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything, or any part, corresponding to the toe of the
      foot; as, the toe of a boot; the toe of a skate.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mach.)
      (a) The journal, or pivot, at the lower end of a revolving
          shaft or spindle, which rests in a step.
      (b) A lateral projection at one end, or between the ends,
          of a piece, as a rod or bolt, by means of which it is
          moved.
      (c) A projection from the periphery of a revolving piece,
          acting as a cam to lift another piece.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Toe biter} (Zo["o]l.), a tadpole; a polliwig.

   {Toe drop} (Med.), a morbid condition of the foot in which
      the toe is depressed and the heel elevated, as in talipes
      equinus. See {Talipes}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>toe
     adj : having a toe or toes of a specified kind; often used in
           combination; "long-toed"; "five-toed" [syn: {toed}]
           [ant: {toeless}]
     n 1: one of the digits of the foot
     2: the part of footwear that provides a covering for the toes
     3: forepart of a hoof
     4: (golf) the part of a clubhead farthest from the shaft
     v 1: walk so that the toes assume an indicated position or
          direction; "She toes inwards"
     2: drive obliquely; "toe a nail" [syn: {toenail}]
     3: hit (a golf ball) with the toe of the club
     4: drive (a golf ball) with the toe of the club
     5: touch with the toe
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
