<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>toll</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll
   one of the branches of the king of Persia's revenues (Ezra 4:13;
   7:24), probably a tax levied from those who used the bridges and
   fords and highways.
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tole \Tole\ (t[=o]l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Toled}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Toling}.] [OE. tollen to draw, to entice; of uncertain
   origin. Cf. {Toll} to ring a bell.]
   To draw, or cause to follow, by displaying something pleasing
   or desirable; to allure by some bait. [Written also {toll}.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Whatever you observe him to be more frighted at then he
         should, tole him on to by insensible degrees, till at
         last he masters the difficulty.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll \Toll\, v. i.
   1. To pay toll or tallage. [R.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To take toll; to raise a tax. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Well could he [the miller] steal corn and toll
            thrice.                               --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            No Italian priest
            Shall tithe or toll in our dominions. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll \Toll\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tolled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Tolling}.]
   To sound or ring, as a bell, with strokes uniformly repeated
   at intervals, as at funerals, or in calling assemblies, or to
   announce the death of a person.
   [1913 Webster]

         The country cocks do crow, the clocks do toll. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]

         Now sink in sorrows with a tolling bell. --Pope.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll \Toll\, v. t.
   To collect, as a toll. --Shak.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll \Toll\, n.
   The sound of a bell produced by strokes slowly and uniformly
   repeated.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll \Toll\, n. [OE. tol, AS. toll; akin to OS. &amp; D. tol, G.
   zoll, OHG. zol, Icel. tollr, Sw. tull, Dan. told, and also to
   E. tale; -- originally, that which is counted out in payment.
   See {Tale} number.]
   1. A tax paid for some liberty or privilege, particularly for
      the privilege of passing over a bridge or on a highway, or
      for that of vending goods in a fair, market, or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Sax. &amp; O. Eng. Law) A liberty to buy and sell within the
      bounds of a manor.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A portion of grain taken by a miller as a compensation for
      grinding.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Toll and team} (O. Eng. Law), the privilege of having a
      market, and jurisdiction of villeins. --Burrill.

   {Toll bar}, a bar or beam used on a canal for stopping boats
      at the tollhouse, or on a road for stopping passengers.

   {Toll bridge}, a bridge where toll is paid for passing over
      it.

   {Toll corn}, corn taken as pay for grinding at a mill.

   {Toll dish}, a dish for measuring toll in mills.

   {Toll gatherer}, a man who takes, or gathers, toll.

   {Toll hop}, a toll dish. [Obs.] --Crabb.

   {Toll thorough} (Eng. Law), toll taken by a town for beasts
      driven through it, or over a bridge or ferry maintained at
      its cost. --Brande &amp; C.

   {Toll traverse} (Eng. Law), toll taken by an individual for
      beasts driven across his ground; toll paid by a person for
      passing over the private ground, bridge, ferry, or the
      like, of another.

   {Toll turn} (Eng. Law), a toll paid at the return of beasts
      from market, though they were not sold. --Burrill.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Tax; custom; duty; impost.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll \Toll\, v. t. [L. tollere. See {Tolerate}.] (O. Eng. Law)
   To take away; to vacate; to annul.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Toll \Toll\, v. t. [See {Tole}.]
   1. To draw; to entice; to allure. See {Tole}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [Probably the same word as toll to draw, and at first
      meaning, to ring in order to draw people to church.] To
      cause to sound, as a bell, with strokes slowly and
      uniformly repeated; as, to toll the funeral bell. ``The
      sexton tolled the bell.'' --Hood.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To strike, or to indicate by striking, as the hour; to
      ring a toll for; as, to toll a departed friend. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Slow tolls the village clock the drowsy hour.
                                                  --Beattie.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To call, summon, or notify, by tolling or ringing.
      [1913 Webster]

            When hollow murmurs of their evening bells
            Dismiss the sleepy swains, and toll them to their
            cells.                                --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>toll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>toll
     n 1: a fee levied for the use of roads or bridges (used for
          maintenance)
     2: value measured by what must be given or done or undergone to
        obtain something; "the cost in human life was enormous";
        "the price of success is hard work"; "what price glory?"
        [syn: {price}, {cost}]
     3: the sound of a bell being struck; "saved by the bell"; "she
        heard the distant toll of church bells" [syn: {bell}]
     v 1: ring slowly; "For whom the bell tolls"
     2: charge a fee for using; "Toll the bridges into New York
        City"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
