<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tomb</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tomb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TOMB, n.  The House of Indifference.  Tombs are now by common consent
invested with a certain sanctity, but when they have been long
tenanted it is considered no sin to break them open and rifle them,
the famous Egyptologist, Dr. Huggyns, explaining that a tomb may be
innocently "glened" as soon as its occupant is done "smellynge," the
soul being then all exhaled.  This reasonable view is now generally
accepted by archaeologists, whereby the noble science of Curiosity has
been greatly dignified.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tomb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tomb \Tomb\,, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tombed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Tombing}.]
   To place in a tomb; to bury; to inter; to entomb.
   [1913 Webster]

         I tombed my brother that I might be blessed. --Chapman.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tomb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tomb \Tomb\, n. [OE. tombe, toumbe, F. tombe, LL. tumba, fr. Gr.
   ? a tomb, grave; perhaps akin to L. tumulus a mound. Cf.
   {Tumulus}.]
   1. A pit in which the dead body of a human being is
      deposited; a grave; a sepulcher.
      [1913 Webster]

            As one dead in the bottom of a tomb.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A house or vault, formed wholly or partly in the earth,
      with walls and a roof, for the reception of the dead. ``In
      tomb of marble stones.'' --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A monument erected to inclose the body and preserve the
      name and memory of the dead.
      [1913 Webster]

            Hang her an epitaph upon her tomb.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tomb bat} (Zo["o]l.), any one of species of Old World bats
      of the genus {Taphozous} which inhabit tombs, especially
      the Egyptian species ({Taphozous perforatus}).
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tomb</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tomb
     n : a place for the burial of a corpse (especially beneath the
         ground and marked by a tombstone); "he put flowers on his
         mother's grave" [syn: {grave}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
