<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>top</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TOP
     
        {Technical/Office Protocol}
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Top \Top\, n. [CF. OD. dop, top, OHG., MNG., &amp; dial. G. topf;
   perhaps akin to G. topf a pot.]
   1. A child's toy, commonly in the form of a conoid or pear,
      made to spin on its point, usually by drawing off a string
      wound round its surface or stem, the motion being
      sometimes continued by means of a whip.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Rope Making) A plug, or conical block of wood, with
      longitudital grooves on its surface, in which the strands
      of the rope slide in the process of twisting.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Top \Top\, n. [AS. top; akin to OFries. top a tuft, D. top top,
   OHG. zopf end, tip, tuft of hair, G. zopf tuft of hair,
   pigtail, top of a tree, Icel. toppr a tuft of hair, crest,
   top, Dan. top, Sw. topp pinnacle, top; of uncertain origin.
   Cf. {Tuft}.]
   1. The highest part of anything; the upper end, edge, or
      extremity; the upper side or surface; summit; apex;
      vertex; cover; lid; as, the top of a spire; the top of a
      house; the top of a mountain; the top of the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

            The star that bids the shepherd fold,
            Now the top of heaven doth hold.      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The utmost degree; the acme; the summit.
      [1913 Webster]

            The top of my ambition is to contribute to that
            work.                                 --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The highest rank; the most honorable position; the utmost
      attainable place; as, to be at the top of one's class, or
      at the top of the school.
      [1913 Webster]

            And wears upon his baby brow the round
            And top of sovereignty.               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The chief person; the most prominent one.
      [1913 Webster]

            Other . . . aspired to be the top of zealots.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The crown of the head, or the hair upon it; the head.
      ``From top to toe'' --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

            All the stored vengeance of Heaven fall
            On her ungrateful top !               --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. The head, or upper part, of a plant.
      [1913 Webster]

            The buds . . . are called heads, or tops, as
            cabbageheads.                         --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Naut.) A platform surrounding the head of the lower mast
      and projecting on all sudes. It serves to spead the
      topmast rigging, thus strengheningthe mast, and also
      furnishes a convenient standing place for the men aloft.
      --Totten.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Wool Manuf.) A bundle or ball of slivers of comkbed wool,
      from which the noils, or dust, have been taken out.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. Eve; verge; point. [R.] ``He was upon the top of his
      marriage with Magdaleine.'' --Knolles.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. The part of a cut gem between the girdle, or
       circumference, and the table, or flat upper surface.
       --Knight.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. pl. Top-boots. [Slang] --Dickens.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Golf)
       (a) A stroke on the top of the ball.
       (b) A forward spin given to the ball by hitting it on or
           near the top.
           [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Note: Top is often used adjectively or as the first part of
         compound words, usually self-explaining; as, top stone,
         or topstone; top-boots, or top boots; top soil, or
         top-soil.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Top and but} (Shipbuilding), a phrase used to denote a
      method of working long tapering planks by bringing the but
      of one plank to the top of the other to make up a constant
      breadth in two layers.

   {Top minnow} (Zo["o]l.), a small viviparous fresh-water fish
      ({Gambusia patruelis}) abundant in the Southern United
      States. Also applied to other similar species.

   {From top to toe}, from head to foot; altogether.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Top \Top\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Topped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Topping}.]
   1. To rise aloft; to be eminent; to tower; as, lofty ridges
      and topping mountains. --Derham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To predominate; as, topping passions. ``Influenced by
      topping uneasiness.'' --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To excel; to rise above others.
      [1913 Webster]

            But write thy, and top.               --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Golf) To strike a ball above the center.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   5. (Naut.) To rise at one end, as a yard; -- usually with up.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Top \Top\, v. t.
   1. To cover on the top; to tip; to cap; -- chiefly used in
      the past participle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Like moving mountains topped with snow. --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

            A mount
            Of alabaster, topped with golden spires. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To rise above; to excel; to outgo; to surpass.
      [1913 Webster]

            Topping all others in boasting.       --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Edmund the base shall top the legitimate. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To rise to the top of; to go over the top of.
      [1913 Webster]

            But wind about till thou hast topped the hill.
                                                  --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To take off the or upper part of; to crop.
      [1913 Webster]

            Top your rose trees a little with your knife.
                                                  --Evelyn.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To perform eminently, or better than before.
      [1913 Webster]

            From endeavoring universally to top their parts,
            they will go universally beyond them. --Jeffrey.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Naut.) To raise one end of, as a yard, so that that end
      becomes higher than the other.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Dyeing) To cover with another dye; as, to top aniline
      black with methyl violet to prevent greening and crocking.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   8. To put a stiffening piece or back on (a saw blade).
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. To arrange, as fruit, with the best on top. [Cant]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   10. To strike the top of, as a wall, with the hind feet, in
       jumping, so as to gain new impetus; -- said of a horse.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   11. To improve (domestic animals, esp. sheep) by crossing
       certain individuals or breeds with other superior.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   12. (Naut.) To raise one end of, as a yard, so that that end
       becomes higher than the other.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   13. To cut, break, or otherwise take off the top of (a steel
       ingot) to remove unsound metal.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   14. (Golf) To strike (the ball) above the center; also, to
       make (as a stroke) by hitting the ball in this way.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To top off},
       (a) to complete by putting on, or finishing, the top or
           uppermost part of; as, to top off a stack of hay;
           hence, to complete; to finish; to adorn.
       (b) to completely fill (an almost full tank) by adding
           more of the liquid it already contains.
           [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TOP
     Technical and Office Protocols
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TOP
     The OS-9 Project (OS-9)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>top</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>top
     adj 1: situated at the top or highest position; "the top shelf"
            [syn: {top(a)}] [ant: {bottom(a)}, {side(a)}]
     2: not to be surpassed; "his top effort" [syn: {greatest}]
     n 1: the upper part of anything; "the mower cuts off the tops of
          the grass"; "the title should be written at the top of
          the first page"
     2: the highest or uppermost side of anything; "put your books
        on top of the desk"; "only the top side of the box was
        painted" [syn: {top side}, {upper side}, {upside}]
     3: the top point of a mountain or hill; "the view from the peak
        was magnificent"; "they clambered to the summit of
        Monadnock" [syn: {peak}, {crown}, {crest}, {tip}, {summit}]
     4: the first half of an inning; while the visiting team is at
        bat; "a relief pitcher took over in the top of the fifth"
        [syn: {top of the inning}] [ant: {bottom}]
     5: the highest level or degree attainable; "his landscapes were
        deemed the acme of beauty"; "the artist's gifts are at
        their acme"; "at the height of her career"; "the peak of
        perfection"; "summer was at its peak"; "...catapulted
        Einstein to the pinnacle of fame"; "the summit of his
        ambition"; "so many highest superlatives achieved by man";
        "at the top of his profession" [syn: {acme}, {height}, {elevation},
         {peak}, {pinnacle}, {summit}, {superlative}]
     6: the greatest possible intensity; "he screamed at the top of
        his lungs"
     7: platform surrounding the head of a lower mast
     8: a conical child's plaything tapering to a steel point on
        which it can be made to spin; "he got a bright red top and
        string for his birthday" [syn: {whirligig}, {teetotum}, {spinning
        top}]
     9: covering for a hole (especially a hole in the top of a
        container); "he removed the top of the carton"; "he
        couldn't get the top off of the bottle"; "put the cover
        back on the kettle" [syn: {cover}]
     10: a garment (especially for women) that extends from the
         shoulders to the waist or hips; "he stared as she
         buttoned her top"
     11: a canvas tent to house the audience at a circus performance;
         "he was afraid of a fire in the circus tent"; "they had
         the big top up in less than an hour" [syn: {circus tent},
          {big top}, {round top}]
     v 1: go beyond; "She exceeded our expectations"; "She topped her
          performance of last year" [syn: {exceed}, {transcend}, {overstep},
           {pass}, {go past}]
     2: pass by, over, or under without making contact; "the balloon
        cleared the tree tops" [syn: {clear}]
     3: be at the top of or constitute the top or highest point; "A
        star tops the Christmas Tree"
     4: be ahead of others; be the first; "she topped her class
        every year" [syn: {lead}]
     5: provide with a top; "the towers were topped with conical
        roofs"
     6: reach or ascend the top of; "The hikers topped the mountain
        just before noon"
     7: strike (the top part of a ball in golf, baseball, or pool)
        giving it a forward spin
     8: cut the top off; "top trees and bushes" [syn: {pinch}]
     9: be the culminating event; "The speech crowned the meeting"
        [syn: {crown}]
     10: finish up or conclude; "They topped off their dinner with a
         cognac"; "top the evening with champagne" [syn: {top off}]
     [also: {topping}, {topped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
