<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>topology</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>topology</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>topology
     
        1. &lt;mathematics&gt; The branch of mathematics dealing with
        {continuous transformations}.
     
        2. &lt;networking&gt; Which {hosts} are directly connected to which
        other hosts in a {network}.  {Network layer} processes need to
        consider the current network topology to be able to {route}
        {packets} to their final destination reliably and efficiently.
     
        (2001-03-29)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>topology</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Topology \To*pol"o*gy\, n. [Gr. ? place + -logy.]
   The art of, or method for, assisting the memory by
   associating the thing or subject to be remembered with some
   place. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

   2. a branch of mathematics which studies the properties of
      geometrical forms which retain their identity under
      certain transformations, such as stretching or twisting,
      which are homeomorphic. See also {topologist}.
      [PJC]

   3. configuration, especially in three dimensions; -- used, e.
      g. of the configurations taken by macromolecules, such as
      superhelical DNA.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>topology</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>topology
     n 1: topographic study of a given place (especially the history
          of place as indicated by its topography); "Greenland's
          topology has been shaped by the glaciers of the ice age"
     2: the study of anatomy based on regions or divisions of the
        body and emphasizing the relations between various
        structures (muscles and nerves and arteries etc.) in that
        region [syn: {regional anatomy}, {topographic anatomy}]
     3: the branch of pure mathematics that deals only with the
        properties of a figure X that hold for every figure into
        which X can be transformed with a one-to-one
        correspondence that is continuous in both directions [syn:
         {analysis situs}]
     4: the configuration of a communication network [syn: {network
        topology}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
