<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>torpedo</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>marine mine \ma*rine" mine`\, n. (Mil.)
   A military explosive device designed to be placed on or under
   the surface of a body of water, and to explode when ships
   pass nearby or come in contact with it. Its function is to
   destroy enemy ships or deny hostile naval forces access to
   certain areas of the sea, usually near the shoreline. Also
   called {underwater mine} and {floating mine}, and previously
   referred to as a {torpedo} (See {torpedo}[2]
   (a) ).
       [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine \Mine\, n. [F., fr. LL. mina. See {Mine}, v. i.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A subterranean cavity or passage; especially:
      (a) A pit or excavation in the earth, from which metallic
          ores, precious stones, coal, or other mineral
          substances are taken by digging; -- distinguished from
          the pits from which stones for architectural purposes
          are taken, and which are called quarries.
      (b) (Mil.) A cavity or tunnel made under a fortification
          or other work, for the purpose of blowing up the
          superstructure with some explosive agent.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Any place where ore, metals, or precious stones are got by
      digging or washing the soil; as, a placer mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Fig.): A rich source of wealth or other good. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) An explosive device placed concealed in a location,
      on land or at sea, where an enemy vehicle or enemy
      personnel may pass through, having a triggering mechanism
      which detects people or vehicles, and which will explode
      and kill or maim personnel or destroy or damage vehicles.
      A mine placed at sea (formerly called a {torpedo}, see
      {torpedo}[2]
      (a) ) is also called an marine mine and underwater mine
          and sometimes called a floating mine, even though it
          may be anchored to the floor of the sea and not
          actually float freely. A mine placed on land (formerly
          called a {torpedo}, see {torpedo}[3]), usually buried,
          is called a land mine.
          [PJC]

   {Mine dial}, a form of magnetic compass used by miners.

   {Mine pig}, pig iron made wholly from ore; in distinction
      from {cinder pig}, which is made from ore mixed with forge
      or mill cinder.

   {gold mine}
      (a) a mine where gold is obtained.
      (b) (Fig.) a rich source of wealth or other good; same as
          {Mine} 3. --Raymond.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Mine \Mine\, n. [F., fr. LL. mina. See {Mine}, v. i.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A subterranean cavity or passage; especially:
      (a) A pit or excavation in the earth, from which metallic
          ores, precious stones, coal, or other mineral
          substances are taken by digging; -- distinguished from
          the pits from which stones for architectural purposes
          are taken, and which are called quarries.
      (b) (Mil.) A cavity or tunnel made under a fortification
          or other work, for the purpose of blowing up the
          superstructure with some explosive agent.
          [1913 Webster]

   2. Any place where ore, metals, or precious stones are got by
      digging or washing the soil; as, a placer mine.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Fig.): A rich source of wealth or other good. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mil.) An explosive device placed concealed in a location,
      on land or at sea, where an enemy vehicle or enemy
      personnel may pass through, having a triggering mechanism
      which detects people or vehicles, and which will explode
      and kill or maim personnel or destroy or damage vehicles.
      A mine placed at sea (formerly called a {torpedo}, see
      {torpedo}[2]
      (a) ) is also called an marine mine and underwater mine
          and sometimes called a floating mine, even though it
          may be anchored to the floor of the sea and not
          actually float freely. A mine placed on land (formerly
          called a {torpedo}, see {torpedo}[3]), usually buried,
          is called a land mine.
          [PJC]

   {Mine dial}, a form of magnetic compass used by miners.

   {Mine pig}, pig iron made wholly from ore; in distinction
      from {cinder pig}, which is made from ore mixed with forge
      or mill cinder.

   {gold mine}
      (a) a mine where gold is obtained.
      (b) (Fig.) a rich source of wealth or other good; same as
          {Mine} 3. --Raymond.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Torpedo \Tor*pe"do\, n.; pl. {Torpedoes}. [L. torpedo, -inis,
   from torpere to be stiff, numb, or torpid. See {Torpid}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. (Zo["o]l.) Any one of numerous species of elasmobranch
      fishes belonging to {Torpedo} and allied genera. They are
      related to the rays, but have the power of giving
      electrical shocks. Called also {crampfish}, and
      {numbfish}. See {Electrical fish}, under {Electrical}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The common European torpedo ({Torpedo vulgaris}) and
         the American species ({Torpedo occidentalis}) are the
         best known.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. An engine or machine for destroying ships by blowing them
      up; a mine[4]. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster +PJC]
      (a) A quantity of explosives anchored in a channel,
          beneath the water, or set adrift in a current, and so
          designed that they will explode when touched or
          approached by a vessel, or when an electric circuit is
          closed by an operator on shore; now called {marine
          mine}. [obsolete]
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

                Damn the torpedoes -- full speed ahead! --Adm.
                                                  David Glasgow
                                                  Farragut (At
                                                  the battle of
                                                  Mobile Bay,
                                                  1864).
      (b) A kind of small submarine boat carrying an explosive
          charge, and projected from a ship against another ship
          at a distance, or made self-propelling, and otherwise
          automatic in its action against a distant ship.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil.) A kind of shell or cartridge buried in earth, to be
      exploded by electricity or by stepping on it; now called
      {land mine}. [obsolete]
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

   4. (Railroad) A kind of detonating cartridge or shell placed
      on a rail, and exploded when crushed under the locomotive
      wheels, -- used as an alarm signal.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An explosive cartridge or shell lowered or dropped into a
      bored oil well, and there exploded, to clear the well of
      obstructions or to open communication with a source of
      supply of oil.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A kind of firework in the form of a small ball, or pellet,
      which explodes when thrown upon a hard object.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. An automobile with a {torpedo body}. [Archaic Cant]
      [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   {Fish torpedo}, a spindle-shaped, or fish-shaped,
      self-propelling submarine torpedo.

   {Spar torpedo}, a canister or other vessel containing an
      explosive charge, and attached to the end of a long spar
      which projects from a ship or boat and is thrust against
      an enemy's ship, exploding the torpedo.

   {Torpedo boat}, a vessel adapted for carrying, launching,
      operating, or otherwise making use of, torpedoes against
      an enemy's ship., especially, a small, fast boat with
      tubes for launching torpedoes.

   {Torpedo nettings}, nettings made of chains or bars, which
      can be suspended around a vessel and allowed to sink
      beneath the surface of the water, as a protection against
      torpedoes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Torpedo \Tor*pe"do\, v. t.
   1. to destroy by, or subject to the action of, a torpedo.
      --London Spectator.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [Fig.] To destroy, cause to halt, or prevent from being
      accomplished; -- used esp. with reference to a plan or an
      enterprise, halted by some action before the plan is put
      into execution.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Electric \E*lec"tric\ ([-e]*l[e^]k"tr[i^]k), Electrical
\E*lec"tric*al\ ([-e]*l[e^]k"tr[i^]*kal), a. [L. electrum amber,
   a mixed metal, Gr. 'h`lektron; akin to 'hle`ktwr the beaming
   sun, cf. Skr. arc to beam, shine: cf. F. ['e]lectrique. The
   name came from the production of electricity by the friction
   of amber.]
   1. Pertaining to electricity; consisting of, containing,
      derived from, or produced by, electricity; as, electric
      power or virtue; an electric jar; electric effects; an
      electric spark; an electric charge; an electric current;
      an electrical engineer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Capable of occasioning the phenomena of electricity; as,
      an electric or electrical machine or substance; an
      electric generator.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Electrifying; thrilling; magnetic. ``Electric Pindar.''
      --Mrs. Browning.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. powered by electricity; as, electrical appliances; an
      electric toothbrush; an electric automobile.
      [WordNet 1.5]

   {Electric atmosphere}, or {Electric aura}. See under {Aura}.
      

   {Electrical battery}. See {Battery}.

   {Electrical brush}. See under {Brush}.

   {Electric cable}. See {Telegraph cable}, under {Telegraph}.
      

   {Electric candle}. See under {Candle}.

   {Electric cat} (Zo["o]l.), one of three or more large species
      of African catfish of the genus {Malapterurus} (esp. {M.
      electricus} of the Nile). They have a large electrical
      organ and are able to give powerful shocks; -- called also
      {sheathfish}.

   {Electric clock}. See under {Clock}, and see
      {Electro-chronograph}.

   {Electric current}, a current or stream of electricity
      traversing a closed circuit formed of conducting
      substances, or passing by means of conductors from one
      body to another which is in a different electrical state.
      

   {Electric eel}, or {Electrical eel} (Zo["o]l.), a South
      American eel-like fresh-water fish of the genus {Gymnotus}
      ({G. electricus}), from two to five feet in length,
      capable of giving a violent electric shock. See
      {Gymnotus}.

   {Electrical fish} (Zo["o]l.), any fish which has an
      electrical organ by means of which it can give an
      electrical shock. The best known kinds are the {torpedo},
      the {gymnotus}, or {electrical eel}, and the {electric
      cat}. See {Torpedo}, and {Gymnotus}.

   {Electric fluid}, the supposed matter of electricity;
      lightning. [archaic]

   {Electrical image} (Elec.), a collection of electrical points
      regarded as forming, by an analogy with optical phenomena,
      an image of certain other electrical points, and used in
      the solution of electrical problems. --Sir W. Thomson.

   {Electric machine}, or {Electrical machine}, an apparatus for
      generating, collecting, or exciting, electricity, as by
      friction.

   {Electric motor}. See {Electro-motor}, 2.

   {Electric osmose}. (Physics) See under {Osmose}.

   {Electric pen}, a hand pen for making perforated stencils for
      multiplying writings. It has a puncturing needle driven at
      great speed by a very small magneto-electric engine on the
      penhandle.

   {Electric railway}, a railway in which the machinery for
      moving the cars is driven by an electric current.

   {Electric ray} (Zo["o]l.), the torpedo.

   {Electric telegraph}. See {Telegraph}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>hit man \hit man\ n.
   1. A professional murderer, esp. one working for a criminal
      organization; also called {torpedo}. [Colloq.]
      [PJC]

   2. A slanderer working for political purposes to damage the
      reputation of an opponent; a {hatchet man}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>torpedo</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>torpedo
     n 1: a professional killer who uses a gun [syn: {gunman}, {gunslinger},
           {hired gun}, {gun}, {gun for hire}, {triggerman}, {hit
          man}, {hitman}, {shooter}]
     2: a large sandwich made of a long crusty roll split lengthwise
        and filled with meats and cheese (and tomato and onion and
        lettuce and condiments); different names are used in
        different sections of the United States [syn: {bomber}, {grinder},
         {hero}, {hero sandwich}, {hoagie}, {hoagy}, {Cuban
        sandwich}, {Italian sandwich}, {poor boy}, {sub}, {submarine},
         {submarine sandwich}, {wedge}, {zep}]
     3: an explosive device that is set off in an oil well (or a gas
        well) to start or to increase the flow of oil (or gas)
     4: a small firework that consists of a percussion cap and some
        gravel wrapped in paper; explodes when thrown forcefully
        against a hard surface
     5: a small explosive device that is placed on a railroad track
        and fires when a train runs over it; the sound of the
        explosion warns the engineer of danger ahead
     6: armament consisting of a long cylindrical self-propelled
        underwater projectile that detonates on contact with a
        target
     7: any sluggish bottom-dwelling ray of the order
        Torpediniformes having a rounded body and electric organs
        on each side of the head capable of emitting strong
        electric discharges [syn: {electric ray}, {crampfish}, {numbfish}]
     v : attack or hit with torpedoes
     [also: {torpedoes} (pl)]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
