<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>touching</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Touch \Touch\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Touched}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Touching}.] [F. toucher, OF. touchier, tuchier; of Teutonic
   origin; cf. OHG. zucchen, zukken, to twitch, pluck, draw, G.
   zukken, zukken, v. intens. fr. OHG. ziohan to draw, G.
   ziehen, akin to E. tug. See {Tuck}, v. t., {Tug}, and cf.
   {Tocsin}, {Toccata}.]
   1. To come in contact with; to hit or strike lightly against;
      to extend the hand, foot, or the like, so as to reach or
      rest on.
      [1913 Webster]

            Him thus intent Ithuriel with his spear
            Touched lightly.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perceive by the sense of feeling.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing but body can be touched or touch. --Greech.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To come to; to reach; to attain to.
      [1913 Webster]

            The god, vindictive, doomed them never more
            Ah, men unblessed! -- to touch their natal shore.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To try; to prove, as with a touchstone. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Wherein I mean to touch your love indeed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To relate to; to concern; to affect.
      [1913 Webster]

            The quarrel toucheth none but us alone. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To handle, speak of, or deal with; to treat of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Storial thing that toucheth gentilesse. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To meddle or interfere with; as, I have not touched the
      books. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To affect the senses or the sensibility of; to move; to
      melt; to soften; especially, to cause feelings of pity,
      compassion, sympathy, or gratitude in.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            What of sweet before
            Hath touched my sense, flat seems to this and harsh.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The tender sire was touched with what he said.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To mark or delineate with touches; to add a slight stroke
      to with the pencil or brush.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lines, though touched but faintly, are drawn
            right.                                --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To infect; to affect slightly. --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To make an impression on; to have effect upon.
       [1913 Webster]

             Its face . . . so hard that a file will not touch
             it.                                  --Moxon.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To strike; to manipulate; to play on; as, to touch an
       instrument of music.
       [1913 Webster]

             [They] touched their golden harps.   --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To perform, as a tune; to play.
       [1913 Webster]

             A person is the royal retinue touched a light and
             lively air on the flageolet.         --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. To influence by impulse; to impel forcibly. `` No decree
       of mine, . . . [to] touch with lightest moment of impulse
       his free will,'' --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. To harm, afflict, or distress.
       [1913 Webster]

             Let us make a covenant with thee, that thou wilt do
             us no hurt, as we have not touched thee. --Gen.
                                                  xxvi. 28, 29.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. To affect with insanity, especially in a slight degree;
       to make partially insane; -- rarely used except in the
       past participle.
       [1913 Webster]

             She feared his head was a little touched. --Ld.
                                                  Lytton.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Geom.) To be tangent to. See {Tangent}, a.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. To lay a hand upon for curing disease.
       [1913 Webster]

   19. To compare with; to be equal to; -- usually with a
       negative; as, he held that for good cheer nothing could
       touch an open fire. [Colloq.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   20. To induce to give or lend; to borrow from; as, to touch
       one for a loan; hence, to steal from. [Slang]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To touch a sail} (Naut.), to bring it so close to the wind
      that its weather leech shakes.

   {To touch the wind} (Naut.), to keep the ship as near the
      wind as possible.

   {To touch up}, to repair; to improve by touches or
      emendation.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Touching \Touch"ing\ (t[u^]ch"[i^]ng), a.
   Affecting; moving; pathetic; as, a touching tale. --
   {Touch"ing*ly}, adv.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Touching \Touch"ing\, prep.
   Concerning; with respect to.
   [1913 Webster]

         Now, as touching things offered unto idols. --1 Cor.
                                                  viii. 1.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Touching \Touch"ing\, n.
   The sense or act of feeling; touch.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touching</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>touching
     adj : arousing affect; "the homecoming of the released hostages
           was an affecting scene"; "poignant grief cannot endure
           forever"; "his gratitude was simple and touching" [syn:
            {affecting}, {poignant}]
     n 1: the event of something coming in contact with the body; "he
          longed for the touch of her hand"; "the cooling touch of
          the night air" [syn: {touch}]
     2: the act of putting two things together with no space between
        them; "at his touch the room filled with lights" [syn: {touch}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
