<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>touch</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Touch \Touch\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Touched}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Touching}.] [F. toucher, OF. touchier, tuchier; of Teutonic
   origin; cf. OHG. zucchen, zukken, to twitch, pluck, draw, G.
   zukken, zukken, v. intens. fr. OHG. ziohan to draw, G.
   ziehen, akin to E. tug. See {Tuck}, v. t., {Tug}, and cf.
   {Tocsin}, {Toccata}.]
   1. To come in contact with; to hit or strike lightly against;
      to extend the hand, foot, or the like, so as to reach or
      rest on.
      [1913 Webster]

            Him thus intent Ithuriel with his spear
            Touched lightly.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To perceive by the sense of feeling.
      [1913 Webster]

            Nothing but body can be touched or touch. --Greech.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To come to; to reach; to attain to.
      [1913 Webster]

            The god, vindictive, doomed them never more
            Ah, men unblessed! -- to touch their natal shore.
                                                  --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To try; to prove, as with a touchstone. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Wherein I mean to touch your love indeed. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To relate to; to concern; to affect.
      [1913 Webster]

            The quarrel toucheth none but us alone. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To handle, speak of, or deal with; to treat of.
      [1913 Webster]

            Storial thing that toucheth gentilesse. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To meddle or interfere with; as, I have not touched the
      books. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To affect the senses or the sensibility of; to move; to
      melt; to soften; especially, to cause feelings of pity,
      compassion, sympathy, or gratitude in.
      [1913 Webster +PJC]

            What of sweet before
            Hath touched my sense, flat seems to this and harsh.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The tender sire was touched with what he said.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To mark or delineate with touches; to add a slight stroke
      to with the pencil or brush.
      [1913 Webster]

            The lines, though touched but faintly, are drawn
            right.                                --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To infect; to affect slightly. --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. To make an impression on; to have effect upon.
       [1913 Webster]

             Its face . . . so hard that a file will not touch
             it.                                  --Moxon.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. To strike; to manipulate; to play on; as, to touch an
       instrument of music.
       [1913 Webster]

             [They] touched their golden harps.   --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. To perform, as a tune; to play.
       [1913 Webster]

             A person is the royal retinue touched a light and
             lively air on the flageolet.         --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. To influence by impulse; to impel forcibly. `` No decree
       of mine, . . . [to] touch with lightest moment of impulse
       his free will,'' --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. To harm, afflict, or distress.
       [1913 Webster]

             Let us make a covenant with thee, that thou wilt do
             us no hurt, as we have not touched thee. --Gen.
                                                  xxvi. 28, 29.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. To affect with insanity, especially in a slight degree;
       to make partially insane; -- rarely used except in the
       past participle.
       [1913 Webster]

             She feared his head was a little touched. --Ld.
                                                  Lytton.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Geom.) To be tangent to. See {Tangent}, a.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. To lay a hand upon for curing disease.
       [1913 Webster]

   19. To compare with; to be equal to; -- usually with a
       negative; as, he held that for good cheer nothing could
       touch an open fire. [Colloq.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   20. To induce to give or lend; to borrow from; as, to touch
       one for a loan; hence, to steal from. [Slang]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {To touch a sail} (Naut.), to bring it so close to the wind
      that its weather leech shakes.

   {To touch the wind} (Naut.), to keep the ship as near the
      wind as possible.

   {To touch up}, to repair; to improve by touches or
      emendation.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Touch \Touch\, v. i.
   1. To be in contact; to be in a state of junction, so that no
      space is between; as, two spheres touch only at points.
      --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To fasten; to take effect; to make impression. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Strong waters pierce metals, and will touch upon
            gold, that will not touch upon silver. --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To treat anything in discourse, especially in a slight or
      casual manner; -- often with on or upon.
      [1913 Webster]

            If the antiquaries have touched upon it, they
            immediately
            quitted it.                           --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Naut) To be brought, as a sail, so close to the wind that
      its weather leech shakes.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To touch and go} (Naut.), to touch bottom lightly and
      without damage, as a vessel in motion.

   {To touch at}, to come or go to, without tarrying; as, the
      ship touched at Lisbon.

   {To touch on} or {To touch upon},
      (a) to come or go to for a short time. [R.]
          [1913 Webster]

                I made a little voyage round the lake, and
                touched on the several towns that lie on its
                coasts.                           --Addison.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) to discuss briefly, as only a small part of a
          discourse.
          [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Touch \Touch\, n. [Cf. F. touche. See {Touch}, v. ]
   1. The act of touching, or the state of being touched;
      contact.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their touch affrights me as a serpent's sting.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Physiol.) The sense by which pressure or traction exerted
      on the skin is recognized; the sense by which the
      properties of bodies are determined by contact; the
      tactile sense. See {Tactile sense}, under {Tactile}.
      [1913 Webster]

            The spider's touch, how exquisitely fine. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Pure tactile feelings are necessarily rare, since
         temperature sensations and muscular sensations are more
         or less combined with them. The organs of touch are
         found chiefly in the epidermis of the skin and certain
         underlying nervous structures.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. Act or power of exciting emotion.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not alone
            The death of Fulvia, with more urgent touches,
            Do strongly speak to us.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An emotion or affection.
      [1913 Webster]

            A true, natural, and a sensible touch of mercy.
                                                  --Hooker.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Personal reference or application. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Speech of touch toward others should be sparingly
            used.                                 --Bacon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A stroke; as, a touch of raillery; a satiric touch; hence,
      animadversion; censure; reproof.
      [1913 Webster]

            I never bare any touch of conscience with greater
            regret.                               --Eikon
                                                  Basilike.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A single stroke on a drawing or a picture.
      [1913 Webster]

            Never give the least touch with your pencil till you
            have well examined your design.       --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Feature; lineament; trait.
      [1913 Webster]

            Of many faces, eyes, and hearts,
            To have the touches dearest prized.   --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The act of the hand on a musical instrument; bence, in the
      plural, musical notes.
      [1913 Webster]

            Soft stillness and the night
            Become the touches of sweet harmony.  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A small quantity intermixed; a little; a dash.
       [1913 Webster]

             Eyes La touch of Sir Peter Lely in them. --Hazlitt.
       [1913 Webster]

             Madam, I have a touch of your condition. --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. A hint; a suggestion; slight notice.
       [1913 Webster]

             A small touch will put him in mind of them.
                                                  --Bacon.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. A slight and brief essay. [Colloq.]
       [1913 Webster]

             Print my preface in such form as, in the
             booksellers' phrase, will make a sixpenny touch.
                                                  --Swift.
       [1913 Webster]

   13. A touchstone; hence, stone of the sort used for
       touchstone. [Obs.] `` Now do I play the touch.'' --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

             A neat new monument of touch and alabaster.
                                                  --Fuller.
       [1913 Webster]

   14. Hence, examination or trial by some decisive standard;
       test; proof; tried quality.
       [1913 Webster]

             Equity, the true touch of all laws.  --Carew.
       [1913 Webster]

             Friends of noble touch .             --Shak.
       [1913 Webster]

   15. (Mus.) The particular or characteristic mode of action,
       or the resistance of the keys of an instrument to the
       fingers; as, a heavy touch, or a light touch; also, the
       manner of touching, striking, or pressing the keys of a
       piano; as, a legato touch; a staccato touch.
       [1913 Webster]

   16. (Shipbilding) The broadest part of a plank worked top and
       but (see {Top and but}, under {Top}, n.), or of one
       worked anchor-stock fashion (that is, tapered from the
       middle to both ends); also, the angles of the stern
       timbers at the counters. --J. Knowles.
       [1913 Webster]

   17. (Football) That part of the field which is beyond the
       line of flags on either side. --Encyc. of Rural Sports.
       [1913 Webster]

   18. A boys' game; tag.
       [1913 Webster]

   19. (Change Ringing) A set of changes less than the total
       possible on seven bells, that is, less than 5,040.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   20. An act of borrowing or stealing. [Slang]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   21. Tallow; -- a plumber's term. [Eng.]
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {In touch}
       (a) (Football), outside of bounds. --T. Hughes.
       (b) in communication; communicating, once or repeatedly.
           

   {To be in touch},
       (a) to be in contact, communication, or in sympathy.
       (b) to be aware of current events.

   {To keep touch}.
       (a) To be true or punctual to a promise or engagement
           [Obs.]; hence, to fulfill duly a function.
           [1913 Webster]

                 My mind and senses keep touch and time. --Sir
                                                  W. Scott.
           [1913 Webster]
       (b) To keep in contact; to maintain connection or
           sympathy; -- with with or of. Also

   {to keep in touch}.

   {Touch and go}, a phrase descriptive of a narrow escape.

   {True as touch} (i. e., touchstone), quite true. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>touch</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>touch
     n 1: the event of something coming in contact with the body; "he
          longed for the touch of her hand"; "the cooling touch of
          the night air" [syn: {touching}]
     2: the faculty of touch; "only sight and touch enable us to
        locate objects in the space around us" [syn: {sense of
        touch}, {skin senses}, {touch modality}, {cutaneous senses}]
     3: a suggestion of some quality; "there was a touch of sarcasm
        in his tone"; "he detected a ghost of a smile on her face"
        [syn: {trace}, {ghost}]
     4: a distinguishing style; "this room needs a woman's touch"
        [syn: {signature}]
     5: the act of putting two things together with no space between
        them; "at his touch the room filled with lights" [syn: {touching}]
     6: a slight but appreciable addition; "this dish could use a
        touch of garlic" [syn: {hint}, {tinge}, {mite}, {pinch}, {jot},
         {speck}, {soupcon}]
     7: a communicative interaction; "the pilot made contact with
        the base"; "he got in touch with his colleagues" [syn: {contact}]
     8: a slight attack of illness; "he has a touch of rheumatism"
        [syn: {spot}]
     9: the act of soliciting money (as a gift or loan); "he watched
        the beggar trying to make a touch"
     10: the sensation produced by pressure receptors in the skin;
         "she likes the touch of silk on her skin"; "the surface
         had a greasy feeling" [syn: {touch sensation}, {tactual
         sensation}, {tactile sensation}, {feeling}]
     11: deftness in handling matters; "he has a master's touch"
     12: the feel of mechanical action; "this piano has a wonderful
         touch"
     v 1: make physical contact with, come in contact with; "Touch the
          stone for good luck"; "She never touched her husband"
     2: perceive via the tactile sense; "Helen Keller felt the
        physical world by touching people and objects around her"
     3: affect emotionally; "A stirring movie"; "I was touched by
        your kind letter of sympathy" [syn: {stir}]
     4: have to do with or be relevant to; "There were lots of
        questions referring to her talk"; "My remark pertained to
        your earlier comments" [syn: {refer}, {pertain}, {relate},
         {concern}, {come to}, {bear on}, {touch on}]
     5: be in direct physical contact with; make contact; "The two
        buildings touch"; "Their hands touched"; "The wire must
        not contact the metal cover"; "The surfaces contact at
        this point" [syn: {adjoin}, {meet}, {contact}]
     6: have an effect upon; "Will the new rules affect me?" [syn: {affect},
         {impact}, {bear upon}, {bear on}, {touch on}]
     7: deal with; usually used with a form of negation; "I wouldn't
        touch her with a ten-foot pole"; "The local Mafia won't
        touch gambling"
     8: cause to be in brief contact with; "He touched his toes to
        the horse's flanks"
     9: to extend as far as; "The sunlight reached the wall"; "Can
        he reach?" "The chair must not touch the wall" [syn: {reach},
         {extend to}]
     10: be equal to in quality or ability; "Nothing can rival cotton
         for durability"; "Your performance doesn't even touch
         that of your colleagues"; "Her persistence and ambition
         only matches that of her parents" [syn: {equal}, {rival},
          {match}]
     11: tamper with; "Don't touch my CDs!" [syn: {disturb}]
     12: make a more or less disguised reference to; "He alluded to
         the problem but did not mention it" [syn: {allude}, {advert}]
     13: comprehend; "He could not touch the meaning of the poem"
     14: consume; "She didn't touch her food all night" [syn: {partake}]
     15: dye with a color [syn: {tint}, {tinct}, {bepaint}, {tinge}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
