<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tractor</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tractor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tractor airplane \Trac"tor air"plane\, n. (Aviation)
   An airplane having one or more tractor propellers; -- called
   also {tractor}.
   [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tractor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tractor \Tract"or\, n. [NL., from L. trahere, tractum, to draw.]
   1. That which draws, or is used for drawing.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. (Med.) Two small, pointed rods of metal, formerly used
      in the treatment called Perkinism.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. a motor vehicle with a powerful engine and large wheels,
      used to pull farm equipment such as plows, harvesting
      machinery, etc., over farm land. Smaller forms of farm
      tractor are completely open, with only a seat for the
      driver.
      [PJC]

   4. a motor vehicle with a driver's cab and a powerful engine,
      fitted with a coupling at the rear, and designed to pull a
      large trailer or semi-trailer on the open highway; --
      called also {truck tractor}. The combination of such a
      tractor with its trailer is called a tractor-trailer, and
      is a common form of truck used for commercial shipping of
      freight.
      [PJC]

   5. (Aviation) A propeller screw placed in front of the
      supporting planes of an a["e]roplane instead of behind
      them, so that it exerts a pull instead of a push; --
      called also {Tractor screw} and {Tractor propeller}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. (Aviation) An airplane having one or more tractor
      propellers; -- called also {tractor airplane}.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tractor</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tractor
     n 1: a wheeled vehicle with large wheels; used in farming and
          other applications
     2: a truck that has a cab but no body; used for pulling large
        trailers or vans
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
