<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>track</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>track</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>track
     
        &lt;storage&gt; The part of a {disk} which passes under one
        read/write head while the head is stationary.  The number of
        tracks on a disk surface therefore corresponds to the number
        of different radial positions of the head(s).  The collection
        of all tracks on all surfaces at a given radial position is
        known a {cylinder} and each track is divided into {sectors}.
     
        (1997-07-15)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>track</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Gauge \Gauge\, n. [Written also gage.]
   1. A measure; a standard of measure; an instrument to
      determine dimensions, distance, or capacity; a standard.
      [1913 Webster]

            This plate must be a gauge to file your worm and
            groove to equal breadth by.           --Moxon.
      [1913 Webster]

            There is not in our hands any fixed gauge of minds.
                                                  --I. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Measure; dimensions; estimate.
      [1913 Webster]

            The gauge and dimensions of misery, depression, and
            contempt.                             --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach. &amp; Manuf.) Any instrument for ascertaining or
      regulating the dimensions or forms of things; a templet or
      template; as, a button maker's gauge.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Physics) Any instrument or apparatus for measuring the
      state of a phenomenon, or for ascertaining its numerical
      elements at any moment; -- usually applied to some
      particular instrument; as, a rain gauge; a steam gauge.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Naut.)
      (a) Relative positions of two or more vessels with
          reference to the wind; as, a vessel has the weather
          gauge of another when on the windward side of it, and
          the lee gauge when on the lee side of it.
      (b) The depth to which a vessel sinks in the water.
          --Totten.
          [1913 Webster]

   6. The distance between the rails of a railway.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The standard gauge of railroads in most countries is
         four feet, eight and one half inches. Wide, or broad,
         gauge, in the United States, is six feet; in England,
         seven feet, and generally any gauge exceeding standard
         gauge. Any gauge less than standard gauge is now called
         narrow gauge. It varies from two feet to three feet six
         inches.
         [1913 Webster]

   7. (Plastering) The quantity of plaster of Paris used with
      common plaster to accelerate its setting.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Building) That part of a shingle, slate, or tile, which
      is exposed to the weather, when laid; also, one course of
      such shingles, slates, or tiles.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Gauge of a carriage}, {car}, etc., the distance between the
      wheels; -- ordinarily called the {track}.

   {Gauge cock}, a stop cock used as a try cock for ascertaining
      the height of the water level in a steam boiler.

   {Gauge concussion} (Railroads), the jar caused by a car-wheel
      flange striking the edge of the rail.

   {Gauge glass}, a glass tube for a water gauge.

   {Gauge lathe}, an automatic lathe for turning a round object
      having an irregular profile, as a baluster or chair round,
      to a templet or gauge.

   {Gauge point}, the diameter of a cylinder whose altitude is
      one inch, and contents equal to that of a unit of a given
      measure; -- a term used in gauging casks, etc.

   {Gauge rod}, a graduated rod, for measuring the capacity of
      barrels, casks, etc.

   {Gauge saw}, a handsaw, with a gauge to regulate the depth of
      cut. --Knight.

   {Gauge stuff}, a stiff and compact plaster, used in making
      cornices, moldings, etc., by means of a templet.

   {Gauge wheel}, a wheel at the forward end of a plow beam, to
      determine the depth of the furrow.

   {Joiner's gauge}, an instrument used to strike a line
      parallel to the straight side of a board, etc.

   {Printer's gauge}, an instrument to regulate the length of
      the page.

   {Rain gauge}, an instrument for measuring the quantity of
      rain at any given place.

   {Salt gauge}, or {Brine gauge}, an instrument or contrivance
      for indicating the degree of saltness of water from its
      specific gravity, as in the boilers of ocean steamers.

   {Sea gauge}, an instrument for finding the depth of the sea.
      

   {Siphon gauge}, a glass siphon tube, partly filled with
      mercury, -- used to indicate pressure, as of steam, or the
      degree of rarefaction produced in the receiver of an air
      pump or other vacuum; a manometer.

   {Sliding gauge}. (Mach.)
      (a) A templet or pattern for gauging the commonly accepted
          dimensions or shape of certain parts in general use,
          as screws, railway-car axles, etc.
      (b) A gauge used only for testing other similar gauges,
          and preserved as a reference, to detect wear of the
          working gauges.
      (c) (Railroads) See Note under {Gauge}, n., 5.

   {Star gauge} (Ordnance), an instrument for measuring the
      diameter of the bore of a cannon at any point of its
      length.

   {Steam gauge}, an instrument for measuring the pressure of
      steam, as in a boiler.

   {Tide gauge}, an instrument for determining the height of the
      tides.

   {Vacuum gauge}, a species of barometer for determining the
      relative elasticities of the vapor in the condenser of a
      steam engine and the air.

   {Water gauge}.
      (a) A contrivance for indicating the height of a water
          surface, as in a steam boiler; as by a gauge cock or
          glass.
      (b) The height of the water in the boiler.

   {Wind gauge}, an instrument for measuring the force of the
      wind on any given surface; an anemometer.

   {Wire gauge}, a gauge for determining the diameter of wire or
      the thickness of sheet metal; also, a standard of size.
      See under {Wire}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>track</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Track \Track\, n. [OF. trac track of horses, mules, trace of
   animals; of Teutonic origin; cf.D. trek a drawing, trekken to
   draw, travel, march, MHG. trechen, pret. trach. Cf. {Trick}.]
   1. A mark left by something that has passed along; as, the
      track, or wake, of a ship; the track of a meteor; the
      track of a sled or a wheel.
      [1913 Webster]

            The bright track of his fiery car.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A mark or impression left by the foot, either of man or
      beast; trace; vestige; footprint.
      [1913 Webster]

            Far from track of men.                --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Zo["o]l.) The entire lower surface of the foot; -- said
      of birds, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A road; a beaten path.
      [1913 Webster]

            Behold Torquatus the same track pursue. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Course; way; as, the track of a comet.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A path or course laid out for a race, for exercise, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Railroad) The permanent way; the rails.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. [Perhaps a mistake for tract.] A tract or area, as of
      land. [Obs.] ``Small tracks of ground.'' --Fuller.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Track scale}, a railway scale. See under {Railway}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>track</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Track \Track\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {tracked}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {tracking}.]
   To follow the tracks or traces of; to pursue by following the
   marks of the feet; to trace; to trail; as, to track a deer in
   the snow.
   [1913 Webster]

         It was often found impossible to track the robbers to
         their retreats among the hills and morasses.
                                                  --Macaulay.
   [1913 Webster]

   2. (Naut.) To draw along continuously, as a vessel, by a
      line, men or animals on shore being the motive power; to
      tow.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>track</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>track
     n 1: a line or route along which something travels or moves; "the
          hurricane demolished houses in its path"; "the track of
          an animal"; "the course of the river" [syn: {path}, {course}]
     2: evidence pointing to a possible solution; "the police are
        following a promising lead"; "the trail led straight to
        the perpetrator" [syn: {lead}, {trail}]
     3: a pair of parallel rails providing a runway for wheels
     4: a course over which races are run [syn: {racetrack}, {racecourse},
         {raceway}]
     5: a distinct selection of music from a recording or a compact
        disc; "he played the first cut on the cd"; "the title
        track of the album" [syn: {cut}]
     6: an endless metal belt on which tracked vehicles move over
        the ground [syn: {caterpillar track}, {caterpillar tread}]
     7: (computer science) one of the circular magnetic paths on a
        magnetic disk that serve as a guide for writing and
        reading data [syn: {data track}]
     8: a groove on a phonograph recording
     9: a bar or bars of rolled steel making a track along which
        vehicles can roll [syn: {rail}, {rails}]
     10: any road or path affording passage especially a rough one
         [syn: {cart track}, {cartroad}]
     11: the act of participating in an athletic competition
         involving running on a track [syn: {running}]
     v 1: carry on the feet and deposit; "track mud into the house"
     2: observe or plot the moving path of something; "track a
        missile"
     3: go after with the intent to catch; "The policeman chased the
        mugger down the alley"; "the dog chased the rabbit" [syn:
        {chase}, {chase after}, {trail}, {tail}, {tag}, {give
        chase}, {dog}, {go after}]
     4: travel across or pass over; "The caravan covered almost 100
        miles each day" [syn: {traverse}, {cover}, {cross}, {pass
        over}, {get over}, {get across}, {cut through}, {cut
        across}]
     5: make tracks upon
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
