<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tradition</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tradition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tradition
   any kind of teaching, written or spoken, handed down from
   generation to generation. In Mark 7:3, 9, 13, Col. 2:8, this
   word refers to the arbitrary interpretations of the Jews. In 2
   Thess. 2:15; 3:6, it is used in a good sense. Peter (1 Pet.
   1:18) uses this word with reference to the degenerate Judaism of
   the "strangers scattered" whom he addresses (comp. Acts 15:10;
   Matt. 15:2-6; Gal. 1:14).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tradition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tradition \Tra*di"tion\, v. t.
   To transmit by way of tradition; to hand down. [Obs.]
   [1913 Webster]

         The following story is . . . traditioned with very much
         credit amongst our English Catholics.    --Fuller.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tradition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tradition \Tra*di"tion\, n. [OE. tradicioun, L. traditio, from
   tradere to give up, transmit. See {Treason}, {Traitor}.]
   1. The act of delivering into the hands of another; delivery.
      ``A deed takes effect only from the tradition or
      delivery.'' --Blackstone.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The unwritten or oral delivery of information, opinions,
      doctrines, practices, rites, and customs, from father to
      son, or from ancestors to posterity; the transmission of
      any knowledge, opinions, or practice, from forefathers to
      descendants by oral communication, without written
      memorials.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Hence, that which is transmitted orally from father to
      son, or from ancestors to posterity; knowledge or belief
      transmitted without the aid of written memorials; custom
      or practice long observed.
      [1913 Webster]

            Will you mock at an ancient tradition begun upon an
            honorable respect?                    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Naught but tradition remains of the beautiful
            village of Grand-Pr['e].              --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Theol.)
      (a) An unwritten code of law represented to have been
          given by God to Moses on Sinai.
          [1913 Webster]

                Making the word of God of none effect through
                your tradition, which ye have delivered. --Mark
                                                  vii. 13.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) That body of doctrine and discipline, or any article
          thereof, supposed to have been put forth by Christ or
          his apostles, and not committed to writing.
          [1913 Webster]

                Stand fast, and hold the traditions which ye
                have been taught, whether by word or our
                epistle.                          --2 Thess. ii.
                                                  15.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Tradition Sunday} (Eccl.), Palm Sunday; -- so called because
      the creed was then taught to candidates for baptism at
      Easter.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tradition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tradition
     n 1: an inherited pattern of thought or action
     2: a specific practice of long standing [syn: {custom}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
