<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>traffic</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>traffic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Traffic \Traf"fic\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trafficked}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Trafficking}.] [F. trafiquer; cf. It. trafficare, Sp.
   traficar, trafagar, Pg. traficar, trafegar, trafeguear, LL.
   traficare; of uncertain origin, perhaps fr. L. trans across,
   over + -ficare to make (see {-fy}, and cf. G. ["u]bermachen
   to transmit, send over, e. g., money, wares); or cf. Pg.
   trasfegar to pour out from one vessel into another, OPg.
   also, to traffic, perhaps fr. (assumed) LL. vicare to
   exchange, from L. vicis change (cf. {Vicar}).]
   1. To pass goods and commodities from one person to another
      for an equivalent in goods or money; to buy or sell goods;
      to barter; to trade.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To trade meanly or mercenarily; to bargain.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>traffic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Traffic \Traf"fic\, v. t.
   To exchange in traffic; to effect by a bargain or for a
   consideration.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>traffic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Traffic \Traf"fic\, n. [Cf. F. trafic, It. traffico, Sp.
   tr['a]fico, tr['a]fago, Pg. tr['a]fego, LL. traficum,
   trafica. See {Traffic}, v.]
   1. Commerce, either by barter or by buying and selling;
      interchange of goods and commodities; trade.
      [1913 Webster]

            A merchant of great traffic through the world.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The traffic in honors, places, and pardons.
                                                  --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: This word, like trade, comprehends every species of
         dealing in the exchange or passing of goods or
         merchandise from hand to hand for an equivalent, unless
         the business of relating may be excepted. It signifies
         appropriately foreign trade, but is not limited to
         that.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. Commodities of the market. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            You 'll see a draggled damsel
            From Billingsgate her fishy traffic bear. --Gay.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. The business done upon a railway, steamboat line, etc.,
      with reference to the number of passengers or the amount
      of freight carried.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Traffic return}, a periodical statement of the receipts for
      goods and passengers, as on a railway line.

   {Traffic taker}, a computer of the returns of traffic on a
      railway, steamboat line, etc.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>traffic</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>traffic
     n 1: the aggregation of things (pedestrians or vehicles) coming
          and going in a particular locality during a specified
          period of time
     2: buying and selling; especially illicit trade
     3: the amount of activity over a communication system during a
        given period of time; "heavy traffic overloaded the trunk
        lines"; "traffic on the internet is lightest during the
        night"
     4: social or verbal interchange (usually followed by `with')
        [syn: {dealings}]
     v 1: deal illegally; "traffic drugs"
     2: trade or deal a commodity; "They trafficked with us for
        gold"
     [also: {trafficking}, {trafficked}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
