<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>train</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>train</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Accommodation \Ac*com`mo*da"tion\, n. [L. accommodatio, fr.
   accommodare: cf. F. accommodation.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The act of fitting or adapting, or the state of being
      fitted or adapted; adaptation; adjustment; -- followed by
      to. ``The organization of the body with accommodation to
      its functions.'' --Sir M. Hale.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Willingness to accommodate; obligingness.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Whatever supplies a want or affords ease, refreshment, or
      convenience; anything furnished which is desired or
      needful; -- often in the plural; as, the accommodations --
      that is, lodgings and food -- at an inn.    --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. An adjustment of differences; state of agreement;
      reconciliation; settlement. ``To come to terms of
      accommodation.'' --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The application of a writer's language, on the ground of
      analogy, to something not originally referred to or
      intended.
      [1913 Webster]

            Many of those quotations from the Old Testament were
            probably intended as nothing more than
            accommodations.                       --Paley.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Com.)
      (a) A loan of money.
      (b) An accommodation bill or note.
          [1913 Webster]

   {Accommodation bill}, or {note} (Com.), a bill of exchange
      which a person accepts, or a note which a person makes and
      delivers to another, not upon a consideration received,
      but for the purpose of raising money on credit.

   {Accommodation coach}, or {train}, one running at moderate
      speed and stopping at all or nearly all stations.

   {Accommodation ladder} (Naut.), a light ladder hung over the
      side of a ship at the gangway, useful in ascending from,
      or descending to, small boats.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>train</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Train \Train\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trained}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Training}.] [OF. trahiner, tra["i]ner,F. tra[^i]ner, LL.
   trahinare, trainare, fr. L. trahere to draw. See {Trail}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To draw along; to trail; to drag.
      [1913 Webster]

            In hollow cube
            Training his devilish enginery.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw by persuasion, artifice, or the like; to attract
      by stratagem; to entice; to allure. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            If but a dozen French
            Were there in arms, they would be as a call
            To train ten thousand English to their side. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, train me not, sweet mermaid, with thy note.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            This feast, I'll gage my life,
            Is but a plot to train you to your ruin. --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To teach and form by practice; to educate; to exercise; to
      discipline; as, to train the militia to the manual
      exercise; to train soldiers to the use of arms.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our trained bands, which are the trustiest and most
            proper strength of a free nation.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The warrior horse here bred he's taught to train.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To break, tame, and accustom to draw, as oxen.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Hort.) To lead or direct, and form to a wall or espalier;
      to form to a proper shape, by bending, lopping, or
      pruning; as, to train young trees.
      [1913 Webster]

            He trained the young branches to the right hand or
            to the left.                          --Jeffrey.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mining) To trace, as a lode or any mineral appearance, to
      its head.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To train a gun} (Mil. &amp; Naut.), to point it at some object
      either forward or else abaft the beam, that is, not
      directly on the side. --Totten.

   {To train}, or {To train up}, to educate; to teach; to form
      by instruction or practice; to bring up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Train up a child in the way he should go; and when
            he is old, he will not depart from it. --Prov. xxii.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

            The first Christians were, by great hardships,
            trained up for glory.                 --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>train</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Train \Train\, v. i.
   1. To be drilled in military exercises; to do duty in a
      military company.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To prepare by exercise, diet, instruction, etc., for any
      physical contest; as, to train for a boat race.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>train</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Train \Train\, n. [F. train, OF. tra["i]n, trahin; cf. (for some
   of the senses) F. traine. See {Train}, v.]
   1. That which draws along; especially, persuasion, artifice,
      or enticement; allurement. [Obs.] ``Now to my charms, and
      to my wily trains.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, something tied to a lure to entice a hawk; also, a
      trap for an animal; a snare. --Halliwell.
      [1913 Webster]

            With cunning trains him to entrap un wares.
                                                  --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is drawn along in the rear of, or after,
      something; that which is in the hinder part or rear.
      Specifically : 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) That part of a gown which trails behind the wearer.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) (Mil.) The after part of a gun carriage; the trail.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) The tail of a bird. ``The train steers their flights,
          and turns their bodies, like the rudder of ship.''
          --Ray.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. A number of followers; a body of attendants; a retinue; a
      suite.
      [1913 Webster]

            The king's daughter with a lovely train. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            My train are men of choice and rarest parts. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A consecution or succession of connected things; a series.
      ``A train of happy sentiments.'' --I. Watts.
      [1913 Webster]

            The train of ills our love would draw behind it.
                                                  --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

            Rivers now
            Stream and perpetual draw their humid train.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Other truths require a train of ideas placed in
            order.                                --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. Regular method; process; course; order; as, things now in
      a train for settlement.
      [1913 Webster]

            If things were once in this train, . . . our duty
            would take root in our nature.        --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The number of beats of a watch in any certain time.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A line of gunpowder laid to lead fire to a charge, mine,
      or the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. A connected line of cars or carriages on a railroad; --
      called also {railroad train}.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. A heavy, long sleigh used in Canada for the
       transportation of merchandise, wood, and the like.
       [1913 Webster]

   11. (Rolling Mill) A roll train; as, a 12-inch train.
       [1913 Webster]

   12. (Mil.) The aggregation of men, animals, and vehicles
       which accompany an army or one of its subdivisions, and
       transport its baggage, ammunition, supplies, and reserve
       materials of all kinds.
       [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Roll train}, or {Train of rolls} (Rolling Mill), a set of
      plain or grooved rolls for rolling metal into various
      forms by a series of consecutive operations.

   {Train mile} (Railroads), a unit employed in estimating
      running expenses, etc., being one of the total number of
      miles run by all the trains of a road, or system of roads,
      as within a given time, or for a given expenditure; --
      called also {mile run}.

   {Train of artillery}, any number of cannon, mortars, etc.,
      with the attendants and carriages which follow them into
      the field. --Campbell (Dict. Mil. Sci.).

   {Train of mechanism}, a series of moving pieces, as wheels
      and pinions, each of which is follower to that which
      drives it, and driver to that which follows it.

   {Train road}, a slight railway for small cars, -- used for
      construction, or in mining.

   {Train tackle} (Naut.), a tackle for running guns in and out.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: Cars.

   Usage: {Train}, {Cars}. At one time ``train'' meaning
          railroad train was also referred to in the U. S. by
          the phrase ``the cars''. In the 1913 dictionary the
          usage was described thus: ``Train is the word
          universally used in England with reference to railroad
          traveling; as, I came in the morning train. In the
          United States, the phrase the cars has been
          extensively introduced in the room of train; as, the
          cars are late; I came in the cars. The English
          expression is obviously more appropriate, and is
          prevailing more and more among Americans, to the
          exclusion of the cars.''
          [1913 Webster +PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>train</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>train
     n 1: public transport provided by a line of railway cars coupled
          together and drawn by a locomotive; "express trains
          don't stop at Princeton Junction" [syn: {railroad train}]
     2: a sequentially ordered set of things or events or ideas in
        which each successive member is related to the preceding;
        "a string of islands"; "train of mourners"; "a train of
        thought" [syn: {string}]
     3: a procession (of wagons or mules or camels) traveling
        together in single file; "we were part of a caravan of
        almost a thousand camels"; "they joined the wagon train
        for safety" [syn: {caravan}, {wagon train}]
     4: a series of consequences wrought by an event; "it led to a
        train of disasters"
     5: piece of cloth forming the long back section of a gown that
        is drawn along the floor; "the bride's train was carried
        by her two young nephews"
     6: wheelwork consisting of a connected set of rotating gears by
        which force is transmitted or motion or torque is changed;
        "the fool got his tie caught in the geartrain" [syn: {gearing},
         {gears}, {geartrain}, {power train}]
     v 1: create by training and teaching; "The old master is training
          world-class violinists"; "we develop the leaders for the
          future" [syn: {develop}, {prepare}, {educate}]
     2: undergo training or instruction in preparation for a
        particular role, function, or profession; "She is training
        to be a teacher"; "He trained as a legal aid" [syn: {prepare}]
     3: train by instruction and practice; especially to teach
        self-control; "Parents must discipline their children";
        "Is this dog trained?" [syn: {discipline}, {check}, {condition}]
     4: prepare (someone) for a future role or function; "He is
        grooming his son to become his successor"; "The prince was
        prepared to become King one day"; "They trained him to be
        a warrior" [syn: {prepare}, {groom}]
     5: train to be discriminative in taste or judgment; "Cultivate
        your musical taste"; "Train your tastebuds"; "She is well
        schooled in poetry" [syn: {educate}, {school}, {cultivate},
         {civilize}, {civilise}]
     6: aim or direct at; as of blows, weapons, or objects such as
        photographic equipment; "Please don't aim at your little
        brother!"; "He trained his gun on the burglar"; "Don't
        train your camera on the women"; "Take a swipe at one's
        opponent" [syn: {aim}, {take}, {take aim}, {direct}]
     7: teach and supervise (someone); act as a trainer or coach
        (to), as in sports; "He is training our Olympic team";
        "She is coaching the crew" [syn: {coach}]
     8: exercise in order to prepare for an event or competition;
        "She is training for the Olympics"
     9: train to grow in a certain way by tying and pruning it;
        "train the vine"
     10: travel by rail or train; "They railed from Rome to Venice";
         "She trained to Hamburg" [syn: {rail}]
     11: drag loosely along a surface; allow to sweep the ground;
         "The toddler was trailing his pants"; "She trained her
         long scarf behind her" [syn: {trail}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
