<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>training</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>training</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Train \Train\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trained}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Training}.] [OF. trahiner, tra["i]ner,F. tra[^i]ner, LL.
   trahinare, trainare, fr. L. trahere to draw. See {Trail}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To draw along; to trail; to drag.
      [1913 Webster]

            In hollow cube
            Training his devilish enginery.       --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To draw by persuasion, artifice, or the like; to attract
      by stratagem; to entice; to allure. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            If but a dozen French
            Were there in arms, they would be as a call
            To train ten thousand English to their side. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            O, train me not, sweet mermaid, with thy note.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            This feast, I'll gage my life,
            Is but a plot to train you to your ruin. --Ford.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To teach and form by practice; to educate; to exercise; to
      discipline; as, to train the militia to the manual
      exercise; to train soldiers to the use of arms.
      [1913 Webster]

            Our trained bands, which are the trustiest and most
            proper strength of a free nation.     --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The warrior horse here bred he's taught to train.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To break, tame, and accustom to draw, as oxen.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Hort.) To lead or direct, and form to a wall or espalier;
      to form to a proper shape, by bending, lopping, or
      pruning; as, to train young trees.
      [1913 Webster]

            He trained the young branches to the right hand or
            to the left.                          --Jeffrey.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Mining) To trace, as a lode or any mineral appearance, to
      its head.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To train a gun} (Mil. &amp; Naut.), to point it at some object
      either forward or else abaft the beam, that is, not
      directly on the side. --Totten.

   {To train}, or {To train up}, to educate; to teach; to form
      by instruction or practice; to bring up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Train up a child in the way he should go; and when
            he is old, he will not depart from it. --Prov. xxii.
                                                  6.
      [1913 Webster]

            The first Christians were, by great hardships,
            trained up for glory.                 --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>training</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Training \Train"ing\, n.
   The act of one who trains; the act or process of exercising,
   disciplining, etc.; education.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Fan training} (Hort.), the operation of training fruit
      trees, grapevines, etc., so that the branches shall
      radiate from the stem like a fan.

   {Horizontal training} (Hort.), the operation of training
      fruit trees, grapevines, etc., so that the branches shall
      spread out laterally in a horizontal direction.

   {Training college}. See {Normal school}, under {Normal}, a.
      

   {Training day}, a day on which a military company assembles
      for drill or parade. [U. S.]

   {Training ship}, a vessel on board of which boys are trained
      as sailors.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: See {Education}.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>training</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>training
     n 1: activity leading to skilled behavior [syn: {preparation}, {grooming}]
     2: the result of good upbringing (especially knowledge of
        correct social behavior); "a woman of breeding and
        refinement" [syn: {education}, {breeding}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
