<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>trailing</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trailing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trailing \Trail"ing\,
   a. &amp; vb. n. from {Trail}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Trailing arbutus}. (Bot.) See under {Arbutus}.

   {Trailing spring}, a spring fixed in the axle box of the
      trailing wheels of a locomotive engine, and so placed as
      to assist in deadening any shock which may occur. --Weale.

   {Trailing wheel}, a hind wheel of a locomotive when it is not
      a driving wheel; also, one of the hind wheels of a
      carriage.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trailing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trail \Trail\ (tr[=a]l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trailed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Trailing}.] [OE. trailen, OF. trailler to trail a
   deer, or hunt him upon a cold scent, also, to hunt or pursue
   him with a limehound, F. trailler to trail a fishing line;
   probably from a derivative of L. trahere to draw; cf. L.
   traha a drag, sledge, tragula a kind of drag net, a small
   sledge, Sp. trailla a leash, an instrument for leveling the
   ground, D. treilen to draw with a rope, to tow, treil a rope
   for drawing a boat. See {Trace}, v. t.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1.
      (a) To hunt by the track; to track.
      (b) to follow behind.
      (c) To pursue. --Halliwell.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. To draw or drag, as along the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

            And hung his head, and trailed his legs along.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shall not trail me through their streets
            Like a wild beast.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Long behind he trails his pompous robe. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil.) To carry, as a firearm, with the breech near the
      ground and the upper part inclined forward, the piece
      being held by the right hand near the middle.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To tread down, as grass, by walking through it; to lay
      flat. --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To take advantage of the ignorance of; to impose upon.
      [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I presently perceived she was (what is vernacularly
            termed) trailing Mrs. Dent; that is, playing on her
            ignorance.                            --C. Bronte.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trailing</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trailing
     adj : having the lower score or lagging position in a contest;
           "behind by two points"; "the 8th inning found the home
           team trailing" [syn: {behind(p)}]
     n : the pursuit (of a person or animal) by following tracks or
         marks they left behind [syn: {tracking}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
