<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>trail</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trail, MN (city, FIPS 65344)
  Location: 47.78372 N, 95.69906 W
  Population (1990): 67 (36 housing units)
  Area: 2.6 sq km (land), 0.0 sq km (water)
  Zip code(s): 56684
Trail, OR
  Zip code(s): 97541
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>T \T\ (t[=e]),
   the twentieth letter of the English alphabet, is a nonvocal
   consonant. With the letter h it forms the digraph th, which
   has two distinct sounds, as in thin, then. See Guide to
   Pronunciation, [sect][sect]262-264, and also [sect][sect]153,
   156, 169, 172, 176, 178-180.
   [1913 Webster] The letter derives its name and form from the
   Latin, the form of the Latin letter being further derived
   through the Greek from the Ph[oe]nician. The ultimate origin
   is probably Egyptian. It is etymologically most nearly
   related to d, s, th; as in tug, duke; two, dual, L. duo;
   resin, L. resina, Gr. "rhti`nh, tent, tense, a., tenuous,
   thin; nostril, thrill. See {D}, {S}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {T bandage} (Surg.), a bandage shaped like the letter T, and
      used principally for application to the groin, or
      perineum.

   {T cart}, a kind of fashionable two seated wagon for pleasure
      driving.

   {T iron}.
   (a) A rod with a short crosspiece at the end, -- used as a
       hook.
   (b) Iron in bars, having a cross section formed like the
       letter T, -- used in structures.

   {T rail}, a kind of rail for railroad tracks, having no
      flange at the bottom so that a section resembles the
      letter T.

   {T square}, a ruler having a crosspiece or head at one end,
      for the purpose of making parallel lines; -- so called
      from its shape. It is laid on a drawing board and guided
      by the crosspiece, which is pressed against the straight
      edge of the board. Sometimes the head is arranged to be
      set at different angles.

   {To a T}, exactly, perfectly; as, to suit to a T. [Colloq.]
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>T rail \T" rail`\
   See under T.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trail \Trail\, v. i.
   1. To be drawn out in length; to follow after.
      [1913 Webster]

            When his brother saw the red blood trail. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To grow to great length, especially when slender and
      creeping upon the ground, as a plant; to run or climb.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trail \Trail\ (tr[=a]l), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trailed}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Trailing}.] [OE. trailen, OF. trailler to trail a
   deer, or hunt him upon a cold scent, also, to hunt or pursue
   him with a limehound, F. trailler to trail a fishing line;
   probably from a derivative of L. trahere to draw; cf. L.
   traha a drag, sledge, tragula a kind of drag net, a small
   sledge, Sp. trailla a leash, an instrument for leveling the
   ground, D. treilen to draw with a rope, to tow, treil a rope
   for drawing a boat. See {Trace}, v. t.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1.
      (a) To hunt by the track; to track.
      (b) to follow behind.
      (c) To pursue. --Halliwell.
          [1913 Webster +PJC]

   2. To draw or drag, as along the ground.
      [1913 Webster]

            And hung his head, and trailed his legs along.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

            They shall not trail me through their streets
            Like a wild beast.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Long behind he trails his pompous robe. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mil.) To carry, as a firearm, with the breech near the
      ground and the upper part inclined forward, the piece
      being held by the right hand near the middle.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To tread down, as grass, by walking through it; to lay
      flat. --Longfellow.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To take advantage of the ignorance of; to impose upon.
      [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

            I presently perceived she was (what is vernacularly
            termed) trailing Mrs. Dent; that is, playing on her
            ignorance.                            --C. Bronte.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trail \Trail\, n.
   1. A track left by man or beast; a track followed by the
      hunter; a scent on the ground by the animal pursued; as, a
      deer trail.
      [1913 Webster]

            They traveled in the bed of the brook, leaving no
            dangerous trail.                      --Cooper.
      [1913 Webster]

            How cheerfully on the false trail they cry! --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A footpath or road track through a wilderness or wild
      region; as, an Indian trail over the plains.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything drawn out to a length; as, the trail of a meteor;
      a trail of smoke.
      [1913 Webster]

            When lightning shoots in glittering trails along.
                                                  --Rowe.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Anything drawn behind in long undulations; a train. ``A
      radiant trail of hair.'' --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Anything drawn along, as a vehicle. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A frame for trailing plants; a trellis. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

   7. The entrails of a fowl, especially of game, as the
      woodcock, and the like; -- applied also, sometimes, to the
      entrails of sheep.
      [1913 Webster]

            The woodcock is a favorite with epicures, and served
            with its trail in, is a delicious dish. --Baird.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. (Mil.) That part of the stock of a gun carriage which
      rests on the ground when the piece is unlimbered. See
      Illust. of {Gun carriage}, under {Gun}.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. The act of taking advantage of the ignorance of a person;
      an imposition. [Prov. Eng.]
      [1913 Webster]

   {Trail boards} (Shipbuilding), the carved boards on both
      sides of the cutwater near the figurehead.

   {Trail net}, a net that is trailed or drawn behind a boat.
      --Wright.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trail</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trail
     n 1: a track or mark left by something that has passed; "there as
          a trail of blood"; "a tear left its trail on her cheek"
     2: a path or track roughly blazed through wild or hilly country
     3: evidence pointing to a possible solution; "the police are
        following a promising lead"; "the trail led straight to
        the perpetrator" [syn: {lead}, {track}]
     v 1: to lag or linger behind; "But in so many other areas we
          still are dragging" [syn: {drag}, {get behind}, {hang
          back}, {drop behind}]
     2: go after with the intent to catch; "The policeman chased the
        mugger down the alley"; "the dog chased the rabbit" [syn:
        {chase}, {chase after}, {tail}, {tag}, {give chase}, {dog},
         {go after}, {track}]
     3: move, proceed, or walk draggingly pr slowly; "John trailed
        behind behis class mates"; "The Mercedes trailed behind
        the horse cart" [syn: {shack}]
     4: hang down so as to drag along the ground; "The bride's
        veiled trailed along the ground"
     5: drag loosely along a surface; allow to sweep the ground;
        "The toddler was trailing his pants"; "She trained her
        long scarf behind her" [syn: {train}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
