<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>transfer</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>transfer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gazetteer</Id>
        <Name>U.S. Gazetteer (1990)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Transfer, PA
  Zip code(s): 16154
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>transfer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Transfer \Trans"fer\, n.
   1. The act of transferring, or the state of being
      transferred; the removal or conveyance of a thing from one
      place or person to another.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Law) The conveyance of right, title, or property, either
      real or personal, from one person to another, whether by
      sale, by gift, or otherwise.
      [1913 Webster]

            I shall here only consider it as a transfer of
            property.                             --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is transferred. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) A picture, or the like, removed from one body or
          ground to another, as from wood to canvas, or from one
          piece of canvas to another. --Fairholt.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A drawing or writing printed off from one surface on
          another, as in ceramics and in many decorative arts.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) (Mil.) A soldier removed from one troop, or body of
          troops, and placed in another.
          [1913 Webster]

   4. (Med.) A pathological process by virtue of which a
      unilateral morbid condition on being abolished on one side
      of the body makes its appearance in the corresponding
      region upon the other side.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Transfer day}, one of the days fixed by the Bank of England
      for the transfer, free of charge, of bank stock and
      government funds. These days are the first five business
      days in the week before three o'clock. Transfers may be
      made on Saturdays on payment of a fee of 2s. 6d.
      --Bithell.

   {Transfer office}, an office or department where transfers of
      stocks, etc., are made.

   {Transfer paper}, a prepared paper used by draughtsmen,
      engravers, lithographers, etc., for transferring
      impressions.

   {Transfer table}. (Railroad) Same as {Traverse table}. See
      under {Traverse}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>transfer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Transfer \Trans*fer"\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Transferred}; p. pr.
   &amp; vb. n. {Transferring}.] [L. transferre; trans across, over
   + ferre to bear: cf. F. transf['e]rer. See {Bear} to carry.]
   1. To convey from one place or person another; to transport,
      remove, or cause to pass, to another place or person; as,
      to transfer the laws of one country to another; to
      transfer suspicion.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To make over the possession or control of; to pass; to
      convey, as a right, from one person to another; to give;
      as, the title to land is transferred by deed.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To remove from one substance or surface to another; as, to
      transfer drawings or engravings to a lithographic stone.
      --Tomlinson.
      [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To sell; give; alienate; estrange; sequester.
        [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>transfer</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>transfer
     n 1: the act of transporting something from one location to
          another [syn: {transportation}, {transferral}, {conveyance}]
     2: someone who transfers or is transferred from one position to
        another; "the best student was a transfer from LSU" [syn:
        {transferee}]
     3: the act of transfering something from one form to another;
        "the transfer of the music from record to tape suppressed
        much of the background noise" [syn: {transference}]
     4: a ticket that allows a passenger to change conveyances
     5: application of a skill learned in one situation to a
        different but similar situation [syn: {transfer of
        training}, {carry-over}]
     6: transferring ownership [syn: {transference}]
     v 1: move around; "transfer the packet from his trouser pockets
          to a pocket in his jacket" [syn: {shift}]
     2: transfer somebody to a different position or location of
        work [syn: {reassign}]
     3: move from one place to another; "transfer the data";
        "transmit the news"; "transfer the patient to another
        hospital"
     4: lift and reset in another soil or situation; "Transplant the
        young rice plants" [syn: {transplant}]
     5: cause to change ownership; "I transferred my stock holdings
        to my children"
     6: change from one vehicle or transportation line to another;
        "She changed in Chicago on her way to the East coast"
        [syn: {change}]
     7: send from one person or place to another; "transmit a
        message" [syn: {transmit}, {transport}, {channel}, {channelize},
         {channelise}]
     8: shift the position or location of, as for business, legal,
        educational, or military purposes; "He removed his
        children to the countryside"; "Remove the troops to the
        forest surrounding the city"; "remove a case to another
        court" [syn: {remove}]
     9: transfer from one place or period to another; "The ancient
        Greek story was transplanted into Modern America" [syn: {transpose},
         {transplant}]
     [also: {transferring}, {transferred}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
