<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>transposition</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>transposition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Transposition \Trans`po*si"tion\, n. [F. transposition, from L.
   transponere, transpositum, to set over, remove, transfer;
   trans across, over + ponere to place. See {Position}.]
   The act of transposing, or the state of being transposed.
   Specifically: 
   [1913 Webster]
   (a) (Alg.) The bringing of any term of an equation from one
       side over to the other without destroying the equation.
       [1913 Webster]
   (b) (Gram.) A change of the natural order of words in a
       sentence; as, the Latin and Greek languages admit
       transposition, without inconvenience, to a much greater
       extent than the English.
       [1913 Webster]
   (c) (Mus.) A change of a composition into another key.
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>transposition</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>transposition
     n 1: any abnormal position of the organs of the body [syn: {heterotaxy}]
     2: an event in which one thing is substituted for another; "the
        replacement of lost blood by a transfusion of donor blood"
        [syn: {substitution}, {permutation}, {replacement}, {switch}]
     3: (genetics) a kind of mutation in which a chromosomal segment
        is transfered to a new position on the same or another
        chromosome
     4: (mathematics) the transfer of a quantity form one side of an
        equation to the other along with a change of sign
     5: (electricity) a rearrangement of the relative positions of
        power lines in order to minimize the effects of mutual
        capacitance and inductance; "he wrote a textbook on the
        electrical effects of transposition"
     6: the act of reversing the order or place of [syn: {reversal}]
     7: (music) playing in a different key from the key intended;
        moving the pitch of a piece of music upwards or downwards
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
