<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>translation</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>translation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Translation \Trans*la"tion\, n. [F. translation, L. translatio a
   transferring, translation, version. See {Translate}, and cf.
   {Tralation}.]
   1. The act of translating, removing, or transferring;
      removal; also, the state of being translated or removed;
      as, the translation of Enoch; the translation of a bishop.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The act of rendering into another language;
      interpretation; as, the translation of idioms is
      difficult.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is obtained by translating something a version;
      as, a translation of the Scriptures.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Rhet.) A transfer of meaning in a word or phrase, a
      metaphor; a tralation. [Obs.] --B. Jonson.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Metaph.) Transfer of meaning by association; association
      of ideas. --A. Tucker.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Kinematics) Motion in which all the points of the moving
      body have at any instant the same velocity and direction
      of motion; -- opposed to rotation.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>translation</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>translation
     n 1: a written communication in a second language having the same
          meaning as the written communication in a first language
          [syn: {interlingual rendition}, {rendering}, {version}]
     2: a uniform movement without rotation
     3: the act of changing in form or shape or appearance; "a
        photograph is a translation of a scene onto a
        two-dimensional surface" [syn: {transformation}]
     4: (mathematics) a transformation in which the origin of the
        coordinate system is moved to another position but the
        direction of each axis remains the same
     5: (genetics) the process whereby genetic information coded in
        messenger RNA directs the formation of a specific protein
        at a ribosome in the cytoplasm
     6: rewording something in less technical terminology
     7: the act of uniform movement [syn: {displacement}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
