<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>trap</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trap
     
        1. A program interrupt, usually an interrupt caused by some
        exceptional situation in the user program.  In most cases, the
        OS performs some action, then returns control to the program.
     
        2. To cause a trap.  "These instructions trap to the monitor."
        Also used transitively to indicate the cause of the trap.
        "The monitor traps all input/output instructions."
     
        This term is associated with assembler programming
        ("interrupt" or "exception" is more common among {HLL}
        programmers) and appears to be fading into history among
        programmers as the role of assembler continues to shrink.
        However, it is still important to computer architects and
        systems hackers (see {system}, sense 1), who use it to
        distinguish {deterministic}ally repeatable exceptions from
        timing-dependent ones (such as I/O interrupts).
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trap \Trap\, a.
   Of or pertaining to trap rock; as, a trap dike.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trap \Trap\, n. [OE. trappe, AS. treppe; akin to OD. trappe,
   OHG. trapo; probably fr. the root of E. tramp, as that which
   is trod upon: cf. F. trappe, which is trod upon: cf. F.
   trappe, which perhaps influenced the English word.]
   1. A machine or contrivance that shuts suddenly, as with a
      spring, used for taking game or other animals; as, a trap
      for foxes.
      [1913 Webster]

            She would weep if that she saw a mouse
            Caught in a trap.                     --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: A snare; an ambush; a stratagem; any device by which
      one may be caught unawares.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let their table be made a snare and a trap. --Rom.
                                                  xi. 9.
      [1913 Webster]

            God and your majesty
            Protect mine innocence, or I fall into
            The trap is laid for me!              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A wooden instrument shaped somewhat like a shoe, used in
      the game of trapball. It consists of a pivoted arm on one
      end of which is placed the ball to be thrown into the air
      by striking the other end. Also, a machine for throwing
      into the air glass balls, clay pigeons, etc., to be shot
      at.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. The game of trapball.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A bend, sag, or partitioned chamber, in a drain, soil
      pipe, sewer, etc., arranged so that the liquid contents
      form a seal which prevents passage of air or gas, but
      permits the flow of liquids.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A place in a water pipe, pump, etc., where air accumulates
      for want of an outlet.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. A wagon, or other vehicle. [Colloq.] --Thackeray.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. A kind of movable stepladder. --Knight.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Trap stairs}, a staircase leading to a trapdoor.

   {Trap tree} (Bot.) the jack; -- so called because it
      furnishes a kind of birdlime. See 1st {Jack}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trap \Trap\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trapped}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Trapping}.] [Akin to OE. trappe trappings, and perhaps from
   an Old French word of the same origin as E. drab a kind of
   cloth.]
   To dress with ornaments; to adorn; -- said especially of
   horses.
   [1913 Webster]

         Steeds . . . that trapped were in steel all glittering.
                                                  --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]

         To deck his hearse, and trap his tomb-black steed.
                                                  --Spenser.
   [1913 Webster]

         There she found her palfrey trapped
         In purple blazoned with armorial gold.   --Tennyson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trap \Trap\, n. [Sw. trapp; akin to trappa stairs, Dan. trappe,
   G. treppe, D. trap; -- so called because the rocks of this
   class often occur in large, tabular masses, rising above one
   another, like steps. See {Tramp}.] (Geol.)
   An old term rather loosely used to designate various
   dark-colored, heavy igneous rocks, including especially the
   feldspathic-augitic rocks, basalt, dolerite, amygdaloid,
   etc., but including also some kinds of diorite. Called also
   {trap rock}.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Trap tufa}, {Trap tuff}, a kind of fragmental rock made up
      of fragments and earthy materials from trap rocks.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trap \Trap\, v. t. [AS. treppan. See {Trap} a snare.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To catch in a trap or traps; as, to trap foxes.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Fig.: To insnare; to take by stratagem; to entrap. ``I
      trapped the foe.'' --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To provide with a trap; as, to trap a drain; to trap a
      sewer pipe. See 4th {Trap}, 5.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trap \Trap\, v. i.
   To set traps for game; to make a business of trapping game;
   as, to trap for beaver.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trap 1. n. A program interrupt, usually an interrupt caused by some
   exceptional situation in the user program. In most cases, the OS
   performs some action, then returns control to the program. 2. vi. To
   cause a trap. "These instructions trap to the monitor." Also used
   transitively to indicate the cause of the trap. "The monitor traps all
   input/output instructions."

   This term is associated with assembler programming (`interrupt' or
   `exception' is more common among {HLL} programmers) and appears to be
   fading into history among programmers as the role of assembler continues
   to shrink. However, it is still important to computer architects and
   systems hackers (see {system}, sense 1), who use it to distinguish
   deterministically repeatable exceptions from timing-dependent ones (such
   as I/O interrupts).


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TRAP
     Tandem Recursive Algorithm Process
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trap</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trap
     n 1: a device in which something (usually an animal) can be
          caught and penned
     2: drain consisting of a U-shaped section of drainpipe that
        holds liquid and so prevents a return flow of sewer gas
     3: something (often something deceptively attractive) that
        catches you unawares; "the exam was full of trap
        questions"; "it was all a snare and delusion" [syn: {snare}]
     4: a device to hurl clay pigeons into the air for trapshooters
     5: the act of concealing yourself and lying in wait to attack
        by surprise [syn: {ambush}, {ambuscade}, {lying in wait}]
     6: informal terms for the mouth [syn: {cakehole}, {hole}, {maw},
         {yap}, {gob}]
     7: a light two-wheeled carriage
     8: a hazard on a golf course [syn: {bunker}, {sand trap}]
     v 1: place in a confining or embarrassing position; "He was
          trapped in a difficult situation"
     2: catch in or as if in a trap; "The men trap foxes" [syn: {entrap},
         {snare}, {ensnare}, {trammel}]
     3: hold or catch as if in a trap; "The gaps between the teeth
        trap food particles"
     4: to hold fast or prevent from moving; "The child was pinned
        under the fallen tree" [syn: {pin}, {immobilize}, {immobilise}]
     [also: {trapping}, {trapped}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
