<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>treat</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Treat \Treat\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Treated}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Treating}.] [{OE}. treten, OF. traitier, F. traiter, from L.
   tractare to draw violently, to handle, manage, treat, v.
   intens. from trahere, tractum, to draw. See {Trace}, v. t.,
   and cf. {Entreat}, {Retreat}, {Trait}.]
   1. To handle; to manage; to use; to bear one's self toward;
      as, to treat prisoners cruelly; to treat children kindly.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To discourse on; to handle in a particular manner, in
      writing or speaking; as, to treat a subject diffusely.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To entertain with food or drink, especially the latter, as
      a compliment, or as an expression of friendship or regard;
      as, to treat the whole company.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To negotiate; to settle; to make terms for. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To treat the peace, a hundred senators
            Shall be commissioned.                --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Med.) To care for medicinally or surgically; to manage in
      the use of remedies or appliances; as, to treat a disease,
      a wound, or a patient.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To subject to some action; to apply something to; as, to
      treat a substance with sulphuric acid. --Ure.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To entreat; to beseech. [Obs.] --Ld. Berners.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Treat \Treat\, v. i.
   1. To discourse; to handle a subject in writing or speaking;
      to make discussion; -- usually with of; as, Cicero treats
      of old age and of duties.
      [1913 Webster]

            And, shortly of this story for to treat. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Now of love they treat.               --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To negotiate; to come to terms of accommodation; -- often
      followed by with; as, envoys were appointed to treat with
      France.
      [1913 Webster]

            Inform us, will the emperor treat!    --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give a gratuitous entertainment, esp. of food or drink,
      as a compliment.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Treat \Treat\, n.
   1. A parley; a conference. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Bid him battle without further treat. --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An entertainment given as an expression of regard.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which affords entertainment; a gratification; a
      satisfaction; as, the concert was a rich treat.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treat</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>treat
     n 1: something considered choice to eat [syn: {dainty}, {delicacy},
           {goody}, {kickshaw}]
     2: an occurrence that cause special pleasure or delight
     v 1: interact in a certain way; "Do right by her"; "Treat him
          with caution, please"; "Handle the press reporters
          gently" [syn: {handle}, {do by}]
     2: subject to a process or treatment, with the aim of readying
        for some purpose, improving, or remedying a condition;
        "process cheese"; "process hair"; "treat the water so it
        can be drunk"; "treat the lawn with chemicals" ; "treat an
        oil spill" [syn: {process}]
     3: provide treatment for; "The doctor treated my broken leg";
        "The nurses cared for the bomb victims"; "The patient must
        be treated right away or she will die"; "Treat the
        infection with antibiotics" [syn: {care for}]
     4: deal with verbally or in some form of artistic expression;
        "This book deals with incest"; "The course covered all of
        Western Civilization"; "The new book treats the history of
        China" [syn: {cover}, {handle}, {plow}, {deal}, {address}]
     5: provide with a gift or entertainment; "Grandmother always
        treated us to the circus"; "I like to treat myself to a
        day at a spa when I am depressed"
     6: provide with choice or abundant food or drink; "Don't worry
        about the expensive wine--I'm treating"; "She treated her
        houseguests with good food every night" [syn: {regale}]
     7: engage in negotiations in order to reach an agreement; "they
        had to treat with the King"
     8: regard or consider in a specific way; "I treated his
        advances as a joke"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
