<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>treated</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treated</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Treat \Treat\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Treated}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Treating}.] [{OE}. treten, OF. traitier, F. traiter, from L.
   tractare to draw violently, to handle, manage, treat, v.
   intens. from trahere, tractum, to draw. See {Trace}, v. t.,
   and cf. {Entreat}, {Retreat}, {Trait}.]
   1. To handle; to manage; to use; to bear one's self toward;
      as, to treat prisoners cruelly; to treat children kindly.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To discourse on; to handle in a particular manner, in
      writing or speaking; as, to treat a subject diffusely.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To entertain with food or drink, especially the latter, as
      a compliment, or as an expression of friendship or regard;
      as, to treat the whole company.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To negotiate; to settle; to make terms for. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            To treat the peace, a hundred senators
            Shall be commissioned.                --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Med.) To care for medicinally or surgically; to manage in
      the use of remedies or appliances; as, to treat a disease,
      a wound, or a patient.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To subject to some action; to apply something to; as, to
      treat a substance with sulphuric acid. --Ure.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To entreat; to beseech. [Obs.] --Ld. Berners.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treated</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>treated
     adj 1: subjected to a physical (or chemical) treatment or action or
            agent; "the sludge of treated sewage can be used as
            fertilizer"; "treated timbers resist rot"; "treated
            fabrics resist wrinkling" [ant: {untreated}]
     2: (of a specimen for study under a microscope) treated with a
        reagent or dye that colors only certain structures
     3: given medical care or treatment; "a treated cold is usually
        gone in 14 days; if left untreated it lasts two weeks"
        [ant: {untreated}]
     4: made hard or flexible or resilient especially by heat
        treatment; "a sword of tempered steel"; "tempered glass"
        [syn: {tempered}, {hardened}, {toughened}] [ant: {untempered}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
