<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>treasury</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treasury</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Treasury
   (Matt. 27:6; Mark 12:41; John 8:20). It does not appear that
   there was a separate building so called. The name was given to
   the thirteen brazen chests, called "trumpets," from the form of
   the opening into which the offerings of the temple worshippers
   were put. These stood in the outer "court of the women." "Nine
   chests were for the appointed money-tribute and for the
   sacrifice-tribute, i.e., money-gifts instead of the sacrifices;
   four chests for freewill-offerings for wood, incense, temple
   decoration, and burnt-offerings" (Lightfoot's Hor. Heb.).
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treasury</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Treasury \Treas"ur*y\, n.; pl. {Treasuries}. [OE. tresorie, F.
   tr['e]sorerie.]
   1. A place or building in which stores of wealth are
      deposited; especially, a place where public revenues are
      deposited and kept, and where money is disbursed to defray
      the expenses of government; hence, also, the place of
      deposit and disbursement of any collected funds.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. That department of a government which has charge of the
      finances.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A repository of abundance; a storehouse.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Hence, a book or work containing much valuable knowledge,
      wisdom, wit, or the like; a thesaurus; as, `` Maunder's
      Treasury of Botany.''
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A treasure. [Obs.] --Marston.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Board of treasury}, the board to which is intrusted the
      management of all matters relating to the sovereign's
      civil list or other revenues. [Eng.] --Brande &amp; C.

   {Treasury bench}, the first row of seats on the right hand of
      the Speaker in the House of Commons; -- so called because
      occupied by the first lord of the treasury and chief
      minister of the crown. [Eng.]

   {Treasury lord}. See {Lord high treasurer of England}, under
      {Treasurer}. [Eng.]

   {Treasury note} (U. S. Finance), a circulating note or bill
      issued by government authority from the Treasury
      Department, and receivable in payment of dues to the
      government.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>treasury</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>treasury
     n 1: the funds of a government or institution or individual [syn:
           {exchequer}]
     2: the government department responsible for collecting and
        managing and spending public revenues
     3: the British cabinet minister responsible for economic
        strategy [syn: {First Lord of the Treasury}]
     4: the federal department that collects revenue and administers
        federal finances; the Treasury Department was created in
        1789 [syn: {Department of the Treasury}, {Treasury
        Department}, {United States Treasury}]
     5: a depository (a room or building) where wealth and precious
        objects can be kept safely
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
