<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tribe</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tribe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tribe
   a collection of families descending from one ancestor. The
   "twelve tribes" of the Hebrews were the twelve collections of
   families which sprang from the sons of Jacob. In Matt. 24:30 the
   word has a wider significance. The tribes of Israel are referred
   to as types of the spiritual family of God (Rev. 7). (See
   ISRAEL, KINGDOM {OF}; JUDAH, KINGDOM {OF}.)
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tribe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tribe \Tribe\, v. t.
   To distribute into tribes or classes. [R.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Our fowl, fish, and quadruped are well tribed. --Abp.
                                                  Nicolson.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tribe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tribe \Tribe\, n. [L. tribus, originally, a third part of the
   Roman people, afterwards, a division of the people, a tribe;
   of uncertain origin: cf. F. tribu.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. A family, race, or series of generations, descending from
      the same progenitor, and kept distinct, as in the case of
      the twelve tribes of Israel, descended from the twelve
      sons of Jacob. ``The Lion of the tribe of Juda.'' --Rev.
      v. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

            A wealthy Hebrew of my tribe.         --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Bot.) A number of species or genera having certain
      structural characteristics in common; as, a tribe of
      plants; a tribe of animals.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: By many recent naturalists, tribe has been used for a
         group of animals or plants intermediate between order
         and genus.
         [1913 Webster]

   3. A nation of savages or uncivilized people; a body of rude
      people united under one leader or government; as, the
      tribes of the Six Nations; the Seneca tribe.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A division, class, or distinct portion of a people, from
      whatever cause that distinction may have originated; as,
      the city of Athens was divided into ten tribes.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Stock Breeding) A family of animals descended from some
      particular female progenitor, through the female line; as,
      the Duchess tribe of shorthorns.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tribe</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tribe
     n 1: a social division of (usually preliterate) people [syn: {folk}]
     2: a federation (as of American Indians) [syn: {federation of
        tribes}]
     3: (biology) a taxonomic category between a genus and a
        subfamily
     4: group of people related by blood or marriage [syn: {kin}, {kin
        group}, {kinship group}, {kindred}, {clan}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
