<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tried</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tried</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tried \Tried\,
   imp. &amp; p. p. of {Try.} Also adj. Proved; tested; faithful;
   trustworthy; as, a tried friend.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tried</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Try \Try\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {tried}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Trying}.] [OE. trien to select, pick out, F. trier to cull,
   to out, LL. tritare to triturate (hence the sense of, to
   thresh, to separate the grain from the straw, to select), L.
   terere, tritum, to rub, bruise, grind, thresh. See {Trite}.]
   1. To divide or separate, as one sort from another; to
      winnow; to sift; to pick out; -- frequently followed by
      out; as, to try out the wild corn from the good. [Obs.]
      --Sir T. Elyot.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To purify or refine, as metals; to melt out, and procure
      in a pure state, as oil, tallow, lard, etc. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            The words of the Lord are pure words: as silver
            tried in a furnace of earth, purified seven times.
                                                  --Ps. xii. 6.
      [1913 Webster]

            For thou, O God, hast proved us: thou hast tried us,
            as silver is tried.                   --Ps. lxvi.
                                                  10.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To prove by experiment; to apply a test to, for the
      purpose of determining the quality; to examine; to prove;
      to test; as, to try weights or measures by a standard; to
      try a man's opinions.
      [1913 Webster]

            Let the end try the man.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To subject to severe trial; to put to the test; to cause
      suffering or trouble to.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thus far to try thee, Adam, I was pleased. --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            These are the times that try men's souls. --Thomas
                                                  Paine (1776)
      [PJC]

   5. To experiment with; to test by use; as, to try a remedy
      for disease; to try a horse.
      [1913 Webster]

            Come, try upon yourselves what you have seen me.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            To ease her cares the force of sleep she tries.
                                                  --Swift.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To strain; to subject to excessive tests; as, the light
      tries his eyes; repeated disappointments try one's
      patience.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) To examine or investigate judicially; to examine by
      witnesses or other judicial evidence and the principles of
      law; as, to try a cause, or a criminal.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To settle; to decide; to determine; specifically, to
      decide by an appeal to arms; as, to try rival claims by a
      duel; to try conclusions.
      [1913 Webster]

            Left I the court, to see this quarrel tried. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   9. To experience; to have or gain knowledge of by experience.
      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Or try the Libyan heat or Scythian cold. --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   10. To essay; to attempt; to endeavor.
       [1913 Webster]

             Let us try . . . to found a path.    --Milton.
       [1913 Webster]

   {To try on}.
       (a) To put on, as a garment, to ascertain whether it fits
           the person.
       (b) To attempt; to undertake. [Slang] --Dickens.
           [1913 Webster]

   Syn: To attempt; endeavor; strive; aim; examine.

   Usage: {Try}, {Attempt}. To try is the generic, to attempt is
          the specific, term. When we try, we are usually
          uncertain as to success; when we attempt, we have
          always some definite object in view which we seek to
          accomplish. We may be indifferent as to the result of
          a trial, but we rarely attempt anything without a
          desire to succeed.
          [1913 Webster]

                He first deceased: she for a little tried
                To live without him; liked it not, and died.
                                                  --Sir H.
                                                  Wotton.
          [1913 Webster]

                Alack, I am afraid they have a waked,
                And 't is not done. The attempt, and not the
                deed,
                Confounds us.                     --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tried</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tried
     adj 1: tested and proved useful or correct; "a tested method" [syn:
             {tested}, {well-tried}]
     2: tested and proved to be reliable [syn: {tested}, {time-tested},
         {tried and true}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tried</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>try
     n : earnest and conscientious activity intended to do or
         accomplish something; "made an effort to cover all the
         reading material"; "wished him luck in his endeavor";
         "she gave it a good try" [syn: {attempt}, {effort}, {endeavor},
          {endeavour}]
     v 1: make an effort or attempt; "He tried to shake off his
          fears"; "The infant had essayed a few wobbly steps";
          "The police attempted to stop the thief"; "He sought to
          improve himself"; "She always seeks to do good in the
          world" [syn: {seek}, {attempt}, {essay}, {assay}]
     2: put to the test, as for its quality, or give experimental
        use to; "This approach has been tried with good results";
        "Test this recipe" [syn: {test}, {prove}, {try out}, {examine},
         {essay}]
     3: put on trial or hear a case and sit as the judge at the
        trial of; "The football star was tried for the murder of
        his wife"; "The judge tried both father and son in
        separate trials" [syn: {judge}, {adjudicate}]
     4: take a sample of; "Try these new crackers"; "Sample the
        regional dishes" [syn: {sample}, {try out}, {taste}]
     5: examine or hear (evidence or a case) by judicial process;
        "The jury had heard all the evidence"; "The case will be
        tried in California" [syn: {hear}]
     6: give pain or trouble to; "I've been sorely tried by these
        students"
     7: test the limits of; "You are trying my patience!" [syn: {strain},
         {stress}]
     8: melt (fat, lard, etc.) in order to separate out impurities;
        "try the yak butter"; "render fat in a casserole" [syn: {render}]
     9: put on a garment in order to see whether it fits and looks
        nice; "Try on this sweater to see how it looks" [syn: {try
        on}]
     [also: {tried}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tried</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tried
     See {try}
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
