<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>trigger</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trigger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trigger
     
        &lt;database&gt; An action causing the automatic invocation of a
        procedure, for instance to preserve {referential integrity}.
        A triggers goes into effect when a user attempts to modify
        data with an insert, delete, or update command.  A trigger can
        instruct the system to take any number of actions when a
        specified change is attempted.  By preventing incorrect,
        unauthorized, or inconsistent changes to data, triggers help
        maintain the integrity of the database.
     
        [Sybase SQL Server Release 10.0 Transact-SQL User's Guide].
     
        (1995-02-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trigger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trigger \Trig"ger\, n. [For older tricker, from D. trekker, fr.
   trekken to draw, pull. See {Trick}, n.]
   1. A catch to hold the wheel of a carriage on a declivity.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Mech.) A piece, as a lever, which is connected with a
      catch or detent as a means of releasing it; especially
      (Firearms), the part of a lock which is moved by the
      finger to release the cock and discharge the piece.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Trigger fish} (Zo["o]l.), a large plectognath fish
      ({Balistes Carolinensis} or {Balistes capriscus}) common
      on the southern coast of the United States, and valued as
      a food fish in some localities. Its rough skin is used for
      scouring and polishing in the place of sandpaper. Called
      also {leather jacket}, and {turbot}.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trigger</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trigger
     n 1: lever that activates the firing mechanism of a gun [syn: {gun
          trigger}]
     2: a device that activates or releases or causes something to
        happen
     3: an act that sets in motion some course of events [syn: {induction},
         {initiation}]
     v 1: put in motion or move to act; "trigger a reaction"; "actuate
          the circuits" [syn: {trip}, {actuate}, {activate}, {set
          off}, {spark off}, {spark}, {trigger off}, {touch off}]
     2: release or pull the trigger on; "Trigger a gun"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
