<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>troll</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TROLL
     
        An {array} language for {continuous simulation}, econometric
        modelling or statistical analysis.
     
        ["TROLL Reference Manual", D0062, Info Proc Services, MIT
        (1973-76)].
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>troll
     
        An {electronic mail} message, {Usenet} posting or other
        (electronic) communication which is intentionally incorrect,
        but not overtly controversial (compare {flame bait}), or the
        act of sending such a message.  Trolling aims to elicit an
        emotional reaction from those with a hair-trigger on the reply
        key.  A really subtle troll makes some people lose their
        minds.
     
        (1994-10-17)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Troll \Troll\, n. [Icel. troll. Cf. {Droll}, {Trull}.] (Scand.
   Myth.)
   A supernatural being, often represented as of diminutive
   size, but sometimes as a giant, and fabled to inhabit caves,
   hills, and like places; a witch.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Troll flower}. (Bot.) Same as {Globeflower}
   (a) .
       [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Troll \Troll\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trolled}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Trolling}.] [OE. trollen to roll, F. tr[^o]ler, Of. troller
   to drag about, to ramble; probably of Teutonic origin; cf. G.
   trollen to roll, ramble, sich trollen to be gone; or perhaps
   for trotler, fr. F. trotter to trot (cf. {Trot}.). Cf.
   {Trawl}.]
   1. To move circularly or volubly; to roll; to turn.
      [1913 Webster]

            To dress and troll the tongue, and roll the eye.
                                                  --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To send about; to circulate, as a vessel in drinking.
      [1913 Webster]

            Then doth she troll to the bowl.      --Gammer
                                                  Gurton's
                                                  Needle.
      [1913 Webster]

            Troll the brown bowl.                 --Sir W.
                                                  Scott.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To sing the parts of in succession, as of a round, a
      catch, and the like; also, to sing loudly or freely.
      [1913 Webster]

            Will you troll the catch ?            --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            His sonnets charmed the attentive crowd,
            By wide-mouthed mortaltrolled aloud.  --Hudibras.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To angle for with a trolling line, or with a book drawn
      along the surface of the water; hence, to allure.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To fish in; to seek to catch fish from.
      [1913 Webster]

            With patient angle trolls the finny deep.
                                                  --Goldsmith.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Troll \Troll\, v. i.
   1. To roll; to run about; to move around; as, to troll in a
      coach and six.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To move rapidly; to wag. --F. Beaumont.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To take part in trolling a song.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To fish with a rod whose line runs on a reel; also, to
      fish by drawing the hook through the water.
      [1913 Webster]

            Their young men . . . trolled along the brooks that
            abounded in fish.                     --Bancroft.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Troll \Troll\, n.
   1. The act of moving round; routine; repetition. --Burke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A song the parts of which are sung in succession; a catch;
      a round.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thence the catch and troll, while ``Laughter,
            holding both his sides,'' sheds tears to song and
            ballad pathetic on the woes of married life. --Prof.
                                                  Wilson.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A trolley.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Troll plate} (Mach.), a rotative disk with spiral ribs or
      grooves, by which several pieces, as the jaws of a chuck,
      can be brought together or spread radially.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>troll 1. v.,n. [From the Usenet group alt.folklore.urban] To utter a
   posting on {Usenet} designed to attract predictable responses or
   {flame}s; or, the post itself. Derives from the phrase "trolling for
   {newbie}s" which in turn comes from mainstream "trolling", a style of
   fishing in which one trails bait through a likely spot hoping for a
   bite. The well-constructed troll is a post that induces lots of newbies
   and flamers to make themselves look even more clueless than they already
   do, while subtly conveying to the more savvy and experienced that it is
   in fact a deliberate troll. If you don't fall for the joke, you get to
   be in on it. See also {YHBT}. 2. n. An individual who chronically trolls
   in sense 1; regularly posts specious arguments, flames or personal
   attacks to a newsgroup, discussion list, or in email for no other
   purpose than to annoy someone or disrupt a discussion. Trolls are
   recognizable by the fact that they have no real interest in learning
   about the topic at hand - they simply want to utter flame bait. Like the
   ugly creatures they are named after, they exhibit no redeeming
   characteristics, and as such, they are recognized as a lower form of
   life on the net, as in, "Oh, ignore him, he's just a troll." Compare
   {kook}. 3. n. [Berkeley] Computer lab monitor. A popular campus job for
   CS students. Duties include helping newbies and ensuring that lab
   policies are followed. Probably so-called because it involves lurking in
   dark cavelike corners.

   Some people claim that the troll (sense 1) is properly a narrower
   category than {flame bait}, that a troll is categorized by containing
   some assertion that is wrong but not overtly controversial. See also
   {Troll-O-Meter}.

   The use of `troll' in either sense is a live metaphor that readily
   produces elaborations and combining forms. For example, one not
   infrequently sees the warning "Do not feed the troll" as part of a
   followup to troll postings.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>troll</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>troll
     n 1: (Scandanavian folklore) a supernatural creature (either a
          dwarf or a giant) that is supposed to live in caves or
          in the mountains
     2: a partsong in which voices follow each other; one voice
        starts and others join in one after another until all are
        singing different parts of the song at the same time;
        "they enjoyed singing rounds" [syn: {round}]
     3: a fisherman's lure that is used in trolling; "he used a
        spinner as his troll"
     4: angling by drawing a baited line through the water [syn: {trolling}]
     v 1: circulate, move around
     2: cause to move round and round; "The child trolled her hoop"
     3: sing the parts of (a round) in succession
     4: angle with a hook and line drawn through the water
     5: sing loudly and without inhibition
     6: praise or celebrate in song; "All tongues shall troll you"
     7: speak or recite rapidly or in a rolling voice
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
