<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>trophy</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trophy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trophy \Tro"phy\, n.; pl. {Trophies}. [F. troph['e]e (cf. It. &amp;
   Sp. trofeo), L. tropaeum, trophaeum, Gr. ?, strictly, a
   monument of the enemy's defeat, fr.? a turn, especially, a
   turning about of the enemy, a putting to flight or routing
   him, fr. ? to turn. See {Trope}.]
   1. (Gr. &amp; Rom. Antiq.) A sign or memorial of a victory raised
      on the field of battle, or, in case of a naval victory, on
      the nearest land. Sometimes trophies were erected in the
      chief city of the conquered people.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: A trophy consisted originally of some of the armor,
         weapons, etc., of the defeated enemy fixed to the trunk
         of a tree or to a post erected on an elevated site,
         with an inscription, and a dedication to a divinity.
         The Romans often erected their trophies in the Capitol.
         [1913 Webster]

   2. The representation of such a memorial, as on a medal; esp.
      (Arch.), an ornament representing a group of arms and
      military weapons, offensive and defensive.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Anything taken from an enemy and preserved as a memorial
      of victory, as arms, flags, standards, etc.
      [1913 Webster]

            Around the posts hung helmets, darts, and spears,
            And captive chariots, axes, shields, and bars,
            And broken beaks of ships, the trophies of their
            wars.                                 --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. Any evidence or memorial of victory or conquest; as, every
      redeemed soul is a trophy of grace.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. An object memorializing a victory in a sporting contest.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Some trophies(5) are unique, temporary possession of
         the same object passing to the new victors of some
         periodic contest in subsequent occurrences. Others are
         objects of little inherent worth, given by the
         authority sponsoring the contest to the victor. A
         trophy is sometimes shaped like a cup, and in such
         cases may be called a {cup}, as the {America's Cup} (in
         Yacht racing). --&gt;
         [1913 Webster]

   {Trophy money}, a duty paid formerly in England, annually, by
      housekeepers, toward providing harness, drums, colors, and
      the like, for the militia.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trophy</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trophy
     n 1: an award for success in war or hunting
     2: something given as a token of victory [syn: {prize}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
