<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tropical</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tropical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Month \Month\ (m[u^]nth), n. [OE. month, moneth, AS.
   m[=o]n[eth], m[=o]na[eth]; akin to m[=o]na moon, and to D.
   maand month, G. monat, OHG. m[=a]n[=o]d, Icel. m[=a]nu[eth]r,
   m[=a]na[eth]r, Goth. m[=e]n[=o][thorn]s. [root]272. See
   {Moon}.]
   One of the twelve portions into which the year is divided;
   the twelfth part of a year, corresponding nearly to the
   length of a synodic revolution of the moon, -- whence the
   name. In popular use, a period of four weeks is often called
   a month.
   [1913 Webster]

   Note: In the common law, a month is a lunar month, or
         twenty-eight days, unless otherwise expressed.
         --Blackstone. In the United States the rule of the
         common law is generally changed, and a month is
         declared to mean a calendar month. --Cooley's
         Blackstone.
         [1913 Webster]

   {A month mind}.
   (a) A strong or abnormal desire. [Obs.] --Shak.
   (b) A celebration made in remembrance of a deceased person a
       month after death. --Strype.

   {Calendar months}, the months as adjusted in the common or
      Gregorian calendar; April, June, September, and November,
      containing 30 days, and the rest 31, except February,
      which, in common years, has 28, and in leap years 29.

   {Lunar month}, the period of one revolution of the moon,
      particularly a synodical revolution; but several kinds are
      distinguished, as the {synodical month}, or period from
      one new moon to the next, in mean length 29 d. 12 h. 44 m.
      2.87 s.; the {nodical month}, or time of revolution from
      one node to the same again, in length 27 d. 5 h. 5 m. 36
      s.; the {sidereal}, or time of revolution from a star to
      the same again, equal to 27 d. 7 h. 43 m. 11.5 s.; the
      {anomalistic}, or time of revolution from perigee to
      perigee again, in length 27 d. 13 h. 18 m. 37.4 s.; and
      the {tropical}, or time of passing from any point of the
      ecliptic to the same again, equal to 27 d. 7 h. 43 m. 4.7
      s.

   {Solar month}, the time in which the sun passes through one
      sign of the zodiac, in mean length 30 d. 10 h. 29 m. 4.1
      s.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tropical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tropical \Trop"ic*al\, a. [Cf. L. tropicus of turning, Gr. ?.
   See {Tropic}, n.]
   1. Of or pertaining to the tropics; characteristic of, or
      incident to, the tropics; being within the tropics; as,
      tropical climate; tropical latitudes; tropical heat;
      tropical diseases.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. [From {Trope}.] Rhetorically changed from its exact
      original sense; being of the nature of a trope;
      figurative; metaphorical. --Jer. Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

            The foundation of all parables is some analogy or
            similitude between the tropical or allusive part of
            the parable and the thing intended by it. --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tropic month}. See {Lunar month}, under {Month}.

   {Tropic year}, the solar year; the period occupied by the sun
      in passing from one tropic or one equinox to the same
      again, having a mean length of 365 days, 5 hours, 48
      minutes, 46.0 seconds, which is 20 minutes, 23.3 seconds
      shorter than the sidereal year, on account of the
      precession of the equinoxes.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tropical</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tropical
     adj 1: relating to or situated in or characteristic of the tropics
            (the region on either side of the equator); "tropical
            islands"; "tropical fruit" [syn: {tropic}]
     2: of or relating to the tropics, or either tropic; "tropical
        year"
     3: characterized by or of the nature of a trope or tropes;
        changed from its literal sense
     4: of weather or climate; hot and humid as in the tropics;
        "tropical weather" [syn: {tropic}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
