<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>trundle</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trundle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Lantern \Lan"tern\ (l[a^]n"t[~e]rn), n. [F. lanterne, L.
   lanterna, laterna, from Gr. lampth`r light, torch. See
   {Lamp}.]
   1. Something inclosing a light, and protecting it from wind,
      rain, etc.; -- sometimes portable, as a closed vessel or
      case of horn, perforated tin, glass, oiled paper, or other
      material, having a lamp or candle within; sometimes fixed,
      as the glazed inclosure of a street light, or of a
      lighthouse light.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. (Arch.)
      (a) An open structure of light material set upon a roof,
          to give light and air to the interior.
      (b) A cage or open chamber of rich architecture, open
          below into the building or tower which it crowns.
      (c) A smaller and secondary cupola crowning a larger one,
          for ornament, or to admit light; such as the lantern
          of the cupola of the Capitol at Washington, or that of
          the Florence cathedral.
          [1913 Webster]

   3. (Mach.) A lantern pinion or trundle wheel. See {Lantern
      pinion} (below).
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Steam Engine) A kind of cage inserted in a stuffing box
      and surrounding a piston rod, to separate the packing into
      two parts and form a chamber between for the reception of
      steam, etc.; -- called also {lantern brass}.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Founding) A perforated barrel to form a core upon.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Zo["o]l.) See {Aristotle's lantern}.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: Fig. 1 represents a hand lantern; fig. 2, an arm
         lantern; fig. 3, a breast lantern; -- so named from the
         positions in which they are carried.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Dark lantern}, a lantern with a single opening, which may be
      closed so as to conceal the light; -- called also
      {bull's-eye}.

   {Lantern jaws}, long, thin jaws; hence, a thin visage.

   {Lantern pinion}, {Lantern wheel} (Mach.), a kind of pinion
      or wheel having cylindrical bars or trundles, instead of
      teeth, inserted at their ends in two parallel disks or
      plates; -- so called as resembling a lantern in shape; --
      called also {wallower}, or {trundle}.

   {Lantern shell} (Zo["o]l.), any translucent, marine, bivalve
      shell of the genus {Anatina}, and allied genera.

   {Magic lantern}, an optical instrument consisting of a case
      inclosing a light, and having suitable lenses in a lateral
      tube, for throwing upon a screen, in a darkened room or
      the like, greatly magnified pictures from slides placed in
      the focus of the outer lens.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trundle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trundle \Trun"dle\, n. [AS. tryndel a little shield. See
   {Trend}, v. i.]
   1. A round body; a little wheel.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A lind of low-wheeled cart; a truck.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A motion as of something moving upon little wheels or
      rollers; a rolling motion.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mach.)
      (a) A lantern wheel. See under {Lantern}.
      (b) One of the bars of a lantern wheel.
          [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trundle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trundle \Trun"dle\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trundled}; p. pr. &amp; vb.
   n. {Trundling}.]
   1. To roll (a thing) on little wheels; as, to trundle a bed
      or a gun carriage.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to roll or revolve; to roll along; as, to trundle
      a hoop or a ball. --R. A. Proctor.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trundle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trundle \Trun"dle\, v. i.
   1. To go or move on small wheels; as, a bed trundles under
      another.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To roll, or go by revolving, as a hoop.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trundle</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trundle
     n 1: a low bed to be slid under a higher bed [syn: {trundle bed},
           {truckle bed}, {truckle}]
     2: small wheel or roller
     v : move heavily; "the streetcar trundled down the avenue"
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
