<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>trust</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TRUST, n.  In American politics, a large corporation composed in
greater part of thrifty working men, widows of small means, orphans in
the care of guardians and the courts, with many similar malefactors
and public enemies.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trust \Trust\, n. [OE. trust, trost, Icel. traust confidence,
   security; akin to Dan. &amp; Sw. tr["o]st comfort, consolation,
   G. trost, Goth. trausti a convention, covenant, and E. true.
   See {True}, and cf. {Tryst}.]
   1. Assured resting of the mind on the integrity, veracity,
      justice, friendship, or other sound principle, of another
      person; confidence; reliance; reliance. ``O ever-failing
      trust in mortal strength!'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Most take things upon trust.          --Locke.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Credit given; especially, delivery of property or
      merchandise in reliance upon future payment; exchange
      without immediate receipt of an equivalent; as, to sell or
      buy goods on trust.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Assured anticipation; dependence upon something future or
      contingent, as if present or actual; hope; belief. ``Such
      trust have we through Christ.'' --2 Cor. iii. 4.
      [1913 Webster]

            His trust was with the Eternal to be deemed
            Equal in strength.                    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which is committed or intrusted to one; something
      received in confidence; charge; deposit.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. The condition or obligation of one to whom anything is
      confided; responsible charge or office.
      [1913 Webster]

            [I] serve him truly that will put me in trust.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Reward them well, if they observe their trust.
                                                  --Denham.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. That upon which confidence is reposed; ground of reliance;
      hope.
      [1913 Webster]

            O Lord God, thou art my trust from my youth. --Ps.
                                                  lxxi. 5.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Law) An estate devised or granted in confidence that the
      devisee or grantee shall convey it, or dispose of the
      profits, at the will, or for the benefit, of another; an
      estate held for the use of another; a confidence
      respecting property reposed in one person, who is termed
      the trustee, for the benefit of another, who is called the
      cestui que trust.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. An equitable right or interest in property distinct from
      the legal ownership thereof; a use (as it existed before
      the Statute of Uses); also, a property interest held by
      one person for the benefit of another. Trusts are active,
      or special, express, implied, constructive, etc. In a

   {passive trust} the trustee simply has title to the trust
      property, while its control and management are in the
      beneficiary.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   9. A business organization or combination consisting of a
      number of firms or corporations operating, and often
      united, under an agreement creating a trust (in sense 1),
      esp. one formed mainly for the purpose of regulating the
      supply and price of commodities, etc.; often,
      opprobriously, a combination formed for the purpose of
      controlling or monopolizing a trade, industry, or
      business, by doing acts in restraint or trade; as, a sugar
      trust. A trust may take the form of a corporation or of a
      body of persons or corporations acting together by mutual
      arrangement, as under a contract or a so-called
      gentlemen's agreement. When it consists of corporations it
      may be effected by putting a majority of their stock
      either in the hands of a board of trustees (whence the
      name trust for the combination) or by transferring a
      majority to a holding company. The advantages of a trust
      are partly due to the economies made possible in carrying
      on a large business, as well as the doing away with
      competition. In the United States severe statutes against
      trusts have been passed by the Federal government and in
      many States, with elaborate statutory definitions.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   Syn: Confidence; belief; faith; hope; expectation.
        [1913 Webster]

   {Trust deed} (Law), a deed conveying property to a trustee,
      for some specific use.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trust \Trust\, a.
   Held in trust; as, trust property; trustmoney.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trust \Trust\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Trusted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Trusting}.] [OE. trusten, trosten. See {Trust}, n.]
   1. To place confidence in; to rely on, to confide, or repose
      faith, in; as, we can not trust those who have deceived
      us.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will never trust his word after.    --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            He that trusts every one without reserve will at
            last be deceived.                     --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To give credence to; to believe; to credit.
      [1913 Webster]

            Trust me, you look well.              --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To hope confidently; to believe; -- usually with a phrase
      or infinitive clause as the object.
      [1913 Webster]

            I trust to come unto you, and speak face to face.
                                                  --2 John 12.
      [1913 Webster]

            We trustwe have a good conscience.    --Heb. xiii.
                                                  18.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. to show confidence in a person by intrusting (him) with
      something.
      [1913 Webster]

            Whom, with your power and fortune, sir, you trust,
            Now to suspect is vain.               --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To commit, as to one's care; to intrust.
      [1913 Webster]

            Merchants were not willing to trust precious cargoes
            to any custody but that of a man-of-war. --Macaulay.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To give credit to; to sell to upon credit, or in
      confidence of future payment; as, merchants and
      manufacturers trust their customers annually with goods.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. To risk; to venture confidently.
      [1913 Webster]

            [Beguiled] by thee
            to trust thee from my side.           --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Trust \Trust\, v. i.
   1. To have trust; to be credulous; to be won to confidence;
      to confide.
      [1913 Webster]

            More to know could not be more to trust. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be confident, as of something future; to hope.
      [1913 Webster]

            I will trust and not be afraid.       --Isa. xii. 2.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To sell or deliver anything in reliance upon a promise of
      payment; to give credit.
      [1913 Webster]

            It is happier sometimes to be cheated than not to
            trust.                                --Johnson.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To trust in}, {To trust on}, to place confidence in,; to
      rely on; to depend. ``Trust in the Lord, and do good.''
      --Ps. xxxvii. 3. ``A priest . . . on whom we trust.''
      --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]

            Her widening streets on new foundations trust.
                                                  --Dryden.
      [1913 Webster]

   {To trust to} or {To trust unto}, to depend on; to have
      confidence in; to rely on; as, to trust to luck.
      [1913 Webster]

            They trusted unto the liers in wait.  --Judges xx.
                                                  36.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>trust</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>trust
     n 1: something (as property) held by one party (the trustee) for
          the benefit of another (the beneficiary); "he is the
          beneficiary of a generous trust set up by his father"
     2: certainty based on past experience; "he wrote the paper with
        considerable reliance on the work of other scientists";
        "he put more trust in his own two legs than in the gun"
        [syn: {reliance}]
     3: the trait of trusting; of believing in the honesty and
        reliability of others; "the experience destroyed his trust
        and personal dignity" [syn: {trustingness}, {trustfulness}]
        [ant: {distrust}]
     4: a consortium of independent organizations formed to limit
        competition by controlling the production and distribution
        of a product or service; "they set up the trust in the
        hope of gaining a monopoly" [syn: {corporate trust}, {combine},
         {cartel}]
     5: complete confidence in a person or plan etc; "he cherished
        the faith of a good woman"; "the doctor-patient
        relationship is based on trust" [syn: {faith}]
     6: a trustful relationship; "he took me into his confidence";
        "he betrayed their trust" [syn: {confidence}]
     v 1: have confidence or faith in; "We can trust in God"; "Rely on
          your friends"; "bank on your good education"; "I swear
          by my grandmother's recipes" [syn: {swear}, {rely}, {bank}]
          [ant: {distrust}, {distrust}]
     2: allow without fear
     3: be confident about something; "I believe that he will come
        back from the war" [syn: {believe}]
     4: expect and wish; "I trust you will behave better from now
        on"; "I hope she understands that she cannot expect a
        raise" [syn: {hope}, {desire}]
     5: confer a trust upon; "The messenger was entrusted with the
        general's secret"; "I commit my soul to God" [syn: {entrust},
         {intrust}, {confide}, {commit}]
     6: extend credit to
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
