<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tub</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TUB
     
        {Technische Universita't Berlin}.  (Berlin technical
        university).
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tub \Tub\, n. [OE. tubbe; of Dutch or Low German origin; cf. LG.
   tubbe, D. tobbe.]
   1. An open wooden vessel formed with staves, bottom, and
      hoops; a kind of short cask, half barrel, or firkin,
      usually with but one head, -- used for various purposes.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The amount which a tub contains, as a measure of quantity;
      as, a tub of butter; a tub of camphor, which is about 1
      cwt., etc.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. Any structure shaped like a tub: as, a certain old form of
      pulpit; a short, broad boat, etc., -- often used jocosely
      or opprobriously.
      [1913 Webster]

            All being took up and busied, some in pulpits and
            some in tubs, in the grand work of preaching and
            holding forth.                        --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. A sweating in a tub; a tub fast. [Obs.] --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. A small cask; as, a tub of gin.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. A box or bucket in which coal or ore is sent up a shaft;
      -- so called by miners.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tub fast}, an old mode of treatment for the venereal
      disease, by sweating in a close place, or tub, and
      fasting. [Obs.] --Shak.

   {Tub wheel}, a horizontal water wheel, usually in the form of
      a short cylinder, to the circumference of which spiral
      vanes or floats, placed radially, are attached, turned by
      the impact of one or more streams of water, conducted so
      as to strike against the floats in the direction of a
      tangent to the cylinder.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tub \Tub\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tubbed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Tubbing}.]
   To plant or set in a tub; as, to tub a plant.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tub \Tub\, v. i.
   To make use of a bathing tub; to lie or be in a bath; to
   bathe. [Colloq.]
   [1913 Webster]

         Don't we all tub in England ?            --London
                                                  Spectator.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>vera</Id>
        <Name>Virtual Entity of Relevant Acronyms (Version 1.9, June 2002)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TUB
     Technische Universitaet Berlin (org.)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tub</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tub
     n 1: a relatively large open container that you fill with water
          and use to wash the body [syn: {bathtub}, {bathing tub},
           {bath}]
     2: a large open vessel for holding or storing liquids [syn: {vat}]
     3: the amount that a tub will hold; "a tub of water" [syn: {tubful}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
