<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tube</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tube</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tube
     
        1. &lt;hardware&gt; A {CRT} terminal.  Never used in the mainstream
        sense of TV; real hackers don't watch TV, except for Loony
        Toons, Rocky &amp; Bullwinkle, Trek Classic, the Simpsons, and the
        occasional cheesy old swashbuckler movie.
     
        2. &lt;electronics&gt; {electron tube}.
     
        3. &lt;jargon&gt; (IBM) To send a copy of something to someone
        else's terminal.  "Tube me that note."
     
        [{Jargon File}]
     
        (1996-02-05)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tube</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Subway \Sub"way`\, n.
   1. An underground way or gallery; especially, a passage under
      a street, in which water mains, gas mains, telegraph
      wires, etc., are conducted.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. An underground railroad, usually having trains powered by
      electricity provided by an electric line running through
      the underground tunnel. It is usually confined to the
      center portion of cities; -- called also {tube}, and in
      Britain, {underground}. In certain other countries (as in
      France or Russia) it is called the {metro}.
      [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tube</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tube \Tube\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tubed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Tubing}.]
   To furnish with a tube; as, to tube a well.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tube</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tube \Tube\, n. [L. tubus; akin to tuba a trumpet: cf F. tube.]
   1. A hollow cylinder, of any material, used for the
      conveyance of fluids, and for various other purposes; a
      pipe.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. A telescope. ``Glazed optic tube.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A vessel in animal bodies or plants, which conveys a fluid
      or other substance.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Bot.) The narrow, hollow part of a gamopetalous corolla.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. (Gun.) A priming tube, or friction primer. See under
      {Priming}, and {Friction}.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. (Steam Boilers) A small pipe forming part of the boiler,
      containing water and surrounded by flame or hot gases, or
      else surrounded by water and forming a flue for the gases
      to pass through.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. (Zo["o]l.)
      (a) A more or less cylindrical, and often spiral, case
          secreted or constructed by many annelids, crustaceans,
          insects, and other animals, for protection or
          concealment. See Illust. of {Tubeworm}.
      (b) One of the siphons of a bivalve mollusk.
          [1913 Webster]

   8. (Elec. Railways) A tunnel for a tube railway; also
      (Colloq.), a tube railway; a subway. [Chiefly Eng.]

   Note: In the New York area, the subways running under the
         Hudson River are sometimes referred to as the tube.
         [Webster 1913 Suppl. +PJC]

   {Capillary tube}, a tube of very fine bore. See {Capillary}.
      

   {Fire tube} (Steam Boilers), a tube which forms a flue.

   {Tube coral}. (Zo["o]l.) Same as {Tubipore}.

   {Tube foot} (Zo["o]l.), one of the ambulacral suckers of an
      echinoderm.

   {Tube plate}, or {Tube sheet} (Steam Boilers), a flue plate.
      See under {Flue}.

   {Tube pouch} (Mil.), a pouch containing priming tubes.

   {Tube spinner} (Zo["o]l.), any one of various species of
      spiders that construct tubelike webs. They belong to
      {Tegenaria}, {Agelena}, and allied genera.

   {Water tube} (Steam Boilers), a tube containing water and
      surrounded by flame or hot gases.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tube</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>jargon</Id>
        <Name>Jargon File (4.3.1, 29 Jun 2001)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tube 1. n. A CRT terminal. Never used in the mainstream sense of TV;
   real hackers don't watch TV, except for Loony Toons, Rocky &amp; Bullwinkle,
   Trek Classic, the Simpsons, Babylon 5, and the occasional cheesy old
   swashbuckler movie. 2. [IBM] To send a copy of something to someone
   else's terminal. "Tube me that note?"


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tube</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tube
     n 1: conduit consisting of a long hollow object (usually
          cylindrical) used to hold and conduct objects or liquids
          or gases [syn: {tubing}]
     2: electronic device consisting of a system of electrodes
        arranged in an evacuated glass or metal envelope [syn: {vacuum
        tube}, {thermionic vacuum tube}, {thermionic tube}, {electron
        tube}, {thermionic valve}]
     3: a hollow cylindrical shape [syn: {pipe}]
     4: (anatomy) any hollow cylindrical body structure [syn: {tube-shaped
        structure}]
     5: electric underground railway [syn: {metro}, {subway}, {underground}]
     v 1: provide with a tube or insert a tube into
     2: convey in a tube; "inside Paris, they used to tube mail"
     3: ride or float on an inflated tube; "We tubed down the river
        on a hot summer day"
     4: place or enclose in a tube
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
