<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>tunnel</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tunnel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Adit \Ad"it\, n. [L. aditus, fr. adire, ?aitum, to go to; ad +
   ire to go.]
   1. An entrance or passage. Specifically: The nearly
      horizontal opening by which a mine is entered, or by which
      water and ores are carried away; -- called also {drift}
      and {tunnel}.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Admission; approach; access. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Yourself and yours shall have
            Free adit.                            --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tunnel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tunnel \Tun"nel\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Tunneled}or {Tunnelled};
   p. pr. &amp; vb. n. {Tunneling} or {Tunnelling}.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. To form into a tunnel, or funnel, or to form like a
      tunnel; as, to tunnel fibrous plants into nests. --Derham.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To catch in a tunnel net.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To make an opening, or a passageway, through or under; as,
      to tunnel a mountain; to tunnel a river.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tunnel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tunnel \Tun"nel\, n. [F. tonnelle a semicircular, wagon-headed
   vault, a tunnel net, an arbor, OF. also tonnel; dim. of tonne
   a tun; -- so named from its resemblance to a tun in shape.
   See {Ton}.]
   1. A vessel with a broad mouth at one end, a pipe or tube at
      the other, for conveying liquor, fluids, etc., into casks,
      bottles, or other vessels; a funnel.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The opening of a chimney for the passage of smoke; a flue;
      a funnel.
      [1913 Webster]

            And one great chimney, whose long tunnel thence
            The smoke forth threw.                --Spenser.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. An artificial passage or archway for conducting canals or
      railroads under elevated ground, for the formation of
      roads under rivers or canals, and the construction of
      sewers, drains, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Mining) A level passage driven across the measures, or at
      right angles to veins which it is desired to reach; --
      distinguished from the drift, or gangway, which is led
      along the vein when reached by the tunnel.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Tunnel head} (Metal.), the top of a smelting furnace where
      the materials are put in.

   {Tunnel kiln}, a limekiln in which coal is burned, as
      distinguished from a flame kiln, in which wood or peat is
      used.

   {Tunnel net}, a net with a wide mouth at one end and narrow
      at the other.

   {Tunnel pit}, {Tunnel shaft}, a pit or shaft sunk from the
      top of the ground to the level of a tunnel, for drawing up
      the earth and stones, for ventilation, lighting, and the
      like.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tunnel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Tunnel \Tun"nel\, v. i.
   To make a tunnel; as, to tunnel under a river.
   [PJC]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>tunnel</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>tunnel
     n 1: a passageway through or under something, usually underground
          (especially one for trains or cars); "the tunnel reduced
          congestion at that intersection"
     2: a hole in the ground made by an animal for shelter [syn: {burrow}]
     v 1: move through by or as by digging; "burrow through the
          forest" [syn: {burrow}]
     2: force a way through
     [also: {tunnelling}, {tunnelled}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
