<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>turned</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>turned</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Turn \Turn\ (t[^u]rn), v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Turned}; p. pr. &amp;
   vb. n. {Turning}.] [OE. turnen, tournen, OF. tourner, torner,
   turner, F. tourner, LL. tornare, fr. L. tornare to turn in a
   lathe, to rounds off, fr. tornus a lathe, Gr. ? a turner's
   chisel, a carpenter's tool for drawing circles; probably akin
   to E. throw. See {Throw}, and cf. {Attorney}, {Return},
   {Tornado}, {Tour}, {Tournament}.]
   1. To cause to move upon a center, or as if upon a center; to
      give circular motion to; to cause to revolve; to cause to
      move round, either partially, wholly, or repeatedly; to
      make to change position so as to present other sides in
      given directions; to make to face otherwise; as, to turn a
      wheel or a spindle; to turn the body or the head.
      [1913 Webster]

            Turn the adamantine spindle round.    --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            The monarch turns him to his royal guest. --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To cause to present a different side uppermost or outmost;
      to make the upper side the lower, or the inside to be the
      outside of; to reverse the position of; as, to turn a box
      or a board; to turn a coat.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To give another direction, tendency, or inclination to; to
      direct otherwise; to deflect; to incline differently; --
      used both literally and figuratively; as, to turn the eyes
      to the heavens; to turn a horse from the road, or a ship
      from her course; to turn the attention to or from
      something. ``Expert when to advance, or stand, or, turn
      the sway of battle.'' --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thrice I deluded her, and turned to sport
            Her importunity.                      --Milton.
      [1913 Webster]

            My thoughts are turned on peace.      --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To change from a given use or office; to divert, as to
      another purpose or end; to transfer; to use or employ; to
      apply; to devote.
      [1913 Webster]

            Therefore he slew him, and turned the kingdom unto
            David.                                --1 Chron. x.
                                                  14.
      [1913 Webster]

            God will make these evils the occasion of a greater
            good, by turning them to advantage in this world.
                                                  --Tillotson.
      [1913 Webster]

            When the passage is open, land will be turned most
            to cattle; when shut, to sheep.       --Sir W.
                                                  Temple.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To change the form, quality, aspect, or effect of; to
      alter; to metamorphose; to convert; to transform; -- often
      with to or into before the word denoting the effect or
      product of the change; as, to turn a worm into a winged
      insect; to turn green to blue; to turn prose into verse;
      to turn a Whig to a Tory, or a Hindu to a Christian; to
      turn good to evil, and the like.
      [1913 Webster]

            The Lord thy God will turn thy captivity, and have
            compassion upon thee.                 --Deut. xxx.
                                                  3.
      [1913 Webster]

            And David said, O Lord, I pray thee, turn the
            counsel of Ahithophel into foolishness. --2 Sam. xv.
                                                  31.
      [1913 Webster]

            Impatience turns an ague into a fever. --Jer.
                                                  Taylor.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To form in a lathe; to shape or fashion (anything) by
      applying a cutting tool to it while revolving; as, to turn
      the legs of stools or tables; to turn ivory or metal.
      [1913 Webster]

            I had rather hear a brazen candlestick turned.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence, to give form to; to shape; to mold; to put in
      proper condition; to adapt. ``The poet's pen turns them to
      shapes.'' --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            His limbs how turned, how broad his shoulders spread
            !                                     --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

            He was perfectly well turned for trade. --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. Specifically:
      (a) To translate; to construe; as, to turn the Iliad.
          [1913 Webster]

                Who turns a Persian tale for half a crown.
                                                  --Pope.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To make acid or sour; to ferment; to curdle, etc.: as,
          to turn cider or wine; electricity turns milk quickly.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) To sicken; to nauseate; as, an emetic turns one's
          stomach.
          [1913 Webster]

   9. To make a turn about or around (something); to go or pass
      around by turning; as, to turn a corner.

            The ranges are not high or steep, and one can turn a
            kopje instead of cutting or tunneling through it.
                                                  --James Bryce.

   {To be turned of}, be advanced beyond; as, to be turned of
      sixty-six.

   {To turn a cold shoulder to}, to treat with neglect or
      indifference.

   {To turn a corner}, to go round a corner.

   {To turn adrift}, to cast off, to cease to care for.

   {To turn a flange} (Mech.), to form a flange on, as around a
      metal sheet or boiler plate, by stretching, bending, and
      hammering, or rolling the metal.

   {To turn against}.
      (a) To direct against; as, to turn one's arguments against
          himself.
      (b) To make unfavorable or hostile to; as, to turn one's
          friends against him.

   {To turn a hostile army}, {To turn the enemy's flank}, or the
      like (Mil.), to pass round it, and take a position behind
      it or upon its side.

   {To turn a penny}, or {To turn an honest penny}, to make a
      small profit by trade, or the like.

   {To turn around one's finger}, to have complete control of
      the will and actions of; to be able to influence at
      pleasure.

   {To turn aside}, to avert.

   {To turn away}.
      (a) To dismiss from service; to discard; as, to turn away
          a servant.
      (b) To avert; as, to turn away wrath or evil.

   {To turn back}.
      (a) To give back; to return.
          [1913 Webster]

                We turn not back the silks upon the merchants,
                When we have soiled them.         --Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) To cause to return or retrace one's steps; hence, to
          drive away; to repel. --Shak.

   {To turn down}.
      (a) To fold or double down.
      (b) To turn over so as to conceal the face of; as, to turn
          down cards.
      (c) To lower, or reduce in size, by turning a valve,
          stopcock, or the like; as, turn down the lights.

   {To turn in}.
      (a) To fold or double under; as, to turn in the edge of
          cloth.
      (b) To direct inwards; as, to turn the toes in when
          walking.
      (c) To contribute; to deliver up; as, he turned in a large
          amount. [Colloq.]

   {To turn in the mind}, to revolve, ponder, or meditate upon;
      -- with about, over, etc. `` Turn these ideas about in
      your mind.'' --I. Watts.

   {To turn off}.
      (a) To dismiss contemptuously; as, to turn off a sycophant
          or a parasite.
      (b) To give over; to reduce.
      (c) To divert; to deflect; as, to turn off the thoughts
          from serious subjects; to turn off a joke.
      (d) To accomplish; to perform, as work.
      (e) (Mech.) To remove, as a surface, by the process of
          turning; to reduce in size by turning.
      (f) To shut off, as a fluid, by means of a valve,
          stopcock, or other device; to stop the passage of; as,
          to turn off the water or the gas.

   {To turn one's coat}, to change one's uniform or colors; to
      go over to the opposite party.

   {To turn one's goods} or {To turn one's money}, and the like,
      to exchange in the course of trade; to keep in lively
      exchange or circulation; to gain or increase in trade.

   {To turn one's hand to}, to adapt or apply one's self to; to
      engage in.

   {To turn out}.
      (a) To drive out; to expel; as, to turn a family out of
          doors; to turn a man out of office.
          [1913 Webster]

                I'll turn you out of my kingdom.  -- Shak.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) to put to pasture, as cattle or horses.
      (c) To produce, as the result of labor, or any process of
          manufacture; to furnish in a completed state.
      (d) To reverse, as a pocket, bag, etc., so as to bring the
          inside to the outside; hence, to produce.
      (e) To cause to cease, or to put out, by turning a
          stopcock, valve, or the like; as, to turn out the
          lights.

   {To turn over}.
      (a) To change or reverse the position of; to overset; to
          overturn; to cause to roll over.
      (b) To transfer; as, to turn over business to another
          hand.
      (c) To read or examine, as a book, while, turning the
          leaves. ``We turned o'er many books together.''
          --Shak.
      (d) To handle in business; to do business to the amount
          of; as, he turns over millions a year. [Colloq.]

   {To turn over a new leaf}. See under {Leaf}.

   {To turn tail}, to run away; to retreat ignominiously.

   {To turn the back}, to flee; to retreat.

   {To turn the back on} or

   {To turn the back upon}, to treat with contempt; to reject or
      refuse unceremoniously.

   {To turn the corner}, to pass the critical stage; to get by
      the worst point; hence, to begin to improve, or to
      succeed.

   {To turn the die} or {To turn the dice}, to change fortune.
      

   {To turn the edge of} or {To turn the point of}, to bend over
      the edge or point of so as to make dull; to blunt.

   {To turn the head of} or {To turn the brain of}, to make
      giddy, wild, insane, or the like; to infatuate; to
      overthrow the reason or judgment of; as, a little success
      turned his head.

   {To turn the scale} or {To turn the balance}, to change the
      preponderance; to decide or determine something doubtful;
      to tip the balance.

   {To turn the stomach of}, to nauseate; to sicken.

   {To turn the tables}, to reverse the chances or conditions of
      success or superiority; to give the advantage to the
      person or side previously at a disadvantage.

   {To turn tippet}, to make a change. [Obs.] --B. Jonson.

   {To turn to profit}, {To turn to advantage}, etc., to make
      profitable or advantageous.

   {To turn turtle}, to capsize bottom upward; -- said of a
      vessel. [Naut. slang]

   {To turn under} (Agric.), to put, as soil, manure, etc.,
      underneath from the surface by plowing, digging, or the
      like.

   {To turn up}.
      (a) To turn so as to bring the bottom side on top; as, to
          turn up the trump.
      (b) To bring from beneath to the surface, as in plowing,
          digging, etc.
      (c) To give an upward curve to; to tilt; as, to turn up
          the nose.

   {To turn upon}, to retort; to throw back; as, to turn the
      arguments of an opponent upon himself.

   {To turn upside down}, to confuse by putting things awry; to
      throw into disorder.
      [1913 Webster]

            This house is turned upside down since Robin Ostler
            died.                                 --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>turned</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>turned
     adj 1: moved around an axis or center [ant: {unturned}]
     2: in an unpalatable state; "sour milk" [syn: {off}, {sour}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
