<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>twin</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twin \Twin\, v. i.
   To depart from a place or thing. [Obs.] ``Ere that we farther
   twin.'' --Chaucer.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twin \Twin\, a. [OE. twin double, AS. getwinne two and two, pl.,
   twins; akin to D. tweeling a twin, G. zwilling, OHG.
   zwiniling, Icel. tvennr, tvinnr, two and two, twin, and to
   AS. twi- two. See {Twice}, {Two}.]
   1. Being one of two born at a birth; as, a twin brother or
      sister.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Being one of a pair much resembling one another; standing
      the relation of a twin to something else; -- often
      followed by to or with. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. (Bot.) Double; consisting of two similar and corresponding
      parts.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Crystallog.) Composed of parts united according to some
      definite law of twinning. See {Twin}, n., 4.
      [1913 Webster]

   {Twin boat}, or {Twin ship} (Naut.), a vessel whose deck and
      upper works rest on two parallel hulls.

   {Twin crystal}. See {Twin}, n., 4.

   {Twin flower} (Bot.), a delicate evergreen plant ({Linn[ae]a
      borealis}) of northern climates, which has pretty,
      fragrant, pendulous flowers borne in pairs on a slender
      stalk.

   {Twin-screw steamer}, a steam vessel propelled by two screws,
      one on either side of the plane of the keel.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twin \Twin\, v. i. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Twinned}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Twinning}.]
   1. To bring forth twins. --Tusser.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To be born at the same birth. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twin \Twin\, n.
   1. One of two produced at a birth, especially by an animal
      that ordinarily brings forth but one at a birth; -- used
      chiefly in the plural, and applied to the young of beasts
      as well as to human young.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. pl. (Astron.) A sign and constellation of the zodiac;
      Gemini. See {Gemini}.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A person or thing that closely resembles another.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. (Crystallog.) A compound crystal composed of two or more
      crystals, or parts of crystals, in reversed position with
      reference to each other.
      [1913 Webster]

   Note: The relative position of the parts of a twin may be
         explained by supposing one part to be revolved 180[deg]
         about a certain axis (called the twinning axis), this
         axis being normal to a plane (called the twinning
         plane) which is usually one of the fundamental planes
         of the crystal. This revolution brings the two parts
         into parallel position, or vice versa. A contact twin
         is one in which the parts are united by a plane
         surface, called the composition face, which is usually
         the same as the twinning plane. A penetration twin is
         one in which the parts interpenetrate each other, often
         very irregularly. Twins are also called, according to
         form, cruciform, geniculated, etc.
         [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twin \Twin\, v. t.
   1. To cause to be twins, or like twins in any way. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

            Still we moved
            Together, twinned, as horse's ear and eye.
                                                  --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To separate into two parts; to part; to divide; hence, to
      remove; also, to strip; to rob. [Obs.]
      [1913 Webster]

            The life out of her body for to twin. --Chaucer.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twin</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>twin
     adj 1: being two identical [syn: {duplicate}, {matching}, {twin(a)},
             {twinned}]
     2: very similar [syn: {siamese}]
     n 1: either of two offspring born at the same time from the same
          pregnancy
     2: (astrology) a person who is born while the sun in in Gemini
        [syn: {Gemini}]
     3: a waterfall in the Snake River in southern Idaho [syn: {Twin
        Falls}]
     4: a duplicate copy [syn: {counterpart}, {similitude}]
     v 1: duplicate or match; "The polished surface twinned his face
          and chest in reverse" [syn: {duplicate}, {parallel}]
     2: bring two objects, ideas, or people together; "This fact is
        coupled to the other one"; "Matchmaker, can you match my
        daughter with a nice young man?"; "The student was paired
        with a partner for collaboration on the project" [syn: {match},
         {mate}, {couple}, {pair}]
     3: grow as twins; "twin crystals"
     4: give birth to twins
     [also: {twinning}, {twinned}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
