<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>twist</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twist</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twist \Twist\, n.
   1. The act of twisting; a contortion; a flexure; a
      convolution; a bending.
      [1913 Webster]

            Not the least turn or twist in the fibers of any one
            animal which does not render them more proper for
            that particular animal's way of life than any other
            cast or texture.                      --Addison.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. The form given in twisting.
      [1913 Webster]

            [He] shrunk at first sight of it; he found fault
            with the length, the thickness, and the twist.
                                                  --Arbuthnot.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. That which is formed by twisting, convoluting, or uniting
      parts. Specifically: 
      [1913 Webster]
      (a) A cord, thread, or anything flexible, formed by
          winding strands or separate things round each other.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) A kind of closely twisted, strong sewing silk, used by
          tailors, saddlers, and the like.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) A kind of cotton yarn, of several varieties.
          [1913 Webster]
      (d) A roll of twisted dough, baked.
          [1913 Webster]
      (e) A little twisted roll of tobacco.
          [1913 Webster]
      (f) (Weaving) One of the threads of a warp, -- usually
          more tightly twisted than the filling.
          [1913 Webster]
      (g) (Firearms) A material for gun barrels, consisting of
          iron and steel twisted and welded together; as,
          Damascus twist.
          [1913 Webster]
      (h) (Firearms &amp; Ord.) The spiral course of the rifling of
          a gun barrel or a cannon.
          [1913 Webster]
      (i) A beverage made of brandy and gin. [Slang]
          [1913 Webster]

   4. [OE.; -- so called as being a two-forked branch. See
      {Twist}, v. t.] A twig. [Obs.] --Chaucer. Fairfax.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. Act of imparting a turning or twisting motion, as to a
      pitched ball; also, the motion thus imparted; as, the
      twist of a billiard ball.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   6. A strong individual tendency, or bent; a marked
      inclination; a bias; -- often implying a peculiar or
      unusual tendency; as, a twist toward fanaticism.
      [Webster 1913 Suppl.]

   {Gain twist}, or {Gaining twist} (Firearms), twist of which
      the pitch is less, and the inclination greater, at the
      muzzle than at the breech.

   {Twist drill}, a drill the body of which is twisted like that
      of an auger. See Illust. of {Drill}.

   {Uniform twist} (Firearms), a twist of which the spiral
      course has an equal pitch throughout.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twist</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twist \Twist\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Twisted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Twisting}.] [OE. twisten, AS. twist a rope, as made of two
   (twisted) strands, fr. twi- two; akin to D. twist a quarrel,
   dissension, G. zwist, Dan. &amp; Sw. tvist, Icel. twistr the
   deuce in cards, tvistr distressed. See {Twice}, {Two}.]
   1. To contort; to writhe; to complicate; to crook spirally;
      to convolve.
      [1913 Webster]

            Twist it into a serpentine form.      --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to turn from the true form or meaning; to pervert;
      as, to twist a passage cited from an author.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To distort, as a solid body, by turning one part
      relatively to another about an axis passing through both;
      to subject to torsion; as, to twist a shaft.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To wreathe; to wind; to encircle; to unite by intertexture
      of parts. ``Longing to twist bays with that ivy.''
      --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

            There are pillars of smoke twisted about wreaths of
            flame.                                --T. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To wind into; to insinuate; -- used reflexively; as,
      avarice twists itself into all human concerns.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To unite by winding one thread, strand, or other flexible
      substance, round another; to form by convolution, or
      winding separate things round each other; as, to twist
      yarn or thread. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence, to form as if by winding one part around another;
      to wreathe; to make up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Was it not to this end
            That thou began'st to twist so fine a story? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To form into a thread from many fine filaments; as, to
      twist wool or cotton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twist</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twist \Twist\, v. i.
   1. To be contorted; to writhe; to be distorted by torsion; to
      be united by winding round each other; to be or become
      twisted; as, some strands will twist more easily than
      others.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To follow a helical or spiral course; to be in the form of
      a helix.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twist</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>twist
     n 1: an unforeseen development; "events suddenly took an awkward
          turn" [syn: {turn}, {turn of events}]
     2: an interpretation of a text or action; "they put an
        unsympathetic construction on his conduct" [syn: {construction}]
     3: any clever (deceptive) maneuver; "he would stoop to any
        device to win a point" [syn: {device}, {gimmick}]
     4: the act of rotating rapidly; "he gave the crank a spin"; "it
        broke off after much twisting" [syn: {spin}, {twirl}, {twisting},
         {whirl}]
     5: a sharp strain on muscles or ligaments; "the wrench to his
        knee occurred as he fell"; "he was sidelined with a
        hamstring pull" [syn: {wrench}, {pull}]
     6: a sharp bend in a line produced when a line having a loop is
        pulled tight [syn: {kink}, {twirl}]
     7: a miniature whirlpool or whirlwind resulting when the
        current of a fluid doubles back on itself [syn: {eddy}]
     8: a jerky pulling movement [syn: {wrench}]
     9: a hairdo formed by braiding or twisting the hair [syn: {braid},
         {plait}, {tress}]
     10: social dancing in which couples vigorously twist their hips
         and arms in time to the music; was popular in the 1960s;
         "they liked to dance the twist"
     11: the act of winding or twisting; "he put the key in the old
         clock and gave it a good wind" [syn: {wind}, {winding}]
     12: turning or twisting around (in place); "with a quick twist
         of his head he surveyed the room" [syn: {turn}]
     v 1: to move in a twisting or contorted motion, (especially when
          struggling); "The prisoner writhed in discomfort"; "The
          child tried to wriggle free from his aunt's embrace"
          [syn: {writhe}, {wrestle}, {wriggle}, {worm}, {squirm}]
     2: cause (a plastic object) to assume a crooked or angular
        form; "bend the rod"; "twist the dough into a braid"; "the
        strong man could turn an iron bar" [syn: {flex}, {bend}, {deform},
         {turn}] [ant: {unbend}]
     3: turn in the opposite direction; "twist a wire"
     4: form into a spiral shape; "The cord is all twisted" [syn: {twine},
         {distort}] [ant: {untwist}]
     5: form into twists; "Twist the bacon around the sausage"
     6: do the twist
     7: twist or pull violently or suddenly, especially so as to
        remove (something) from that to which it is attached or
        from where it originates; "wrench a window off its
        hinges"; "wrench oneself free from somebody's grip"; "a
        deep sigh was wrenched from his chest" [syn: {wrench}]
     8: practice sophistry; change the meaning of or be vague about
        in order to mislead or deceive [syn: {twist around}, {pervert},
         {convolute}, {sophisticate}]
     9: twist suddenly so as to sprain; "wrench one's ankle"; "The
        wrestler twisted his shoulder"; "the hikers sprained their
        ankles when they fell"; "I turned my ankle and couldn't
        walk for several days" [syn: {sprain}, {wrench}, {turn}, {wrick},
         {rick}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
