<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>twisted</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twisted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twist \Twist\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Twisted}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Twisting}.] [OE. twisten, AS. twist a rope, as made of two
   (twisted) strands, fr. twi- two; akin to D. twist a quarrel,
   dissension, G. zwist, Dan. &amp; Sw. tvist, Icel. twistr the
   deuce in cards, tvistr distressed. See {Twice}, {Two}.]
   1. To contort; to writhe; to complicate; to crook spirally;
      to convolve.
      [1913 Webster]

            Twist it into a serpentine form.      --Pope.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Hence, to turn from the true form or meaning; to pervert;
      as, to twist a passage cited from an author.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. To distort, as a solid body, by turning one part
      relatively to another about an axis passing through both;
      to subject to torsion; as, to twist a shaft.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. To wreathe; to wind; to encircle; to unite by intertexture
      of parts. ``Longing to twist bays with that ivy.''
      --Waller.
      [1913 Webster]

            There are pillars of smoke twisted about wreaths of
            flame.                                --T. Burnet.
      [1913 Webster]

   5. To wind into; to insinuate; -- used reflexively; as,
      avarice twists itself into all human concerns.
      [1913 Webster]

   6. To unite by winding one thread, strand, or other flexible
      substance, round another; to form by convolution, or
      winding separate things round each other; as, to twist
      yarn or thread. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   7. Hence, to form as if by winding one part around another;
      to wreathe; to make up.
      [1913 Webster]

            Was it not to this end
            That thou began'st to twist so fine a story? --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   8. To form into a thread from many fine filaments; as, to
      twist wool or cotton.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twisted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Twisted \Twist"ed\, a.
   Contorted; crooked spirally; subjected to torsion; hence,
   perverted.
   [1913 Webster]

   {Twisted curve} (Geom.), a curve of double curvature. See
      {Plane curve}, under {Curve}.

   {Twisted surface} (Geom.), a surface described by a straight
      line moving according to any law whatever, yet so that the
      consecutive positions of the line shall not be in one
      plane; a warped surface.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>twisted</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>twisted
     adj 1: wound or wrapped around something; "hair twined around her
            fingers"; "bulky with twisted stitches around the
            edges" [syn: {twined}]
     2: strained or wrenched out of normal shape; "old trees with
        contorted branches"; "scorched and distorted fragments of
        steel"; "trapped under twisted steel girders" [syn: {contorted},
         {distorted}]
     3: having an intended meaning altered or misrepresented; "many
        of the facts seemed twisted out of any semblance to
        reality"; "a perverted translation of the poem" [syn: {distorted},
         {misrepresented}, {perverted}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
