<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WordDefinition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://services.aonaware.com/webservices/">
  <Word>type</Word>
  <Definitions>
    <Definition>
      <Word>type</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>devils</Id>
        <Name>THE DEVIL'S DICTIONARY ((C)1911 Released April 15 1993)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>TYPE, n.  Pestilent bits of metal suspected of destroying
civilization and enlightenment, despite their obvious agency in this
incomparable dictionary.


</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>type</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>easton</Id>
        <Name>Easton's 1897 Bible Dictionary</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Type
   occurs only once in Scripture (1 Cor. 10:11, A.V. marg.). The
   Greek word _tupos_ is rendered "print" (John 20:25), "figure"
   (Acts 7:43; Rom. 5:14), "fashion" (Acts 7:44), "manner" (Acts
   23:25), "form" (Rom. 6:17), "example" or "ensample" (1 Cor.
   10:6, 11; Phil. 3:17; 1 Thess. 1:7; 2 Thess. 3:9; 1 Tim. 4:12).
   It properly means a "model" or "pattern" or "mould" into which
   clay or wax was pressed, that it might take the figure or exact
   shape of the mould. The word "type" is generally used to denote
   a resemblance between something present and something future,
   which is called the "antitype."
   
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>type</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>foldoc</Id>
        <Name>The Free On-line Dictionary of Computing (27 SEP 03)</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>type
     
        &lt;theory, programming&gt; (Or "data type") A set of values from
        which a variable, constant, function, or other expression may
        take its value.  A type is a classification of data that tells
        the {compiler} or {interpreter} how the programmer intends to
        use it.  For example, the process and result of adding two
        variables differs greatly according to whether they are
        integers, floating point numbers, or strings.
     
        Types supported by most programming languages include
        {integers} (usually limited to some range so they will fit in
        one {word} of storage), {Booleans}, {floating point numbers},
        and characters.  {Strings} are also common, and are
        represented as {lists} of characters in some languages.
     
        If s and t are types, then so is s -&gt; t, the type of
        {functions} from s to t; that is, give them a term of type s,
        functions of type s -&gt; t will return a term of type t.
     
        Some types are {primitive} - built-in to the language, with no
        visible internal structure - e.g. Boolean; others are
        composite - constructed from one or more other types (of
        either kind) - e.g. lists, {structures}, {unions}.
     
        Some languages provide {strong typing}, others allow {implicit
        type conversion} and/or {explicit type conversion}.
     
        (2002-02-22)
     
     
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>type</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>-type \-type\ [See {Type}, n.]
   A combining form signifying impressed form; stamp; print;
   type; typical form; representative; as in stereotype
   phototype, ferrotype, monotype.
   [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>type</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Type \Type\, n. [F. type; cf. It. tipo, from L. typus a figure,
   image, a form, type, character, Gr. ? the mark of a blow,
   impression, form of character, model, from the root of ? to
   beat, strike; cf. Skr. tup to hurt.]
   [1913 Webster]
   1. The mark or impression of something; stamp; impressed
      sign; emblem.
      [1913 Webster]

            The faith they have in tennis, and tall stockings,
            Short blistered breeches, and those types of travel.
                                                  --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   2. Form or character impressed; style; semblance.
      [1913 Webster]

            Thy father bears the type of king of Naples. --Shak.
      [1913 Webster]

   3. A figure or representation of something to come; a token;
      a sign; a symbol; -- correlative to antitype.
      [1913 Webster]

            A type is no longer a type when the thing typified
            comes to be actually exhibited.       --South.
      [1913 Webster]

   4. That which possesses or exemplifies characteristic
      qualities; the representative. Specifically:
      (a) (Biol.) A general form or structure common to a number
          of individuals; hence, the ideal representation of a
          species, genus, or other group, combining the
          essential characteristics; an animal or plant
          possessing or exemplifying the essential
          characteristics of a species, genus, or other group.
          Also, a group or division of animals having a certain
          typical or characteristic structure of body maintained
          within the group.
          [1913 Webster]

                Since the time of Cuvier and Baer . . . the
                whole animal kingdom has been universally held
                to be divisible into a small number of main
                divisions or types.               --Haeckel.
          [1913 Webster]
      (b) (Fine Arts) The original object, or class of objects,
          scene, face, or conception, which becomes the subject
          of a copy; esp., the design on the face of a medal or
          a coin.
          [1913 Webster]
      (c) (Chem.) A simple compound, used as a mode or pattern
          to which other compounds are conveniently regarded as
          being related, and from which they may be actually or
          theoretically derived.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: The fundamental types used to express the simplest and
         most essential chemical relations are hydrochloric
         acid, {HCl}; water, {H2O}; ammonia, {NH3}; and methane,
         {CH4}.
         [1913 Webster]

   5. (Typog.)
      (a) A raised letter, figure, accent, or other character,
          cast in metal or cut in wood, used in printing.
      (b) Such letters or characters, in general, or the whole
          quantity of them used in printing, spoken of
          collectively; any number or mass of such letters or
          characters, however disposed.
          [1913 Webster]

   Note: Type are mostly made by casting type metal in a mold,
         though some of the larger sizes are made from maple,
         mahogany, or boxwood. In the cut, a is the body; b, the
         face, or part from which the impression is taken; c,
         the shoulder, or top of the body; d, the nick
         (sometimes two or more are made), designed to assist
         the compositor in distinguishing the bottom of the face
         from t`e top; e, the groove made in the process of
         finishing, -- each type as cast having attached to the
         bottom of the body a jet, or small piece of metal
         (formed by the surplus metal poured into the mold),
         which, when broken off, leaves a roughness that
         requires to be removed. The fine lines at the top and
         bottom of a letter are technically called ceriphs, and
         when part of the face projects over the body, as in the
         letter f, the projection is called a kern.
         [1913 Webster] The type which compose an ordinary book
         font consist of Roman CAPITALS, small capitals, and
         lower-case letters, and Italic CAPITALS and lower-case
         letters, with accompanying figures, points, and
         reference marks, -- in all about two hundred
         characters. Including the various modern styles of
         fancy type, some three or four hundred varieties of
         face are made. Besides the ordinary Roman and Italic,
         some of the most important of the varieties are 
         [1913 Webster] Old English. Black Letter. Old Style.
         French Elzevir. Boldface. Antique. Clarendon. Gothic.
         Typewriter. Script.
         [1913 Webster] The smallest body in common use is
         diamond; then follow in order of size, pearl, agate,
         nonpareil, minion, brevier, bourgeois (or two-line
         diamond), long primer (or two-line pearl), small pica
         (or two-line agate), pica (or two-line nonpareil),
         English (or two-line minion), Columbian (or two-line
         brevier), great primer (two-line bourgeois), paragon
         (or two-line long primer), double small pica (or
         two-line small pica), double pica (or two-line pica),
         double English (or two-line English), double great
         primer (or two-line great primer), double paragon (or
         two-line paragon), canon (or two-line double pica).
         Above this, the sizes are called five-line pica,
         six-line pica, seven-line pica, and so on, being made
         mostly of wood. The following alphabets show the
         different sizes up to great primer.
         [1913 Webster] Brilliant . . abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz
         Diamond . . abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Pearl . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Agate . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Nonpareil . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Minion . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Brevier . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Bourgeois . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Long primer . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Small pica . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Pica . . . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz English . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Columbian . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz Great primer . . .
         abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz
         [1913 Webster] The foregoing account is conformed to
         the designations made use of by American type founders,
         but is substantially correct for England. Agate,
         however, is called ruby, in England, where, also, a
         size intermediate between nonpareil and minion is
         employed, called emerald.
         [1913 Webster]

   {Point system of type bodies} (Type Founding), a system
      adopted by the type founders of the United States by which
      the various sizes of type have been so modified and
      changed that each size bears an exact proportional
      relation to every other size. The system is a modification
      of a French system, and is based on the pica body. This
      pica body is divided into twelfths, which are termed
      ``points,'' and every type body consist of a given number
      of these points. Many of the type founders indicate the
      new sizes of type by the number of points, and the old
      names are gradually being done away with. By the point
      system type founders cast type of a uniform size and
      height, whereas formerly fonts of pica or other type made
      by different founders would often vary slightly so that
      they could not be used together. There are no type in
      actual use corresponding to the smaller theoretical sizes
      of the point system. In some cases, as in that of ruby,
      the term used designates a different size from that
      heretofore so called.
      [1913 Webster] 1 American 9 Bourgeois [bar] [bar] 11/2
      German [bar] 2 Saxon 10 Long Primer [bar] [bar] 21/2 Norse
      [bar] 3 Brilliant 11 Small Pica [bar] [bar] 31/2 Ruby 12
      Pica [bar] [bar] 4 Excelsior [bar] 41/2 Diamond 14 English
      [bar] [bar] 5 Pearl 16 Columbian [bar] [bar] 51/2 Agate
      [bar] 6 Nonpareil 18 Great Primer [bar] [bar] 7 Minion
      [bar] 8 Brevier 20 Paragon [bar] [bar] Diagram of the
      "points" by which sizes of Type are graduated in the
      "Point System".
      [1913 Webster]

   {Type founder}, one who casts or manufacture type.

   {Type foundry}, {Type foundery}, a place for the manufacture
      of type.

   {Type metal}, an alloy used in making type, stereotype
      plates, etc., and in backing up electrotype plates. It
      consists essentially of lead and antimony, often with a
      little tin, nickel, or copper.

   {Type wheel}, a wheel having raised letters or characters on
      its periphery, and used in typewriters, printing
      telegraphs, etc.

   {Unity of type} (Biol.), that fundamental agreement in
      structure which is seen in organic beings of the same
      class, and is quite independent of their habits of life.
      --Darwin.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>type</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>gcide</Id>
        <Name>The Collaborative International Dictionary of English v.0.44</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>Type \Type\, v. t. [imp. &amp; p. p. {Typed}; p. pr. &amp; vb. n.
   {Typing}.]
   1. To represent by a type, model, or symbol beforehand; to
      prefigure. [R.] --White (Johnson).
      [1913 Webster]

   2. To furnish an expression or copy of; to represent; to
      typify. [R.]
      [1913 Webster]

            Let us type them now in our own lives. --Tennyson.
      [1913 Webster]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
    <Definition>
      <Word>type</Word>
      <Dictionary>
        <Id>wn</Id>
        <Name>WordNet (r) 2.0</Name>
      </Dictionary>
      <WordDefinition>type
     n 1: a subdivision of a particular kind of thing; "what type of
          sculpture do you prefer?" [ant: {antitype}]
     2: a person of a specified kind (usually with many
        eccentricities); "a real character"; "a strange
        character"; "a friendly eccentric"; "the capable type"; "a
        mental case" [syn: {character}, {eccentric}, {case}]
     3: (biology) the taxonomic group whose characteristics are used
        to define the next higher taxon
     4: printed characters; "small type is hard to read"
     5: a small metal block bearing a raised character on one end;
        produces a printed character when inked and pressed on
        paper; "he dropped a case of type, so they made him pick
        them up"
     6: all of the tokens of the same symbol; "the word `element'
        contains five different types of character"
     v 1: write by means of a keyboard with types; "type the
          acceptance letter, please" [syn: {typewrite}]
     2: identify as belonging to a certain type; "Such people can
        practically be typed" [syn: {typecast}]
</WordDefinition>
    </Definition>
  </Definitions>
</WordDefinition>
